<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000256547"><TermName>Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(birt-hog-doo-BAY SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which benign (not cancer) skin lesions called fibrofolliculomas form in the hair follicles on the face, neck, and chest. Patients with Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome have an increased risk of kidney cancer and benign kidney tumors. They may also have lung cysts and a condition called a pneumothorax, in which all or part of the lung collapses. The signs and symptoms of Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome usually do not appear until young adulthood. It is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called FLCN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731523" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731522" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793770" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing areas of the body affected by Birt-Hogg-Dube syndrome, including the skin, lungs, and kidneys." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Areas of the body affected by Birt-Hogg-Dube (BHD) syndrome. BHD syndrome is an inherited disorder that causes an increased risk of kidney cancer, benign (not cancer) skin lesions, collapsed lungs, and lung cysts.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799115" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observan las áreas del cuerpo afectadas por el síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé, como la piel, los pulmones y los riñones." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Áreas del cuerpo afectadas por el síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé (BHD). El síndrome de BDH es un trastorno hereditario que aumenta el riesgo de cáncer de riñón, lesiones benignas (no cancerosas) en la piel, colapso pulmonar (pulmón que se desinfla) y quistes pulmonares.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman fibrofoliculomas en la piel, es decir, lesiones benignas (no cancerosas) en los folículos pilosos de la cara, el cuello y el tórax. Los pacientes con síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé tienen mayor riesgo de presentar cáncer de riñón y tumores benignos de riñón. También pueden tener quistes en los pulmones y una afección llamada neumotórax, por la que se desinfla todo el pulmón o una parte de este. Los signos y síntomas del síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dubé no suelen aparecer hasta la edad adulta temprana. La causa del síndrome es una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama <GeneName>FLCN</GeneName>.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-08-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/2322/birt-hogg-dube-syndrome">Birt-Hogg-Dube syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/birt-hogg-dube-syndrome/">Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
