<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000257519"><TermName>head and neck cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in certain areas of the head and neck, including tissues in the nasal cavity    (the hollow space inside the nose), sinuses, lips, mouth, salivary glands, throat, and larynx (voice box). Most head and neck cancers begin in squamous cells (thin, flat cells that line the moist surfaces of the head and neck). The most important factors that increase a person’s risk of developing head and neck cancer are tobacco use, heavy alcohol use, and infection with certain types of high-risk human papillomavirus (HPV).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710297" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;head and neck cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710298" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cabeza y cuello&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814842" type="image/jpeg" alt="Head and neck cancer regions; drawing shows areas of the head and neck where cancer can occur, including the paranasal sinuses, nasal cavity, oral cavity, lips, tongue, salivary glands, larynx (voice box), and pharynx. The pharynx includes the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Cancers of the head and neck can form in the tissues of the paranasal sinuses, nasal cavity, oral cavity, lips, tongue, salivary glands, larynx (voice box), and pharynx. The pharynx includes the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749384" type="image/jpeg" alt="Regiones en el cáncer de cabeza y cuello. Dibujo del perfil de la cabeza y el cuello de una persona en el que se señalan las áreas donde se puede formar un cáncer. Estas áreas son los senos paranasales, la cavidad nasal, la cavidad oral, los labios, la lengua, las glándulas salivales, la laringe y las tres partes de la faringe: la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Los cánceres de cabeza y cuello se pueden formar en los tejidos de los senos paranasales, la cavidad nasal, la cavidad oral, los labios, la lengua, las glándulas salivales, la laringe y las tres partes de la faringe: la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de cabeza y cuello</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en ciertas áreas de la cabeza y el cuello, incluso en tejidos de la cavidad nasal (espacio hueco dentro de la nariz), senos paranasales, labios, boca, glándulas salivares, garganta y laringe. La mayoría de los cánceres de cabeza y cuello comienzan en las células escamosas (células delgadas y planas que revisten las superficies húmedas de la cabeza y el cuello). Los factores más importantes que aumentan el riesgo de una persona de presentar cáncer de cabeza y cuello son el consumo de tabaco, el consumo excesivo de bebidas alcohólicas y la infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) de riesgo alto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-08-01</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/head-and-neck">Head and Neck Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello">Cáncer de cabeza y cuello</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
