<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000269448"><TermName>palliative care</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PA-lee-uh-tiv kayr)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Care given to improve the quality of life and help reduce pain in people who have a serious or life-threatening disease, such as cancer. The goal of palliative care is to prevent or treat, as early as possible, the symptoms of the disease and the side effects caused by treatment of the disease. It also attends to the psychological, social, and spiritual problems caused by the disease or its treatment. For cancer, palliative care may include therapies, such as surgery, radiation therapy, or chemotherapy, to remove, shrink, or slow the growth of a tumor that is causing pain. It may also include family and caregiver support. Palliative care may be given with other treatments from the time of diagnosis until the end of life.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710146" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;palliative care&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710145" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cuidados paliativos&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/><SpanishTermName>cuidados paliativos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Atención que se brinda para mejorar la calidad de vida y ayudar a aliviar el dolor de las personas que tienen una enfermedad grave o potencialmente mortal, como el cáncer. La meta de los cuidados paliativos es prevenir o tratar lo antes posible los síntomas de una enfermedad y los efectos secundarios del tratamiento. También atienden a los problemas psicológicos, sociales y espirituales provocados por la enfermedad o su tratamiento. En el caso del cáncer, es posible que los cuidados paliativos incluyan tratamientos, como la cirugía, la radioterapia o la quimioterapia, para extirpar, reducir o hacer más lento el crecimiento de un tumor que está causando dolor. A veces también incluye el apoyo a la familia y a los cuidadores. En ocasiones, los cuidados paliativos se administran junto con otros tratamientos desde el momento del diagnóstico hasta el final de la vida. También se llama asistencia paliativa y atención paliativa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2002-12-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-03-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/advanced-cancer/care-choices/palliative-care-fact-sheet">Palliative Care in Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/cancer-avanzado/opciones-de-cuidado/hoja-informativa-cuidados-paliativos">Cuidados paliativos durante el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping">Coping with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq/information-summaries/supportive-care">PDQ® Cancer Information Summaries: Supportive and Palliative Care</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar">Cómo hacer frente al cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq/sumarios-de-informacion/cuidados-medicos-apoyo">Sumarios del PDQ® de información sobre el cáncer: Cuidados médicos de apoyo</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
