<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270742"><TermName>targeted therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TAR-geh-ted THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment that uses drugs or other substances to target specific molecules that cancer cells need to survive and spread. Targeted therapies work in different ways to treat cancer. Some stop cancer cells from growing by interrupting signals that cause them to grow and divide, stopping signals that help form blood vessels, delivering cell-killing substances to cancer cells, or starving cancer cells of hormones they need to grow. Other targeted therapies help the immune system kill cancer cells or directly cause cancer cell death. Most targeted therapies are either small-molecule drugs or monoclonal antibodies. Also called molecularly targeted therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710252" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;targeted therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710251" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia dirigida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>terapia dirigida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento en el que se usan medicamentos u otras sustancias dirigidas a  dianas moleculares (moléculas específicas) que las células cancerosas necesitan para sobrevivir y diseminarse. Las terapias dirigidas actúan de diferentes maneras en el tratamiento del cáncer. Algunas detienen la multiplicación de las células cancerosas porque interrumpen las señales que hacen que se desarrollen y se dividan, previenen la formación de vasos sanguíneos, transportan sustancias que destruyen las células cancerosas o impiden la elaboración  de las hormonas que estas necesitan para su desarrollo. Otras terapias dirigidas ayudan al sistema inmunitario a destruir  células cancerosas, o las destruyen de manera directa. La mayoría de estas terapias consisten en medicamentos micromoleculares (molécula pequeña) o anticuerpos monoclonales. También se llama terapia molecular dirigida, tratamiento dirigido y tratamiento selectivo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-03-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/targeted-therapies">Targeted Therapy to Treat Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/terapia-dirigida/hoja-informativa-terapias-dirigidas">Terapias dirigidas contra el cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000741769" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">precision medicine</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000741769" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">medicina de precisión</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
