<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270733"><TermName>autologous stem cell transplant</TermName><TermPronunciation>(aw-TAH-luh-gus ... TRANZ-plant)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a patient’s healthy stem cells (blood-forming cells) are collected from the blood or bone marrow before treatment, stored, and then given back to the patient after treatment. An autologous stem cell transplant replaces a patient’s stem cells that were destroyed by treatment with radiation or high doses of chemotherapy. An autologous stem cell transplant is most often used to treat blood cancers, such as leukemia and lymphoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;autologous stem cell transplant&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710192" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trasplante autógeno de células madre&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806255" type="image/jpeg" alt="Autologous stem cell transplant; (Panel 1): Drawing of stem cells being removed from a patient’s blood using an apheresis machine. Blood is collected from a vein in the arm and flows through the machine that removes the stem cells. The remaining blood is returned to a vein in the other arm. (Panel 2): Drawing of a health care provider giving a patient chemotherapy to kill cancer cells. The chemotherapy is given as an infusion through a catheter in the patient’s chest. (Panel 3): Drawing of a patient receiving stem cells as an infusion through a catheter in the chest." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Autologous stem cell transplant. (Step 1): Blood is taken from a vein in the patient’s arm and flows through an apheresis machine that removes the stem cells. The remaining blood is returned to a vein in the other arm. (Step 2): The patient receives chemotherapy to kill cancer cells. Healthy cells, including blood-forming cells, are also destroyed by the cancer treatment. (Step 3): After the patient completes chemotherapy or radiation therapy (not shown), the stem cells are given back to the patient to replace the blood-forming cells that were destroyed by the cancer treatment. The stem cells help the bone marrow recover and make healthy blood cells.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808550" type="image/jpeg" alt="Trasplante autógeno de células madre; (Panel 1): en la imagen se observa la extracción de células madre de la sangre de un paciente mediante una máquina de aféresis. Se extrae sangre de una vena del brazo y esta pasa por una máquina que separa las células madre; la sangre que queda se devuelve por una vena del otro brazo. (Panel 2): en la imagen se muestra cómo un proveedor de atención de la salud administra quimioterapia a un paciente para destruir las células cancerosas. La quimioterapia se administra al paciente mediante infusión a través de un catéter en el pecho. (Panel 3): en la imagen se observa a un paciente que recibe células madre mediante infusión a través de un catéter en el pecho." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Trasplante autógeno de células madre. Paso 1: se extrae sangre de una vena del  brazo del paciente y pasa por una máquina de aféresis que separa las células madre. Luego, la sangre que queda se devuelve por una vena del otro brazo. Paso 2: el paciente recibe quimioterapia para destruir las células cancerosas. El tratamiento contra el cáncer también destruye las células sanas, incluso las células formadoras de la sangre. Paso 3: después de que el paciente termina la quimioterapia o la radioterapia (no se muestra), las células madre se devuelven al paciente para  reemplazar las células formadoras de la sangre que el tratamiento contra el cáncer destruyó. Las células madre ayudan a que la médula ósea se recupere y produzca células sanguíneas sanas.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>trasplante autógeno de células madre</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se extraen células madre (células formadoras de sangre) sanas de la sangre o la médula ósea de un paciente antes del tratamiento. Estas células se almacenan y se devuelven al paciente después del tratamiento. El trasplante autógeno de células madre reemplaza las células madre del paciente destruidas por el tratamiento con radiación o dosis altas de quimioterapia. Este tipo de trasplante a menudo se usa para el tratamiento de los cánceres en la sangre, como las leucemias y los linfomas. También se llama autotrasplante de células madre, trasplante autogénico de células madre y trasplante de células madre autógenas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-02-08</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/stem-cell-transplant" UseWith="en">Stem Cell Transplants in Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/trasplante-de-celulas-madre">Trasplantes de células madre en el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
