<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270800"><TermName>Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cancer of the immune system that is marked by the presence of a type of cell called the Reed-Sternberg cell. The two major types of Hodgkin lymphoma are classic Hodgkin lymphoma and nodular lymphocyte-predominant Hodgkin lymphoma. Signs and symptoms include painless, swollen lymph nodes, an enlarged spleen,  fever, weight loss, fatigue, and night sweats.  Also called Hodgkin disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710286" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710285" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma de Hodgkin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000576466" type="image/jpeg" alt="Reed-Sternberg cell; photograph shows normal lymphocytes compared with a Reed-Sternberg cell." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Reed-Sternberg cell. Reed-Sternberg cells are large, abnormal lymphocytes (a type of white blood cell) that may contain more than one nucleus. These cells are found in people with Hodgkin lymphoma. Reed-Sternberg cells are also called Hodgkin and Reed-Sternberg cells.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000583752" type="image/jpeg" alt="Célula de Reed-Sternberg. En la fotografía se observan linfocitos normales y se los compara con una célula de Reed-Sternberg." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Célula de Reed-Sternberg. Las células de Reed-Sternberg son linfocitos (tipo de glóbulo blanco) grandes y anormales que en ocasiones contienen más de un núcleo. Estas células se encuentran en personas con linfoma de Hodgkin. Las células de Reed-Sternberg también se llaman células de Hodgkin y Reed-Sternberg.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>linfoma de Hodgkin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer del sistema inmunitario que se caracteriza por la presencia de un tipo de célula llamada célula de Reed-Sternberg. Los dos tipos principales de linfoma de Hodgkin son el linfoma de Hodgkin clásico y el linfoma de Hodgkin con predominio linfocítico nodular. Los signos y síntomas son ganglios linfáticos inflamados que no duelen, bazo agrandado, fiebre, pérdida de peso, cansancio y sudor nocturno. También se llama enfermedad de Hodgkin y linfoma hodgkiniano.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-05-28</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
