<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270863">
  <TermName>multiple endocrine adenomatosis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MUL-tih-pul EN-doh-krin A-deh-NOH-muh-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that affects the endocrine glands and can cause tumors in the parathyroid and pituitary glands and the pancreas. These tumors  are usually benign (not cancer). They cause the glands to secrete high levels of hormones, which can lead to other medical problems, such as kidney stones, fertility problems, and severe ulcers. In some cases, tumors inside the pancreas can become malignant (cancer). Also called MEN1 syndrome, multiple endocrine neoplasia type 1 syndrome, and Wermer syndrome.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709798" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;multiple endocrine adenomatosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709797" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenomatosis endocrina múltiple&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813445" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing shows parts of the body affected by MEN1 syndrome, including the pituitary gland, parathyroid glands, and pancreas. There is also an inset that shows the back view of the thyroid gland with the four pea-sized parathyroid glands." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Multiple endocrine neoplasia 1 (MEN1) syndrome is a rare, inherited disorder that affects the endocrine glands or organs. MEN1 syndrome usually causes pituitary gland, parathyroid gland, or pancreas tumors. The tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813446" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo del cuerpo de una niña donde se observan partes del cuerpo que afecta el síndrome de NEM1, como la hipófisis, las glándulas paratiroideas y el páncreas. En un recuadro se muestra una vista posterior y agrandada de la glándula tiroidea y se señalan las cuatro glándulas paratiroideas del tamaño de una arveja." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple 1 (NEM1 o MEN1) es un trastorno hereditario raro que afecta las glándulas y órganos endocrinos. Por lo general, el síndrome de NEM1 causa tumores en la hipófisis, las glándulas paratiroideas o el páncreas. Los tumores pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>adenomatosis endocrina múltiple</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro que afecta las glándulas endocrinas y causa tumores en las glándulas paratiroideas, la hipófisis y el páncreas. Por lo general, estos tumores son benignos (no cancerosos) y hacen que las glándulas produzcan concentraciones altas de hormonas; es posible que esto cause otros problemas médicos, como cálculos renales, alteraciones reproductivas y úlceras graves.   En algunos casos, los tumores dentro del páncreas se vuelven malignos (cancerosos). También se llama adenomatosis múltiple endocrina, AEE, AME, síndrome de NEM1, síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple de tipo 1 y síndrome de Wermer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-08-22</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/3829/multiple-endocrine-neoplasia-type-1">Multiple endocrine neoplasia type 1 (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000799404" url="/types/multiple-endocrine-neoplasia/patient-child-men-syndromes-treatment-pdq">Childhood Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia (MEN) Syndromes Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000800622" url="/espanol/tipos/neoplasia-endocrina-multiple/paciente-tratamiento-sindromes-nem-infantil-pdq">Tratamiento de los síndromes de neoplasia endocrina múltiple infantiles</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
