<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000285933"><TermName>microsatellite instability</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MY-kroh-SA-teh-lite in-stuh-BIH-lih-tee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A change that occurs in certain cells (such as cancer cells) in which the number of repeated DNA bases in a microsatellite (a short, repeated sequence of DNA) is different from what it was when the microsatellite was inherited. Microsatellite instability may be caused by mistakes that don’t get corrected when DNA is copied in a cell. It is found most often in colorectal cancer, gastric cancer, and endometrial cancer, but it may also be found in many other types of cancer. Knowing whether a cancer has microsatellite instability may help plan the best treatment. Also called MSI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A characteristic of cells that contain an abnormality in DNA mismatch repair. The presence of microsatellite instability can be a marker of a germline pathogenic variant in one of the DNA mismatch repair genes, as in the case of Lynch syndrome. Microsatellite instability can also occur sporadically. Also called MSI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710102" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;microsatellite instability&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710101" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inestabilidad microsatelital&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inestabilidad microsatelital</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio que se presenta en ciertas células (como las células cancerosas) en el cual el número de bases repetidas del ADN en un microsatélite (secuencia de ADN corta y repetida) es diferente del número que se heredó. Es posible que la causa de la inestabilidad microsatelital sean errores que no se corrigen cuando se copia el ADN de la célula. Esta alteración se encuentra más a menudo en el cáncer colorrectal, el cáncer de estómago y el cáncer de endometrio, pero también se encuentra en otros tipos de cáncer. Saber si un cáncer tiene inestabilidad microsatelital quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento más eficaz. También se llama IMS e inestabilidad de los microsatélites.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Característica de las células que exhiben una anormalidad en la reparación de los errores de emparejamiento del DNA. La inestabilidad microsatelital se usa como marcador de una variante patógena de la línea germinal en uno de los genes que participan en la reparación de los errores de emparejamiento del DNA, como en el síndrome de Lynch. La inestabilidad microsatelital también ocurre de manera esporádica. También se llama IMS e inestabilidad de los microsatélites.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-02-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-10-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
