<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000304688">
  <TermName>Klinefelter syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KLINE-fel-ter SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A genetic disorder in males caused by having one or more extra X chromosomes. Males with this disorder may have larger than normal breasts, a lack of facial and body hair, a rounded body type, and small testicles. They may learn to speak much later than other children and may have difficulty learning to read and write. Klinefelter syndrome increases the risk of developing extragonadal germ cell tumors and breast cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000710090" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Klinefelter syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000710089" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Klinefelter&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Klinefelter</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno genético que ocurre en varones cuando tienen más cromosomas X que lo normal. Los varones con este trastorno a veces tienen mamas más grandes que lo normal, poco vello en la cara y el cuerpo, figura corporal redondeada y testículos pequeños. Es posible que se demoren más que otros niños para aprender a hablar y tal vez tengan dificultades para aprender a leer y escribir. El síndrome de Klinefelter aumenta el riesgo de tumores extragonadales de células germinativas y de cáncer de mama.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-05-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2007-09-21</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/8705/klinefelter-syndrome">Klinefelter syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/klinefelter-syndrome/">Klinefelter syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13471/sindrome-de-klinefelter">Síndrome de Klinefelter (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/klinefelterssyndrome.html">Síndrome de Klinefelter (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
