<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000305992"><TermName>hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee LY-oh-MY-oh-muh-TOH-sis ... REE-nul sel KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which benign (not cancer) skin lesions called leiomyomas form in the smooth muscle tissue around the hair follicles. They usually form on the arms, legs, chest, and abdomen. Benign leiomyomas may also form as fibroids in the uterus in females. People with hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer have an increased risk of kidney cancer. The signs and symptoms of hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer usually do not appear until young adulthood. Hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer is caused by a mutation in the <GeneName>FH</GeneName> gene. It is inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. Also called HLRCC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710180" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710179" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leiomiomatosis hereditaria y cáncer de células renales&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793769" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing areas of the body affected by hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer, including the skin, kidneys, and uterus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Areas of the body affected by hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer (HLRCC). HLRCC is an inherited disorder that causes an increased risk of kidney cancer. It can also cause lesions in the skin and uterus (in females).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799114" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observan las áreas del cuerpo afectadas por la leiomiomatosis hereditaria y el cáncer de células renales, como la piel, los riñones y el útero." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Áreas del cuerpo afectadas por la leiomiomatosis hereditaria y el cáncer de células renales (CCR). El CCR es un trastorno hereditario que aumenta el riesgo de cáncer de riñón. A veces, también produce lesiones en la piel y el útero.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>leiomiomatosis hereditaria y cáncer de células renales</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman leiomiomas (lesiones en la piel que son benignas, es decir, no cancerosas) en el tejido muscular liso alrededor de los folículos del pelo. Por lo general, las lesiones aparecen  en los brazos, las piernas, el tórax y el abdomen. También es posible que los leiomiomas benignos se formen como fibromas uterinos en las mujeres. Las personas con este trastorno presentan mayor riesgo de cáncer de riñón. Los signos y síntomas de la leiomiomatosis hereditaria y cáncer de células renales no se suelen observar hasta la edad adulta joven. Este trastorno hereditario se produce por una mutación en el gen <GeneName>FH</GeneName> y es de herencia autosómica dominante. También se llama HLRCC y leiomiomatosis hereditaria y carcinoma de células renales.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-12-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10096/hereditary-leiomyomatosis-and-renal-cell-cancer">Hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12840/leiomiomatosis-hereditaria-y-cancer-de-celulas-renales">Leiomiomatosis hereditaria y cáncer de células renales (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/hereditary-leiomyomatosis-and-renal-cell-cancer/">Hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
