<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000306512"><TermName>Gliadel Wafer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GLY-uh-del WAY-fer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with surgery and radiation therapy to treat high-grade glioma that has not already been treated and with surgery to treat glioblastoma multiforme that has recurred (come back). Gliadel Wafer is a form of carmustine contained in a wafer. The wafer has a coating that dissolves slowly and releases carmustine directly into the area where the brain tumor was removed. This form may have fewer side effects and work better than other forms of carmustine. Gliadel Wafer is a type of alkylating agent and a type of nitrosourea. Also called carmustine implant and polifeprosan 20 carmustine implant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731613" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Gliadel Wafer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731612" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oblea Gliadel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>oblea Gliadel</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con cirugía y radioterapia para el tratamiento del glioma de grado alto que no se ha tratado, además se usa con cirugía para el tratamiento del glioblastoma multiforme que recidivó (volvió). La oblea Gliadel es una forma de carmustina contenida  en una oblea. La cubierta de la oblea se disuelve lentamente y libera la carmustina de manera directa en el área del encéfalo donde se extirpó el tumor. Es posible que esta forma de la carmustina produzca menos efectos secundarios y tal vez sea más eficaz que otras formas del medicamento. La carmustina es un tipo de alquilante y de nitrosourea. También se llama implante de carmustina e implante de polifeprosán 20 con carmustina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-12-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000762277" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/carmustineimplant">Carmustine Implant</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
