<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000321374">
  <TermName>fatigue</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(fuh-TEEG)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An extreme sense of tiredness and lack of energy that can interfere with a person's usual daily activities. A person with fatigue may feel weak, worn out, heavy, slow, or run down. They may also have trouble speaking or concentrating, short-term memory loss, and mood or emotional changes. There are many causes of fatigue, including anemia, poor nutrition, pain, anxiety, depression, sleep or thyroid disorders, and taking certain medicines. Fatigue may also be caused by cancer or cancer treatment. Certain types of fatigue, including cancer-related fatigue, may not be completely relieved by sleep and may last for a long time after treatment ends.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000731813" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fatigue&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000731812" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fatiga&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>fatiga</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Sensación extrema de cansancio y falta de energía, que puede interferir con las actividades cotidianas de una persona. Es posible que la persona con fatiga se encuentre débil, agotada, lenta, exhausta o con sensación de pesadez. En ocasiones, también presenta dificultad para hablar o concentrarse, pérdida de la memoria a corto plazo y cambios emocionales o de estado de ánimo. Hay muchas causas de fatiga, como la anemia, la  nutrición deficiente, el dolor, la ansiedad, la depresión, los trastornos del sueño o de la tiroides y ciertos medicamentos. A veces, también se produce por el cáncer o el tratamiento de este. Ciertos tipos de fatiga, como la relacionada con el cáncer, quizás no se alivien por completo al dormir y  persistan mucho tiempo después de que termine el tratamiento. También se llama cansancio excesivo y cansancio extremo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-07-26</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-02-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fatigue">Cancer Fatigue</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fatiga">La fatiga y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
