<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000322883">
  <TermName>sensitivity</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SEN-sih-TIH-vih-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, sensitivity may describe how well a test can detect a specific disease or condition in people who actually have the disease or condition. No test has 100% sensitivity because some people who have the disease or condition will not be identified by the test (false-negative test result). Sensitivity may also refer to the way the body reacts to the environment or to drugs, chemicals, or other substances. For example, a person who is sensitive to the sun may have skin that burns easily or get a rash when exposed to the sun. A person who is sensitive to caffeine may need only small amounts of it to feel its effects.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The frequency with which a test shows a true positive result among individuals who actually have the disease or the genetic variant in question. A test with high sensitivity has a low false-negative rate, which means it does a good job of correctly identifying affected individuals or carriers of a genetic variant.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000731826" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sensitivity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000731827" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sensibilidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sensibilidad</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En medicina, la sensibilidad describe qué tan bien una prueba puede detectar una enfermedad o afección determinada en las personas que tienen la enfermedad o afección. Ninguna prueba es 100 % sensible porque no logra identificar a algunas personas que tienen la enfermedad o afección (resultado negativo falso). La sensibilidad también se refiere a la forma en que el cuerpo reacciona ante factores del ambiente como medicamentos, sustancias químicas o de otro tipo. Por ejemplo, una persona sensible a la luz del sol tiene un tipo de piel que se quema fácil o que presenta sarpullido después de exponerse al sol. Una persona sensible a la cafeína necesita cantidades muy pequeñas para sentir sus efectos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Frecuencia en la que una prueba produce resultados positivos verdaderos  en las personas que efectivamente tienen la enfermedad o variante genética en estudio. Una prueba con sensibilidad alta tiene una tasa de negativos falsos baja y por lo tanto es eficaz para identificar a las personas afectadas o a los portadores de una variante genética.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-07-26</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2013-07-16</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
