<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000330109">
  <TermName>stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... non-HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer is found (1) in one area outside the lymph nodes and in nearby lymph nodes; or (2) in two or more areas above or below the diaphragm (the thin muscle below the lungs and heart that separates the chest from the abdomen), and may have spread to nearby lymph nodes; or (3) to have started in the stomach or intestines and can be completely removed by surgery. Cancer may have spread to certain nearby lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000711574" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000711575" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000633800" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma; drawing shows cancer in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm, in the liver, and in the appendix. The colon and small intestine are also shown. An inset shows a lymph node with a lymph vessel, an artery, and a vein. Lymphoma cells containing cancer are shown in the lymph node." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer is found in one area outside the lymph nodes and in nearby lymph nodes (a); or in two or more areas above (b) or below (c) the diaphragm; or cancer started in the stomach, appendix, or intestines (d) and can be removed by surgery. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000650476" type="image/jpeg" alt="Linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II. En la imagen se observa cáncer en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y debajo del diafragma, en el hígado y en el apéndice. También se muestran el intestino delgado y el colon. En una ampliación se observa un ganglio linfático con un vaso linfático, una arteria y una vena. En el ganglio linfático hay células de linfoma (cancerosas)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) se encuentra cáncer en un área fuera de los ganglios linfáticos y en los ganglios linfáticos cercanos a esa área (a); 2) se encuentra cáncer en dos o más áreas por encima (b) o debajo (c) del diafragma; 3) el cáncer comenzó en el estómago, el apéndice o los intestinos (d) y se puede extirpar por completo mediante cirugía.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1)  se encuentra cáncer en un área fuera de los ganglios linfáticos y en los ganglios linfáticos cercanos a esa área;  
2) se encuentra cáncer en dos o más áreas por encima o debajo del diafragma (músculo delgado ubicado debajo de los pulmones y el corazón, que separa el pecho del abdomen) y es posible que se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos; 3) el cáncer comenzó en el estómago o los intestinos y se puede extirpar por completo mediante cirugía.  Es posible que se haya  diseminado a algunos ganglios linfáticos cercanos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-08-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-04-05</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258002" url="/types/lymphoma/patient/child-nhl-treatment-pdq">Childhood Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256783" url="/espanol/tipos/linfoma/paciente/tratamiento-lnh-infantil-pdq">Tratamiento del linfoma no Hodgkin infantil</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
