<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000335507"><TermName>selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(seh-LEK-tiv SAYR-uh-TOH-nin ree-UP-tayk in-HIH-bih-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of drug that is used to treat depression and some other conditions. Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors stop or delay the body from reabsorbing a substance called serotonin, which leaves more of it available for the body to use. Raising serotonin levels can help regulate mood, appetite, digestion, sleep, and many other bodily functions. Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors include drugs such as citalopram, escitalopram, fluoxetine, paroxetine, and sertraline. Also called SSRI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711254" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711255" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor selectivo de la recaptación de serotonina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor selectivo de la recaptación de serotonina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de la depresión y otras afecciones. Los inhibidores selectivos de la recaptación de serotonina impiden o retrasan la reabsorción en el cuerpo de una sustancia llamada serotonina, que queda disponible en más cantidad para que el cuerpo la utilice. El aumento de la concentración de serotonina  a veces ayuda a regular el estado de ánimo, el apetito, la digestión, el sueño y muchas otras funciones corporales. Los inhibidores selectivos de la recaptación de serotonina incluyen medicamentos como el citalopram, el escitalopram, la fluoxetina, la paroxetina y la sertralina. También se llama inhibidor de la recaptación selectiva de serotonina e ISRS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-09-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-12-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
