<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339348">
  <TermName>X-linked recessive inheritance</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(…. linkt reh-SEH-siv in-HAYR-ih-tunts)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>X-linked recessive inheritance refers to genetic conditions associated with mutations in genes on the X chromosome. A male carrying such a mutation will be affected, because he carries only one X chromosome. A female carrying a mutation in one gene, with a normal gene on the other X chromosome, is generally unaffected.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>One of the ways a genetic trait or condition caused by a  mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome can be passed down (inherited) from parent to child. In X-linked recessive inheritance, a daughter inherits a single mutated gene on the X chromosome from one of her parents. The X chromosome she inherits from the other parent will usually cancel the effect of the mutation, and she most likely will not have the genetic condition. If she inherits a mutated copy of the gene from both parents, she will be affected with the condition. Fathers cannot pass X-linked recessive conditions to their sons. When a son inherits a mutated gene on the X chromosome from his mother, the genetic condition is more likely to occur. X-linked recessive conditions most often occur in males.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000736967" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;X-linked recessive inheritance&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804196" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802198" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an X-linked recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their children. The panel on the left shows an affected father (who only has one X chromosome) with a mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome; an unaffected mother (who has two X chromosomes) with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an unaffected daughter (carrier), who has two X chromosomes, with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an unaffected son (who only has one X chromosome) with a normal gene on the X chromosome. The panel on the right shows an unaffected father with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an affected mother (carrier) with a normal gene on one X chromosome and a mutated gene on the other X chromosome; an unaffected daughter with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an unaffected son with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an affected son with a mutated gene on the X chromosome." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">X-linked recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child through mutations (changes) in a gene on the X chromosome. In males (who only have one X chromosome), a mutation in the copy of the gene on the single X chromosome causes the condition. Females (who have two X chromosomes) must have a mutation on both X chromosomes in order to be affected with the condition. If only the father   or the mother has the mutated X-linked gene, the daughters are usually not affected and are called carriers because one of their X chromosomes has the mutation but the other one is normal. Sons will be affected if they inherit the mutated X-linked gene from their mother. Fathers cannot pass X-linked recessive conditions to their sons.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802198" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an X-linked recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their children. The panel on the left shows an affected father (who only has one X chromosome) with a mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome; an unaffected mother (who has two X chromosomes) with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an unaffected daughter (carrier), who has two X chromosomes, with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an unaffected son (who only has one X chromosome) with a normal gene on the X chromosome. The panel on the right shows an unaffected father with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an affected mother (carrier) with a normal gene on one X chromosome and a mutated gene on the other X chromosome; an unaffected daughter with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an unaffected son with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an affected son with a mutated gene on the X chromosome." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="en">X-linked recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child through mutations (changes) in a gene on the X chromosome. In males (who only have one X chromosome), a mutation in the copy of the gene on the single X chromosome causes the condition. Females (who have two X chromosomes) must have a mutation on both X chromosomes in order to be affected with the condition. If only the father   or the mother has the mutated X-linked gene, the daughters are usually not affected and are called carriers because one of their X chromosomes has the mutation but the other one is normal. Sons will be affected if they inherit the mutated X-linked gene from their mother. Fathers cannot pass X-linked recessive conditions to their sons.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802817" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X en dos familias conformadas por padre, madre e hijos. En el lado izquierdo se muestran un padre afectado con un gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X); una madre no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X); una hija no afectada (portadora) con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X y un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X. En el lado derecho se muestra un padre no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una madre no afectada (portadora) con un gen normal en un cromosoma X y un gen mutado en el otro cromosoma X; una hija no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X; un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una hija no afectada (portadora) con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X; y un hijo afectado con un gen mutado en el cromosoma X." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="es">La herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X es una de las formas en que un rasgo o afección genética pasa de padres a hijos cuando hay mutaciones (cambios) en un gen del cromosoma X. En los hombres, la presencia de una mutación en un gen del único cromosoma X (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X) causa la enfermedad. Las mujeres presentan la afección únicamente cuando la mutación está en ambos cromosomas X (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X). Cuando el gen mutado ligado al cromosoma X solo está en uno de los padres (la madre o el padre), las hijas de la pareja por lo general no están afectadas, pero son portadoras porque tienen la mutación en un cromosoma X y el otro cromosoma X es normal. Los hijos estarán afectados si heredan el cromosoma X mutado de su madre. Los padres no pueden pasar afecciones recesivas ligadas al cromosoma X a sus hijos varones.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802817" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X en dos familias conformadas por padre, madre e hijos. En el lado izquierdo se muestran un padre afectado con un gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X); una madre no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X); una hija no afectada (portadora) con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X y un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X. En el lado derecho se muestra un padre no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una madre no afectada (portadora) con un gen normal en un cromosoma X y un gen mutado en el otro cromosoma X; una hija no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X; un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una hija no afectada (portadora) con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X; y un hijo afectado con un gen mutado en el cromosoma X." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">La herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X es una de las formas en que un rasgo o afección genética pasa de padres a hijos cuando hay mutaciones (cambios) en un gen del cromosoma X. En los hombres, la presencia de una mutación en un gen del único cromosoma X (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X) causa la enfermedad. Las mujeres presentan la afección únicamente cuando la mutación está en ambos cromosomas X (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X). Cuando el gen mutado ligado al cromosoma X solo está en uno de los padres (la madre o el padre), las hijas de la pareja por lo general no están afectadas, pero son portadoras porque tienen la mutación en un cromosoma X y el otro cromosoma X es normal. Los hijos estarán afectados si heredan el cromosoma X mutado de su madre. Los padres no pueden pasar afecciones recesivas ligadas al cromosoma X a sus hijos varones.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Este tipo de herencia se refiere a las afecciones genéticas asociadas a mutaciones en los genes del cromosoma X. Un  varón que presenta una mutación de este tipo se verá afectado siempre, ya que solo tiene  un cromosoma X. Una mujer que presenta una mutación en un gen de uno de los cromosomas X, pero  tiene un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X, por lo general no se ve afectada.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Una de las formas en que se hereda (pasa de padres a hijos) un rasgo genético o una afección causada por un gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X. En la herencia recesiva ligada al cromosoma X, una hija presentará la afección si hereda una copia del gen mutado de cada uno de los padres (una copia viene de la madre y la otra del padre). Por el contrario, es probable que la hija no presente la afección genética si de sus padres hereda solo un gen mutado en uno de los cromosomas X y hereda un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X, lo que suele cancelar el efecto de la mutación. Los padres no pueden pasar las afecciones recesivas ligadas al cromosoma X a sus hijos varones. Cuando un hijo varón hereda un gen mutado en el cromosoma X de su madre, es más probable que presente la afección genética. Las afecciones recesivas ligadas al cromosoma X se presentan con mayor frecuencia en los hombres.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
