<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339341"><TermName>heterozygous genotype</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HEH-teh-roh-ZY-gus JEE-noh-tipe)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The presence of two different alleles at a particular gene locus. A heterozygous genotype may include one normal allele and one mutated allele or two different mutated alleles (compound heterozygote).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term that describes having two different versions of the same gene (one inherited from the mother and one inherited from the father). In a heterozygous genotype, each gene may have a different mutation (change) or one of the genes may be mutated and the other one is normal. For example, familial hypercholesterolemia (very high levels of cholesterol in the blood) can occur when a person is heterozygous for the <GeneName>LDLR </GeneName> gene, inheriting a mutated gene from one parent and a normal gene from the other parent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736963" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;heterozygous genotype&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804193" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genotipo heterocigoto&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>genotipo heterocigoto</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Presencia de dos alelos diferentes en  un locus génico determinado. El  genotipo heterocigoto presenta un alelo normal y un alelo mutado o dos alelos con mutaciones diferentes (heterocigoto compuesto). También se llama genotipo heterocigótico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que describe la presencia de dos versiones del mismo gen (una heredada de la madre y la otra del padre). En un genotipo heterocigoto cada gen puede presentar una mutación (cambio) diferente, o es posible que solo uno de los genes esté mutado y  el otro sea normal. Por ejemplo, la hipercolesterolemia familiar (concentraciones muy altas de colesterol en la sangre)  se presenta en personas heterocigotas para el gen  <GeneName>LDLR</GeneName>, que heredaron un gen mutado de un padre y un gen normal del otro padre. También se llama genotipo heterocigótico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/glossary/index.cfm?id=101">Heterozygous (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Heterocigoto">Heterocigoto (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
