<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339333">
  <TermName>genetic heterogeneity</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(jeh-NEH-tik HEH-teh-roh-jeh-NEE-ih-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term used to describe different genetic mechanisms that produce the same or similar phenotypes. There are two types of genetic heterogeneity: allelic heterogeneity and locus heterogeneity. Allelic heterogeneity occurs when different variants at a single gene locus cause the same or similar phenotypic expressions of a disease or condition. Locus heterogeneity occurs when variants at different gene loci cause the same or similar phenotypic expressions of a disease or condition.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term that describes when different gene mutations (changes) cause the same disease or condition. Genetic heterogeneity occurs when a single gene has different mutations (allelic heterogeneity) or when there are mutations in different genes (locus heterogeneity), and in both cases the same disease or condition occurs. For example, tuberous sclerosis (an inherited disorder in which tumors form in the kidneys, brain, eyes, heart, lungs, and skin) is caused by having mutations in a gene on chromosome 9 or chromosome 16.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000736957" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genetic heterogeneity&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804189" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;heterogeneidad genética&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>heterogeneidad genética</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que describe diferentes mecanismos genéticos que producen el mismo fenotipo, o fenotipos similares. Hay dos tipos de heterogeneidad genética: la heterogeneidad alélica y la heterogeneidad de locus. La heterogeneidad alélica se presenta cuando variantes  diferentes en un locus génico específico producen  la misma expresión fenotípica de una enfermedad o afección, o una expresión fenotípica similar. La heterogeneidad de locus se presenta  cuando variantes en diferentes locus génicos causan la misma expresión fenotípica de una enfermedad o afección, o una expresión fenotípica similar.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que se usa cuando diferentes mutaciones (cambios) en genes causan la misma enfermedad o afección. La heterogeneidad genética se presenta cuando hay varias formas en que los genes causan una enfermedad o afección, ya sea   debido a un solo gen con mutaciones diferentes (heterogeneidad alélica), o a mutaciones en diferentes genes (heterogeneidad alélica). Por ejemplo, la causa de la esclerosis tuberosa (trastorno hereditario en el que se forman tumores en los riñones, el encéfalo, los  ojos, el corazón, los pulmones y la piel) son mutaciones en un gen en el cromosoma 9 o en un gen en el cromosoma 16.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
