<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339331">
  <TermName>variable expressivity</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(VAYR-ee-uh-bul ek-spreh-SIH-vih-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Variation in the traits, signs, or symptoms that can occur in individuals with the same condition. When there is variable expressivity, the trait may vary in clinical expression from mild to severe.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Refers to the difference in the way that signs and symptoms of a genetic condition can show up in individual patients who have that condition. For example, some patients with neurofibromatosis type 1 may have only mild symptoms, such as brown spots and freckling on the skin, and others may have more severe symptoms, such as brain tumors and tumors on the nerves.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000736955" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;variable expressivity&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000747087" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;expresividad variable&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>expresividad variable</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Se refiere a la diferencia en la forma en que los signos y síntomas de una afección genética se presentan en un paciente con esa afección. Por ejemplo, algunos pacientes con neurofibromatosis de tipo 1 tienen síntomas leves, como manchas marrones y pecas en la piel, mientras que otros pacientes tienen síntomas más graves, como tumores de encéfalo y tumores en los nervios.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Variación en los rasgos, signos o síntomas que se presentan en personas que tienen la misma afección. Cuando hay expresividad variable, la expresión clínica del rasgo oscila entre leve y grave.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
