<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339337"><TermName>allele</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-LEEL)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of two or more versions of a genetic sequence at a particular region on a chromosome. An individual inherits two alleles for each gene, one from each parent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of two or more alternative versions of a gene. A person inherits two alleles for each gene, one from the mother and one from the father. These two alleles may be the same or different. The alleles a person inherits help determine certain traits or characteristics, such as hair, skin, and eye color, height, and blood type. In some cases, one or both alleles may be mutated (changed from the original, normal version), which may cause disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736960" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;allele&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804192" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alelo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>alelo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una de las dos o más versiones de una secuencia genética en determinada región de un cromosoma. Las personas heredan dos alelos de cada gen, uno de la madre y otro del padre. También se llama alelomorfo y gen alelo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una de las dos o más versiones alternativas de un gen. Las personas heredan dos alelos de cada gen, uno de la madre y otro del padre. Estos dos alelos pueden ser iguales o diferentes. Los alelos que las personas heredan contribuyen a determinar ciertos rasgos o características, como el color del pelo, la piel y los ojos, la altura y el grupo sanguíneo. En algunos casos, es posible que uno o ambos alelos estén mutados (hayan cambiado respecto a la versión original, normal), lo que tal vez produzca una enfermedad. También se llama alelomorfo y gen alelo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/glossary/index.cfm?id=4">Allele (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Alelo">Alelo (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
