<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339330"><TermName>nonpenetrance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(non-PEH-neh-trunts)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An instance in which an individual has a trait-associated or disease-causing genetic variant, but the individual does not have the phenotype or condition. An example of nonpenetrance is a woman with a BRCA1 pathogenic variant who lives to be elderly and never develops breast or ovarian cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term that describes when a person has a disease-causing mutation (change) in a gene but never develops the disease. For example, a woman may have a certain <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> gene mutation that increases her risk of breast cancer, but because the gene mutation is nonpenetrant, she never develops breast cancer. However, she can still pass the <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> gene mutation to her children, who may develop cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736954" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nonpenetrance&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804187" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ausencia de penetrancia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ausencia de penetrancia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describe un caso en el que una persona presenta una variante genética asociada a un rasgo o que causa una enfermedad, pero no exhibe el fenotipo o la afección. Un ejemplo de ausencia de penetrancia es una mujer con una variante patógena en <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> que llega a la vejez sin presentar cáncer de mama ni de ovario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que se usa cuando una persona no presenta cierta enfermedad a pesar de tener una mutación (cambio en un gen) que causa la enfermedad. Por ejemplo, es posible que una mujer tenga cierta mutación en el gen <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> que aumenta el riesgo de cáncer de mama, pero si  la mutación en ese gen no es penetrante la mujer no se enfermará de cáncer de mama. Sin embargo, tiene la capacidad de pasar el gen  <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> a sus hijos, quienes tal vez presenten cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
