<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339335"><TermName>assisted reproductive technology</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-SIS-ted REE-proh-DUK-tiv tek-NAH-loh-jee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedures that use donor or nondonor eggs and sperm to create embryos in vitro. Examples of assisted reproductive technology include in vitro fertilization (IVF), gamete intrafallopian transfer (GIFT), and zygote intrafallopian transfer (ZIFT). These procedures may be used prior to preimplantation genetic testing (PGT).
 Also called ART.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of procedure used to treat infertility. The most common type of assisted reproductive technology is in vitro fertilization (IVF), which involves removing eggs from a woman’s ovary and combining them with sperm in the laboratory to form embryos. The embryos are then either placed in a woman’s uterus or frozen for future use. Assisted reproductive technology sometimes uses donor eggs or sperm or may involve a surrogate or gestational carrier (a woman who carries and gives birth to a baby for a person who is not able to have children). Other types of assisted reproductive technology include gamete intrafallopian transfer (GIFT) and zygote intrafallopian transfer (ZIFT), but these are used less often. Also called ART.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736959" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;assisted reproductive technology&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;técnicas de reproducción asistida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>técnicas de reproducción asistida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimientos para la creación <Emphasis>in vitro </Emphasis> de embriones mediante  el empleo de óvulos y espermatozoides (donados o propios). Los ejemplos de las técnicas de reproducción asistida son la fecundación in vitro, la transferencia intratubárica de gameto y la transferencia intratubárica de cigoto. A menudo después de estos procedimientos se hacen pruebas genéticas preimplantación. También se llama procreación asistida, tecnología de reproducción asistida y TRA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimientos para el tratamiento de la infertilidad. El tipo más común de las técnicas de reproducción asistida es la fecundación in vitro, para la cual se extraen óvulos del ovario de la mujer y se combinan con espermatozoides en el laboratorio a fin de formar embriones que se colocan en el útero o que se congelan para el futuro. Algunos tipos de técnicas de reproducción asistida implican el uso de óvulos o espermatozoides donados, o quizás incluya la participación de una gestante subrogada o portadora gestacional (mujer que lleva en su vientre el bebé de una persona que no puede tener hijos, hasta dar a luz). Otros tipos menos comunes de técnicas de reproducción asistida son la transferencia intratubárica de gameto y la transferencia intratubárica de cigoto. También se llama procreación asistida, tecnología de reproducción asistida y TRA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
