<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000340934"><TermName>pertuzumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(per-TOO-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat breast cancer that is HER2 positive. It is used in patients whose cancer has spread to other parts of the body and has not already been treated with other anticancer drugs. It is also used before surgery in patients with locally advanced, inflammatory, or early-stage breast cancer and after surgery in patients with early-stage breast cancer who have a high risk that their cancer will recur (come back). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Pertuzumab binds to a protein called HER2, which is found on some cancer cells. Blocking this protein may help kill cancer cells. Pertuzumab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Perjeta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pertuzumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711656" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pertuzumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pertuzumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para tratar el cáncer de mama positivo para HER2. Se usa para pacientes cuyo cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y  todavía no se trató con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. También se usa antes de la cirugía para pacientes con cáncer de mama localmente avanzado, inflamatorio o en estadio temprano, y se usa después de la cirugía para pacientes de cáncer de mama en estadio temprano con un riesgo alto de que el cáncer recidive (vuelva). Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El pertuzumab se une a una proteína de la superficie de algunas células cancerosas que se llama HER2. Bloquear la acción de esta proteína tal vez ayude a destruir las células cancerosas. El pertuzumab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Perjeta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-08-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000735473" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/pertuzumab">Pertuzumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
