<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000346515"><TermName>Adriamycin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AY-dree-uh-MY-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that comes from the bacterium  <ScientificName>Streptomyces peucetius</ScientificName> and is used alone or with other drugs to treat many types of cancer, including leukemia, lymphoma, neuroblastoma, sarcoma, Wilms tumor, and certain cancers of the lung, breast, stomach, ovary, thyroid, and bladder. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Adriamycin damages the cell’s DNA and may kill cancer cells. It also blocks a certain enzyme needed for cell division and DNA repair.  Adriamycin is a type of  anthracycline antibiotic and a type of  topoisomerase inhibitor.   Also called doxorubicin hydrochloride and hydroxydaunorubicin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805183" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Adriamycin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805184" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Adriamycin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Adriamycin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se obtiene de la bacteria <ScientificName>Streptomyces peucetius</ScientificName> y se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de  muchos tipos de cáncer, como la   leucemia, el linfoma, el neuroblastoma, el sarcoma, el tumor de Wilms y ciertos tipos de cáncer de pulmón, mama, estómago, ovario, tiroides y vejiga. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Adriamycin daña el ADN de la célula y es posible que destruya células cancerosas. Además,  bloquea cierta enzima necesaria para la multiplicación celular y la reparación del ADN. Adriamycin es un antibiótico de tipo antraciclina y es un tipo de  inhibidor de la topoisomerasa.  También se llama clorhidrato de doxorrubicina e hidroxidaunorrubicina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-11-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-02-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000542867" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/doxorubicinhydrochloride">Doxorubicin Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
