<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000350363"><TermName>stage 0 bladder cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... BLA-der KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage 0 bladder cancer refers to noninvasive bladder cancer. This means that cancer cells are found in tissue lining the inside of the bladder but have not invaded the bladder wall. Stage 0 is divided into stages 0a and 0is, depending on the type of tumor. Stage 0a is also called noninvasive papillary carcinoma, which may look like long, thin growths extending into the bladder lumen (the space where urine collects). Stage 0is is also called carcinoma in situ, which is a flat tumor on the tissue lining the inside of the bladder.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711271" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage 0 bladder cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711270" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vejiga en estadio 0&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000747928" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage 0 bladder cancer (noninvasive bladder cancer); drawing shows the bladder, lumen (the space where urine collects), ureter, prostate, and urethra. The first inset shows stage 0a (also called noninvasive papillary carcinoma) on the inner lining of the bladder. The second inset shows stage 0is (also called carcinoma in situ) on the inner lining of the bladder. Also shown are the connective tissue and muscle layers of the bladder and the layer of fat around the bladder." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage 0 bladder cancer (noninvasive bladder cancer). Cancer cells are found in tissue lining the inside of the bladder but have not invaded into the bladder wall. Stage 0a (also called noninvasive papillary carcinoma) may look like long, thin growths extending into the bladder lumen (the space where urine collects). Stage 0is (also called carcinoma in situ) is a flat tumor on the tissue lining the inside of the bladder. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752480" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de vejiga en estadio 0 (cáncer de vejiga no invasivo). En la imagen se muestran la vejiga, el lumen de la vejiga (espacio donde se almacena la orina), los uréteres, la próstata y la uretra. En una ampliación con dos recuadros se observa un cáncer en estadio 0a (también llamado carcinoma papilar no invasivo) en el revestimiento interno de la vejiga y un cáncer en estadio 0is (también llamado carcinoma in situ) en el revestimiento interno de la vejiga. También se señalan el tejido conjuntivo y las capas de tejido muscular de la vejiga, así como la grasa que la rodea." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de vejiga en estadio 0  (cáncer de vejiga no invasivo). Se encuentran células cancerosas en el revestimiento interno de la vejiga, pero no han invadido la pared de la vejiga. El estadio 0a (también se llama carcinoma papilar no invasivo) a veces tiene el aspecto de tumores  largos y delgados que   crecen dentro del lumen (espacio donde se almacena la orina) de la vejiga. El estadio 0is  (también se llama carcinoma in situ) es un tumor plano en el tejido que reviste el interior de la vejiga.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vejiga en estadio 0</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de vejiga en estadio 0 es cáncer de vejiga no invasivo. Esto significa que se encuentran células cancerosas en el tejido que reviste el interior de la vejiga, pero estas células no han invadido la pared de la vejiga. El estadio 0 se divide en los estadios 0a y 0is, según el tipo de tumor. El estadio 0a también se llama carcinoma papilar  no invasivo y a veces tiene el aspecto de bultos largos y delgados que se extienden hacia dentro del lumen (espacio donde se almacena la orina) de la vejiga. El estadio 0is también se llama carcinoma in situ y es un tumor plano en el tejido que reviste el interior de la vejiga.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-01-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-01-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000811057" url="/types/bladder/stages">Bladder Cancer Stages</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000811361" url="/espanol/tipos/vejiga/estadios">Estadios del cáncer de vejiga</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
