<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000354470"><TermName>ureteroscopy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(YER-eh-ter-OS-koh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a ureteroscope to look inside the ureter (tube that connects the bladder to the kidney) and the renal pelvis (part of the kidney that collects urine and funnels it into the ureter). A ureteroscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing. It may also have a tool to remove tissue to be checked under a microscope for signs of disease.  The ureteroscope is inserted through the urethra into the bladder, ureter, and renal pelvis. Ureteroscopy may be used to check for cancer or other abnormal growths in the ureter and renal pelvis and to treat stones in the kidney or ureter.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711286" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ureteroscopy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711287" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ureteroscopia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000649520" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of a female and male ureteroscopy showing the lower pelvis of a female, including the right and left kidneys, renal pelvis, ureter, uterus, bladder, and urethra, and the lower pelvis of a male, including the ureter, bladder, prostate, urethra, and penis. In both the female and male figures, a ureteroscope (a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing) is shown passing through the urethra into the bladder and ureter. In the female figure, the ureteroscope is also shown passing into the renal pelvis. There is also an inset that shows a person lying on an examination table with their knees bent and legs apart, covered by a drape, and a doctor looking at an image of the inside of the ureter and/or renal pelvis on a computer monitor." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">A ureteroscopy is a procedure that uses a ureteroscope (a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing) to look inside the ureter and renal pelvis to check for abnormal areas. The ureteroscope is inserted through the urethra into the bladder, ureter, and renal pelvis. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000671003" type="image/jpeg" alt="Se muestra un dibujo de una ureteroscopia en una mujer, en la que se observa la pelvis inferior y se señalan los riñones derecho e izquierdo, la pelvis renal, el uréter, el útero, la vejiga, y la uretra. Así mismo, se muestra un dibujo de una ureteroscopia en un hombre en la que se observa la pelvis inferior y se señalan el uréter, la vejiga, la próstata, la uretra y el pene. En ambos dibujos se ve un ureteroscopio (instrumento delgado en forma de tubo con una luz y una lente para observar) que pasa a través de la uretra hacia la vejiga y el uréter. En la figura de la mujer el ureteroscopio también se introduce en la pelvis renal. Además, hay un recuadro en el que se observa a una persona acostada en una camilla con las rodillas flexionadas y las piernas separadas, cubiertas por una sábana, y un médico que mira una imagen del interior del uréter o la pelvis renal en el monitor de unacomputadora." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Una ureteroscopia es un procedimiento en el que se usa un ureteroscopio (instrumento delgado en forma de tubo con una luz y una lente para observar) para ver el interior del uréter y la pelvis renal, y verificar si hay áreas anormales.  El ureteroscopio se inserta a través de la uretra hacia la vejiga, el uréter y la pelvis renal.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>ureteroscopia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento durante el cual se usa un ureteroscopio para observar el interior del uréter (tubo que conecta la vejiga con el riñón) y la pelvis renal (parte del riñón donde se acumula la orina y se dirige hacia el uréter). El ureteroscopio es un instrumento delgado en forma de tubo con una luz y una lente para observar. En ocasiones también tiene una herramienta para extraer tejido que se observa al microscopio para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad. Durante el procedimiento, se hace pasar el ureteroscopio a través de la uretra hacia la vejiga, y luego por el uréter hasta la pelvis renal. La uroteroscopia se usa para encontrar cáncer o bultos anormales en el uréter o la pelvis renal, y para tratar cálculos en los riñones o en el uréter.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-01-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-08-28</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
