<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000367465"><TermName>all-trans retinoic acid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(all-tranz REH-tih-NOH-ik A-sid)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. All-trans retinoic acid is made in the body from vitamin A and helps cells to grow and develop, especially in the embryo. A form of all-trans retinoic acid made in the laboratory is put on the skin to treat conditions such as acne and is taken by mouth to treat acute promyelocytic leukemia (a fast-growing cancer in which there are too many immature blood-forming cells in the blood and bone marrow). All-trans retinoic acid is being studied in the prevention and treatment of other types of cancer. Also called ATRA, retinoic acid, tretinoin, and vitamin A acid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711185" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;all-trans retinoic acid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711186" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ácido holo-trans-retinoico&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>ácido holo-trans-retinoico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. El ácido  holo-trans-retinoico se elabora en el cuerpo a partir de la vitamina A y ayuda a las células a crecer y desarrollarse, especialmente en el embrión. Una forma de ácido holo-trans-retinoico que se produce en el laboratorio se aplica sobre la piel para tratar afecciones tales como el acné y se toma por boca para tratar la leucemia promielocítica aguda (cáncer de crecimiento rápido por el que se forman demasiadas células hematopoyéticas en la sangre y la médula ósea). El ácido  holo-trans-retinoico está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. También se llama ácido de vitamina A, ácido retinoico, ácido todo-trans-retinoico, ATRA y tretinoína.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-02-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
