<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000368449"><TermName>stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer on the head and neck (not on the eyelid)</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… non-MEH-luh-NOH-muh skin KAN-ser ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of the following is found: (1) the tumor is any size and cancer may have spread to the bone and the bone has minor damage, or to tissue covering the nerves below the dermis, or below the subcutaneous tissue. Cancer has spread to the lymph nodes as follows: (a) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is 3 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of  the lymph node; or (b) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor,  the affected node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (c) more than one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the affected nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes; or (d) one or more lymph nodes on the opposite side of the body as the tumor or on both sides of the body, the affected nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes; OR  (2) the tumor is any size and cancer may have spread to tissue covering the nerves below the dermis, or below the subcutaneous tissue, or to bone marrow or to bone, including the bottom of the skull, and one of the following is found:  (a) cancer has spread to one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (b) cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is larger than 3 centimeters, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of  the lymph node; or (c) cancer has spread to one lymph node on the opposite side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is any size, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (d) cancer has spread to more than one lymph node on one or both sides of the body and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes; OR (3) the tumor is any size and cancer has spread to bone marrow or to bone, including the bottom of the skull, and the bone has been damaged. Cancer may have also spread to the lymph nodes; OR (4) cancer has spread to other parts of the body, such as the lung.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711240" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer on the head and neck (not on the eyelid)&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711241" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello (que no es de párpado) en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000600819" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer of the head and neck (1); drawing shows a primary tumor on the face and cancer that has spread to: (a) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the node is 3 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; (b) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor and the node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters; (c) more than one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor and the nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller; and (d) one or more lymph nodes on the opposite or both sides of the body as the tumor and the nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller. Also shown is a 10-centimeter ruler and a 4-inch ruler." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer of the head and neck (1). The tumor is any size. Cancer may have spread to the bone and the bone has minor damage, or to tissue covering the nerves below the dermis, or below the subcutaneous tissue. Cancer has spread to: (a) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the node is 3 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (b) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (c) more than one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes; or (d) one or more lymph nodes on the opposite side of the body as the tumor or on both sides of the body, the nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller, and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726760" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer of the head and neck (2); drawing shows a primary skin tumor on the face and cancer that has spread to: (a) one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters; (b) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is larger than 3 centimeters, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; (c) one lymph node on the opposite side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is any size, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; and (d) more than one lymph node on one or both sides of the body and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes. Also shown is a 10-centimeter ruler and a 4-inch ruler." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer of the head and neck (2). The tumor is any size and cancer has spread to: (a) one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters and cancer has not spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (b) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is larger than 3 centimeters, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node; or (c) one lymph node on the opposite side of the body as the tumor, the affected node is any size, and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph node;  or (d) more than one lymph node on one or both sides of the body and cancer has spread through to the outside covering of the lymph nodes.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000794077" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer of the head and neck (3); drawing shows a primary skin tumor on the face and other parts of the body where nonmelanoma skin cancer may spread, including the base of the skull, the lung, the bone, and the bone marrow. An inset shows cancer cells spreading through the blood and lymph system to another part of the body where metastatic cancer has formed." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="en">Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer of the head and neck (3). The tumor is any size and cancer has spread to bone marrow or to bone, including the base of the skull, and the bone has been damaged; or cancer has spread to other parts of the body, such as the lung.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738954" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello en estadio IV (Parte 1). En la imagen se observa un tumor primario en la cara y cáncer que se diseminó en una de las siguientes formas: a) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio mide 3 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; b) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio mide más de 3 cm pero no más de 6 cm; c) a más de un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, los ganglios miden 6 cm o menos; y d) uno o más ganglios linfáticos del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor o a ambos lados del cuerpo, los ganglios miden 6 cm o menos. También se observan una regla de 10 cm y una regla de 4 in." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello en estadio IV (Parte 1). El tumor es de cualquier tamaño. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado al hueso y este tiene poco daño, al tejido que reviste los nervios debajo de la dermis, o debajo del tejido subcutáneo. El cáncer se diseminó en una de las siguientes formas: a) a un ganglio linfático  del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio mide 3 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; b) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio mide más de 3 cm pero no más de 6 cm y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos; c) a más de un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, los ganglios miden 6 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos; o d) a uno o más ganglios linfáticos del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor o a ambos lados del cuerpo, los ganglios miden 6 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738955" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello en estadio IV (Parte 2). En el dibujo se observa un tumor primario en la cara y cáncer que se diseminó en una de las siguientes formas: a) a un ganglio linfático que mide más de 6 cm; b) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio mide más de 3 cm y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio; c) a un ganglio linfático del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor, el ganglio es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio; y d) a más de un ganglio linfático de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo, y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios. También se observan una regla de 10 cm y una regla de 4 in." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello en estadio IV (Parte 2). El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el  cáncer se diseminó en una de las siguientes formas: a) a un ganglio linfático que mide más de 6 cm y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; b) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio linfático mide más de 3 cm y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; c) a un ganglio linfático del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor, el ganglio linfático es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; o d) a más de un ganglio linfático de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo, y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800796" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello en estadio IV (Parte 3). En el dibujo se observa un tumor primario en la cara y otras partes del cuerpo donde es posible que el cáncer de piel no melanoma se disemine, como la base del cráneo, el pulmón, el hueso y la médula ósea. En el recuadro se muestran las células cancerosas que se diseminan a través de la sangre y el sistema linfático a otra parte del cuerpo donde se formó el cáncer metastásico." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_9"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello en estadio IV (Parte 3). El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a la médula ósea o al hueso, incluso a la base del cráneo, y hay daño en el hueso; o el cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo como el pulmón.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel no melanoma de cabeza y cuello (que no es de párpado) en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentra una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado al hueso y este tiene poco daño, al tejido que reviste los nervios debajo de la dermis, o debajo del tejido subcutáneo. El cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos en una de las siguientes formas: a) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio linfático afectado mide 3 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; b) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio linfático afectado mide más de 3 cm pero no más de 6 cm, y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; c) a más de un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden 6 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos; o d) a uno o más ganglios linfáticos del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor o a ambos lados del cuerpo, los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden 6 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos; 2) el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que se haya diseminado al tejido que reviste los nervios debajo de la dermis, o debajo del tejido subcutáneo, o a la médula ósea o al hueso, incluso a la base del cráneo, y se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó a un ganglio linfático que mide más de 6 cm y el cáncer no se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; b) el cáncer se diseminó a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor, el ganglio linfático afectado mide más de 3 cm y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; c) el cáncer se diseminó a un ganglio linfático del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor, el ganglio linfático afectado es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo del ganglio linfático; o d) el cáncer se diseminó a más de un ganglio linfático de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo, y el cáncer se diseminó a través del recubrimiento externo de los ganglios linfáticos; 3) el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a la médula ósea o al hueso, incluso a la base del cráneo, y hay daño en el hueso. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos; 4) el cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo, como el pulmón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-05-28</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-02-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258035" url="/types/skin/patient/skin-treatment-pdq">Skin Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256809" url="/espanol/tipos/piel/paciente/tratamiento-piel-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de piel</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
