<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000377716"><TermName>Peutz-Jeghers syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(putz-JAY-gerz SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare genetic disorder in which many polyps (abnormal growths of tissue) form in the lining of the gastrointestinal tract, and  dark-colored spots appear on certain areas of the skin, such as around the mouth, eyes, and nose. People with Peutz-Jeghers syndrome have a very high risk of developing gastrointestinal cancer and other types of cancer, including cancers of the breast, pancreas, ovary, lung, and cervix. Peutz-Jeghers syndrome is usually caused by mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>STK11</GeneName> gene. Some people with Peutz-Jeghers syndrome do not have a mutation in the <GeneName>STK11</GeneName> gene. In these cases, the cause of the disorder is unknown. Also called PJS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731316" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Peutz-Jeghers syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731317" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Peutz-Jeghers&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Peutz-Jeghers</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético raro en el que se forman muchos pólipos (masas de tejido anormal) en el revestimiento del tubo digestivo  y aparecen manchas oscuras en ciertas áreas de la piel, como alrededor de la boca, los ojos y la nariz.  Las personas con síndrome de Peutz-Jeghers tienen un riesgo muy alto de presentar cáncer gastrointestinal y otros tipos de cáncer, como los de mama, páncreas, ovario, pulmón o cuello uterino. Por lo general, la causa del síndrome de Peutz-Jeghers    son mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>STK11</GeneName>. Algunas personas con este síndrome  no presentan ninguna mutación en el gen <GeneName>STK11</GeneName>. En esos casos, la causa del trastorno es desconocida. También se llama poliposis hamartomatosa de Peutz-Jeghers, síndrome de poliposis intestinal hereditaria y SPJ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-06-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-05-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7378/peutz-jeghers-syndrome">Peutz-Jeghers syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/peutz-jeghers-syndrome/">Peutz-Jeghers syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000244.htm">síndrome de Peutz-Jeghers (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
