<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000386203">
  <TermName>everolimus</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(eh-veh-ROH-lih-mus)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
          A drug used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of breast cancer, kidney cancer, and pancreatic, lung, and gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors. It is used under the brand name Afinitor to treat these cancers and to treat a type of benign kidney tumor called renal angiomyolipoma and a type of benign brain tumor called subependymal giant cell astrocytoma in patients who have tuberous sclerosis. Everolimus is also used under the brand name Afinitor Disperz to treat subependymal giant cell astrocytoma and certain types of seizures in patients who have tuberous sclerosis. It is also used under the brand name Zortress to keep the body from rejecting a kidney or liver transplant. Everolimus is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. It blocks a protein involved in cell division, which may help keep abnormal cells, including cancer cells, from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Everolimus also lowers the body’s immune response. It is a type of kinase inhibitor, a type of angiogenesis inhibitor, and a type of immunosuppressant. Also called RAD001.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713182" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;everolimus&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713181" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;everólimus&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>everólimus</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para  el tratamiento de determinados tipos de cáncer de mama, cáncer de riñón,  tumores de páncreas, tumores de pulmón y tumores neuroendocrinos gastrointestinales. Se utiliza bajo la marca comercial Afinitor para el tratamiento de estos cánceres y de un tipo de tumor benigno de riñón llamado angiomiolipoma renal. Además, se usa para el tratamiento  de un tipo de tumor benigno de encéfalo llamado astrocitoma subependimario de células gigantes en pacientes que tienen esclerosis tuberosa. El everólimus también se usa bajo la marca comercial Afinitor Disperz para tratar el astrocitoma subependimario de células gigantes y ciertos tipos de convulsiones en pacientes con esclerosis tuberosa. Por otra parte, la marca comercial Zortress se usa para evitar que el cuerpo rechace un trasplante de riñón o de hígado. El everólimus también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. Bloquea una proteína que participa en la división celular, lo que tal vez evite la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso las células cancerosas. Es posible que también evite la formación de los vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer.  El everólimus además disminuye la respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo. Es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas, de inhibidor de la angiogénesis y de inmunodepresor. También se llama RAD001.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2004-08-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-05-18</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000640318" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/everolimus">Everolimus</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
