<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000390306">
  <TermName>parenteral nutrition</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(puh-REN-teh-rul noo-TRIH-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of nutritional support that is given directly into the bloodstream through a catheter placed into a vein. Parenteral nutrition bypasses the digestive system and may be given when a person is not able to eat or drink by mouth or has a disease or condition that affects their ability to absorb nutrients through the digestive system. There are two types of parenteral nutrition: partial parenteral nutrition (PPN) and total parenteral nutrition (TPN). PPN is supplemental nutrition that is given when a person cannot get enough calories or the right amount of nutrients that their body needs from the food they are eating. TPN is complete nutrition that provides all the calories, proteins, carbohydrates, fats, vitamins, and minerals that a person needs when they cannot digest food. Also called hyperalimentation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713513" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;parenteral nutrition&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713514" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nutrición parenteral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>nutrición parenteral</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma de apoyo nutricional que se administra directamente en el torrente sanguíneo mediante un catéter que se coloca en una vena. La nutrición parenteral no pasa por el aparato digestivo. Este tipo de alimentación se administra cuando la persona no puede comer o beber por la boca, o tiene una enfermedad o afección que afecta su capacidad de absorber los nutrientes en el aparato digestivo. Hay dos tipos de nutrición parenteral: la nutrición parenteral parcial (NPP) y la nutrición parenteral total (NPT). La NPP es una nutrición complementaria que recibe una persona que no puede obtener suficientes calorías, o los nutrientes que el cuerpo necesita, a partir de los alimentos que come. La NPT es una alimentación completa que aporta todas las calorías, proteínas, carbohidratos, grasas, vitaminas y minerales que una persona necesita cuando no puede digerir los alimentos. También se llama alimentación parenteral, hiperalimentación y nutrición parentérica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2004-11-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-08-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/nutrition">Nutrition During Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/nutricion" UseWith="es">Nutrición durante el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
