<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000390943"><TermName>Breast Imaging Reporting and Data System</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest IH-muh-jing reh-port-ing ... SIS-tem)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A reporting system used  to describe the results of a mammogram, breast ultrasound, or breast MRI in a standard way. The Breast Imaging Reporting and Data System  ranks the test findings according to one of seven categories, ranging from normal or benign (not cancer) to highly suspicious or malignant (cancer). Each category includes follow-up recommendations to help manage a person’s care.  For mammograms, the Breast Imaging Reporting and Data System includes four additional categories that describe the level of breast density seen, ranging from little or no dense tissue to very dense tissue.  Also called BI-RADS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713363" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Breast Imaging Reporting and Data System&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713362" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Sistema de informes y registro de datos de imagen de mama&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/><SpanishTermName>Sistema de informes y registro de datos de imagen de mama</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sistema de informes que se usa para describir de manera estandarizada los resultados de las mamografías, ecografías mamarias o imágenes por resonancia magnética de las mamas. El sistema de informes y registro de datos de imagen de mama clasifica los resultados de las pruebas según 1 de 7 categorías, que van desde un resultado normal o benigno (no canceroso) hasta altamente sospechoso o maligno (cáncer). Cada categoría incluye recomendaciones de seguimiento para ayudar a gestionar la atención de la persona.  En el caso de las mamografías, este sistema incluye 4 categorías adicionales que describen el grado de densidad mamaria observado, que va desde tejido poco o nada denso hasta tejido muy denso. También se llama BI-RADS, Sistema de base de datos e informes de imágenes de la mama, Sistema de base de datos e informes de imágenes mamarias y Sistema de informes y registro de datos de estudios por imágenes de la mama.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-09-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-03-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/mammograms-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Mammograms</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-mamografias">Mamografías</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
