<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000403140">
  <TermName>PCR</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A laboratory method used to make many copies of a specific piece of DNA from a sample that contains very tiny amounts of that DNA. PCR allows these pieces of DNA to be amplified so they can be detected.  PCR may be used to look for certain changes in a gene or chromosome, which may help find and diagnose a genetic condition or a disease, such as cancer. It may also be used to look at pieces of the DNA of certain bacteria, viruses, or other microorganisms to help diagnose an infection. Also called polymerase chain reaction.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A common laboratory technique used during molecular genetic testing to  produce many copies of a specific sequence of DNA . PCR allows these DNA sequences to be amplified so there is a sufficient quantity of DNA to be analyzed by  molecular genetic tests. Also called polymerase chain reaction.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermName>PCR</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Método de laboratorio que sirve para hacer muchas copias de un trozo determinado de ADN a partir de una muestra que tiene cantidades diminutas de este ADN. Con la PCR se amplifica (multiplica) ese trozo de ADN para que se pueda detectar.   A veces la PCR se usa para identificar determinados cambios en un gen o cromosoma que ayudan a detectar y diagnosticar una afección genética o una enfermedad, como el cáncer. También se usa para identificar trozos de ADN de determinadas bacterias, virus o microorganismos para diagnosticar una infección. También se llama reacción en cadena de la polimerasa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Técnica de laboratorio habitual que se usa durante el análisis genético molecular para producir muchas copias de una secuencia específica de ADN. La PCR permite amplificar estas secuencias para generar suficiente cantidad de ADN a fin de efectuar un análisis mediante pruebas de genética molecular. También se llama reacción en cadena de la polimerasa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2016-09-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Polymerase-Chain-Reaction">Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Reaccion-en-cadena-de-la-polimerasa">Reacción en cadena de la polimerasa (PCR) (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
