<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000407748">
  <TermName>Sertoli-Leydig cell tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ser-TOH-lee-LY-dig sel TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare tumor that forms in the tissues that surround and support the ovaries. Sertoli-Leydig cell tumors make a male sex hormone called testosterone. These tumors can cause the appearance of male physical features, such as facial hair, a deep voice, and other symptoms. Sertoli-Leydig cell tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). They tend to have a good prognosis if diagnosed and treated early. Sertoli-Leydig cell tumors are a type of sex cord-stromal tumor. Also called androblastoma and arrhenoblastoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713336" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Sertoli-Leydig cell tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_8"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713337" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor de células de Sertoli y de Leydig&quot;" language="es" id="_9"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor de células de Sertoli y de Leydig</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor raro que se forma en los tejidos que rodean y sostienen los ovarios. Estos tumores producen una hormona sexual masculina llamada testosterona, que causa la aparición de rasgos físicos masculinos, como vello facial, voz grave, además de otros síntomas. Los tumores de células de Sertoli y de Leydig pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos), y suelen tener un buen pronóstico si se diagnostican y se tratan a tiempo. Los tumores de células de Sertoli y de Leydig son un tipo de tumor de estroma de cordón sexual. También se llama androblastoma, arrenoblastoma, tumor de células de Sertoli-Leydig y tumor de células gonadales de Sertoli-Leydig.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2025-02-07</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
