<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000409765">
  <TermName>genital wart</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(JEH-nih-tul wort)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A raised growth on the surface of the genitals or in or around the anus caused by infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). HPV can spread by skin-to-skin contact, usually during oral, anal, or genital sex with an infected partner. These warts can also occur on the lips and tongue and in the mouth and throat.  Genital warts often appear as small, skin-colored bumps that may be clumped together. They are usually painless and do not cause any symptoms, so a person may not know they have them. However, sometimes they can grow large and cause itching and bleeding.   Genital warts do not become cancer, but they may come back after treatment. Also called condyloma acuminatum.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000730808" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genital wart&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000730809" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;verruga genital&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>verruga genital</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Lesión elevada en la superficie de los genitales, o dentro o alrededor del ano, causada por la infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). Estos virus se transmiten por el contacto piel a piel, a menudo durante una relación sexual oral, anal o genital con una pareja infectada. Estas verrugas también aparecen en los labios y la lengua, así como en la boca y la garganta.   Las verrugas genitales suelen surgir como pequeños bultos del mismo color de la piel que pueden estar agrupados. Por lo general, no producen dolor ni síntomas, por lo que es posible que las personas no sepan que las tienen; no obstante, en ocasiones crecen, pican y sangran. Las verrugas genitales no se convierten en cáncer, pero es posible que reaparezcan después del tratamiento. También se llama condiloma acuminado, papiloma venéreo y verruga venérea.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2004-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-06-12</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
