<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413912">
  <TermName>stage III gallbladder cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... GAWL-bla-der KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB, depending on where the cancer has spread. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread through the connective tissue layer of the gallbladder wall to (1) the serosa (layer of tissue that covers the gallbladder); and/or    (2) the liver; and/or (3) one nearby organ or structure (such as the stomach, small intestine, colon, pancreas, or the bile ducts outside the liver). In stage IIIB, cancer has formed in the mucosa (innermost layer) of the gallbladder wall and may have spread to the muscle, connective tissue, or serosa  and may have also spread to the liver or to one nearby organ or structure (such as the stomach, small intestine, colon, pancreas, or the bile ducts outside the liver). Cancer has spread to one to three nearby lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713280" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III gallbladder cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713281" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vesícula biliar en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de vesícula biliar en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB, según el lugar donde el cáncer se diseminó. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa de tejido conjuntivo  de la pared de la vesícula biliar y se diseminó a 1) la serosa (capa de tejido que cubre la vesícula biliar); o 2) el hígado; o 3) un órgano o estructura cercanos (como el estómago, el intestino delgado, el colon, el páncreas o las vías biliares fuera del hígado). En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se formó en la mucosa (capa más interna) de la pared de la vesícula biliar y es posible que se haya diseminado al músculo, el tejido conjuntivo o la serosa (capa de tejido que cubre la vesícula biliar), y quizá que se haya diseminado al hígado u otro órgano o estructura  cercanos (como el estómago, el intestino delgado, el colon, el páncreas o las vías biliares fuera del hígado). El cáncer se diseminó hasta 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos cercanos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-01-18</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000270720" url="/types/gallbladder/patient/gallbladder-treatment-pdq">Gallbladder Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256804" url="/espanol/tipos/vesicula-biliar/paciente/tratamiento-vesicula-biliar-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de vesícula biliar</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
