<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413920"><TermName>stage 0 transitional cell carcinoma in situ of the renal pelvis and ureter</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... tran-ZIH-shuh-nul sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too ... REE-nul PEL-vus ... YER-eh-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Abnormal cells are found in tissue lining the inside of the renal pelvis or ureter. These abnormal cells may become cancer and spread into nearby normal tissue. Stage 0 is divided into stages 0a and 0is, depending on the type of tumor. Stage 0a is also called noninvasive papillary carcinoma, which may look like long, thin growths that grow out from the tissue lining the inside of the renal pelvis or ureter. Stage 0is is also called carcinoma in situ, which is a flat tumor on the tissue lining the inside of the renal pelvis or ureter.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713292" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage 0 transitional cell carcinoma in situ of the renal pelvis and ureter&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713293" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células de transición de pelvis renal y uréter in situ en estadio 0&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células de transición de pelvis renal y uréter in situ en estadio 0</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células anormales en el tejido que reviste el interior de la pelvis renal o el uréter. Es posible que estas células anormales se vuelvan cancerosas y se diseminen al tejido normal cercano. El estadio 0 se divide en los estadios 0a y 0is, según el tipo de tumor. El estadio 0a también se llama carcinoma papilar no invasor, que a veces tiene el aspecto de bultos alargados y delgados que sobresalen del tejido que reviste el interior de la pelvis renal o el uréter. El estadio 0is también se llama  carcinoma in situ; es un tumor plano en el tejido que reviste el interior de la pelvis renal o el uréter.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2018-02-06</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000343585" url="/types/kidney/patient/transitional-cell-treatment-pdq">Transitional Cell Cancer of the Renal Pelvis and Ureter Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256834" url="/espanol/tipos/rinon/paciente/tratamiento-celulas-de-transicion-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de células de transición de pelvis renal y de uréter</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
