<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000415316">
  <TermName>Faslodex</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FAZ-loh-dex)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of breast cancer. It is used alone or with ribociclib succinate in postmenopausal women who have not been treated with hormone therapy or whose disease got worse after treatment with hormone therapy. It is also used with palbociclib or abemaciclib in women whose disease got worse after treatment with hormone therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Faslodex binds to proteins called estrogen receptors, which are found in some breast cancer cells. These proteins may cause cancer cells to grow. Faslodex blocks these proteins and may keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of antiestrogen. Also called fulvestrant and ICI 182780.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713086" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Faslodex&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713085" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Faslodex&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Faslodex</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer mama. Se utiliza solo o con el succinato de ribociclib en mujeres posmenopáusicas que no se trataron con terapia con hormonas o cuya enfermedad empeoró después de recibir la terapia con hormonas. También se usa con palbociclib o abemaciclib en mujeres cuya enfermedad empeoró después de recibir terapia con hormonas. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Faslodex se une a unas proteínas llamadas receptores de estrógeno, que se encuentran en algunas células de cáncer de mama. A veces, estas proteínas hacen que las células cancerosas se multipliquen. Faslodex bloquea estas proteínas y es posible que impida la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de antiestrógeno. También se llama fulvestrant e ICI 182780.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-10-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000491908" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/fulvestrant">Fulvestrant</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
