<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000415548">
  <TermName>systemic inflammatory response syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(sis-TEH-mik in-FLA-muh-TOR-ee reh-SPONTS SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A serious condition in which there is inflammation throughout the whole body. Systemic inflammatory response syndrome may be caused by an infection, trauma, surgery, ischemia (lack of blood supply to a part of the body), or certain conditions, such as an autoimmune disorder or pancreatitis. To be diagnosed with systemic inflammatory response syndrome, a person must have two or more of the following: low or high body temperature, increased heart rate, increased breathing rate, and an abnormal white blood cell count. When systemic inflammatory response syndrome occurs as a result of a known infection, it may be called sepsis. Sepsis can be severe or life threatening and lead to multiple organ failure and shock. Also called SIRS.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713384" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;systemic inflammatory response syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713385" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de respuesta inflamatoria sistémica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de respuesta inflamatoria sistémica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección grave por la que se inflama todo el cuerpo. La causa del síndrome de respuesta inflamatoria sistémica puede ser una infección, un traumatismo, una cirugía, una isquemia (falta de riego sanguíneo en una parte del cuerpo) o determinadas afecciones, como un trastorno autoinmunitario o una pancreatitis. Para recibir un diagnóstico de síndrome de respuesta inflamatoria sistémica, una persona debe presentar dos o más de los siguientes síntomas: temperatura del cuerpo más alta o más baja que lo normal, aumento de la frecuencia cardiaca, aumento de la frecuencia respiratoria o un recuento anormal de glóbulos blancos. Cuando se produce el síndrome de respuesta inflamatoria sistémica como consecuencia de una infección conocida, se denomina sepsis. La sepsis puede ser grave o poner en peligro la vida y provocar una insuficiencia orgánica múltiple y conmoción. También se llama SRIS.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-03-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-12-09</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
