<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000415914">
  <TermName>spine</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(spine)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The bones, muscles, tendons, and other tissues that reach from the base of the skull to the tailbone. The spine encloses the spinal cord and the fluid surrounding the spinal cord. Also called backbone, spinal column, and vertebral column.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733031" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;spine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733032" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;espina vertebral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797134" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the spine; drawing shows a side view of the spine, including the cervical spine (C1-C7), thoracic spine (T1-T12), lumbar spine (L1-L5), sacral spine (S1-S5), and the coccyx (tailbone). Also shown are the spinal cord, vertebra (back bone), conus medullaris (the end of the spinal cord), cauda equina (the bundle of spinal nerves that extend beyond the conus medullaris), and a lumbar disc. The clivus (a bone at the base of the skull near the spinal cord) is also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Anatomy of the spine. The spine is made up of bones, muscles, tendons, nerves, and other tissues that reach from the base of the skull near the spinal cord (clivus) to the coccyx (tailbone). The vertebrae (back bones) of the spine include the cervical spine (C1-C7), thoracic spine (T1-T12), lumbar spine (L1-L5), sacral spine (S1-S5), and the tailbone. Each vertebra is separated by a disc. The vertebrae surround and protect the spinal cord. The spinal cord is divided into segments, each containing a pair of spinal nerves that send messages between the brain and the rest of the body. Many spinal nerves extend beyond the conus medullaris (the end of the spinal cord) to form a bundle of nerves called the cauda equina.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798360" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la columna vertebral. En el dibujo se observa una vista lateral de la columna vertebral, que incluye la región cervical (C1-C7), la región torácica (T1-T12), la región lumbar (L1-L5), la región sacra (S1-S5) y el cóccix (hueso coccígeo). También se muestran la médula espinal, las vertebras (huesos de la columna), el cono medular (parte final de la médula espinal), la cola de caballo (conjunto de nervios raquídeos que continúan más allá del cono medular) y los discos lumbares. Además, se muestra el clivus (hueso en la base del cráneo cerca de la médula espinal)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Anatomía de la columna vertebral. La columna vertebral está formada por huesos, músculos, tendones, nervios y otros tejidos que  se extienden desde la base del cráneo cerca del  comienzo de la médula espinal (a la altura del clivus) hasta el cóccix (hueso coccígeo). Las vértebras (huesos de la columna) forman la región cervical (C1-C7), la región torácica (T1-T12), la región lumbar (L1-L5), la región sacra (S1-S5) y el cóccix. Entre cada vértebra hay un disco que la separa de la siguiente. Las vértebras rodean  y protegen la médula espinal. La médula espinal se divide en segmentos y cada segmento tiene un par de nervios raquídeos que envían mensajes entre el encéfalo y el resto del cuerpo. Hay muchos nervios raquídeos que continúan más allá del cono medular (parte final de la médula espinal); este conjunto de nervios se llama cola de caballo.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>espina vertebral</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Los huesos, músculos, tendones y otros tejidos que van desde la base del cráneo hasta el cóccix (hueso coccígeo). La espina vertebral encierra la médula espinal y el líquido que rodea la médula espinal. También se llama columna espinal, columna vertebral, espina dorsal y raquis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2008-11-21</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
