<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000428286"><TermName>diffuse large B-cell lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(dih-FYOOS larj ... sel lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe a group of fast-growing B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas (NHL) in which the cancer cells look large when viewed under a microscope. Diffuse large B-cell lymphomas are the most common type of NHL and are marked by rapidly growing tumors in the lymph nodes, spleen, liver, bone marrow, or other tissues and organs. Signs and symptoms may include swollen lymph nodes, fever, drenching night sweats, fatigue, and weight loss. Diffuse large B-cell lymphomas can occur at any age but are more common in older adults. They may sometimes be called by the more general term, large B-cell lymphoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713338" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;diffuse large B-cell lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713339" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma difuso de células B grandes&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma difuso de células B grandes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que se utiliza para describir un grupo de linfomas no Hodgkin (LNH) de células B de crecimiento rápido, cuyas células cancerosas se observan de gran tamaño al microscopio. Los linfomas difusos de células B grandes son el tipo más común de LNH y se caracterizan por la formación de tumores de crecimiento rápido en los ganglios linfáticos, el bazo, el hígado, la médula ósea, u otros tejidos y órganos. Los signos y síntomas incluyen inflamación de los ganglios linfáticos, fiebre, sudores nocturnos excesivos, fatiga y pérdida de peso. Los linfomas difusos de células B grandes se presentan a cualquier edad, pero son más frecuentes en los adultos mayores. A veces, se conocen con el término más general de linfoma de células B grandes. También se llama linfoma B difuso de células grandes y linfoma difuso de linfocitos B grandes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-09-27</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
