<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000428385">
  <TermName>stage IVB laryngeal cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... luh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage IV laryngeal cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC.  In stage IVB, (1) cancer may have spread from the supraglottis, glottis, or subglottis to the space in front of the spine, the area around the carotid artery, or the area between the lungs.  The vocal cords may not work normally. Cancer has spread: (a) to one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters. Cancer has not spread through the outside covering of the lymph node; or (b) to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters. Cancer has spread through the outside covering of the lymph node; or (c) to more than one lymph node anywhere in the neck. Cancer has spread through the outside covering of the lymph nodes; or (d) to one lymph node of any size on the side of the neck opposite the primary tumor. Cancer has spread through the outside covering of the lymph node; OR (2) cancer has spread from the supraglottis, glottis, or subglottis to the space in front of the spine, the area around the carotid artery, or the area between the lungs. Cancer may have also spread to one or more lymph nodes anywhere in the neck and the lymph nodes may be any size.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713433" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVB laryngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713432" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de laringe en estadio IVB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de laringe en estadio IVB</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer de laringe en estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC.  En el estadio IVB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado de la supraglotis, glotis o subglotis al espacio delante de la columna vertebral, el área que rodea la arteria carótida o el área entre los pulmones. Las cuerdas vocales tal vez no funcionen de forma normal. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático que mide más de 6 cm; el cáncer no se diseminó a través de la capa externa del ganglio linfático; b) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático no mide más de 3 cm; el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa externa del ganglio linfático; c) el cáncer se diseminó a más de 1 ganglio linfático en cualquier parte del cuello; el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa externa de los ganglios linfáticos; d) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático de cualquier tamaño del lado del cuello contrario al tumor primario; el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa externa del ganglio linfático. 2) El cáncer se diseminó de la supraglotis, glotis o subglotis al espacio delante de la columna vertebral, el área que rodea la arteria carótida o el área entre los pulmones. También es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos en cualquier parte del cuello; los ganglios linfáticos son de cualquier tamaño.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-10-02</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258016" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/laryngeal-treatment-pdq">Laryngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000393556" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-laringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de laringe</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
