<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430497"><TermName>stage IVA hypopharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... HY-poh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV hypopharyngeal cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, the tumor (1) has spread to the thyroid cartilage, the bone above the thyroid cartilage, the thyroid gland, the cartilage around the trachea, the esophageal muscle, or the nearby muscles and fatty tissue in the neck. Cancer may have also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor. The affected lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) is found in the hypopharynx and may have spread to the thyroid cartilage, the bone above the thyroid cartilage, the thyroid gland, the cartilage around the trachea, the esophagus, or the nearby muscles and fatty tissue in the neck. Cancer has spread to one of the following: (a) one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor. The affected lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters; or (b) more than one lymph node anywhere in the neck. The affected lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713625" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVA hypopharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713626" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de hipofaringe en estadio IVA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de hipofaringe en estadio IVA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de hipofaringe en estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor se diseminó al cartílago tiroideo, el hueso encima del cartílago tiroideo, la tiroides, el cartílago que rodea la tráquea, el músculo esofágico, o a los músculos cercanos y el tejido adiposo del cuello. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor. El ganglio linfático afectado mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El tumor se encuentra en la hipofaringe y es posible que se haya diseminado al cartílago tiroideo, el hueso encima del cartílago tiroideo, la tiroides, el cartílago que rodea la tráquea, el esófago, o a los músculos cercanos y el tejido adiposo del cuello. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor; el ganglio linfático afectado mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 6 cm; b) el cáncer se diseminó a más de 1 ganglio linfático en cualquier parte del cuello; los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden 6 cm o menos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-09-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258014" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/hypopharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Hypopharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256820" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-hipofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de hipofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
