<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430404">
  <TermName>advance directive</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ad-VANS duh-REK-tiv)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A legal document that states a person’s wishes about receiving medical care if that person is no longer able to make medical decisions because of a serious illness or injury. An advance directive may also give a person (such as a spouse, relative, or friend) the authority to make medical decisions for another person when that person can no longer make decisions. There are different types of advance directives, including a living will, durable power of attorney (DPA) for health care, and do not resuscitate (DNR) orders. In the United States, the laws for advance directives may be different for each state, and each state may allow only certain types of advance directives.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713398" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;advance directive&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713399" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;instrucciones por adelantado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>instrucciones por adelantado</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Documento jurídico por el que una persona expresa qué atención medica desea recibir en caso de que no pueda tomar decisiones médicas debido a una enfermedad o lesión grave. Es posible que en estas instrucciones también se autorice a otra persona (cónyuge, familiar o amigo) a tomar decisiones médicas cuando la persona ya no pueda hacerlo. Hay distintos tipos de instrucciones por adelantado: testamento vital,  poder notarial permanente (PNP) y orden de no reanimar (ONR). En los Estados Unidos, las leyes que rigen las instrucciones por adelantado a veces son diferentes en cada estado o solo permiten ciertos tipos de instrucciones por adelantado. También se llama directrices o voluntades anticipadas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-02-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/managing-care/advance-directives">Advance Directives</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/manejo-del-cancer/instrucciones-adelantadas">Instrucciones por adelantado</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
