<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430481"><TermName>DNR order</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… OR-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A legal document in which a person or their proxy (such as a spouse, relative, friend, or lawyer) states that health care providers should not use cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) if that person’s heart or breathing stops. CPR is a life-saving procedure used to try to restart the heart and breathing after one or both have stopped.  A DNR order is a decision only about CPR. It does not affect other treatments that may be used to help keep a person alive, such as medicine, food, or fluids. A DNR order may be included as part of an advance directive, such as a living will. Also called do not resuscitate order.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733256" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;DNR order&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>ONR</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Documento legal por el que una persona o su representante (por ejemplo, un cónyuge, pariente, amigo o abogado) indica a los proveedores de atención de la salud que no deben iniciar  la reanimación cardiopulmonar (RCP) si se detiene el corazón o si la persona deja de respirar. La RCP es un procedimiento para salvar vidas que se usa con el fin de intentar reiniciar el corazón y la respiración después de que uno o ambos se hayan detenido.  Una ONR es una decisión solo sobre la RCP, no afecta a otros tratamientos que se usen para ayudar a mantener con vida a una persona, como medicamentos, alimentos o líquidos. Una ONR puede incluirse como parte de una directiva anticipada, como un testamento vital. También se llama NDR, orden de no reanimar y PNR.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-06-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000430404" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">advance directive</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000430404" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">instrucciones por adelantado</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
