<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430698">
  <TermName>ionizing radiation</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(I-uh-NY-zing RAY-dee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of high-energy radiation that has enough energy to remove an electron (negative particle) from an atom or molecule, causing it to become ionized. Ionizing radiation can cause chemical changes in cells and damage DNA. This may increase the risk of developing certain health conditions, such as cancer. Ionizing radiation can come from natural sources, such as radon and cosmic rays (rays that enter the earth's atmosphere from outer space).  It may also come from medical imaging equipment, such as x-ray, CT scan, or PET scan machines. Nuclear power plant accidents and atomic weapons also release high levels of ionizing radiation. Being exposed to very high doses of ionizing radiation can cause immediate damage to a person’s body, including severe skin or tissue damage, acute radiation sickness, and death.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713676" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ionizing radiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiación ionizante&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>radiación ionizante</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de radiación de alta energía que tiene suficiente energía como para eliminar un electrón (partícula negativa) de un átomo o molécula y causar su ionización. La  radiación ionizante produce cambios químicos en las células y daña el ADN. Esto aumenta el riesgo de padecer de ciertas afecciones, como el cáncer. La radiación ionizante proviene de fuentes naturales, como el radón y los rayos cósmicos (rayos que entran en la atmósfera terrestre desde el espacio exterior), y de aparatos de imaginología médica, como las máquinas de radiografía, de tomografía computarizada (TC) o de tomografía  por emisión de positrones (TEP). Los accidentes de plantas nucleares y las armas atómicas también liberan niveles altos de radiación ionizante. Es posible que la exposición a dosis muy altas de radiación ionizante provoque daños inmediatos en el cuerpo, que incluyen daños graves en la piel o los tejidos, enfermedad aguda por radiación y muerte.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2016-09-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/radiation/electromagnetic-fields-fact-sheet">Electromagnetic Fields and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/radiacion/hoja-informativa-campos-electromagneticos">Campos electromagnéticos y cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
