<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430864">
  <TermName>intraductal papilloma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(IN-truh-DUK-tul PA-pih-LOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer), wart-like growth in a milk duct of the breast. It is usually found close to the nipple and may cause a discharge from the nipple. It may also cause pain and a lump in the breast that can be felt. It usually affects women aged 35-55 years. Having a single papilloma does not increase the risk of breast cancer.  When there are multiple intraductal papillomas, they are usually found farther from the nipple. There may not be a nipple discharge and the papillomas may not be felt.   Having multiple intraductal papillomas may increase the risk of breast cancer.  Also called intraductal breast papilloma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713670" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intraductal papilloma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713669" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;papiloma intraductal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>papiloma intraductal</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso), similar a una verruga, en un conducto galactóforo de la mama (seno). Por lo general, se encuentra cerca del pezón, por donde a veces produce secreción. En ocasiones, también causa dolor y un bulto en la mama que se puede palpar. Suele afectar a mujeres de 35 a 55 años. Tener un solo papiloma no suele aumentar el riesgo de cáncer. Cuando hay múltiples papilomas intraductales, suelen estar lejos del pezón, no producen secreción ni son palpables. Es posible que tener múltiples papilomas intraductales aumente el riesgo de cáncer de mama. También se llama papiloma intracanalicular y papiloma intraductal de la mama.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2009-04-10</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
