<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000438731">
  <TermName>stage 0 breast carcinoma in situ</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... brest KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which abnormal cells are found in the tissues of the breast. There are 2 types of stage 0 breast carcinoma in situ: ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) and Paget disease of the nipple. DCIS is a condition in which the abnormal cells are found in the lining of a breast duct. The abnormal cells have not spread outside the duct to other tissues in the breast. Paget disease of the nipple is a condition in which abnormal cells are found in the skin cells of the nipple and may spread to the areola. Patients with Paget disease of the nipple may also have DCIS or invasive breast cancer in the same breast. Also called breast carcinoma in situ.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713749" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage 0 breast carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713748" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de mama in situ en estadio 0&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma de mama in situ en estadio 0</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que se encuentran células anormales en el tejido de la mama. Hay dos tipos de carcinoma de mama in situ en estadio 0: carcinoma ductal in situ  (CDIS) y enfermedad de Paget del pezón. El CDIS es una afección no invasiva por la que se encuentran células anormales en el revestimiento de un conducto de la mama. Las células anormales no se diseminaron fuera del conducto a otros tejidos de la mama. La enfermedad de Paget del pezón es una afección por la que se encuentran células anormales en la piel del pezón que a veces se diseminan a la areola. Es posible que los pacientes con enfermedad de Paget del pezón también tengan CDIS o cáncer de mama invasivo en la misma mama. También se llama carcinoma de mama in situ.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-09-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-04-10</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955" url="/types/breast/patient/breast-treatment-pdq">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762" url="/espanol/tipos/seno/paciente/tratamiento-seno-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de mama</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
