<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000439429">
  <TermName>throat</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(throte)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The hollow, muscular tube inside the neck that starts behind the nose and ends at the top of the trachea (windpipe) and esophagus (the tube that goes to the stomach). The throat acts as a passageway for air to enter the lungs and food and liquid to enter the esophagus. It contains many structures, including the tonsils, adenoids, pharynx, and larynx.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713688" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;throat&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000713689" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;garganta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813315" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the throat; drawing shows the pharynx, which includes the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx. Also shown are the adenoids, tonsils, larynx, esophagus, and trachea." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Anatomy of the throat. The throat is a hollow, muscular tube inside the neck that acts as a passageway for air to enter the lungs and for food and liquid to enter the esophagus. It contains many structures, including the adenoids, tonsils, pharynx (the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx), larynx, esophagus, and trachea. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813376" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la garganta. En el dibujo se observa la faringe y se señalan sus partes, que incluyen la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe. Además, se señala una adenoide, una amígdala, la laringe, y la primera parte del esófago y la tráquea en el cuello." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Anatomía de la garganta. La garganta es un tubo muscular hueco dentro del cuello, que cumple una función de conducto por donde pasa el aire a los pulmones, y los alimentos y bebidas al esófago. La garganta contiene varias estructuras, como las adenoides, las amígdalas, la faringe (nasofaringe, orofaringe e hipofaringe),  la laringe, el esófago y la tráquea.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>garganta</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tubo muscular hueco dentro del cuello que comienza detrás de la nariz y termina en la parte superior de la tráquea y el esófago (tubo que se comunica con el estómago). Cumple una función de conducto por donde pasa el aire a los pulmones, y pasan los alimentos y bebidas al esófago. La garganta contiene múltiples estructuras, como las amígdalas, las adenoides, la faringe y la laringe.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-07-08</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
