<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000043989">
  <TermName>viral vector</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(VY-rul VEK-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of a virus used to deliver genetic material into a cell. Before the virus is used in this way, it is changed in the laboratory so that it cannot cause disease in people. Viral vectors may be used to carry genes that can change cancer cells back to normal cells or to replace a gene that isn’t working correctly with a working copy of the gene. In cancer vaccines, viral vectors can be used to deliver specific cancer-related antigens into the body. The antigens may stimulate the immune system to recognize and kill the cancer cells. Viral vectors may also be used in vaccines to help prevent certain types of viral infections. Examples of viral vectors are adenoviruses, adeno-associated viruses, retroviruses, lentiviruses, and herpes simplex viruses.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704001" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;viral vector&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704000" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vector vírico&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>vector vírico</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de virus que se usa para introducir material genético en una célula. Antes de usarse de esa forma, el virus se altera en el laboratorio para que no cause enfermedades en las personas. Los vectores víricos también se usan para transportar genes que pueden hacer que las células cancerosas se vuelvan normales, o para sustituir un gen que no funciona bien por una copia que funciona de forma correcta. En las vacunas contra el cáncer, los vectores víricos pueden usarse para introducir en el cuerpo antígenos específicos relacionados con el cáncer. Los antígenos tal vez estimulen al sistema inmunitario para que reconozca y destruya las células cancerosas. También es posible usar los vectores víricos en vacunas para ayudar a prevenir ciertos tipos de infecciones víricas. Ejemplos de vectores víricos son los adenovirus, los virus adenoasociados, los retrovirus, los lentivirus y los virus del herpes simple. También se llama vector viral.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2023-12-15</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
