<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000440111"><TermName>PTSD</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An anxiety disorder that develops in reaction to physical injury or severe mental or emotional distress, such as military combat, violent assault, natural disaster, or other life-threatening events. Having cancer may also lead to PTSD. Symptoms interfere with day-to-day living and include reliving the event in nightmares or flashbacks; avoiding people, places, and things connected to the event; feeling alone and losing interest in daily activities; and having trouble concentrating and sleeping. Also called post-traumatic stress disorder.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>TEPT</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno de ansiedad que se presenta como reacción a una lesión física o un sufrimiento mental o emocional grave, como el combate militar, el asalto violento, los desastres naturales y otros acontecimientos de peligro mortal. El cáncer, a veces, también causa el TEPT. Los síntomas de este trastorno dificultan la vida diaria. Por ejemplo, revivir el acontecimiento durante una pesadilla o una memoria retrospectiva, evitar a las personas, los lugares y los objetos asociados con el acontecimiento, sentirse solo y perder el interés en las actividades diarias, así como tener dificultad para concentrarse y dormir. También se llama trastorno de estrés postraumático.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-01-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062831" url="/about-cancer/coping/survivorship/new-normal/ptsd-pdq">Cancer-Related Post-Traumatic Stress</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256660" url="/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/supervivencia/nueva-normalidad/ptsd-pdq">Estrés postraumático relacionado con el cáncer</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
