<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044042"><TermName>inflammation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-fluh-MAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A normal part of the body’s response to injury or infection. Inflammation occurs when the body releases chemicals that trigger an immune response to fight off infection or heal damaged tissue. Once the injury or infection is healed, the inflammatory process ends. Chronic inflammation is an abnormal immune response in which the inflammatory process does not end when it should or may begin when there is no infection or injury. Over time, chronic inflammation can damage healthy cells, tissues, and organs. This can lead to diseases such as cancer, heart disease, diabetes, asthma, Alzheimer disease, and autoimmune conditions.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inflammation&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704078" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inflamaci?n&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>inflamación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Reacción normal de una parte del cuerpo a una herida, lesión  o infección. La inflamación ocurre cuando el cuerpo elabora sustancias químicas que producen una respuesta inmunitaria para combatir la infección o sanar el tejido dañado. El proceso inflamatorio termina una vez que se cura la herida o la infección. La inflamación crónica es una respuesta inmunitaria anormal, en la que el proceso inflamatorio no termina cuando debería, o que aparece cuando no hay una  infección o una herida. Con el tiempo, la inflamación crónica puede dañar las células, los tejidos y los órganos sanos, lo que en ocasiones produce enfermedades como el cáncer, cardiopatías, diabetes, asma, enfermedad de Alzheimer y afecciones autoinmunitarias. También se llama respuesta inflamatoria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2023-02-27</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
