<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044175">
  <TermName>port-a-cath</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(port-uh-cath)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A device used to draw blood and give treatments, including intravenous fluids, blood transfusions, or drugs such as chemotherapy and antibiotics. The port is placed under the skin, usually in the right side of the chest. It is attached to a catheter (a thin, flexible tube) that is guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. A needle is inserted through the skin into the port to draw blood or give fluids and other treatments. A port-a-cath may stay in place for many weeks, months, or years.   Also called port.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000727813" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;port-a-cath&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000727814" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;catéter implantable&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000756805" type="image/jpeg" alt="Port-a-cath (Port); drawing showing a port-a-cath under the skin in the right side of the chest. It is attached to a catheter that is threaded into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. The left inset shows the port-a-cath under the skin. The right inset shows a needle being inserted into the port-a-cath and blood being drawn from the port-a-cath through a syringe attached to the needle." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Port-a-cath (Port). A port-a-cath is a device that is usually placed under the skin in the right side of the chest. It is attached to a catheter (a thin, flexible tube) that is threaded into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. A port-a-cath is used to give intravenous fluids, blood transfusions, chemotherapy, and other drugs. It is also used for taking blood samples. A port-a-cath may stay in place for a long time and helps reduce the need for repeated needle sticks.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000774008" type="image/jpeg" alt="Catéter implantable (vía). En la imagen se observa un catéter implantable debajo de la piel en el lado derecho del pecho. El catéter se introduce hasta la vena cava superior (vena grande en el lado superior derecho del corazón). En el recuadro izquierdo, se muestra el catéter implantable debajo de la piel. En el recuadro derecho, se muestra una aguja que se introduce en el catéter implantable, que luego se usa para conectar una jeringa y extraer sangre por el catéter implantable." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Catéter implantable (vía). Dispositivo que se coloca debajo de la piel, por lo general en el lado derecho del pecho. El catéter (tubo delgado y flexible) se introduce hasta la vena cava superior (vena grande en el lado superior derecho del corazón). El catéter implantable se usa para administrar líquidos intravenosos, transfusiones de sangre, quimioterapia y otros medicamentos. También se usa para extraer muestras de sangre. El catéter implantable se puede dejar colocado  durante mucho tiempo y ayuda a evitar los pinchazos múltiples.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>catéter implantable</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para extraer sangre y administrar tratamientos, como líquidos intravenosos, transfusiones de sangre o medicamentos como quimioterapia y antibióticos.  El catéter implantable se  coloca debajo de la piel, por lo general en el lado derecho del pecho. Se conecta con un catéter (tubo delgado y flexible) que se introduce hasta una vena grande en el lado superior derecho del corazón llamada vena cava superior. Se introduce una aguja a través de la piel hasta el extremo del catéter para extraer sangre o administrar líquidos y otros tratamientos. El catéter implantable a veces se deja en el cuerpo durante muchas semanas, meses o años. También se llama catéter venoso central con reservorio subcutáneo, catéter venoso central de larga duración y vía central de acceso subcutáneo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-09-09</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
