<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044232">
  <TermName>aromatase inhibitor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(uh-ROH-muh-tays in-HIH-bih-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that blocks the activity of an enzyme called aromatase, which the body uses to make estrogen in the ovaries and other tissues. Blocking aromatase lowers the amount of estrogen made by the body, which may stop the growth of cancer cells that need estrogen to grow. Aromatase inhibitors are used to treat some types of breast cancer or to keep it from coming back. They may also be used to help prevent breast cancer in some women who are at a high risk of developing it. Examples of aromatase inhibitors are anastrozole, letrozole, and exemestane. Aromatase inhibitors are a type of hormone therapy. Also called AI drug.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704331" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aromatase inhibitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704330" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de la aromatasa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>inhibidor de la aromatasa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que bloquea la actividad de una enzima llamada aromatasa, que el cuerpo usa para elaborar estrógeno en los ovarios y en otros tejidos. Al bloquear la aromatasa se reduce la cantidad de estrógeno que produce el cuerpo, lo que quizás impida la multiplicación de células cancerosas que necesitan el estrógeno para su desarrollo. Los inhibidores de la aromatasa se usan para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer de mama o para impedir que este regrese. También se usan para prevenir el cáncer de mama en ciertas mujeres con riesgo alto de presentar este  cáncer. Algunos ejemplos de inhibidores de la aromatasa son el anastrozol, el letrozol y el exemestano. Los  inhibidores de la aromatasa son un tipo de terapia hormonal. También se llama bloqueador de la aromatasa y medicamento inhibidor de la aromatasa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-12-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/breast-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Hormone Therapy for Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal-seno" UseWith="es">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de seno</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
