<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044253"><TermName>keratoacanthoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAYR-uh-toh-AK-un-THOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A fast-growing, dome-shaped skin tumor that usually occurs on sun-exposed areas of the body, especially the head, neck, arms, legs, and back of the hands. Keratoacanthomas often begin in a hair follicle. They may look like squamous cell skin cancer, but they are usually benign and rarely spread to other parts of the body. Keratoacanthomas are usually caused by sun exposure, but they may also be caused by a human papilloma virus infection, a weakened immune system, certain genetic conditions, exposure to some cancer-causing chemicals, and an injury to the skin. They usually go away on their own but can sometimes come back. They occur more often in older men.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704369" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;keratoacanthoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704368" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;queratoacantoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>queratoacantoma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor de piel en forma de cúpula que crece rápido y a menudo surge en las áreas del cuerpo expuestas al sol, en especial, en la cabeza, el cuello, los brazos, las piernas y el dorso de las manos. Los queratoacantomas con frecuencia comienzan en un folículo piloso. Es posible que se parezcan a un cáncer de células escamosas de piel, pero en general son benignos y es infrecuente que se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo. La causa más común de los queratoacantomas  es la exposición a la luz del sol, aunque también tienen otras  causas, como una infección por un virus del papiloma humano, un sistema inmunitario debilitado, ciertas afecciones genéticas, la exposición a algunas sustancias químicas que producen cáncer y una lesión en la piel. Por lo general desaparecen solos, pero a veces vuelven. Son más frecuentes en hombres de edad avanzada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-07-26</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
