<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044271"><TermName>PDQ</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>PDQ is an online source of cancer information that is developed and maintained by the National Cancer Institute (NCI). It makes current, credible, and accurate cancer information available to health professionals and the public. PDQ contains information about cancer treatment, supportive and palliative care, screening, prevention, genetics, and integrative, complementary, and alternative medicine. This information is updated with the most recent evidence from scientific research.   PDQ also contains drug information summaries on many cancer-related drugs and dictionaries of cancer terms, drug terms, and genetics terms. Most of this information and more specific information about PDQ can be found on the NCI's website at <ExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq/">http://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq</ExternalRef>. Also called Physician Data Query.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>PDQ</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El PDQ es un recurso en línea que el Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI) produce y mantiene. Ofrece información actual, fiable y exacta sobre el cáncer, y la pone a disposición de profesionales para la salud y el público en general. El PDQ contiene información sobre el cáncer relacionada con el tratamiento, los cuidados  médicos de apoyo y paliativos, los  exámenes de detección, la prevención, las características genéticas y la medicina integral, alternativa y complementaria. Esta información se actualiza según la evidencia más reciente de la investigación científica. También incluye  resúmenes de información sobre los medicamentos que se usan durante el tratamiento del cáncer y diccionarios de términos relacionados con el cáncer, la genética y los medicamentos. Es posible obtener más información acerca del PDQ en el portal de Internet del NCI en <ExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq/">http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq</ExternalRef>. También se llama Physician Data Query.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-11-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq">PDQ® -  NCI's Comprehensive Database</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq">Base de datos integral del NCI - PDQ®</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
