<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000442897"><TermName>nevoid basal cell carcinoma syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NEE-voyd BAY-sul sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that affects many organs and tissues in the body. People with this disorder have a very high risk of developing basal cell skin cancer during adolescence or early adulthood. They are also at risk of developing medulloblastoma (a type of brain cancer) and other types of cancer. Nevoid basal cell carcinoma syndrome may also cause benign (not cancer) tumors in the jaw, heart, or ovaries. Other signs and symptoms include a large head and unusual facial features; small pits in the skin on the hands and feet; abnormalities of the spine, ribs, or skull; eye problems; and developmental problems. Nevoid basal cell carcinoma syndrome is caused by a mutation (change) in the PTCH1 gene. Also called basal cell nevus syndrome, BCNS, Gorlin syndrome, and NBCCS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713761" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nevoid basal cell carcinoma syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713760" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome del carcinoma nevoide de células basales&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765737" type="image/jpeg" alt="Photographs showing a skin cancer lesion that looks reddish brown and slightly raised (left panel) and the back of a person’s ear with a skin cancer lesion that looks like an open sore with a pearly rim (right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Basal cell carcinoma. A skin cancer lesion that looks reddish brown and slightly raised (left panel) and a skin cancer lesion that looks like an open sore with a pearly rim (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766226" type="image/jpeg" alt="Las fotografías muestran una lesión de cáncer de piel que aparece de color rojizo oscuro y ligeramente abultada (panel izquierdo) y la parte trasera de la oreja de una persona con lesión cancerosa en la piel que luce como una llaga abierta con un anillo perlado (panel derecho)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Carcinoma de célula basal. Una lesión de cáncer de piel que aparece de color rojizo oscuro y ligeramente abultada (panel izquierdo) y una lesión cancerosa en la piel que luce como una llaga abierta con un anillo perlado (panel derecho).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>síndrome del carcinoma nevoide de células basales</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro que afecta muchos órganos y tejidos del cuerpo. Las personas con este trastorno presentan un riesgo muy alto de cáncer de piel de células basales durante la adolescencia o al principio de la edad adulta. Además, tienen un aumento del riesgo de meduloblastoma (tipo de cáncer de encéfalo) y de otros tipos de cáncer. El síndrome del carcinoma nevoide de células basales a veces causa tumores benignos (no cancerosos) en el maxilar, el corazón y los ovarios. Otros signos y síntomas son una cabeza larga y una cara de aspecto inusual; hoyuelos en la piel de las manos y los pies; malformaciones en la columna vertebral, las costillas o el cráneo; problemas de los ojos y retrasos del desarrollo. La causa del  síndrome del carcinoma nevoide de células basales es una mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>. También se llama SCNCB, síndrome de Gorlin, síndrome de nevo de células basales, síndrome del carcinoma nevoide basocelular y SNCB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-08-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-02-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7166/basal-cell-nevus-syndrome">Nevoid basal cell carcinoma syndrome  (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/gorlin-syndrome/">Gorlin syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001452.htm">Síndrome del carcinoma basocelular congénito (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
