<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044348"><TermName>sepsis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SEP-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An extreme immune response to infection that can lead to tissue damage, organ failure, or death if not treated right away. Sepsis occurs when chemicals released by the body into the bloodstream to fight an infection trigger inflammation, blood clots, and leaky blood vessels throughout the body. This reduces blood flow and the amount of oxygen and nutrients to the body’s tissues and organs. Bacterial infections are the most common cause of sepsis, but it can also be caused by other types of infections. Signs and symptoms may include fever or very low body temperature, chills, fast heart rate, rapid or trouble breathing, warm or sweaty skin, confusion, and severe pain. Sepsis can occur in anyone with an infection, but is more common in older adults, infants, pregnant women, or people who are in the hospital or who have a weakened immune system, chronic medical condition, or severe injury or illness.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704521" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sepsis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704520" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sepsis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sepsis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Respuesta inmunitaria extrema a una infección que causa daños en los tejidos, insuficiencia orgánica o la muerte si no se trata de inmediato. La sepsis se produce cuando las sustancias químicas liberadas por el organismo en el torrente sanguíneo con el fin de combatir una infección provocan inflamación, coágulos y fugas en los vasos sanguíneos de todo el cuerpo. Esto reduce el flujo de sangre y la cantidad de oxígeno y nutrientes que llegan a los tejidos y órganos del cuerpo. Las infecciones bacterianas son la causa más frecuente de sepsis, pero también se produce por otros tipos de infecciones. Los signos y síntomas incluyen fiebre o temperatura corporal muy baja, escalofríos, frecuencia cardiaca acelerada, respiración rápida o dificultosa, piel caliente o sudorosa, confusión y dolor intenso. La sepsis puede afectar a cualquier persona que presente una infección, pero es más frecuente en adultos mayores, lactantes, mujeres embarazadas, o personas hospitalizadas o con un sistema inmunitario debilitado, una enfermedad crónica o una lesión o enfermedad grave.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2022-12-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
