<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000443575">
  <TermName>mature teratoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(muh-CHOOR TAYR-uh-TOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of germ cell tumor that is usually made up of several different types of tissue, such as hair, muscle, and bone. Mature teratomas have cells that look almost like normal cells under a microscope. Some mature teratomas make enzymes or hormones that may cause signs and symptoms of disease. They are benign (not cancer) but may come back after being removed by surgery. Mature teratomas usually occur in the sacrum or tailbone in newborns or in the testicles or ovaries at the start of puberty. They are often called dermoid cysts.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mature teratoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;teratoma maduro&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>teratoma maduro</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de tumor de células germinativas  que suele estar compuesto de muchos tipos diferentes de tejido, como pelo, músculo y hueso. Los teratomas maduros tienen células que se parecen mucho a las células normales cuando se observan al microscopio. Algunos teratomas maduros elaboran enzimas u hormonas que a veces causan signos y síntomas de enfermedad. Estos tumores son benignos (no cancerosos), pero quizás vuelvan después de que se extirpan mediante cirugía. A  menudo, los teratomas surgen en el sacro o en el hueso coccígeo de recién nacidos, o aparecen en los testículos u ovarios al comienzo de la pubertad. Con frecuencia se llaman  quistes dermoides.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-04-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-02-13</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
