<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044370"><TermName>Chamberlain procedure</TermName><TermPronunciation>(CHAYM-ber-len proh-SEE-jer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a tube is inserted into the chest to view the tissues and organs in the area between the lungs and between the breastbone and heart. The tube is inserted through an incision next to the breastbone. This procedure is usually used to get a tissue sample from the lymph nodes on the left side of the chest. Also called anterior mediastinotomy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704548" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Chamberlain procedure&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704549" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;procedimiento de Chamberlain&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466554" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopy; shows mediastinoscope with light and lens inserted into the chest through an incision above the breastbone. Drawing shows right and left lungs, trachea, and lymph nodes. Inset shows anterior mediastinotomy (Chamberlain procedure) with incision beside the breastbone." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Mediastinoscopy. A mediastinoscope is inserted into the chest through an
incision above the breastbone to look for abnormal areas between the
lungs. A mediastinoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light
and a lens for viewing. It may also have a cutting tool. Tissue samples
may be taken from lymph nodes on the right side of the chest and checked
under a microscope for signs of cancer. In an anterior mediastinotomy
(Chamberlain procedure), the incision is made beside the breastbone to
remove tissue samples from the lymph nodes on the left side of the
chest.
</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000494346" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopia. En la imagen se observa un mediastinoscopio con una lente y una luz. El mediastinoscopio se introduce en el tórax a través de una incisión por encima del esternón. Se observan el pulmón derecho e izquierdo, la tráquea y los ganglios linfáticos. En el recuadro se muestra una mediastinotomía (procedimiento de Chamberlain)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Mediastinoscopia. Se realiza una incisión (corte) por encima del esternón y se introduce un mediastinoscopio en el tórax para determinar si hay áreas anormales entre los pulmones. Un mediastinoscopio es un instrumento delgado en forma de tubo, con una luz y una lente para observar. A veces tiene una herramienta para cortar. Se toman muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos del lado derecho del tórax para observarlas al microscopio y verificar si hay signos de cáncer. En una mediastinotomía anterior (procedimiento de Chamberlain), se hace una incisión junto al esternón para extraer muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos del lado izquierdo del tórax.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>procedimiento de Chamberlain</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se introduce un tubo (mediastinoscopio)  en el tórax para observar los tejidos y los órganos ubicados entre los pulmones, y entre el esternón y el corazón. El tubo se introduce a través de una incisión  que se hace junto al esternón. Por lo general, este procedimiento se usa para obtener una muestra de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos del lado izquierdo del tórax. También se llama mediastinotomía anterior.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2006-10-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
