<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044372">
  <TermName>benign prostatic hypertrophy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(beh-NINE prah-STA-tik hy-PER-troh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) condition in which the prostate gland is larger than normal. As the prostate gets bigger, it may press against the bladder and urethra, which can slow or block the flow of urine from the bladder. This can cause urinary symptoms, such as feeling a need to urinate often or right away, waking up many times during the night to urinate, trouble urinating, leaking urine, pain during urination or after ejaculation (the release of semen through the penis during orgasm), and blood in the urine. Benign prostatic hypertrophy does not increase a person’s risk of developing prostate cancer. However, if not treated, it can lead to a weak bladder, urinary retention, urinary tract infections, bladder stones, or bladder or kidney damage. Benign prostatic hypertrophy is most common in older men. Also called benign prostatic hyperplasia, BPH, and enlarged prostate.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704552" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;benign prostatic hypertrophy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704553" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hipertrofia prostática benigna&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000462221" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing shows normal male reproductive and urinary anatomy and benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH). Panel on the left shows the normal prostate and flow of urine from the bladder through the urethra. Panel on the right shows an enlarged prostate pressing on the bladder and urethra, blocking the flow of urine." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">Normal prostate and benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH). A normal prostate does not block the flow of urine from the bladder. An enlarged prostate  presses on the bladder and urethra and blocks the flow of urine. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000462222" type="image/jpeg" alt="Un dibujo en dos paneles muestra la anatomía reproductora y urinaria normal así como hiperplasia prostática benigna (HPB). El panel de la izquierda muestra la próstata normal y el flujo de orina de la vejiga a la uretra. El panel de la derecha muestra un agrandamiento de próstata que ejerce presión sobre la vejiga y la uretra, con la obstrucción del flujo de la orina." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Próstata normal e hiperplasia prostática benigna (HPB). Una próstata normal no obstruye el flujo de la orina desde la vejiga. El agrandamiento de la próstata  ejerce presión sobre la vejiga y la uretra, y obstruye el flujo de la orina.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>hipertrofia prostática benigna</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección benigna (no cancerosa) por la que  la próstata
se vuelve más grande de lo normal. A medida que la próstata aumenta de tamaño, presiona la vejiga y la uretra, lo que bloquea
el flujo de
la
orina desde la vejiga y lo hace más lento. Esto puede causar síntomas urinarios, como la sensación de tener que orinar a menudo o de inmediato, despertarse muchas veces durante la noche para orinar, problemas para orinar, pérdidas de orina, dolor al orinar o después de la eyaculación (liberación de semen a través del pene durante el orgasmo) y sangre en la orina. La hipertrofia prostática benigna no aumenta el riesgo de presentar cáncer de próstata. Sin embargo, si no se trata, puede producir debilitamiento de la vejiga, retención urinaria, infecciones del tracto urinario, cálculos en la vejiga o daños en la vejiga o los riñones. La hipertrofia prostática benigna es más frecuente en hombres de edad avanzada. También se llama hiperplasia prostática benigna, HPB y próstata agrandada.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-05-16</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/understanding-prostate-changes" UseWith="en">Understanding Prostate Changes and Conditions</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/significado-cambios-en-la-prostata" UseWith="es">Significado de los cambios en la próstata: Guía de salud para los hombres</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
