<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044386"><TermName>HPV</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of more than 200 common viruses. Some  HPVs, called cutaneous HPVs, are transmitted by casual contact and can infect the skin and cause common skin warts. Other HPVs, known as mucosal HPVs, can infect the moist surfaces or inner lining of some organs and body cavities, such as the cervix, vagina, vulva, penis, anus, mouth, and throat. Infection with some mucosal HPVs (collectively known as low-risk HPVs) can cause warts in or around the genitals, anus, mouth, and respiratory tract but rarely cause cancer. Long-lasting infection with other mucosal HPVs (collectively known as high-risk HPVs) can cause cell changes that become cancer over time if not found and removed.  HPV-related cancers include cancers of the cervix, anus, oropharynx, vagina, vulva, and penis. Mucosal HPVs are transmitted through intimate skin-to-skin contact, most often during vaginal, anal, or oral sex.  Also called human papillomavirus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813972" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;VPH&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>VPH</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de más de 200 virus comunes. Algunos de estos virus llamados VPH cutáneos, se transmiten mediante el contacto casual,  infectan la piel y causan las verrugas cutáneas comunes. Otros de estos virus conocidos como VPH mucosos, infectan las superficies húmedas o del revestimiento interno de algunos órganos y cavidades corporales, como el cuello uterino, la vagina, la vulva, el pene, el ano, la boca o la garganta. Las infecciones por ciertos VPH mucosos (conocidos colectivamente como  VPH de riesgo bajo)  pueden causar verrugas en, o alrededor de, los genitales, el ano, la boca y las vías respiratorias, pero rara vez producen cáncer. La infección duradera por otros VPH mucosos (conocidos colectivamente como VPH de riesgo alto) puede causar cambios en las células que, si no se encuentran y se extirpan,  con el tiempo se vuelven cancerosos.  Los cánceres relacionados con este grupo de virus son los  de cuello uterino, ano, orofaringe, vagina, vulva y pene. Los VPH mucosos se trasmiten por el contacto íntimo piel con piel, en especial durante las relaciones sexuales vaginales, anales u orales. También se llama PVH y virus del papiloma humano.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-09-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-and-cancer">HPV and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/vph-y-cancer?redirect=true">El virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-vaccine-fact-sheet">Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/hoja-informativa-vacuna-vph">Vacunas contra el virus del papiloma humano (VPH)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000658573" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/recombinant-HPV-bivalent-vaccine">Recombinant Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Bivalent Vaccine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000658589" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/recombinant-HPV-quadrivalent-vaccine">Recombinant Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Quadrivalent Vaccine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
