<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044441">
  <TermName>nicotinamide</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(NIH-koh-TIH-nuh-MIDE)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of niacin (vitamin B3) that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Nicotinamide is found in many plant and animal products and in dietary supplements. It is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Nicotinamide may be used to treat diabetes and certain skin conditions and is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. It may increase blood flow to cancer cells and block certain enzymes they need to repair damage to their DNA. This may make cancer cells easier to kill with radiation therapy and chemotherapy. Nicotinamide is a type of radiosensitizing agent and a type of chemosensitizing agent. Also called niacinamide.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704600" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nicotinamide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704599" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nicotinamida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>nicotinamida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma de la niacina (vitamina B3) que el cuerpo necesita en cantidades pequeñas para funcionar y estar sano. La nicotinamida se encuentra en muchos productos vegetales y animales, y en complementos alimentarios. Es soluble en agua (se disuelve en el agua) y se debe tomar todos los días. La nicotinamida se usa  para tratar la diabetes y algunas afecciones de la piel, y está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Es posible que aumente el flujo de sangre a las células cancerosas e impida la acción de ciertas enzimas que las células necesitan para reparar el daño al ADN. Esto quizás facilite la destrucción de las células cancerosas con radioterapia y quimioterapia. La nicotinamida es un tipo de radiosensibilizador y de quimiosensibilizador. También se llama amida del ácido nicotínico, niacinamida y vitamina PP.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2013-04-15</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
