<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044472">
  <TermName>UV radiation</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… RAY-dee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Invisible rays that are part of the energy that comes from the sun. UV radiation that reaches the Earth's surface is made up of two types of rays, called UVA and UVB. UV radiation also comes from sun lamps and tanning beds. It can cause skin damage, premature aging, melanoma, and other types of skin cancer. It can also cause problems with the eyes and the immune system. Skin specialists recommend that people use sunscreens that protect the skin from both kinds of UV radiation. In medicine, UV radiation also comes from special lamps or a laser and is used to treat certain skin conditions such as psoriasis, vitiligo, and skin tumors of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Also called ultraviolet radiation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704628" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;UV radiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704629" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiación UV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>radiación UV</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Rayos invisibles que forman parte de la energía que proviene del sol. La radiación UV que llega a la superficie de la Tierra se compone de dos tipos de rayos que se llaman UVA y UVB. Las lámparas solares y cámaras de bronceado también emiten radiación UV. Es posible que produzca daños en  la piel, envejecimiento prematuro, melanoma y otros tipos de cáncer de piel; además de problemas en los ojos y el sistema inmunitario. Los especialistas de la piel recomiendan que las personas usen protectores o filtros solares  que protejan la piel de ambas clases de radiación UV. En el campo de la medicina, la radiación UV de lámparas o rayos láser especiales se usa para tratar ciertas afecciones de la piel como psoriasis, vitiligo y tumores del linfoma cutáneo de células T. También se llama radiación ultravioleta y rayos UV.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2010-06-08</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062802" url="/types/skin/patient/skin-prevention-pdq">Skin Cancer Prevention</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/sunlight" UseWith="en">Sunlight</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000751556" url="/espanol/tipos/piel/paciente/prevencion-piel-pdq">Prevención del cáncer de piel</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/luz-solar" UseWith="es">Luz solar</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
