<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044481"><TermName>nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NON-steh-ROY-dul AN-tee-in-FLA-muh-TOR-ee ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that works in a different way than a steroid to reduce pain, redness, swelling, and fever in the body. Some nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs may also help keep blood clots from forming. The side effects of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs include bleeding and stomach, kidney, and heart problems. Examples of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs are aspirin, ibuprofen, ketoprofen, celecoxib, diclofenac, and ketorolac. Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs may also help prevent some types of cancer. Also called NSAID.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704638" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704639" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicamento antinflamatorio no esteroide&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicamento antiinflamatorio no esteroide</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que disminuye el dolor, el enrojecimiento, la hinchazón y la fiebre en el cuerpo de manera diferente a un esteroide. Algunos antiinflamatorios no esteroides también previenen la formación de coágulos de sangre. Sus efectos secundarios son sangrados y problemas de estómago, riñón y corazón. La aspirina, el ibuprofeno, el ketoprofeno, el celecoxib, el diclofenaco y el ketorolaco son ejemplos de antiinflamatorios no esteroides. Estos medicamentos a veces ayudan a prevenir ciertos tipos de cáncer. También se llama AINE, analgésico y antiinflamatorio no esteroide, antiinflamatorio no esteroidal, antiinflamatorio no esteroide, antiinflamatorio no esteroideo, antiinflamatorio no hormonal y fármaco antiinflamatorio no esteroide.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-10-13</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
