<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445043"><TermName>lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in tissues of the lung, usually in the cells lining air passages. The two main types are small cell lung cancer and non-small cell lung cancer. These types are diagnosed based on how the cells look under a microscope.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714622" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714623" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466533" type="image/jpeg" alt="Respiratory system anatomy; drawing shows the right lung with the upper, middle, and lower lobes, the left lung with the upper and lower lobes, and the trachea, bronchi, lymph nodes, and diaphragm. An inset shows the bronchioles, alveoli, artery, and vein." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the respiratory system showing the trachea, the right and left lungs and their lobes, and the bronchi. The lymph nodes and the diaphragm are also shown. Oxygen is inhaled into the lungs and passes through the alveoli (the tiny air sacs at the end of the bronchioles) and into the bloodstream (see inset), where it travels to the tissues throughout the body.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466537" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del aparato respiratorio. En la imagen se muestra el pulmón derecho con los lóbulos superior, medio e inferior; el pulmón izquierdo con los lóbulos superior e inferior; así como la tráquea, los bronquios, los ganglios linfáticos y el diafragma. En el recuadro se muestran los bronquiolos, los alvéolos, una arteria y una vena." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del aparato respiratorio. Se observa la tráquea,  los pulmones derecho  e izquierdo con sus lóbulos, y los bronquios.  También se muestran los ganglios linfáticos y el diafragma.  El oxígeno se inhala a los pulmones, pasa a través de los alvéolos (bolsas diminutas llenas de aire al final de los bronquiolos) al torrente sanguíneo (ver recuadro), y llega a los tejidos de todo el cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos del pulmón, por lo general, en las células que recubren las vías respiratorias. Los dos tipos más importantes de cáncer de pulmón son el cáncer de pulmón de células pequeñas y el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas. Estos tipos de cáncer se diagnostican con base en el aspecto que tengan las células bajo un microscopio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2006-11-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/lung">Lung Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/pulmon">Cáncer de pulmón</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
