<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445089">
  <TermName>survivorship</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ser-VY-ver-ship)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In cancer, survivorship focuses on the health and well-being of a person with cancer from the time of diagnosis until the end of life. This includes the physical, mental, emotional, social, and financial  effects of cancer that begin at diagnosis and continue through treatment and beyond. The survivorship experience also includes issues related to follow-up care (including regular health and wellness checkups), late effects of treatment, cancer recurrence, second cancers, and quality of life. Family members, friends, and caregivers are also considered part of the survivorship experience.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714659" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;survivorship&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;supervivencia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>supervivencia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el ámbito del cáncer, la supervivencia se enfoca en la salud y el bienestar de la persona con cáncer desde el momento del diagnóstico hasta la etapa final de la vida. Incluye los efectos físicos, mentales, emocionales, sociales y económicos del cáncer, que comienzan con el diagnóstico y continúan durante el tratamiento y después de este. La experiencia de supervivencia también incluye asuntos  relacionados con la atención de seguimiento (controles regulares de salud y bienestar), los efectos tardíos del tratamiento, la recidiva del cáncer, los segundos cánceres y la calidad de vida. Los familiares, los amigos y los cuidadores  del paciente también se consideran parte de la experiencia de supervivencia. También se llama sobrevivencia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-02-10</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping/survivorship">Cancer Survivorship</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/supervivencia">Supervivencia al cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
