<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445075"><TermName>pharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in tissues of the pharynx. The pharynx is the hollow, muscular tube inside the neck that starts behind the nose and opens into the larynx and esophagus. Pharyngeal cancer includes cancer of the nasopharynx (the upper part of the pharynx behind the nose), the oropharynx (the middle part of the pharynx), and the hypopharynx (the bottom part of the pharynx). Most pharyngeal cancers are squamous cell carcinomas (cancers that begin in thin, flat cells that look like fish scales under a microscope).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714777" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714776" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de faringe&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713970" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the pharynx; drawing shows the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx. Also shown are the nasal cavity, oral cavity, hyoid bone, larynx, esophagus, and trachea." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the pharynx. The pharynx is a hollow, muscular tube inside the neck that starts behind the nose and opens into the larynx and esophagus. The three parts of the pharynx are the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732292" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la faringe. En el dibujo se observan la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe. También se muestran la cavidad nasal, la cavidad oral, el hioides, la laringe, el esófago y la tráquea." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la faringe. La faringe es un tubo muscular hueco dentro del cuello que comienza detrás de la nariz y se comunica con la laringe y el esófago. Las tres partes de la faringe son la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de faringe</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos de la faringe, un tubo muscular hueco dentro del cuello que comienza detrás de la nariz y se comunica con la laringe  y el esófago. El cáncer de faringe incluye los cánceres de nasofaringe (parte superior de la faringe detrás de la nariz), orofaringe (parte media de la faringe) e hipofaringe (parte inferior de la faringe). La mayoría de estos cánceres son carcinomas de células escamosas (cánceres que comienzan en unas células delgadas y planas que cuando se observan al microscopio se parecen a las escamas de los peces). También se llama cáncer faríngeo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-06-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/head-and-neck" UseWith="en">Head and Neck Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello" UseWith="es">Cáncer de cabeza y cuello</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
