<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044524">
  <TermName>overactive thyroid</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... THY-royd)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition that occurs when the thyroid gland makes more thyroid hormones than the body needs. Thyroid hormones control the way the body uses energy and affect the body’s metabolism. Overactive thyroid may be caused by an autoimmune disorder called Graves’ disease, benign lumps in the thyroid gland, and inflammation of the thyroid gland. It may also be caused by consuming too much iodine in the diet or by taking too much thyroid hormone medicine. Signs and symptoms include weight loss, fatigue, rapid or irregular heartbeat, sweating, diarrhea, nervousness, mood swings, shaky hands, trouble sleeping, trouble tolerating heat, muscle weakness, and a goiter (an enlarged thyroid gland that may cause the bottom of the neck to look swollen). Overactive thyroid can usually be controlled with treatment. Also called hyperthyroidism.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704706" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;overactive thyroid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704707" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tiroides hiperactiva&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tiroides hiperactiva</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección que se presenta cuando la glándula tiroidea elabora más hormonas tiroideas que las que el cuerpo necesita.  Estas hormonas controlan la manera en que el organismo utiliza la energía y afectan el metabolismo corporal. Las causas de la tiroides  hiperactiva pueden ser un trastorno autoinmunitario que se llama enfermedad de Graves, bultos benignos o inflamación de la glándula tiroidea además de consumir demasiado yodo en la alimentación o tomar cantidades excesivas de medicamentos que contienen hormona tiroidea. Los signos y síntomas incluyen pérdida de peso, cansancio, latidos cardiacos rápidos o irregulares, sudores, diarrea, nerviosismo, cambios repentinos del  humor, temblores en las manos, dificultades para dormir, intolerancia al calor, debilidad en los músculos y bocio (agrandamiento de la glándula tiroidea que a veces causa hinchazón en la parte  inferior del cuello). A menudo, la  tiroides  hiperactiva se controla con el tratamiento. También se llama hiperfunción tiroidea e hipertiroidismo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-07-26</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
