<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044521"><TermName>pancreatic cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in the tissues of the pancreas. The pancreas is an organ in the abdomen that helps the body digest and use the energy that comes from food. Pancreatic cancer occurs when cells in the pancreas grow out of control and form a tumor. Pancreatic cancer can develop in exocrine pancreas cells, which produce digestive juices. It can also develop in endocrine pancreas cells, which produce hormones. Most pancreatic cancers begin in exocrine cells and are usually found at an advanced stage. Pancreatic endocrine cancers are less common but tend to have a better prognosis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704700" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancreatic cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704701" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de páncreas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de páncreas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos del páncreas. El páncreas es un órgano situado en el abdomen que ayuda al cuerpo a hacer la digestión y a usar la energía procedente de los alimentos. El cáncer de páncreas se presenta cuando las células del páncreas se multiplican sin control y forman un tumor. A veces se forma a partir de las células exocrinas, que producen los jugos digestivos, y otras veces a partir de las células endocrinas, que producen hormonas. En la mayoría de los casos, el cáncer de páncreas comienza en las células exocrinas y suele encontrarse en un estadio avanzado. Los cánceres endocrinos de páncreas son menos frecuentes, pero suelen tener mejor pronóstico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2025-02-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/pancreatic">Pancreatic Cancer </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/pancreas">Cáncer de páncreas</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
