<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446190">
  <TermName>stage IVA salivary gland cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...SA-lih-VAYR-ee gland KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage IV salivary gland cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, (1) cancer has spread to the skin, jawbone, ear canal, and/or facial nerve. Cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the head or neck as the tumor. The lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller and cancer has not grown outside the lymph node; OR (2) the tumor is any size and cancer may have spread to soft tissue around the salivary gland or to the skin, jawbone, ear canal, and/or facial nerve. Cancer has spread  (a) to  one lymph node on the same side of the head or neck as the tumor; the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller and cancer has grown outside the lymph node; or  (b) to  one lymph node on the same side of the head or neck as the tumor; the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters  but not larger than 6 centimeters and cancer has not grown outside the lymph node; or  (c)to more than one lymph node on the same side of the head or neck as the tumor; the lymph nodes are  6 centimeters or smaller and cancer has not grown outside the lymph nodes; or (d) to lymph nodes on both sides of the head or neck or on the side opposite the primary tumor; the lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller and cancer has not grown outside the lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714708" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVA salivary gland cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de glándulas salivales en estadio IVA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de glándulas salivales en estadio IVA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer de glándulas salivales en estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó a la piel, la mandíbula, el conducto auditivo externo o el nervio facial. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado de la cabeza o el cuello que el tumor. El ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó fuera del ganglio linfático. 2) El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que se haya diseminado al tejido blando que rodea la glándula salival o a la piel, la mandíbula, el conducto auditivo externo o el nervio facial. El cáncer se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: a) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado de la cabeza o el cuello que el tumor; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó fuera del ganglio linfático; b) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado de la cabeza o el cuello que el tumor; el ganglio linfático mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 6 cm y el cáncer no se diseminó fuera del ganglio linfático; c) el cáncer se diseminó a más de 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado de la cabeza o el cuello que el tumor; los ganglios linfáticos miden 6 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó fuera de los ganglios linfáticos; d) el cáncer se diseminó a ganglios linfáticos de ambos lados de la cabeza o el cuello, o del lado contrario al tumor primario; los ganglios linfáticos miden 6 cm o menos y el cáncer no se diseminó fuera de los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2008-06-30</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-01-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258034" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/salivary-gland-treatment-pdq">Salivary Gland Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000530606" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-glandulas-salivales-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de glándulas salivales</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
