<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446208">
  <TermName>stage II penile cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... PEE-nile KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, cancer has spread (1) to tissue just under the skin of the penis. Cancer has spread to lymph vessels, blood vessels, and/or nerves; or (2) to tissue just under the skin of the penis. Under a microscope, the cancer cells look very abnormal or the cells are sarcomatoid; or  (3) into the corpus spongiosum (spongy erectile tissue in the shaft and glans that fills with blood to make an erection).  In stage IIB, cancer has spread through the layer of connective tissue that surrounds the corpus cavernosum and into the corpus cavernosum (spongy erectile tissue that runs along the shaft of the penis).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714731" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II penile cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714730" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pene en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de pene en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se diseminó 1)  al tejido que está justo debajo de la piel del pene. El cáncer se diseminó a los vasos linfáticos, los vasos sanguíneos o los nervios; o 2) al tejido que está justo debajo de la piel del pene. Las células cancerosas se ven muy anormales o son sarcomatoides cuando se observan al microscopio; o 3) al cuerpo esponjoso (tejido esponjoso eréctil del cuerpo del pene y el glande que se llena de sangre durante una erección). En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa de tejido conjuntivo que rodea el cuerpo cavernoso (tejido esponjoso eréctil del cuerpo del pene) y dentro del cuerpo cavernoso.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-07-23</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000438960" url="/types/penile/patient/penile-treatment-pdq">Penile Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000502300" url="/espanol/tipos/pene/paciente/tratamiento-pene-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pene</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
