<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446557">
  <TermName>pleuropulmonary blastoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PLOOR-oh-PUL-muh-NAYR-ee blas-TOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare,
          fast-growing cancer that forms in the tissues of the lung
          and pleura (the thin layer of tissue that covers the lungs
          and lines the inside of the chest). It may also form in the
          organs between the lungs, including the heart, aorta, and
          pulmonary artery, or in the diaphragm. Pleuropulmonary
          blastoma may sometimes spread to other parts of the body,
          especially to the brain. It usually occurs in infants and
          young children. Some patients with pleuropulmonary blastoma
          have mutations (changes) in a gene called
          
      <GeneName>DICER1</GeneName>
      .
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714605" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pleuropulmonary blastoma&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714604" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;blastoma pleuropulmonar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804518" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing areas where pleuropulmonary blastoma may form, including the aorta, pulmonary artery, lung, heart, pleura, and diaphragm. Also shown is cancer in the left lung." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Pleuropulmonary blastoma is a rare, fast-growing cancer that forms in the tissues of the lung and pleura (the thin layer of tissue that covers the lungs and lines the inside of the chest). It may also form in the organs between the lungs, including the heart, aorta, and pulmonary artery, or in the diaphragm (the main breathing muscle below the lungs). Pleuropulmonary blastoma usually occurs in infants and young children.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804726" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo se observa una niña pequeña y se señalan las siguientes áreas del cuerpo donde es posible que se forme el blastoma pleuropulmonar: la aorta, la arteria pulmonar, el pulmón, el corazón, la pleura y el diafragma. También se muestra cáncer en el pulmón izquierdo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El blastoma pleuropulmonar es un cáncer raro de crecimiento rápido que se forma en los tejidos del pulmón y la pleura (capa delgada de tejido que recubre los pulmones y reviste el interior del tórax). También es posible que se forme en órganos y estructuras que están cerca a los pulmones, como el corazón, la aorta, la arteria pulmonar, o el diafragma (músculo importante para la respiración que está debajo de los pulmones). El blastoma pleuropulmonar suele presentarse en lactantes y niños pequeños.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>blastoma pleuropulmonar</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Cáncer raro de
crecimiento rápido que se forma en los tejidos del pulmón y
la pleura (capa delgada de tejido que
recubre los pulmones y
reviste el interior del
tórax). También es
posible que se forme en los órganos ubicados entre los
pulmones, como el corazón, la aorta y la arteria pulmonar,
o en el diafragma. El blastoma pleuropulmonar a veces se
disemina a otras partes del cuerpo,
en especial al
encéfalo. Se suele presentar en lactantes y niños pequeños.
Algunos pacientes de blastoma pleuropulmonar tienen
mutaciones (cambios) en un gen que se llama

      <GeneName>DICER1</GeneName>
      . También se llama blastoma pulmonar y neumoblastoma.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-04-12</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
