<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446525"><TermName>small intestine cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... in-TES-tin KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare cancer that forms in tissues of the small intestine (a long tube-like organ that connects the stomach to  the large intestine). The most common type of small intestine cancer is adenocarcinoma (cancer that begins in cells that make and release mucus and other fluids). Other types of small intestine cancer include leiomyosarcoma (cancer that begins in the smooth muscle cells of the small intestine), gastrointestinal (GI) neuroendocrine tumor (a slow-growing type of cancer that begins in the lining of the GI tract), GI stromal tumor (a type of tumor that usually begins in cells in the wall of the GI tract), and lymphoma (cancer that begins in immune system cells).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714774" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;small intestine cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de intestino delgado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000751388" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the small intestine showing the duodenum, jejunum, and ileum. Also shown are the stomach, appendix, large intestine, and rectum." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">The small intestine is a long tube-like organ that connects the stomach to the large intestine. The small intestine includes the duodenum, jejunum, and ileum.
</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000751586" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen del intestino delgado se observa el duodeno, el yeyuno y el íleon. También se muestran el estómago, el apéndice, el intestino grueso y el recto." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">El intestino delgado es un órgano en forma de tubo largo que conecta el estómago con el intestino grueso. Las partes del intestino delgado son  el duodeno, el yeyuno y el íleon.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de intestino delgado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer raro que se forma en los tejidos del intestino delgado (órgano en forma de tubo largo que conecta el estómago con el intestino grueso). El tipo más común de este cáncer es el adenocarcinoma (cáncer que comienza en las células que elaboran y secretan moco y otros líquidos). Otros tipos de cáncer de intestino delgado son el leiomiosarcoma (cáncer que empieza en las células musculares lisas del intestino delgado), el tumor neuroendocrino gastrointestinal (un tipo de cáncer de crecimiento lento que empieza en el tejido que reviste el tubo gastrointestinal), el tumor de estroma gastrointestinal (un tipo de tumor que suele comenzar en las células de la pared del tubo gastrointestinal) y el linfoma (cáncer que comienza en las células del sistema inmunitario).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-05-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/small-intestine">Small Intestine Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/intestino-delgado">Cáncer de intestino delgado</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
