<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446539">
  <TermName>SNP</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(snip)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The most common type of change in DNA (molecules inside cells that carry genetic information). SNPs occur when a single nucleotide (building block of DNA) is replaced with another. These changes may cause disease, and may affect how a person reacts to bacteria, viruses, drugs, and other substances. Also called single nucleotide polymorphism.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A DNA sequence variation that occurs when a single nucleotide (adenine, thymine, cytosine, or guanine) is different from the reference sequence. SNPs are usually present in at least 1% of the population and are the most common type of genetic variation among people. SNPs may increase the risk of developing certain diseases, act as biomarkers to help predict the risk of developing certain diseases or how a person may respond to certain drugs, or be used to track the inheritance of disease-causing variants within families. Also called single nucleotide polymorphism.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000738749" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;SNP&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>SNP</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El tipo de cambio más común en el ADN (moléculas dentro de las células que contienen información genética). Los SNP se presentan cuando un solo nucleótido (elemento fundamental del ADN) es reemplazado por otro. Es posible que estos cambios causen enfermedades y afecten la respuesta del cuerpo ante las bacterias, los virus, los medicamentos y otras sustancias. También se llama polimorfismo de un solo nucleótido.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Variación de una secuencia de DNA que ocurre cuando se altera un solo nucleótido (adenina, timina, citosina o guanina) de la secuencia de referencia. Los SNP suelen presentarse en al menos el 1 % de la población y son el tipo más común de variación genética en las personas. Es posible que aumenten el riesgo de ciertas enfermedades, sirvan de biomarcadores para ayudar a predecir el riesgo de algunas afecciones o para predecir la respuesta de una persona a determinados medicamentos. También se usan  para  rastrear la herencia de variantes que causan enfermedades en una familia. También se llama polimorfismo de un solo nucleótido.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2007-07-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Single-Nucleotide-Polymorphisms">Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms (SNPs) (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Polimorfismos-de-nucleotido-%C3%BAnico">Polimorfismos de nucleótido único (SNPs)
 (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
