<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044659">
  <TermName>dehydration</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(dee-hy-DRAY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition that occurs when the body loses too much water and other fluids that it needs to work normally. Dehydration is usually caused by severe diarrhea and vomiting, but it may also be caused by not drinking enough water or other fluids, sweating too much, fever, urinating too much, or taking certain medicines. Signs and symptoms include thirst, dry mouth, headache, fatigue, dark-colored urine, urinating less than normal, sunken eyes or cheeks, dry and cool skin, dizziness, fainting, muscle cramps, rapid heartbeat, and rapid breathing. Dehydration can be severe, especially in young children and older adults.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000728054" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dehydration&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000728053" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deshidratación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>deshidratación</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección que se debe a la pérdida excesiva de agua y otros líquidos necesarios para el funcionamiento normal del cuerpo. La causa de la deshidratación suele ser la diarrea y los vómitos intensos. En ocasiones, también ocurre por no beber suficiente agua ni otros líquidos,  sudar mucho, tener fiebre, orinar demasiado o tomar ciertos medicamentos. Los signos y síntomas son sed, boca seca, dolor de cabeza, fatiga, orina de color oscuro, orinar menos que lo normal, ojos y mejillas hundidos, piel seca y fría, mareos, desmayos, calambres en los músculos, latidos rápidos del corazón y respiración acelerada. La deshidratación a veces es grave, en especial en niños pequeños y en adultos de edad avanzada.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-07-26</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
