<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044661">
  <TermName>dietitian</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(dy-eh-TIH-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A health professional who has special training in diet and nutrition. Dietitians offer advice on nutrition and healthy eating habits to help people improve their health and well-being. Dietitians also help people who are recovering from illness or surgery or who have medical conditions, such as food allergies, eating disorders, swallowing problems, diabetes, heart or kidney disease, or cancer, meet their nutritional needs. Dietitians may provide nutritional counseling, meal planning, medical nutrition therapy (such as a special diet, dietary supplements, or intravenous or tube feedings), and nutrition education programs.  Also called registered dietitian.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705809" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dietitian&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705810" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dietista&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>dietista</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Profesional de la salud que tiene una formación especial en dietética y nutrición. Las personas que se dedican a esta profesión brindan orientación sobre nutrición y hábitos de alimentación saludables para ayudar a mejorar la salud y el bienestar. También ayudan  a cumplir las necesidades nutricionales durante la recuperación de enfermedades o cirugías, y asesoran a personas con determinadas afecciones, como alergias alimentarias, trastornos de la alimentación, problemas para tragar, diabetes, enfermedades del corazón o el riñón,  y cáncer. Además, proporcionan asesoramiento dietético y pueden diseñar planes alimentarios, formular terapias nutricionales médicas (regímenes o dietas especiales, suplementos nutricionales, alimentación intravenosa o enteral [por sonda]) y crear programas educativos sobre nutrición. También se llama bromatólogo, dietético, dietoterapeuta, especialista en dietética y nutricionista.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-08-31</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
