<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044662">
  <TermName>nutritionist</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(noo-TRIH-shuh-nist)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A person who gives advice about healthy eating and lifestyle choices. Training and qualifications for nutritionists can vary, with some having formal education in nutrition, while others might not. Nutritionists may provide dietary counseling, meal planning, and nutrition education. A certified nutrition specialist is a nutrition expert with an advanced degree in nutrition or a related field who has passed a certification exam. Certified nutrition specialists are qualified to provide specialized nutrition advice to people who have certain medical conditions, such as obesity, high blood pressure, or diabetes, and medical nutrition therapy for managing and treating many health conditions.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000728059" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nutritionist&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000728060" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;asesor nutricional&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>asesor nutricional</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Persona que da recomendaciones sobre alimentación y estilo de vida saludables. El entrenamiento y la preparación de los asesores nutricionales varía mucho. Algunos, tienen una educación formal en nutrición, mientras que otros quizás no. El asesor nutricional a veces brinda asesoramiento dietético, diseña planes alimentarios y crea programas educativos. Un especialista en nutrición certificado o diplomado es un experto en nutrición graduado con un título superior en nutrición o dietética, o en un campo relacionado con la nutrición, que ha aprobado un examen de certificación. Estos especialistas, que también se conocen como nutricionistas, están calificados para brindar asesoramiento especializado a personas con determinadas afecciones médicas, como obesidad, presión arterial alta o diabetes, y  formulan terapia nutricional médica para controlar y tratar muchos problemas de salud. También se llama consejero nutricional.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-08-01</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
