<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044677"><TermName>informed consent</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-FORMD kun-SENT)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process in
          which patients are given important information, including
          possible risks and benefits, about a medical procedure or
          treatment, genetic testing, or a clinical trial. This is to
          help them decide if they want to be treated, tested, or
          take part in the trial. Patients are also given any new
          information that might affect their decision to
          continue. Also called consent process.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process of
          information exchange between a clinician and an individual
          or their legal proxy designed to facilitate autonomous,
          informed decision making. The informed consent process for
          genetic testing should include an explanation of the
          medical and psychosocial risks, benefits, limitations, and
          potential implications of genetic analysis, a discussion of
          privacy, confidentiality, the documentation and handling of
          genetic test results, as well as options for managing the
          hereditary disease risk. Also called consent process.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728071" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;informed consent&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728072" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;consentimiento informado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>consentimiento informado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso en el que se
proporciona a los pacientes
información importante, como los riesgos y beneficios
posibles de un procedimiento o tratamiento
médico, una prueba genética o un ensayo clínico.
Esto se hace para ayudar a los pacientes a decidir si se
quieren someter a tratamientos o pruebas, o participar en
un ensayo clínico. Los pacientes también reciben cualquier
información nueva que pudiera afectar su decisión de
continuar. También se llama proceso de consentimiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso de intercambio de información entre un profesional de la salud  y una persona o su representante legal,  que tiene como fin facilitar la toma de decisiones autónomas y con conocimiento de causa. El proceso de consentimiento informado para hacer una prueba genética debe incluir una explicación de los riesgos médicos y psicosociales, los beneficios, las limitaciones y las posibles implicaciones del análisis genético; también incluye una exposición acerca de la privacidad, la confidencialidad, 
          la documentación y el procesamiento de los resultados de las pruebas genéticas, además de las opciones para el tratamiento del riesgo de enfermedades hereditarias. También se llama proceso de consentimiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2018-01-31</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
