<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446806">
  <TermName>phenylketonuria</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FEH-nil-KEE-tone-yoor-ee-uh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An inherited disorder that causes a build-up of a substance called phenylalanine in the blood and other body fluids. Phenylalanine is an amino acid (a building block of proteins), so certain foods, such as meat, eggs, nuts, and milk, contain high levels. Some artificial sweeteners, such as aspartame, also contain high levels of phenylalanine. The signs and symptoms of phenylketonuria can be mild or severe and may include light skin and hair, skin rashes, seizures, developmental delays, and movement, behavioral, and mental or psychological problems. The breath, skin, or urine may also have a musty odor. If not treated, phenylketonuria can lead to permanent intellectual disability. All babies born in the United States and many other countries are screened for phenylketonuria using a simple blood test. There is no cure, but phenylketonuria can be managed with a diet low in phenylalanine. Also called PKU.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714766" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;phenylketonuria&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714767" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fenilcetonuria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>fenilcetonuria</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario que causa la acumulación de una sustancia llamada fenilalanina en la sangre y otros líquidos del cuerpo. La fenilalanina es un aminoácido (componente básico de las proteínas) que se encuentra en concentraciones elevadas en ciertos alimentos, como la carne, los huevos, los frutos secos y la leche. Algunos edulcorantes artificiales, como el aspartamo, también contienen concentraciones altas de fenilalanina. Los signos y síntomas de la fenilcetonuria pueden ser leves o graves, y es posible que incluyan   piel y cabello claro, erupciones en la piel, convulsiones, retraso en el desarrollo y problemas de movimiento, comportamiento y mentales o psicológicos. A veces, el aliento, la piel o la orina tienen un olor  rancio. Si no se trata, esta afección quizás provoque una discapacidad intelectual permanente. En los Estados Unidos y muchos otros países se hace una prueba de sangre a los recién nacidos para detectar la fenilcetonuria. No existe cura para esta enfermedad, pero se controla con una dieta baja en fenilalanina. También se llama FCU.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7383/phenylketonuria">Phenylketonuria (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/phenylketonuria/">Phenylketonuria (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13560/fenilcetonuria">Fenilcetonuria (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001166.htm">Fenilcetonuria (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
