<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044780">
  <TermName>granulosa cell tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(GRAN-yoo-LOH-suh sel TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, slow-growing type of cancer that usually forms in the tissues that surround and support the ovaries. It may also form in the testicles, but this is very uncommon. Granulosa cell tumors make a female sex hormone called estrogen. This can cause abnormal vaginal bleeding and early puberty in females and an abnormal growth of breast tissue in males. Granulosa cell tumors tend to have a good prognosis (outcome) if diagnosed and treated early. They can occur in both adults and children. Granulosa cell tumors are the most common type of sex cord-stromal tumor in females.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705958" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;granulosa cell tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705957" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor de células de la granulosa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor de células de la granulosa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer raro de crecimiento lento que suele formarse en los tejidos que rodean y sostienen los ovarios. A veces también se forma en los testículos, pero esto es muy infrecuente. Los tumores de células de la granulosa producen una hormona sexual femenina llamada estrógeno. En las mujeres, esto puede causar sangrado vaginal anormal y pubertad precoz. En los varones, causa el crecimiento anormal del tejido mamario. Estos tumores suelen tener un buen pronóstico (desenlace) si se diagnostican y tratan de manera oportuna. Si bien los tumores de células de la granulosa se presentan en niños y adultos de ambos sexos; son el tipo más común de tumor de estroma de cordón sexual en mujeres.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-10-31</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
