<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044845">
  <TermName>mast cell</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(mast sel)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of white blood cell that is found in connective tissues all through the body, especially under the skin, near blood vessels and lymph vessels, in nerves, and in the lungs and intestines. Mast cells play an important role in how the immune system responds to certain bacteria and parasites and they help control other types of immune responses. They contain chemicals such as histamine, heparin, cytokines, and growth factors. They release these chemicals during allergic reactions and certain immune responses. These chemicals have many effects, including the widening of blood vessels and angiogenesis. During an allergic response, they can cause flushing (a hot, red face) and itching.  In large amounts, they can also cause abdominal cramps, muscle pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, low blood pressure, and shock. Mast cells are part of the body’s immune system.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000728172" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mast cell&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000728173" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mastocito&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mastocito</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de glóbulo blanco que se encuentra en los tejidos conjuntivos de todo el cuerpo; en particular, debajo de la piel, cerca de los vasos sanguíneos y los vasos linfáticos, en los nervios, y en los pulmones y los intestinos. Los mastocitos tienen una función importante en la respuesta del sistema inmunitario a ciertas bacterias y parásitos; además, ayudan a controlar otros tipos de respuestas inmunitarias. Contienen sustancias químicas como la histamina, la heparina, las citocinas y los factores de crecimiento. Liberan estas sustancias químicas durante las reacciones alérgicas y ciertas respuestas inmunitarias. Estas sustancias tienen muchos efectos; por ejemplo, ensanchan los vasos sanguíneos y producen angiogénesis. Durante una respuesta alérgica, es posible que causen enrojecimiento (cara caliente y roja) y picazón. En grandes cantidades, también causan cólicos abdominales, dolor muscular, náuseas, vómitos, diarrea, presión arterial baja y choque. Los mastocitos forman parte del sistema inmunitario del cuerpo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2017-09-08</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
