<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044882"><TermName>Lynch syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(linch SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited disorder that increases the risk of developing colorectal cancer, endometrial cancer, ovarian cancer, and many other types of cancer, such as cancers of the stomach, small intestine, pancreas, bile duct, urinary tract, and brain, often before age 50. Lynch syndrome is caused by mutations (changes) in genes that affect DNA mismatch repair, a process that fixes mistakes that occur when DNA is copied. These genes are <GeneName>MLH1</GeneName>, <GeneName>MSH2</GeneName>, <GeneName>MSH6</GeneName>, <GeneName>PMS2</GeneName>, and <GeneName>EPCAM</GeneName>.  Also called hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer and HNPCC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728190" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Lynch syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Lynch&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Lynch</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario que aumenta el riesgo de cáncer colorrectal y cánceres de endometrio, ovario, estómago, intestino delgado, páncreas, vías biliares, vías urinarias o encéfalo, a menudo antes de los 50 años. La causa del síndrome de Lynch son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes que afectan a la reparación de errores de emparejamiento del ADN, un proceso que corrige los errores que ocurren durante la duplicación de ADN. Estos genes son <GeneName>MLH1</GeneName>, <GeneName>MSH2</GeneName>, <GeneName>MSH6</GeneName>, <GeneName>PMS2</GeneName> y <GeneName>EPCAM</GeneName>. También se llama cáncer colorrectal hereditario no polipósico y HNPCC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2023-05-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12282/sindrome-de-lynch">Síndrome de Lynch (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/lynch-syndrome/">Lynch syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
