<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044893"><TermName>imatinib mesylate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ih-MA-tih-nib MEH-zih-layt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of leukemia and other blood cancers, gastrointestinal stromal tumors, skin tumors called dermatofibrosarcoma protuberans, and a certain type of a rare condition called systemic mastocytosis. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Imatinib mesylate blocks certain proteins made by the <GeneName>BCR</GeneName>::<GeneName>ABL1</GeneName>, <GeneName>PDGFR</GeneName>, or <GeneName>c-KIT</GeneName> oncogene, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. Imatinib mesylate is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called Gleevec, Imkeldi, and STI571.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706105" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;imatinib mesylate&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706106" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesilato de imatinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mesilato de imatinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de leucemia y otros cánceres de sangre. También se utiliza para el tratamiento de los tumores de estroma gastrointestinal, los tumores de piel llamados dermatofibrosarcomas protuberantes y una afección rara llamada mastocitosis sistémica. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. El mesilato de imatinib bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan de los genes <GeneName>BCR</GeneName>::<GeneName>ABL1</GeneName> y <GeneName>PDGFR</GeneName>, o del oncogén <GeneName>c-KIT</GeneName>, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas y las destruya. El mesilato de imatinib es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama Gleevec, Imkeldi y STI571.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-12-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000487488" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/imatinibmesylate">Imatinib Mesylate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
