<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044964"><TermName>complementary and alternative medicine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-pleh-MEN-tuh-ree... all-TER-nuh-tiv MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe a medical product or practice that is used together with (complementary) or instead of (alternative) standard medical care. Usually, less is known about most types of complementary and alternative medicine than about standard treatments, which go through a long and careful research process to prove they are safe and effective. Complementary and alternative medicine may include dietary supplements, megadose vitamins, herbal preparations, special teas, acupuncture, massage therapy, magnet therapy, spiritual healing, and meditation. Also called CAM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706212" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complementary and alternative medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706213" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina complementaria y alternativa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicina complementaria y alternativa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que se usa para describir un producto médico o una práctica médica que se usan además de (complementaria) o en lugar de (alternativa) la atención médica estándar. Por lo general, no se sabe mucho de la mayoría de los tipos de medicina complementaria y alternativa en comparación con los tratamientos estándar, que se someten a un proceso de investigación largo y cuidadoso con el fin de probar que son seguros  y eficaces. La medicina complementaria y alternativa incluye los suplementos alimentarios, las dosis altas de vitaminas, los preparados de hierbas, ciertos tés, la acupuntura, la terapia de masaje, la terapia con imanes, la curación espiritual y la meditación. También se llama MCA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-01-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/cam">Complementary and Alternative Medicine </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/mca">Medicina complementaria y alternativa</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
