<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000450133">
  <TermName>stage IVA maxillary sinus cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...MAK-sih-LAYR-ee SY-nus KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage IV maxillary sinus cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, (1) cancer has spread to any of the following: the eye, the skin of the cheek, the part of the sphenoid bone behind the upper jaw, the area behind the upper jaw, the bone between the eyes, and/or the sphenoid or frontal sinuses. Cancer may have also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the cancer, and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is found in the maxillary sinus and may have spread to any of the following: the bones around the maxillary sinus (including the roof of the mouth and the nose), the bone between the eyes, the tissues under the skin, the skin of the cheek, the eye, the part of the eye socket near the nose, or the bottom of the eye socket, the area behind the cheek bone, the part of the sphenoid bone behind the upper jaw, the area behind the upper jaw, and/or the ethmoid, sphenoid, or frontal sinuses. Cancer has also spread to one of the following: one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the cancer and the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters; or more than one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the cancer and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters; or lymph nodes on the opposite side of the neck as the cancer or on both sides of the neck, and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714987" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVA maxillary sinus cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000714988" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de seno paranasal maxilar en estadio IVA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de seno paranasal maxilar en estadio IVA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer de seno paranasal maxilar en estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó a cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: el ojo; la piel de la mejilla; la parte del hueso esfenoides detrás del maxilar superior, el área detrás del maxilar superior; el hueso entre los ojos; los senos paranasales esfenoidales o frontales. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el cáncer; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El cáncer se encuentra en los senos paranasales maxilares y es posible que se haya diseminado a cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: los huesos que rodean los senos paranasales maxilares (incluso el paladar y la nariz); el hueso entre los ojos; los tejidos debajo de  la piel; la piel de la mejilla; el ojo, la parte de la cavidad orbitaria (cuenca del ojo) cerca de la nariz o la parte inferior de la cavidad orbitaria; el área detrás del hueso de la mejilla; la parte del hueso esfenoides detrás del maxilar superior; los senos paranasales etmoidales, esfenoidales o frontales. El cáncer también se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el cáncer (este ganglio mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 6 cm);  más de 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el cáncer (estos ganglios linfáticos no miden más de 6 cm); ganglios linfáticos en el cuello del lado contrario al cáncer o de ambos lados del cuello (estos ganglios linfáticos no miden más de 6 cm).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-02-15</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-07-24</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258028" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/paranasal-sinus-treatment-pdq">Paranasal Sinus and Nasal Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000558933" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-seno-paranasal-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de seno paranasal y de cavidad nasal</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
