<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045011"><TermName>lymphoscintigraphy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LIM-foh-sin-TIH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A method used to check the lymph system for disease. A radioactive substance that flows through the lymph ducts and can be taken up by lymph nodes is injected into the body. A scanner or probe is used to follow the movement of this substance on a computer screen. Lymphoscintigraphy is used to find the sentinel lymph node (the first node to receive lymph from a tumor), which may be removed and checked for tumor cells. Lymphoscintigraphy is also used to diagnose certain diseases or conditions, such as lymphoma or lymphedema.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706264" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphoscintigraphy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706265" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfocentellografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfocentellografía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método que se usa para examinar el sistema linfático en busca de una enfermedad. Se inyecta en el cuerpo una sustancia radiactiva que fluye por los conductos linfáticos y que es absorbida por los ganglios linfáticos. Se usa un escáner o una sonda para observar el movimiento de esta sustancia en la pantalla de una computadora.   La linfocentellografía ayuda a encontrar el ganglio linfático centinela (primer ganglio que recibe la linfa de un tumor) de modo que sea posible extirparlo y examinarlo para determinar si tiene células tumorales.   La linfocentellografía también se usa para diagnosticar ciertas enfermedades o afecciones, como el linfoma o el linfedema. También se llama centellografía linfática, gammagrafía linfática, linfocintigrafía, linfoescintigrafía y linfogammagrafía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2009-07-16</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
