<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045085"><TermName>ductal carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DUK-tul KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The most common type of breast cancer. It begins in the lining of the milk ducts (thin tubes that carry milk from the lobules of the breast to the nipple). Ductal carcinoma may be either ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) or invasive ductal carcinoma. DCIS is a noninvasive condition in which abnormal cells are found in the lining of a breast duct and have not spread outside the duct to other tissues in the breast. In some cases, DCIS may become invasive cancer. In invasive ductal carcinoma, cancer has spread outside the breast duct to surrounding normal tissue. It can also spread through the blood and lymph systems to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704979" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ductal carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704978" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma ductal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma ductal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo más común de cáncer de mama (seno). Empieza en el revestimiento de los conductos galactóforos (tubos delgados que llevan la leche desde los lobulillos de la mama hasta el pezón). El carcinoma ductal puede ser carcinoma ductal in situ (CDIS) o carcinoma ductal invasivo. El CDIS es una afección no invasiva por la que se encuentran células anormales en el revestimiento de un conducto de la mama que no se diseminaron fuera del conducto a otros tejidos de la mama. En algunos casos, el CDIS se convierte en cáncer invasivo. En el carcinoma ductal invasivo, el cáncer se diseminó fuera del conducto de la mama al tejido normal que lo rodea. También es posible que se disemine a otras partes del cuerpo a través de la sangre y el sistema linfático. También se llama carcinoma canalicular, carcinoma intracanalicular y carcinoma intraductal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
