<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045094">
  <TermName>plexiform neurofibroma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PLEK-sih-form NOOR-oh-fy-BROH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A tumor that forms in the tissue that covers and protects the nerves. Plexiform neurofibromas can occur anywhere in the body outside of the brain and spinal cord. They can occur on the face (including around the eye), neck, arms, legs, back, chest, abdomen, and internal organs. Large tumors can cause a nerve to become thick and misshapen, which can affect the structure of nearby bone, skin, and muscle. Plexiform neurofibromas can cause severe pain, mobility problems, vision and hearing loss, high blood pressure, and other medical problems. Most plexiform neurofibromas are not cancer, but some may become cancer. They most commonly occur in children who have a rare genetic condition called neurofibromatosis type 1.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704989" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;plexiform neurofibroma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000704988" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neurofibroma plexiforme&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>neurofibroma plexiforme</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor que se forma en el tejido que cubre y protege los nervios, fuera del encéfalo y la médula espinal. En ocasiones estos tumores se forman en la cara (incluso alrededor del ojo), el cuello, los brazos, las piernas, la espalda, el tórax, el abdomen y los órganos internos. Los tumores grandes deforman el nervio que se vuelve grueso, y a veces afectan la estructura del hueso, la piel o el músculo cercanos. Los neurofibromas plexiformes causan dolor intenso, problemas de movimiento, ceguera y sordera, presión arterial alta y otros problemas médicos. La mayoría de los neurofibromas plexiformes son benignos, pero algunos se vuelven cancerosos. Estos tumores son comunes en niños con una afección genética rara llamada neurofibromatosis de tipo 1.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-07-02</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
