<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045100"><TermName>classic familial adenomatous polyposis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KLA-sik fuh-MIH-lee-ul A-deh-NOH-muh-tus PAH-lee-POH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited disorder in which many polyps (usually hundreds to thousands) form on the inner walls of the colon and rectum. Polyps are abnormal growths that may become cancer if they are not removed. People with classic familial adenomatous polyposis have a very high risk of developing colorectal cancer at an early age and are also at risk of developing cancers of the stomach, small intestine, pancreas, bile duct, liver, adrenal gland, thyroid, and brain. They may also have dental and eye problems and benign (not cancer) tumors in the stomach, small intestine, bone, soft tissue, skin, and adrenal glands. Classic familial adenomatous polyposis is caused by mutations (changes) in a gene called <GeneName>APC</GeneName> that are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. It is a type of hereditary cancer syndrome.  Also called classic familial polyposis, classic FAP, familial adenomatous polyposis, and FAP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704998" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;classic familial adenomatous polyposis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704999" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;poliposis adenomatosa familiar clásica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>poliposis adenomatosa familiar clásica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario por el que se forman muchos pólipos (a menudo, cientos o miles) en las paredes internas del colon y el recto. Los pólipos son bultos anormales  que a veces se convierten en cáncer si no se extirpan. Las personas  con poliposis adenomatosa familiar clásica tienen un riesgo muy alto de presentar  cáncer colorrectal a una edad temprana, y también tienen riesgo de presentar cáncer de estómago, intestino delgado, páncreas, vías biliares, hígado, glándula suprarrenal, tiroides y encéfalo. Estos pacientes a veces también tienen problemas en los dientes y los ojos, así como tumores benignos (no cancerosos) de estómago, intestino delgado, hueso, tejido blando, piel y glándula suprarrenal. La causa de la poliposis adenomatosa familiar clásica son mutaciones (cambios) en un gen llamado <GeneName>APC</GeneName>, que se hereda de manera autosómica dominante. Es un tipo de síndrome de cáncer hereditario. También se llama PAF, PAF clásica, poliposis adenomatosa familiar, poliposis familiar adenomatosa clásica y poliposis familiar clásica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-01-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6408/familial-adenomatous-polyposis">Familial adenomatous polyposis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/familial-adenomatous-polyposis/">Familial adenomatous polyposis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
