<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045114"><TermName>allogeneic bone marrow transplant</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-loh-jeh-NAY-ik bone MAYR-oh TRANZ-plant)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a patient receives healthy stem cells (blood-forming cells) from a donor to replace their own stem cells that have been destroyed by treatment with radiation or high doses of chemotherapy. In an allogeneic bone marrow transplant, the healthy stem cells come from the bone marrow of a related donor who is not an identical twin of the patient or from an unrelated donor who is genetically similar to the patient.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705014" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;allogeneic bone marrow transplant&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705015" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trasplante alogénico de médula ósea&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trasplante alogénico de médula ósea</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento durante el cual un paciente recibe células madre (células formadoras de sangre) sanas que provienen de un donante. Estas células reemplazan las células madre que se destruyeron con el tratamiento de radioterapia o de dosis altas de quimioterapia. En un trasplante alogénico de médula ósea, las células madre sanas se obtienen de la médula ósea de un donante emparentado que no es un gemelo del paciente, o de un donante no emparentado con características genéticas similares a las del paciente. También se llama alotrasplante de médula ósea, trasplante alógeno de médula ósea y trasplante de médula ósea alogénica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2023-11-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/stem-cell-transplant" UseWith="en">Stem Cell Transplants in Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/trasplante-de-celulas-madre">Trasplantes de células madre en el tratamiento del cáncer </RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
