<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045128">
  <TermName>stage III testicular cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...tes-TIH-kyoo-ler KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Cancer may have spread to one or more nearby lymph nodes. Cancer has spread to distant lymph nodes or to the lungs. All tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal. In stage IIIB, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Cancer has spread (1) to one or more nearby lymph nodes and has not spread to other parts of the body; or (2) to one or more nearby lymph nodes. Cancer has spread to distant lymph nodes or to the lungs. The level of one or more tumor markers is moderately above normal. In stage IIIC, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Cancer has spread (1) to one or more nearby lymph nodes and has not spread to other parts of the body; or (2) to one or more nearby lymph nodes. Cancer has spread to distant lymph nodes or to the lungs. The level of one or more tumor markers is high. OR, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum.  Cancer has not spread to distant lymph nodes or the lung, but has spread to other parts of the body, such as the liver or bone.  Tumor marker levels may range from normal to high.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705042" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III testicular cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705043" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de testículo en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de testículo en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó a ganglios linfáticos lejanos o el pulmón. Todas las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales son normales o un poco más altas que las normales. En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. El cáncer se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: 1 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos pero no  a otras partes del cuerpo; 1 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos y a ganglios linfáticos lejanos o el pulmón. Las concentraciones de uno o más marcadores tumorales son un poco más altas que las normales. En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo, es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto y, además, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: 1 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos pero no a otras partes del cuerpo; 1 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos y a ganglios linfáticos lejanos o el pulmón. Las concentraciones de uno o más marcadores tumorales son un poco más altas que las normales. 2) El cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. El cáncer no se diseminó a ganglios linfáticos lejanos ni al pulmón, pero se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo, como el hígado o el hueso. Las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales oscilan entre normales y altas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2018-10-24</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000257530" url="/types/testicular/patient/testicular-treatment-pdq">Testicular Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256799" url="/espanol/tipos/testiculo/paciente/tratamiento-testiculo-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de testículo</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
