<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045127">
  <TermName>stage II testicular cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...tes-TIH-kyoo-ler KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA, IIB, and IIC. In stage IIA, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Cancer has spread to 1 to 5 nearby lymph nodes  and the lymph nodes are 2 centimeters or smaller. All tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal. In stage IIB, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Cancer has spread to (1) one nearby lymph node and the lymph node is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters; or (2)  more than 5 nearby lymph nodes and the lymph nodes are not larger than 5 centimeters; or (3) a nearby lymph node and the cancer has spread outside the lymph node. All tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal. In stage IIC, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Cancer has spread to a nearby lymph node and the lymph node is larger than 5 centimeters. All tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705040" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II testicular cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705041" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de testículo en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de testículo en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA, IIB y IIC. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. El cáncer se diseminó hasta 1 a 5 ganglios linfáticos cercanos y estos miden 2 cm o menos. Todas las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales son normales o un poco más altas que las normales. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. El cáncer se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: 1 ganglio linfático cercano y este mide 2 cm pero no más de 5 cm; más de 5 ganglios linfáticos cercanos y estos miden no más de 5 cm; 1 ganglio linfático cercano y el cáncer se diseminó fuera de este. Todas las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales son normales o un poco más altas que las normales. En el estadio IIC, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. El cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático cercano y este mide más de 5 cm. Todas las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales son normales o un poco más altas que las normales.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2018-10-24</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000257530" url="/types/testicular/patient/testicular-treatment-pdq">Testicular Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256799" url="/espanol/tipos/testiculo/paciente/tratamiento-testiculo-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de testículo</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
