<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045124"><TermName>stage III bladder cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... BLA-der KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, cancer (1) has grown all the way through the bladder muscles and bladder wall into the layer of fat surrounding the bladder and may have spread to the reproductive organs (prostate, seminal vesicles, uterus, or vagina) but has not spread to lymph nodes; or (2) has spread to one lymph node in the pelvis that is not near the major arteries in the pelvis, called the common iliac arteries. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to more than one lymph node in the pelvis that is not near the common iliac arteries or to at least one lymph node that is near the common iliac arteries.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705035" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III bladder cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705034" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vejiga en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749310" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing showing stage IIIA bladder cancer in a male (left panel) and a female (right panel); both panels show cancer in the bladder and in (a) the layer of fat around the bladder and (b) one lymph node in the pelvis. Also shown are the right and left common iliac arteries, the prostate (left panel), and the uterus (right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA bladder cancer. Cancer (a) has grown all the way through the bladder muscles and bladder wall into the layer of fat around the bladder and may have spread to the prostate and/or seminal vesicles in men or the uterus and/or vagina in women but has not spread to lymph nodes; or (b) has spread to one lymph node in the pelvis that is not near the common iliac arteries.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791435" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing showing stage IIIB bladder cancer in a male (left panel) and a female (right panel); both panels show cancer in the bladder and in (a) more than one lymph node in the pelvis that is not near the common iliac artery and (b) one lymph node near the common iliac artery. Also shown are the right and left common iliac arteries, the prostate (left panel), and the uterus (the right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB bladder cancer. Cancer has spread to (a) more than one lymph node in the pelvis that is not near the common iliac arteries; or (b) at least one lymph node that is near the common iliac arteries.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752482" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de vejiga en estadio lllA. Se muestra una imagen con dos paneles. En el de la izquierda, se observa cáncer en un hombre y en el de la derecha, en una mujer. En ambos paneles, se observa cáncer en la vejiga y en la capa de grasa que la rodea (a), así como en un ganglio linfático de la pelvis (b). También se muestran las arterias ilíacas comunes derecha e izquierda, la próstata (panel izquierdo) y el útero (panel derecho)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de vejiga en estadio lllA. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones:  el cáncer se diseminó a través del tejido muscular y la pared de la vejiga a la capa de grasa que rodea la vejiga (a), y es posible que se haya diseminado a la próstata o las vesículas seminales en los hombres, y al útero o la vagina en las mujeres, pero no a los ganglios linfáticos;  o el cáncer se diseminó en la pelvis a un ganglio linfático que no está cerca de las arterias ilíacas comunes (b).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792551" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de vejiga en estadio lllB. Se muestra una imagen con dos paneles. En el de la izquierda, se observa cáncer en un hombre y en el de la derecha, en una mujer. En ambos paneles, se observa cáncer en la vejiga y en más de un ganglio linfático que no está cerca de la arteria ilíaca común (a), así como en un ganglio linfático cerca de la arteria ilíaca común (b). También se muestran las arterias ilíacas comunes derecha e izquierda, la próstata (panel de la izquierda) y el útero (panel de la derecha)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de vejiga en estadio lllB. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: el cáncer se diseminó en la pelvis a más de un ganglio linfático que no está cerca de las arterias ilíacas comunes (a); o el cáncer se diseminó a por lo menos un ganglio linfático cerca de las arterias ilíacas comunes (b).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vejiga en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se diseminó a través del tejido muscular y la pared de la vejiga a la capa de grasa que rodea la vejiga, y es posible que se haya diseminado a los órganos genitales (la próstata, las vesículas seminales, el útero o la vagina), pero no se ha diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos; 2) el cáncer se diseminó en la pelvis a un ganglio linfático que no está cerca de las arterias ilíacas comunes (arterias principales de la pelvis). En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se diseminó en la pelvis a más de un ganglio linfático qué no está cerca de las arterias ilíacas comunes, o  a por lo menos un ganglio linfático cerca de las arterias ilíacas comunes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2022-12-06</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000811057" url="/types/bladder/stages">Bladder Cancer Stages</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000811361" url="/espanol/tipos/vejiga/estadios">Estadios del cáncer de vejiga</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
