<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045126">
  <TermName>stage I testicular cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...tes-TIH-kyoo-ler KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stages IA, IB, and IS. In stage IA, cancer is found in the testicle, including the rete testis, but has not spread to the blood vessels or lymph vessels in the testicle. All tumor marker levels are normal. In stage IB, cancer (1) is found in the testicle, including the rete testis,  and has spread to the blood vessels or lymph vessels in the testicle; or (2) has spread into the hilar soft tissue (tissue made of fibers and fat with blood vessels and lymph vessels), the epididymis, or the outer membranes  around the testicle; or (3)  has spread to the spermatic cord; or (4) has spread to the scrotum. All tumor marker levels are normal. In stage IS, cancer is found anywhere in the testicle and may have spread into the spermatic cord or scrotum. Tumor marker levels range from slightly above normal to high.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705038" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I testicular cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705039" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de testículo en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de testículo en estadio I</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA, IB y IS. En el estadio IA, el cáncer se encuentra en el testículo (incluso en la red testicular), pero no se diseminó a los vasos sanguíneos ni a los conductos linfáticos del testículo. Todas las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales son normales. En el estadio IB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se encuentra en el testículo (incluso la red testicular), pero no se diseminó a los vasos sanguíneos ni a los conductos linfáticos del testículo; 2) el cáncer se diseminó al tejido blando hiliar (tejido formado por fibras y grasa que tiene vasos sanguíneos y conductos linfáticos), el epidídimo o las membranas externas que rodean el testículo; 3) el cáncer se diseminó al cordón espermático; 4) el cáncer se diseminó al escroto. Todas las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales son normales. En el estadio IS, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier parte del testículo y es posible que se haya diseminado al cordón espermático o el escroto. Las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales oscilan entre un poco más altas que las normales y altas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2018-10-24</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000257530" url="/types/testicular/patient/testicular-treatment-pdq">Testicular Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
