<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045131">
  <TermName>stage III prostate cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...PROS-tayt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III is
          divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA,
          cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate. The
          prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level is at least 20 and
          the Grade Group is 1, 2, 3, or 4 (Gleason score is 8 or
          less). In stage IIIB, cancer has spread from the prostate
          to the seminal vesicles or to nearby tissue or organs, such
          as the rectum, bladder, or pelvic wall. The PSA can be any
          level and the Grade Group is 1, 2, 3, or 4. In stage IIIC,
          cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate and
          may have spread to the seminal vesicles or to nearby tissue
          or organs, such as the rectum, bladder, or pelvic wall. The
          PSA can be any level and the Grade Group is 5 (Gleason
          score is 9 or 10).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705048" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III prostate cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705049" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de próstata en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795017" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA prostate cancer; drawing shows cancer in one side of the prostate. The PSA level is at least 20 and the Grade Group is 1, 2, 3, or 4. Also shown are the bladder, rectum, and urethra." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIA prostate cancer. Cancer is found in the prostate only. Cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate. The prostate-specific antigen level is at least 20 and the Grade Group is 1, 2, 3, or 4.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795018" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB prostate cancer; drawing shows cancer that has spread from the prostate to the seminal vesicles and to nearby tissue. The PSA can be any level and the Grade Group is 1, 2, 3, or 4. Also shown are the pelvic wall, bladder, and rectum." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIB prostate cancer. Cancer has spread from the prostate to the seminal vesicles or to nearby tissue or organs, such as the rectum, bladder, or pelvic wall. The prostate-specific antigen can be any level and the Grade Group is 1, 2, 3, or 4.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795019" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIC prostate cancer; drawing shows cancer in one side of the prostate. The PSA can be any level and the Grade Group is 5. Also shown are the bladder, rectum, and urethra." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIC prostate cancer. Cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate and may have spread to the seminal vesicles or to nearby tissue or organs, such as the rectum, bladder, or pelvic wall. The prostate-specific antigen can be any level and the Grade Group is 5.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796707" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIIA. En la imagen se observa cáncer en un lado de la próstata. La concentración del PSA es de por lo menos 20 y el grupo de grado es 1, 2, 3 o 4. También se muestran la vejiga, el recto y la uretra." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIIA. El cáncer se encuentra solo en la próstata, en uno o ambos lados. La concentración del antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es de por lo menos 20 y el grupo de grado es 1, 2, 3 o 4.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796708" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIIB. En la imagen se observa cáncer que se diseminó de la próstata a las vesículas seminales y al tejido cercano. El PSA es de cualquier concentración y el grupo de grado es 1, 2, 3 o 4. También se muestran la pared pélvica, la vejiga y el recto." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_9">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIIB. El cáncer se diseminó de la próstata a las vesículas seminales o a los tejidos u órganos cercanos, como el recto, la vejiga o la pared pélvica. El antígeno prostático específico es de cualquier concentración y el grupo de grado es 1, 2, 3 o 4.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796709" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIIC. En la imagen se observa cáncer en un lado de la próstata. El PSA es de cualquier concentración y el grupo de grado es 5. También se muestran la vejiga, el recto y la uretra." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_10">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIIC. El cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos lados de la próstata y es posible que se haya diseminado a las vesículas seminales o a los tejidos u órganos cercanos, como el recto, la vejiga o la pared pélvica. El antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es de cualquier concentración y el grupo de grado es 5.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de próstata en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los
estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer
se encuentra en uno o ambos lados de la próstata, la
concentración del antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es
de por lo menos 20 y el grupo de grado 1, 2, 3 o 4 (puntaje de Gleason 8 o menos). En el estadio IIIB, el
cáncer se diseminó de la próstata a las vesículas seminales
o a los tejidos u órganos cercanos, como el recto, la
vejiga o la pared pélvica; el PSA es de cualquier
concentración y el grupo de grado es 1, 2, 3 o 4. En el
estadio IIIC, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos lados de la próstata y es posible que se haya diseminado a las vesículas seminales o a los tejidos u órganos
cercanos, como el recto, la vejiga o la pared pélvica; el
PSA es de cualquier concentración y el grupo de grado es 5 (puntaje de Gleason 9 o
10).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-01-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062965" url="/types/prostate/patient/prostate-treatment-pdq">Prostate Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256810" url="/espanol/tipos/prostata/paciente/tratamiento-prostata-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de próstata</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
