<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045130">
  <TermName>stage II prostate cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...PROS-tayt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer is more advanced than in stage I, but has not spread outside the prostate. Stage II is divided into stages IIA, IIB, and IIC. In stage IIA, cancer (1) is found in one-half or less of one side of the prostate. The prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level is at least 10 but lower than 20 and the Grade Group is 1 (Gleason score is 6 or less); or (2) is found in more than one-half of one side of the prostate or in both sides of the prostate. The PSA level is lower than 20 and the Grade Group is 1. In stage IIB, cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate. The PSA level is lower than 20 and the Grade Group is 2 (Gleason score is 7). In stage IIC, cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate. The PSA level is lower than 20 and the Grade Group is 3 or 4 (Gleason score is 7 or 8).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705047" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II prostate cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705046" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de próstata en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795014" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing of stage IIA prostate cancer; the top panel shows cancer in one-half or less of one side of the prostate. The PSA level is at least 10 but less than 20 and the Grade Group is 1. The bottom panel shows cancer in more than one-half of one side of the prostate. The PSA level is less than 20 and the Grade Group is 1. In both panels, the bladder, rectum, and urethra are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIA prostate cancer. Cancer is found in the prostate only. Cancer is found in one-half or less of one side of the prostate. The prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level is at least 10 but less than 20 and the Grade Group is 1; OR cancer is found in more than one-half of one side of the prostate or in both sides of the prostate. The PSA level is less than 20 and the Grade Group is 1.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795015" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIB prostate cancer; drawing shows cancer in one side of the prostate. The PSA level is less than 20 and the Grade Group is 2. Also shown are the bladder, rectum, and urethra." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIB prostate cancer. Cancer is found in the prostate only. Cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate. The prostate-specific antigen level is less than 20 and the Grade Group is 2.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795016" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIC prostate cancer; drawing shows cancer in both sides of the prostate. The PSA level is less than 20 and the Grade Group is 3 or 4. Also shown are the bladder, rectum, and urethra." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIC prostate cancer. Cancer is found in the prostate only. Cancer is found in one or both sides of the prostate. The prostate-specific antigen level is less than 20 and the Grade Group is 3 or 4.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796704" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIA. Se observa una imagen con dos paneles. En el panel superior, se observa cáncer en la mitad o menos  de un lado de la próstata. La concentración del PSA es de 10 a menos de 20 y el grupo de grado es 1. En el panel inferior, se observa cáncer en más de la mitad de un lado de la próstata. La concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 1. En ambos paneles, también se muestran la vejiga, el recto y la uretra." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIA. El cáncer se encuentra solo en la próstata. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se encuentra en la mitad o menos de un lado de la próstata, la concentración del antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es de 10 a menos de 20 y el grupo de grado es 1; 2) el cáncer se encuentra en más de la mitad de un lado de la próstata o en ambos lados de la próstata, la concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 1.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796705" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIB. En la imagen se observa cáncer en un lado de la próstata. La concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 2. También se muestran la vejiga, el recto y la uretra." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_9">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIB. El cáncer se encuentra solo en la próstata, en uno o ambos lados. La concentración del antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 2.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796706" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de  próstata en estadio IIC. En la imagen se observa cáncer en ambos lados de la próstata. La concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 3 o 4. También se muestran la vejiga, el recto y la uretra." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_10">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de próstata en estadio IIC. El cáncer se encuentra solo en la próstata, en uno o ambos lados. La concentración del antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 3 o 4.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de próstata en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer está más avanzado que en el estadio I, pero no se diseminó fuera de la próstata. El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA, IIB y IIC. En el estadio IIA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se encuentra en la mitad o menos de un lado de la próstata, la concentración del antígeno prostático específico (PSA) es de 10 a menos de 20 y el grupo de grado es 1 (puntaje de Gleason de 6 o menos); 2) el cáncer se encuentra en más de la mitad de un lado de la próstata o en ambos lados de la próstata, la concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 1. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos lados de la próstata, la concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 2 (puntaje de Gleason de 7). En el estadio IIC, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos lados de la próstata, la concentración del PSA es menor de 20 y el grupo de grado es 3 o 4 (puntaje de Gleason de 7 u 8).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-01-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062965" url="/types/prostate/patient/prostate-treatment-pdq">Prostate Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256810" url="/espanol/tipos/prostata/paciente/tratamiento-prostata-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de próstata</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
