<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045155"><TermName>cytarabine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sy-TAYR-uh-been)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat adults and children with acute myeloid leukemia and to prevent and treat a type of leukemia that has spread to the meninges (the tissue that covers and protects the brain and spinal cord). It may also be used to treat acute lymphoblastic leukemia and blastic phase chronic myelogenous leukemia. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Cytarabine stops cells from making DNA and may kill cancer cells. It is a type of antimetabolite. Also called ARA-C.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705092" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cytarabine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705093" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;citarabina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>citarabina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos y niños con leucemia mieloide aguda, y para prevenir y tratar un tipo de leucemia que se diseminó a las meninges (tejido que cubre y protege el encéfalo y la médula espinal). También se usa para el tratamiento de la leucemia linfoblástica aguda  y la leucemia mieloide crónica en fase blástica. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. La citarabina impide que las células elaboren ADN y es posible que destruya células cancerosas. Es un tipo de antimetabolito. También se llama ARA-C.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-12-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000540242" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/cytarabine">Cytarabine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
