<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045151">
  <TermName>brachytherapy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BRAY-kee-THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of radiation therapy in which radioactive implants, such as pellets, seeds, ribbons, wires, needles, balloons, or capsules, are placed in the body, directly into or near the tumor. The radiation is delivered through a flexible tube called a catheter or a larger device called an applicator. Brachytherapy is often used to treat cancers of the head and neck, breast, cervix, prostate, and eye. Depending on the type of cancer and treatment plan, the implant may be kept in place for a few minutes, many days, or permanently. Also called implant radiation therapy and radiation brachytherapy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705085" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;brachytherapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705084" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;braquiterapia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>braquiterapia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia para la que se colocan en el cuerpo implantes radiactivos, como gránulos, semillas, cintas, alambres, agujas, globos o cápsulas, directamente en el tumor o cerca de este. La radiación se administra a través de un tubo flexible llamado catéter o un dispositivo más grande llamado aplicador. La braquiterapia suele usarse para tratar cánceres de cabeza y cuello, mama, cuello uterino, próstata y ojo. Según el tipo de cáncer y el plan de tratamiento, el implante puede mantenerse en su lugar durante unos minutos, muchos días o de forma permanente. También se llama braquirradioterapia, braquiterapia con radiación, curieterapia y radioterapia con implante.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
</GlossaryTerm>
