<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045192"><TermName>mitoxantrone hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MY-toh-ZAN-trone HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat acute myeloid leukemia in adults,   advanced prostate cancer that did not get better with hormone therapy, and  certain forms of multiple sclerosis. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Mitoxantrone hydrochloride damages the cell’s DNA and may kill cancer cells.  It also blocks a certain enzyme needed for cell division and DNA repair.  Mitoxantrone hydrochloride may also stop certain immune cells from causing damage to the brain and spinal cord. It is a type of antineoplastic antibiotic and a type of  topoisomerase inhibitor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000730775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mitoxantrone hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000730774" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de mitoxantrona&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de mitoxantrona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de la leucemia mieloide aguda en adultos, el cáncer de próstata en estadio avanzado que no mejoró con terapia hormonal, y ciertas formas de esclerosis múltiple. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de mitoxantrona daña el ADN de la célula y es posible que destruya células cancerosas. Además, bloquea determinada enzima necesaria para la multiplicación celular  y la reparación del ADN. El clorhidrato de mitoxantrona quizás también evite que determinadas células inmunitarias causen lesiones en el encéfalo y la médula espinal. Es un tipo de antibiótico antineoplásico y un inhibidor de la topoisomerasa. También se llama hidrocloruro de mitoxantrona.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000764240" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/mitoxantronehydrochloride">Mitoxantrone Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
