<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045263">
  <TermName>bone marrow transplant</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(bone MAYR-oh TRANZ-plant)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure in which a patient receives healthy  stem cells (blood-forming cells) to replace their own stem cells that have been destroyed by treatment with radiation or high doses of chemotherapy. The healthy stem cells may come from the bone marrow of the patient or from a related or unrelated donor. A bone marrow transplant may be autologous (using a patient’s own stem cells that were collected and saved before treatment), allogeneic (using stem cells from a related or unrelated donor), or syngeneic (using stem cells donated by an identical twin). Also called BMT.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705223" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bone marrow transplant&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705222" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trasplante de médula ósea&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>trasplante de médula ósea</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento por el que un paciente recibe células madre (células formadoras de sangre) sanas para reemplazar sus propias células madre destruidas por enfermedad, radioterapia o dosis altas de quimioterapia. Las células madre sanas se obtienen de la médula ósea del paciente o de un donante emparentado o no emparentado. Un trasplante de médula ósea puede ser autógeno (se usan las células madre de la médula del propio paciente que se recolectan y almacenan antes del tratamiento), alogénico (se usan las células madre de un donante emparentado o no emparentado) o  singénico (se usan las células madre donadas por un gemelo). También se llama TMO.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-01-23</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/stem-cell-transplant">Stem Cell Transplants in Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/trasplante-de-celulas-madre" UseWith="es">Trasplantes de células madre en el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
