<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045289">
  <TermName>goserelin acetate</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(GOH-seh-REH-lin A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat prostate cancer, relieve the symptoms of advanced breast cancer, and treat problems with the endometrium (lining of the uterus). Goserelin acetate initially causes the pituitary gland to make more luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), temporarily increasing testosterone levels in men and estrogen levels in women. With continued use, goserelin acetate lowers the amount of LH and FSH the pituitary gland releases, leading to a drop in testosterone levels in men and estrogen levels in women. Goserelin acetate may stop the growth of cancer cells that need testosterone or estrogen to grow. It is a type of hormone therapy called a luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist. Also called ZDX and Zoladex.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705272" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;goserelin acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000756039" type="audio/mpeg" alt="" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>acetato de goserelina</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento del cáncer de próstata, el control de los síntomas del cáncer de mama en estadio avanzado y el tratamiento de problemas del endometrio (revestimiento del útero). Al principio, el acetato de goserelina hace que la hipófisis produzca más hormona luteinizante (LH) y hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH), lo que aumenta de forma temporal la concentración de testosterona en los hombres y de estrógeno en las mujeres. Con el uso continuo, reduce la cantidad de LH y FSH que libera la hipófisis, lo que disminuye la concentración de testosterona en los hombres y de estrógeno en las mujeres. El acetato de goserelina en ocasiones detiene la multiplicación de células cancerosas que necesitan testosterona o estrógeno para su desarrollo. Pertenece a un grupo de medicamentos de terapia hormonal llamados agonistas de la  hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante (LHRH). También se llama ZDX y Zoladex.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2025-01-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000753175" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/goserelinacetate">Goserelin Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
