<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045283"><TermName>stage III laryngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... luh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer has formed in the supraglottis, glottis, or subglottis area of the larynx.  In stage III cancer of the supraglottis, (1) cancer is in the larynx only and the vocal cords do not work, and/or cancer has spread near or through the inner part of the thyroid cartilage. Cancer may have also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is in one area of the supraglottis and the vocal cords work normally. Cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (3) cancer is in more than one area of the supraglottis or has spread to the area at the base of the tongue or to tissues near the vocal cords. The vocal cords work normally. Cancer has also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller. In stage III cancer of the glottis, (1) cancer is in the larynx only and the vocal cords do not work, and/or cancer has spread near or through the inner part of the thyroid cartilage. Cancer may have also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is in one or both vocal cords and the vocal cords work normally. Cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (3) cancer has spread to the supraglottis, subglottis, or both, and/or the vocal cords do not work normally. Cancer has also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller. In stage III cancer of the subglottis, (1) cancer is in the larynx only and the vocal cords do not work, and/or cancer has spread near or through the inner part of the thyroid cartilage. Cancer may have also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is in the subglottis only. Cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (3) cancer has spread to one or both vocal cords and the vocal cords may not work normally. Cancer has also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705262" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III laryngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705263" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de laringe en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de laringe en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el estadio III, el cáncer se formó en el área de la supraglotis, glotis o subglotis de la laringe. En el cáncer de supraglotis en estadio III, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer solo está en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales no funcionan, o el cáncer se diseminó cerca del cartílago tiroideo o a través de este. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El cáncer solo está en un área de la supraglotis y las cuerdas vocales funcionan de forma normal. El cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 3) El cáncer está en más de un área de la supraglotis o se diseminó al área de la base de la lengua o los tejidos cercanos a las cuerdas vocales. Las cuerdas vocales funcionan de forma normal. El cáncer también se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario y el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. En el cáncer de glotis en estadio III, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer solo está en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales no funcionan, o el cáncer se diseminó cerca del cartílago tiroideo o a través de este. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El cáncer está en una o ambas cuerdas vocales y estas funcionan de forma normal. El cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 3) El cáncer se diseminó a la supraglotis, la subglotis, o a ambas, y las cuerdas vocales no funcionan de forma normal. El cáncer también se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. En el cáncer de subglotis en estadio III, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer solo está en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales no funcionan, o el cáncer se diseminó cerca del cartílago tiroideo o a través de este. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El cáncer solo está en la subglotis. El cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 3) El cáncer se diseminó a una o ambas cuerdas vocales y es posible que estas no funcionen de forma normal. El cáncer también se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-04-01</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258016" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/laryngeal-treatment-pdq">Laryngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000393556" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-laringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de laringe</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
