<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045292"><TermName>pegaspargase</TermName><TermPronunciation>(peg-A-spar-jays)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat adults and children with acute lymphoblastic leukemia.  It is used in patients whose cancer has not already been treated or who cannot be treated with asparaginase. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Pegaspargase is made up of the enzyme L-asparaginase that is linked to a substance called PEG, which makes the drug stay in the body longer.    L-asparaginase comes from the bacterium <ScientificName>E. coli</ScientificName> and breaks down the amino acid asparagine. This may stop  the growth of cancer cells that need asparagine to grow. Pegaspargase  is a type of protein synthesis inhibitor. Also called Oncaspar and PEG-asparaginase.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705279" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pegaspargase&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705278" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pegaspargasa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pegaspargasa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos y niños con leucemia linfoblástica aguda. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer no se ha tratado o que no pueden recibir asparaginasa. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. La pegaspargasa contiene la enzima L-asparaginasa unida a una sustancia llamada  PEG que permite que el medicamento permanezca más tiempo en el cuerpo. La L-asparaginasa se obtiene de la bacteria <ScientificName>E. coli</ScientificName> y su función es descomponer el aminoácido asparagina. Es posible que de esta manera detenga la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan asparaginasa para multiplicarse. La pegaspargasa es un tipo de inhibidor de la síntesis de proteínas. También se llama Oncaspar y PEG-asparaginasa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000506663" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/pegaspargase">Pegaspargase</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
