<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045308">
  <TermName>hydroxyurea</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(hy-DROK-see-yoo-REE-uh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other anticancer drugs or radiation therapy under the brand name Hydrea to treat certain types of chronic myelogenous leukemia and head and neck cancer and under the brand name Droxia to treat certain patients with sickle cell anemia. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Hydroxyurea stops cells from making DNA and may kill cancer cells. It may also make cancer cells easier to kill with radiation therapy.  Hydroxyurea may also help keep abnormal red blood cells from forming, which may reduce the number of painful sickle cell crises and the need for blood transfusions.   Hydroxyurea is a type of antimetabolite.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000730877" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hydroxyurea&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000730876" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hidroxiurea&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hidroxiurea</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo, con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer o con la radioterapia, bajo la marca comercial Hydrea, para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de leucemia mielógena crónica y cáncer de cabeza y cuello. También se utiliza bajo la marca comercial Droxia para tratar a ciertos pacientes con anemia de células falciformes. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y   tipos de cáncer. La hidroxiurea impide que las células elaboren ADN y quizás destruya células cancerosas. También, en ocasiones hace que sea más fácil destruir las células cancerosas con radioterapia. Por otro lado, es posible que la hidroxiurea ayude a evitar que se formen glóbulos rojos anormales, lo que tal vez reduzca el número de crisis  dolorosas de células falciformes y la necesidad de transfusiones. La hidroxiurea es un tipo de antimetabolito.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-12-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000780126" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/hydroxyurea">Hydroxyurea</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
