<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045300">
  <TermName>nilutamide</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ny-LOO-tuh-mide)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat prostate cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients who have had surgery to remove the testicles (orchiectomy). Nilutamide binds to proteins called androgen receptors, which are found in some prostate cancer cells. These proteins bind to androgens (male hormones) and may cause cancer cells to grow. Nilutamide blocks these proteins and may keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of antiandrogen. Also called Nilandron.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705288" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nilutamide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705289" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nilutamida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>nilutamida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de próstata que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se utiliza en pacientes que se sometieron a cirugía para extirpar los testículos (orquiectomía). La nilutamida se une a proteínas que se llaman receptores de andrógenos, que se encuentran en algunas células del cáncer de próstata. Estas proteínas se unen a los andrógenos (hormonas masculinas) y es posible que causen la formación de células cancerosas. La nilutamida bloquea estas proteínas y quizás impida que las células cancerosas se multipliquen. La nilutamida es un tipo de antiandrógeno. También se llama Nilandron.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2018-05-15</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000784029" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/Nilutamide">Nilutamide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
