<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045313">
  <TermName>inflammatory breast cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(in-FLA-muh-TOR-ee brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, fast-growing type of breast cancer in which cancer cells block lymph vessels in the skin of the breast, causing the breast to look swollen or inflamed. Inflammatory breast cancer usually does not form a lump that can be felt and may not be seen on a mammogram. Instead, the skin of the breast may appear pink, reddish purple, or bruised and have dimpling or ridges that look like the skin of an orange. These symptoms usually come on quickly. Most inflammatory breast cancers are invasive ductal carcinomas, which means they develop from cells that line the milk ducts of the breast and then spread beyond the ducts. Inflammatory breast cancer is more commonly diagnosed in younger women, Black women, and in women with overweight or obesity.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705300" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inflammatory breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705301" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama inflamatorio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000415524" type="image/jpeg" alt="Inflammatory breast cancer of the left breast showing redness, swelling, peau d'orange, and an inverted nipple." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Inflammatory breast cancer is a type of breast cancer in which the cancer cells block the lymph vessels in the skin of the breast. This causes the breast to look red and swollen. The skin may also appear dimpled or pitted, like the skin of an orange (peau d'orange), and the nipple may be inverted (facing inward).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000415524" type="image/jpeg" alt="" language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama inflamatorio</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo raro de cáncer de mama que  crece rápido en el que las células cancerosas obstruyen los vasos linfáticos de la piel y hacen que la mama (seno) se vea inflamada o hinchada. El cáncer de mama inflamatorio por lo general no produce una masa o bulto  palpable y es posible que no se observe en la mamografía. En su lugar, la piel de la mama se ve rosada, de color púrpura rojizo o  amoratada, y presenta hoyuelos  o surcos que la hacen parecerse a la cáscara de una naranja. Estos síntomas por lo general aparecen rápido. La mayoría de los cánceres inflamatorios de la mama son carcinomas ductales invasivos, lo que significa que se forman a partir de las células que recubren los conductos galactóforos (lácteos) de la mama y luego se diseminan fuera de los conductos. El cáncer de mama inflamatorio se diagnostica con mayor frecuencia en mujeres jóvenes, mujeres negras y mujeres que presentan sobrepeso u obesidad. También se llama carcinoma inflamatorio de mama.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-10-28</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/ibc-fact-sheet">Inflammatory Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-seno-inflamatorio">Cáncer inflamatorio de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
