<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045310"><TermName>stage III anal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... AY-nul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III anal cancer is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA,  the tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and has spread to lymph nodes near the anus or groin.  In stage IIIB, the tumor is any size and has spread to nearby organs, such as the vagina, urethra, or bladder. Cancer has not spread to lymph nodes. In stage IIIC, the tumor is any size and may have spread to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to lymph nodes near the anus or groin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705294" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III anal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705295" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de ano en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de ano en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de ano en estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor mide 5 cm o menos y se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos cerca del ano o la ingle. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a órganos cercanos, como la vagina, la uretra o la vejiga. El cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos. En el estadio IIIC, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que se haya diseminado a los órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos cerca del ano o la ingle.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2018-01-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258179" url="/types/anal/patient/anal-treatment-pdq">Anal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256763" url="/espanol/tipos/ano/paciente/tratamiento-ano-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de ano</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
