<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045359">
  <TermName>lymphedema</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LIM-fuh-DEE-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which lymph builds up in tissues and causes swelling. Lymphedema usually affects an arm or leg, but it can also affect other parts of the body. Lymphedema can occur when lymph vessels or nodes become damaged or blocked, which affects the flow of lymph in the body. This is most commonly caused by cancer or cancer treatment, such as surgery or radiation therapy. It can also be caused by infection with certain parasites or by having certain inherited conditions in which the lymph nodes or lymph vessels are abnormal or absent. Lymphedema cannot be cured, but treatment can help relieve swelling, pain, and other symptoms.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705368" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphedema&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705369" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfedema&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814722" type="image/jpeg" alt="Lymphedema; drawing showing a female figure with a red, swollen arm. The lymph nodes and lymphatic vessels are also shown in the figure. There is a pull-out from the swollen arm showing a top layer of red, hardened skin. There is also a pull-out box from a lymphatic vessel below the skin that shows a cancerous tumor blocking the flow of lymph fluid through a lymphatic vessel and a buildup of fluid and white blood cells in the surrounding tissues." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Lymphedema is swelling caused by a buildup of lymph fluid in the body, usually in an arm or leg. The lymph system helps the body fight infection and is made up of lymph nodes, lymphatic vessels, and organs that collect and carry lymph fluid through the body. When part of the lymph system is damaged or blocked by cancer or cancer treatment, the flow of lymph fluid through the body is disrupted. This can lead to increased fluid in the tissues, inflammation, and the release of  white blood cells, which can cause swelling in the affected body part. Discoloration and hardening of the skin in the affected area can also occur.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815031" type="image/jpeg" alt="Linfedema. En el dibujo se observa una mujer con un brazo rojo e hinchado. También se señalan ganglios y vasos linfáticos en su cuerpo. Hay una ampliación del brazo hinchado en el que se observa la capa superior de la piel endurecida y roja. Además, en un recuadro se ve un vaso linfático debajo de la piel y un tumor canceroso que interrumpe el flujo de la linfa por el vaso, así como una acumulación de líquido y glóbulos blancos en los tejidos que rodean el vaso." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="es">El linfedema es la hinchazón que se produce por la acumulación de la linfa en el cuerpo, por lo general en una extremidad: brazo  o pierna. El sistema linfático ayuda al cuerpo a combatir infecciones, y se compone de ganglios linfáticos, vasos linfáticos y órganos que recogen y transportan la linfa  o líquido linfático. Cuando un cáncer o su tratamiento dañan o  bloquean parte del sistema linfático, el flujo de la linfa por el cuerpo se interrumpe. Esto puede causar acumulación de líquido en los tejidos, inflamación y liberación de glóbulos blancos, lo que produce la hinchazón del área afectada. En ocasiones también se observa  cambio de color y endurecimiento de la piel en dicha área.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>linfedema</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que se acumula una cantidad extra de linfa en los tejidos y se produce hinchazón. El linfedema suele afectar las extremidades (brazos y piernas) u otras partes del cuerpo. Ocurre cuando los vasos o los ganglios linfáticos se dañan o bloquean, lo que afecta al flujo de la linfa en el cuerpo. Las causas más frecuentes son el cáncer o los tratamientos  como la cirugía o la radioterapia. Otras causas son infecciones por determinados parásitos o ciertas afecciones hereditarias en las que los ganglios o los vasos linfáticos son anormales o están ausentes. El linfedema no tiene cura, sin embargo, hay tratamientos disponibles que alivian la hinchazón, el dolor y otros síntomas. También se llama edema linfático y linfoedema.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-03-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/lymphedema">Lymphedema</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/linfedema">Linfedema</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
