<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045357"><TermName>stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, the tumor is larger than 4 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes and one or more of the following may be found: (1) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (2) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (3) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has developed pneumonitis.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705366" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705367" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000520465" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIA lung cancer; drawing shows a primary tumor (larger than 4 cm but not larger than 5 cm) in the left lung and cancer in (a) the left main bronchus and (b) the inner membrane covering the lung (inset). Also shown is (c) part or all of the lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation). The carina, pleura, and a rib (inset) are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IIA lung cancer. The tumor is larger than 4 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes and one or more of the following may be found: (a) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (b) cancer has spread to the inner membrane that covers the lung; and/or (c) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation of the lung).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000537558" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIA. En la imagen se observa un tumor primario en el pulmón izquierdo que mide más de 4 cm, pero no más de 5 cm. Además se observan las siguientes situaciones: a)  el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal izquierdo; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana interna que recubre el pulmón (recuadro inferior); c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón). También se observan la carina y la pleura y, en el recuadro inferior, una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIA. El tumor mide más de 4 cm, pero no más de 5 cm. El cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos y se presentan una o más de las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana interna que recubre el pulmón; c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el tumor mide más de 4 cm, pero no más de 5 cm. El cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos y se presentan una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; 2) el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre el pulmón;  3) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-06-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956" url="/types/lung/patient/non-small-cell-lung-treatment-pdq">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766" url="/espanol/tipos/pulmon/paciente/tratamiento-pulmon-celulas-no-pequenas-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
