<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045367">
  <TermName>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, the tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are around the trachea or aorta, or where the trachea divides into the bronchi. Also, one or more of the following may be found: (1) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (2) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (3) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has developed pneumonitis; OR cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are in the lung or near the bronchus. Also, one or more of the following is found: (1) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters but not larger than 7 centimeters; and/or (2) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung as the primary tumor; and/or (3) cancer has spread to any of the following: the membrane that lines the inside of the chest wall, the chest wall, the nerve that controls the diaphragm, or the outer layer of tissue of the sac around the heart; OR cancer may have spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are in the lung or near the bronchus. Also, one or more of the following is found: (1) the tumor is larger than 7 centimeters; and/or (2) there are one or more separate tumors in a different lobe of the lung with the primary tumor; and/or (3) the tumor is any size and cancer has spread to any of the following: the trachea, carina, esophagus, breastbone or backbone, diaphragm, heart, major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart (aorta or vena cava), or the nerve that controls the larynx (voice box).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705381" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705380" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000521911" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA lung cancer (1); drawing shows a primary tumor (5 cm or smaller) in the left lung (top inset) and cancer in lymph nodes around the trachea. Also shown is cancer that has spread to (a) the left main bronchus and (b) the membrane covering the lung (bottom inset). Also shown is (c) part or all of the lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation). The carina, pleura, and a rib (bottom inset) are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIA lung cancer (1). The tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are around the trachea or aorta (not shown),  or where the trachea divides into the bronchi. Also, one or more of the following may be found: (a) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (b) cancer has spread to the inner membrane that covers the lung; and/or (c) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation of the lung).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000682116" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA lung cancer (2); drawing shows (a) a primary tumor (larger than 5 cm but not larger than 7 cm) in the left lung and cancer in lymph nodes in the lung or near the bronchus on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. Also shown is (b) separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung as the primary tumor and cancer that has spread to (c) the chest wall and the membranes covering the lung and chest wall (top right inset); (d) the nerve that controls the diaphragm; and (e) the sac around the heart (bottom right inset). The trachea, left main bronchus, diaphragm, heart, and a rib (top right inset) are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIA lung cancer (2). Cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are in the lung or near the bronchus. Also, one or more of the following is found: (a) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters but not larger than 7 centimeters; and/or (b) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung as the primary tumor; and/or cancer has spread to any of the following: (c) the chest wall and/or the membrane that lines the inside of the chest wall, (d) the nerve that controls the diaphragm, and/or (e) the outer layer of tissue of the sac around the heart.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000682121" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA lung cancer (3); drawing shows (a) a primary tumor (larger than 7 cm) in the left lung and (b) separate tumors in a different lobe of the lung with the primary tumor. Also shown is cancer that has spread to the (c) trachea, (d) carina, (e) esophagus, (f) breastbone, (g) diaphragm, (h) heart, and (i) the aorta and vena cava." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIA lung cancer (3). Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are in the lung or near the bronchus. Also, one or more of the following is found: (a) the primary tumor is larger than 7 centimeters; and/or (b) there are one or more separate tumors in a different lobe of the lung with the primary tumor; and/or the tumor is any size and cancer has spread to any of the following: (c) trachea, (d) carina, (e) esophagus, (f) breastbone or backbone, (g) diaphragm, (h) heart, (i) major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart (aorta or vena cava), or the nerve that controls the larynx (not shown).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000537567" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIA (Parte 1). En la imagen se observan un tumor primario que mide 5 cm o menos (recuadro superior) en el pulmón izquierdo y ganglios linfáticos cancerosos alrededor de la tráquea. También se observa lo siguiente: a) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal izquierdo; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana que recubre el pulmón (recuadro inferior); c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón). Además se muestran la carina, la pleura y en el recuadro inferior, una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIA (Parte 1). El tumor mide 5 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están alrededor de la tráquea o la aorta (no se muestra), o donde la tráquea se divide para formar los bronquios. Además, se presentan uno o más de los siguientes casos: a) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre el pulmón; c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000686748" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIA (Parte 2). En la imagen se observa lo siguiente: a) un tumor primario que mide más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm en el pulmón izquierdo y ganglios linfáticos cancerosos en el pulmón o cerca del bronquio del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario; b) tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario; c) el cáncer se diseminó a la pared torácica, así como a la membrana que recubre el pulmón y la membrana que reviste la pared torácica (recuadro superior izquierdo); d) el cáncer se diseminó al nervio que controla el diafragma; e) el cáncer se diseminó al pericardio (recuadro inferior izquierdo). También se muestran la tráquea, el bronquio principal izquierdo, el diafragma, el corazón y, en el recuadro superior derecho, una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_9">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIA (Parte 2). El cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están en el pulmón o cerca del bronquio. Además, se presentan uno o más de los siguientes casos:

a) el tumor mide más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm; b)
hay uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario;
c) el cáncer se diseminó a la
pared torácica o la membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica; d) el cáncer se diseminó al nervio que controla el diafragma; e) el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más externa del pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000686753" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIA (Parte 3). En la imagen se observa lo siguiente: a) un tumor primario que mide más de 7 cm en el pulmón izquierdo; b) tumores separados en un lóbulo del pulmón diferente al del tumor primario. También se observa cáncer que se diseminó a los siguientes sitios: c) la tráquea, d) la carina, e) el esófago, f) el esternón, g) el diafragma, h) el corazón, i) la aorta y la vena cava." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_10">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIA (Parte 3). Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están en el pulmón o cerca del bronquio. Además, se presentan una o más de las siguientes situaciones: a) el tumor mide más de 7 cm; b) hay uno o más tumores separados en un lóbulo del pulmón diferente al del tumor primario. También es posible que el tumor sea de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se haya diseminado a cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: c) la tráquea, d) la carina, e) el esófago, f) el esternón o la columna vertebral, g) el diafragma, h) el corazón, i) los vasos sanguíneos principales que entran o salen del corazón (aorta o vena cava), o el nervio que controla la laringe (no se muestra).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no
pequeñas en estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA,
IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor mide 5
cm o menos, y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios
linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor
primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están
alrededor de la tráquea o la aorta, o donde la tráquea se divide para formar los
bronquios. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: el cáncer se diseminó al
bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; el cáncer se
diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre
el pulmón; todo el pulmón o una parte de este se
desinfló o presenta neumonitis. 2) El
cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado
del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios
linfáticos cancerosos están en el pulmón o cerca del
bronquio. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: el tumor mide más de 5 cm, pero no
más de 7 cm; hay uno o más tumores separados
en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario;
el cáncer se diseminó a la
membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica, la
pared torácica, el nervio que controla el diafragma o la
capa más externa del pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón). 3) Es posible que el
cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos del
mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los
ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están en el pulmón o
cerca del bronquio. Además, se presentan una o más de las
siguientes situaciones: el tumor mide más de 7
cm; hay uno o más tumores separados en un lóbulo del pulmón diferente al del tumor primario; el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se
diseminó a la tráquea, la carina,
el esófago, el esternón, la columna vertebral, el diafragma, el corazón,
los vasos sanguíneos principales que entran o salen del corazón (la aorta o la vena cava), o el nervio que controla la laringe.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-06-18</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956" url="/types/lung/patient/non-small-cell-lung-treatment-pdq">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766" url="/espanol/tipos/pulmon/paciente/tratamiento-pulmon-celulas-no-pequenas-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
