<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045368"><TermName>lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that begins in cells of the immune system. There are two basic categories of lymphomas. One kind is Hodgkin lymphoma, which is marked by the presence of a type of cell called the Reed-Sternberg cell. The other category is non-Hodgkin lymphomas, which includes a large, diverse group of cancers of immune system cells. Non-Hodgkin lymphomas can be further divided into cancers that have an indolent (slow-growing) course and those that have an aggressive (fast-growing) course. These subtypes behave and respond to treatment differently. Both Hodgkin and non-Hodgkin lymphomas can occur in children and adults, and prognosis and treatment depend on the stage and the type of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705383" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705382" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que empieza en las células del sistema inmunitario. Hay dos categorías básicas de linfomas: el linfoma de Hodgkin y el linfoma no Hodgkin. El linfoma de Hodgkin se caracteriza por la presencia de un tipo de célula llamada célula de Reed-Sternberg. Los linfomas no Hodgkin incluyen un grupo grande y diverso de cánceres de células del sistema inmunitario que se  dividen, en general, en los cánceres de crecimiento lento (indolentes o de bajo grado de malignidad ) y los  de crecimiento rápido (agresivos o de alto grado de malignidad). Cada subtipo se comporta y responde al tratamiento de distinto modo. Ambas categorías de linfomas se presentan en niños y adultos, y el pronóstico y tratamiento dependen del estadio y el tipo de cáncer. También se llama linfoma maligno.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2007-09-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
