<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045398"><TermName>triacetyluridine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(try-A-seh-til-YOOR-ih-deen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used in the emergency treatment of adults and children who receive too much fluorouracil or capecitabine or who have heart or central nervous system toxicity or other serious side effects that occur within 4 days of ending treatment with these drugs. Triacetyluridine may help protect healthy cells from some of the side effects caused by certain anticancer drugs. It is a type of chemoprotective agent and a type of pyrimidine analog. Also called PN401, uridine triacetate, and Vistogard.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705415" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;triacetyluridine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705414" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;triacetiluridina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>triacetiluridina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa como tratamiento de urgencia en adultos y niños que reciben demasiado fluorouracilo o capecitabina, sufren toxicidad en el corazón o el sistema nervioso central, o tienen otros efectos secundarios graves dentro de los 4 días que siguen al tratamiento con estos medicamentos.  a veces ayuda a proteger  las células sanas de algunos efectos secundarios de ciertos medicamentos anticancerosos. Es un tipo de quimioprotector y de análogo de la pirimidina. También se llama PN401, triacetato de uridina y Vistogard.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-03-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000777651" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/uridinetriacetate">Uridine Triacetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
