<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045390">
  <TermName>desmoid tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(DEZ-moyd TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare type of soft tissue tumor that forms in fibrous connective tissue of the body, usually in the abdomen, head and neck, shoulders, upper arms, and thighs. Desmoid tumors are intermediate tumors, meaning they can grow into and damage nearby tissue (locally aggressive) but do not spread to other parts of the body. They are painful, difficult to completely remove with surgery, and often come back after surgery. Desmoid tumors occur in adults and children. Also called aggressive fibromatosis and desmoid-type fibromatosis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705405" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;desmoid tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705404" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor desmoide&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor desmoide</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo raro de tumor de tejido blando que se forma en el tejido conjuntivo fibroso del cuerpo, por lo general aparece en el abdomen, la cabeza y el cuello, los hombros, los brazos y los muslos. Los tumores desmoides  son tumores intermedios, lo que significa que crecen en el tejido cercano y lo dañan (localmente agresivos), pero no se diseminan a otras partes del cuerpo. Son dolorosos, difíciles de extirpar completamente con cirugía y, a menudo, vuelven después del tratamiento. Se presentan en niños y adultos. También se llama fibromatosis agresiva y fibromatosis tipo desmoide.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2025-03-19</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/pediatric-adult-rare-tumor/rare-tumors/rare-soft-tissue-tumors/desmoid-tumor" UseWith="en">Desmoid Tumor</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/pediatric-adult-rare-tumor/espanol/tumores-raros/tumores-raros-tejidos-blandos/tumor-desmoide" UseWith="en">Tumor desmoide</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000806988" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">fibrous connective tissue</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000806988" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">tejido fibroso</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
