<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000454778">
  <TermName>NCCIH</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A federal agency that uses science to explore complementary and integrative health (CIH) practices, trains CIH researchers, and provides authoritative information about CIH to professionals and the public. NCCIH awards grants for research projects, training, and career development in CIH; sponsors conferences, educational programs, and exhibits; studies ways to use proven CIH practices along with conventional medical practice; and supports adding CIH to medical, dental, and nursing school programs. NCCIH is part of the National Institutes of Health. Also called National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermName>NCCIH</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Agencia federal que usa la ciencia para explorar la práctica de la salud complementaria e integral, capacitar investigadores y proporcionar información confiable sobre este tema a los profesionales y el público. El NCCIH subvenciona proyectos de investigación, capacitación y desarrollo profesional al respecto. También auspicia conferencias, programas educativos y exposiciones. Asimismo, estudia las formas de utilizar los procedimientos comprobados en salud complementaria e integral junto con el ejercicio profesional de la medicina convencional. Además, apoya la incorporación de esta práctica en los programas de las facultades de medicina, odontología y enfermería. El NCCIH forma parte de los Institutos Nacionales de Salud. También se llama Centro Nacional de Salud Complementaria e Integral.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-02-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2015-03-23</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.nccih.nih.gov/" UseWith="en">National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.nccih.nih.gov/health/espanol" UseWith="es">Centro Nacional de Salud Complementaria e Integral</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
