<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000454762"><TermName>methadone hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEH-thuh-DONE HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat moderate to severe pain. It is also used to help people who are addicted to opioid drugs, such as heroin or prescription pain medicines. Methadone hydrochloride works by binding to opioid receptors, mainly the mu opioid receptor, in the central nervous system. This blocks pain signals and changes how the body responds to pain. It also reduces cravings and withdrawal symptoms in people with opioid use disorder. Methadone hydrochloride is a type of synthetic opioid agonist that works as an analgesic (pain reliever).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715022" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;methadone hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715021" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de metadona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de metadona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el dolor de moderado a grave. También se usa para ayudar a las personas adictas a los opioides, como la heroína o los analgésicos que se venden con receta médica. El clorhidrato de metadona se une a los receptores de opioides, sobre todo al receptor de opioides mi (µ), en el sistema nervioso central. Esto bloquea las señales del dolor y modifica la respuesta del cuerpo a este. También reduce las ansias de consumo y los síntomas de abstinencia en personas con trastorno por consumo de opioides. El clorhidrato de metadona es un tipo de agonista opioide sintético que actúa como analgésico (calmante del dolor).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-04-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062845" url="/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/pain/pain-pdq">Cancer Pain</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256654" url="/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/dolor/dolor-pdq">El dolor y el cáncer</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
