<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000454841"><TermName>stage IV mycosis fungoides/Sézary syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... my-KOH-sis fun-GOY-deez/sey-zah-REE SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>When there is a high number of Sézary cells in the blood, the disease is called Sézary syndrome. Stage IV is divided into stages IVA1, IVA2, and IVB. In stage IVA1, patches, papules, plaques, or tumors may cover any amount of the skin surface, and 80% or more of the skin surface may be reddened. The lymph nodes may be abnormal, but they are not cancerous. There is a high number of Sézary cells in the blood. In stage IVA2, patches, papules, plaques, or tumors may cover any amount of the skin surface, and 80% or more of the skin surface may be reddened. The lymph nodes are very abnormal, or cancer has formed in the lymph nodes. There may be a high number of Sézary cells in the blood. In stage IVB, cancer has spread to other organs in the body, such as the spleen or liver.  Patches, papules, plaques, or tumors may cover any amount of the skin surface, and 80% or more of the skin surface may be reddened. The lymph nodes may be abnormal or cancerous. There may be a high number of Sézary cells in the blood.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715093" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV mycosis fungoides/Sezary syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715094" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;micosis fungoide o síndrome de Sézary en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>micosis fungoide o síndrome de Sézary en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cuando hay muchas células de Sézary en la sangre, la enfermedad se llama síndrome de Sézary. El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA1, IVA2 y IVB. En el estadio IVA1, las manchas, pápulas, placas o tumores cubren cualquier cantidad de piel, y se observa enrojecimiento en el 80 % o más de la superficie de la piel. Los ganglios linfáticos a veces son anormales, pero no son cancerosos. Hay muchas células de Sézary en la sangre. En el estadio IVA2, la manchas, pápulas, placas o tumores cubren cualquier cantidad de piel, y se observa enrojecimiento en el 80 % o más de la superficie de la piel. Los ganglios linfáticos son muy anormales o son cancerosos. Es posible que haya muchas células de Sézary en la sangre. En el estadio IVB, el cáncer se diseminó a otros órganos del cuerpo, como el bazo o el hígado. Las manchas, pápulas, placas o tumores cubren cualquier cantidad de piel, y se observa enrojecimiento en el 80 % o más de la superficie de la piel. Los ganglios linfáticos pueden ser anormales o cancerosos. Es posible que haya muchas células de Sézary en la sangre.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-11-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-10-08</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258022" url="/types/lymphoma/patient/mycosis-fungoides-treatment-pdq">Mycosis Fungoides (Including Sézary Syndrome) Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433316" url="/espanol/tipos/linfoma/paciente/tratamiento-micosis-fungoide-pdq">Tratamiento de la micosis fungoide (incluso el síndrome de Sézary)</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
