<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045491">
  <TermName>Cockayne syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KAH-kayn SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare genetic disorder that is caused by inheriting two mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>ERCC6</GeneName>
       gene or in the 
      <GeneName>ERCC8</GeneName>
       gene. These genes make proteins involved in DNA repair. Cockayne syndrome is marked by shorter-than-average height, an abnormally small head, premature aging, sensitivity to light, and learning and developmental delays. Other signs and symptoms may include hearing loss, vision problems, tooth decay, bone abnormalities, and nervous system problems. The signs and symptoms usually appear during infancy and get worse over time. Cockayne syndrome is inherited in an autosomal recessive manner.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000731011" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cockayne syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000731010" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Cockayne&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802195" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an autosomal recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their four children: an unaffected father (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene on a chromosome pair; an unaffected mother (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter with two normal genes; an unaffected son (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; and an affected son with two mutated genes." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Autosomal recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child. A genetic condition can occur when the child inherits one copy of a mutated (changed) gene from each parent. The parents of a child with an autosomal recessive condition usually do not have the condition. Unaffected parents are called carriers because they each carry one copy of the mutated gene and can pass it to their children.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802815" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia autosómica recesiva en una familia conformada por padre, madre y cuatro hijos: se muestran un par de cromosomas con un gen mutado y un gen normal en el padre no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en la madre no afectada (portadora); dos genes normales en una hija no afectada; un gen mutado y un gen normal en un hijo no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en una hija no afectada (portadora) y dos genes mutados en un hijo afectado." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">La herencia autosómica recesiva es una de las formas en que un rasgo o una afección genética pasa de padres a hijos. El niño presenta la afección genética cuando hereda dos copias de un gen mutado (cambiado), una del padre y otra de la madre. Por lo general, la madre y el padre no presentan la afección que se hereda de manera autosómica recesiva. Se dice que la madre y el padre no afectados son portadores porque cada uno tiene una copia del gen mutado que puede pasar a sus hijos. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Cockayne</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno genético raro que se produce cuando se heredan dos mutaciones (cambios) en los genes 
      <GeneName>ERCC6</GeneName>
       o 
      <GeneName>ERCC8</GeneName>
      . Estos genes elaboran proteínas que participan en la reparación del ADN. El síndrome de Cockayne se caracteriza por estatura baja, cabeza anormalmente pequeña, envejecimiento prematuro, sensibilidad a la luz y retrasos en el aprendizaje y el desarrollo. Otros signos y síntomas pueden incluir sordera, problemas de visión, caries dental, anomalías óseas y problemas del sistema nervioso. Los signos y síntomas por lo general aparecen durante la infancia y empeoran con el tiempo. El síndrome de Cockayne se hereda de manera autosómica recesiva.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6122/cockayne-syndrome">Cockayne syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/cockayne-syndrome/">Cockayne syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12817/sindrome-de-cockayne">Síndrome de Cockayne (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
