<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045499"><TermName>Fanconi anemia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fan-KOH-nee uh-NEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare inherited disorder in which the bone marrow does not make enough blood cells, including red blood cells, white blood cells, and platelets. It is usually diagnosed before age 15 years. Signs and symptoms include frequent infections, a tendency to bleed easily, and extreme tiredness. People with Fanconi anemia may also have brown spots on the skin, short height, malformed thumbs or forearms, small head or eyes, hearing loss, and abnormalities of the kidneys, gastrointestinal tract, heart, genitals, brain, and spinal cord. They also have an increased risk of developing certain types of cancer, including leukemia and cancers of the skin, head, neck, gastrointestinal system, and genitals. Fanconi anemia is caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes involved in DNA repair.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705545" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Fanconi anemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705544" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anemia de Fanconi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>anemia de Fanconi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que la médula ósea no produce suficientes células sanguíneas (glóbulos rojos, glóbulos blancos y plaquetas). Por lo general, se diagnostica antes de los 15 años. Los signos y síntomas incluyen infecciones frecuentes, hemorragias que se producen con facilidad y cansancio extremo.  Las personas con anemia de Fanconi a veces también tienen manchas marrones en la piel, estatura baja, pulgares o antebrazos con malformaciones, cabeza u ojos pequeños, sordera y anormalidades en los riñones, el tubo digestivo, el corazón, los genitales, el encéfalo y la médula espinal. Además, presentan un riesgo más alto de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como leucemia y cánceres de piel, cabeza, cuello, aparato digestivo y  genitales. La causa de la anemia de Fanconi son mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que participan en la reparación del ADN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6425/fanconi-anemia">Fanconi anemia (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/fanconi-anemia/">Fanconi anemia (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13183/anemia-de-fanconi">Anemia de Fanconi (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000334.htm">Anemia de Fanconi (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
