<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045525">
  <TermName>rituximab</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(rih-TUK-sih-mab)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs under the brand names Riabni, Rituxan, Ruxience, and Truxima to treat certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic leukemia, and B-cell acute leukemia  that are CD20 positive.   Rituximab is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Rituximab  binds to a protein called CD20, which is found on B cells (a type of white blood cell) and some types of cancer cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Rituximab is a type of monoclonal antibody. </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705567" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rituximab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705566" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rituximab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>rituximab</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos bajo las marcas comerciales Riabni, Rituxan, Ruxience y Truxima para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B, leucemia linfocítica crónica y leucemia aguda de células B  positivos para CD20. El rituximab también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. El rituximab se une a una proteína llamada CD20, que se encuentra en las células B (tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. El rituximab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-05-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495778" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/rituximab">Rituximab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
