<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045580"><TermName>lymphography</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lim-FAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses x-rays or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to make pictures of the lymphatic system. A dye is injected into the body to make the lymphatic vessels and lymph nodes easier to see in the pictures. Lymphography may be used to check for blockages or leaks in the lymphatic system and to help diagnose certain conditions, such as lymphedema or lymphoma, or find out whether cancer has spread. It may also be used to help plan treatment or find out how well treatment is working. Lymphography is also sometimes used before surgery to learn more about the structure of a person's lymphatic system. Also called lymphangiography.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705618" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705617" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfografía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se toma una serie de radiografías o imágenes por resonancia magnética (IRM) con el fin de crear imágenes del sistema linfático. Se inyecta un tinte en el cuerpo para que los vasos y los ganglios linfáticos se vean con más claridad en las imágenes. La linfografía sirve para comprobar si hay obstrucciones o fugas en el sistema linfático y para ayudar a diagnosticar determinadas afecciones, como el linfedema o el linfoma, o averiguar si el cáncer se diseminó. También se utiliza para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento o determinar si es eficaz. La linfografía a veces se usa antes de una cirugía para saber cómo se ve la estructura del sistema linfático de una persona. También se llama linfangiografía y linfoangiografía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-03-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
