<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045604">
  <TermName>autoimmune disease</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AW-toh-ih-MYOON dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which the body’s immune system mistakes its own healthy tissues as foreign and attacks them. Most autoimmune diseases cause inflammation that can affect many parts of the body. The parts of the body affected depend on which autoimmune disease a person has. Common signs and symptoms include fatigue, fever, muscle aches, joint pain and swelling, skin problems, abdominal pain, digestion problems, and swollen glands. The symptoms often come and go and can be mild or severe. There are many different types of autoimmune diseases. They are more common in women and can run in families. Also called autoimmune condition.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;autoimmune disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad autoinmunitaria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>enfermedad autoinmunitaria</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo ataca los tejidos sanos propios porque los confunde con tejidos  ajenos. La mayoría de las enfermedades autoinmunitarias producen inflamación que afecta muchas partes del cuerpo. Estas partes varían según el tipo de enfermedad autoinmunitaria. Los signos y síntomas comunes son cansancio,  fiebre, dolor en los músculos, dolor e hinchazón en las articulaciones, problemas de la piel, dolor en el abdomen, problemas de digestión y glándulas  hinchadas. Los síntomas a menudo son intermitentes (aparecen y desaparecen) y pueden ser leves o intensos. Hay  muchos tipos de enfermedades autoinmunitarias. Son más comunes en las mujeres  y  se pueden presentar en varios miembros de la misma familia. También se llama afección autoinmunitaria y enfermedad autoinmune.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-07-26</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
