<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045602">
  <TermName>astrocytoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AS-troh-sy-TOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of glioma that forms in star-shaped cells called astrocytes in the brain and spinal cord. Astrocytomas may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). They are grouped based on their grade, which is determined by how abnormal the tumor cells look under a microscope and how quickly the tumor is likely to grow, spread, and come back after treatment. Low-grade astrocytomas, such as pilocytic astrocytomas, tend to grow slowly and are more common in children. High-grade astrocytomas, such as glioblastoma, tend to grow and spread within the brain and spinal cord quickly and are more common in adults.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705656" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;astrocytoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705655" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;astrocitoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000765034" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the brain; two-panel drawing showing the cerebrum, ventricles (fluid-filled spaces), cerebellum, brain stem (pons and medulla), and spinal cord. Also shown are the meninges and skull (left panel) and the choroid plexus, hypothalamus, pineal gland, pituitary gland, and optic nerve (right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Anatomy of the brain showing the cerebrum, ventricles (with cerebrospinal fluid shown in blue), cerebellum, brain stem (pons and medulla), and other parts of the brain.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000765614" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del encéfalo; un dibujo de dos paneles muestra el cerebro, los ventrículos (espacios llenos de líquido), el cerebelo, el tronco encefálico (protuberancia y bulbo raquídeo) y la médula espinal. También se muestra las meninges y el cráneo (panel izquierdo) y el plexo coroideo, el hipotálamo, la glándula pineal, la hipófisis y el nervio óptico (panel derecho)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Anatomía del encéfalo donde se muestra el cerebro, los ventrículos (con el líquido cefalorraquídeo en azul), el cerebelo, el tronco encefálico (la protuberancia y el bulbo raquídeo) y otras partes del encéfalo.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>astrocitoma</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de glioma que empieza en unas células pequeñas en forma de estrella llamadas astrocitos que se encuentran en el encéfalo (tumor cerebral) y la médula espinal. Los astrocitomas pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). Se clasifican en función de su grado, que se determina según cuán anormal es el aspecto de las células tumorales al microscopio y por la rapidez con que el tumor puede crecer, diseminarse y reaparecer después del tratamiento. Los astrocitomas de grado bajo, como los astrocitomas pilocíticos, suelen crecer de forma lenta y son más frecuentes en niños. Los astrocitomas de grado alto, como el glioblastoma, con frecuencia crecen y se diseminan rápido por el encéfalo y la médula espinal, y son más habituales en adultos. También se llama astroglioma y glioma astrocítico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-06-12</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/brain">Brain Tumors</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cerebro">Tumores cerebrales</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
