<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045656">
  <TermName>NCI clinical trials cooperative group</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... KLIH-nih-kul TRY-uls koh-AH-pruh-tiv groop)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A group of researchers, cancer centers, and community doctors who are involved in studies that test new ways to screen, prevent, diagnose, and treat cancer. Clinical trials run by cooperative groups are funded and supported by the National Cancer Institute (NCI), and large numbers of patients take part in many locations. The current U.S. cooperative groups are the Alliance for Clinical Trials in Oncology, ECOG-ACRIN Cancer Research Group, NRG Oncology, SWOG, and Children’s Oncology Group (COG). The NCI clinical trials cooperative groups are part of the National Clinical Trials Network (NCTN).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705741" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;NCI clinical trials cooperative group&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705742" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grupo cooperativo de ensayos clínicos del NCI&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>grupo cooperativo de ensayos clínicos del NCI</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Grupo de investigadores, centros oncológicos y médicos comunitarios que participan en estudios en los que se prueban nuevas maneras de detectar, prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar el cáncer. El Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI) patrocina y apoya los ensayos clínicos que dirigen grupos cooperativos. En estos estudios participan  muchos pacientes en múltiples sitios. En los Estados Unidos los grupos cooperativos vigentes son la Alliance for Clinical Trials in Oncology, el ECOG-ACRIN Cancer Research Group, el NRG Oncology, el SWOG y el Children’s Oncology Group (COG). Los grupos cooperativos de ensayos clínicos del NCI participan en la National Clinical Trials Network (NCTN).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-05-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000776355" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">National Clinical Trials Network</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000776355" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">Red Nacional de Ensayos Clínicos</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
