<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045671">
  <TermName>DNA</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The molecule inside cells that contains the genetic information needed for a person and most other organisms to develop and grow and is passed from one generation to the next. DNA is made up of two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a double helix. Each strand has a backbone that is made up of sugar and phosphate molecules that attach to one of four bases: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The bases pair up with one another (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds, which act like rungs on a ladder. This holds the two strands of DNA together. Also called deoxyribonucleic acid.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The molecule inside cells that contains the genetic information responsible for the development and function of an organism. DNA molecules allow this information to be passed from one generation to the next. DNA is made up of a double-stranded helix held together by weak hydrogen bonds between purine-pyrimidine nucleotide base pairs: adenine (A) paired with thymine (T), and guanine (G) paired with cytosine (C). Also called deoxyribonucleic acid.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000734585" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ADN&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN. En la imagen se muestra un cromosoma, un nucleosoma, una histona, un gen y varios pares de bases nucleotídicas formadas por la unión de guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También se muestra una célula y su núcleo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Estructura del ADN. La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el interior del núcleo de una célula, donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos cadenas que se enroscan y forman un espiral parecido a una escalera de caracol que se llama hélice. Los cuatro componentes básicos del ADN son los nucleótidos: adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C). Los nucleótidos se unen entre sí (A con T y G con C) mediante enlaces químicos y forman pares de bases que conectan las dos cadenas de ADN. Los genes son pequeñas piezas de ADN que tienen información genética específica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN. En la imagen se muestra un cromosoma, un nucleosoma, una histona, un gen y varios pares de bases nucleotídicas formadas por la unión de guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También se observa una célula y su núcleo." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Estructura del ADN. La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el núcleo celular,  donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos cadenas que conforman una estructura helicoidal que se llama hélice. Los nucleótidos adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C) son los cuatro elementos fundamentales del ADN que forman pares de bases (A con T y G con C) mediante enlaces químicos que unen las dos cadenas del ADN. Los genes son segmentos pequeños de ADN que contienen información genética específica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>ADN</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Molécula del interior de las células que contiene la información genética  necesaria para que las personas y la mayoría de organismos se desarrollen y crezcan. Estas moléculas se transmite de una generación a la siguiente. El ADN está compuesto por dos cadenas que se enroscan formando una estructura de doble hélice, como una escalera en  espiral. Cada cadena está formada por una cadena principal (esqueleto) compuesta por moléculas de azúcar y fosfato  que se unen a una de cuatro bases: la adenina (A), la timina (T), la guanina (G) y la citosina (C). Las bases se emparejan entre ellas (A con T y G con C) para formar enlaces químicos que actúan como peldaños de una escalera. Estos peldaños mantienen juntas las dos cadenas del ADN. También se llama ácido desoxirribonucleico y DNA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Molécula del interior de las células que contiene la información genética  responsable del desarrollo y el funcionamiento de un organismo. Estas moléculas son el medio de transmisión de la información genética de una generación a la siguiente. La estructura del ADN es una hélice bicatenaria unida por enlaces de hidrógeno débiles entre los pares de bases nucleotídicas purínicas y pirimidínicas: la adenina (A) se une con la timina (T) y la guanina (G) se une con la citosina (C). También se llama ácido desoxirribonucleico y DNA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2023-07-14</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Deoxyribonucleic-Acid">Deoxyribonucleic Acid (DNA) (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/understanding/basics/dna/ " UseWith="en">What is DNA? (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/ADN-acido-Desoxirribonucleico">ADN (Ácido Desoxirribonucleico) (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/genetica/entender/basica/adn/">¿Qué es el ADN? (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
