<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045680">
  <TermName>epidermal growth factor receptor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(eh-pih-DER-mul grothe FAK-ter reh-SEP-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A protein found on certain types of cells that binds to a substance called epidermal growth factor. The epidermal growth factor receptor protein is involved in cell signaling pathways that control cell division and survival. Sometimes, mutations (changes) in the EGFR gene cause epidermal growth factor receptor proteins to be made in higher than normal amounts on some types of cancer cells. This causes cancer cells to divide more rapidly. Drugs that block epidermal growth factor receptor proteins are being used in the treatment of some types of cancer. Epidermal growth factor receptors are a type of receptor tyrosine kinase. Also called EGFR, ErbB1, and HER1.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermal growth factor receptor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000705776" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Proteína que se encuentra en la superficie de algunas células y que se une al factor de crecimiento epidérmico. La proteína receptora del factor de crecimiento epidérmico participa en las vías de señalización celular que controlan la multiplicación y supervivencia de las células. A veces, las mutaciones en el gen 
      <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName>
       hacen que se produzca una cantidad mayor a la normal de proteínas  receptoras del factor de crecimiento epidérmico en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, lo que hace que estas células se multipliquen más rápido. Los medicamentos que bloquean las proteínas receptoras del factor de crecimiento epidérmico se están usando para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Esta proteína es un tipo de receptor tirosina–cinasa. También se llama EGFR, ErbB1 y HER1.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-08-23</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
