<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045697"><TermName>glial tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GLEE-ul TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of tumors that form in glial cells in the brain and spinal cord. Glial cells support and protect the nerve cells in the central nervous system and help them work the way they should. Glial tumors can form anywhere in the brain or spinal cord and may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). They can also be low grade or high grade, determined by how abnormal the tumor cells look under a microscope and how quickly the tumor is likely to grow, spread, and come back after treatment. The three main types of glial tumors are astrocytomas, oligodendrogliomas, and ependymomas. They can occur in both adults and children. Also called glioma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731178" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;glial tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731179" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor neuroglial&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765034" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the brain; two-panel drawing showing the cerebrum, ventricles (fluid-filled spaces), cerebellum, brain stem (pons and medulla), and spinal cord. Also shown are the meninges and skull (left panel) and the choroid plexus, hypothalamus, pineal gland, pituitary gland, and optic nerve (right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the brain showing the cerebrum, ventricles (with cerebrospinal fluid shown in blue), cerebellum, brain stem (pons and medulla), and other parts of the brain.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765614" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del encéfalo; un dibujo de dos paneles muestra el cerebro, los ventrículos (espacios llenos de líquido), el cerebelo, el tronco encefálico (protuberancia y bulbo raquídeo) y la médula espinal. También se muestra las meninges y el cráneo (panel izquierdo) y el plexo coroideo, el hipotálamo, la glándula pineal, la hipófisis y el nervio óptico (panel derecho)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del encéfalo donde se muestra el cerebro, los ventrículos (con el líquido cefalorraquídeo en azul), el cerebelo, el tronco encefálico (la protuberancia y el bulbo raquídeo) y otras partes del encéfalo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>tumor neuroglial</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de tumores que se forman en las células neurogliales del encéfalo y la médula espinal. Las células neurogliales sostienen y protegen las células nerviosas del sistema nervioso central y ayudan a que funcionen como deben. Los tumores neurogliales se forman en cualquier parte del encéfalo (tumor cerebral) o la médula espinal y son benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). También pueden ser de grado bajo o de grado alto, lo que se determina por el aspecto anormal de las células tumorales al microscopio y la rapidez con que el tumor puede crecer, diseminarse y reaparecer después del tratamiento. Los tres tipos principales de tumor neuroglial son los astrocitomas, los oligodendrogliomas y los ependimomas.  Es posible que se presenten en adultos y niños. También se llama glioma y tumor glial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-06-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cerebro" UseWith="es">Tumores cerebrales</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/brain" UseWith="en">Brain Tumors</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
