<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045696"><TermName>Gleason score</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GLEE-sun...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A way of describing prostate cancer based on how abnormal the cancer cells in a biopsy sample look under a microscope and how quickly they are likely to grow and spread. Most prostate cancers contain cells that are different grades. The Gleason score is calculated by adding together the two grades of cancer cells that make up the largest areas of the biopsied tissue sample. The Gleason score usually ranges from 6 to 10. The lower the Gleason score, the more the cancer cells look like normal cells and are likely to grow and spread slowly. The Gleason score is used to help plan treatment and determine prognosis (outcome).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707097" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Gleason score&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707098" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Puntaje de Gleason&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>puntaje de Gleason</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma de describir el cáncer de próstata según qué tan anormales se ven al microscopio las células cancerosas de una muestra de biopsia, y qué tan probable es que se multipliquen y diseminen. La mayoría de los cánceres de próstata tienen células de diferentes grados. El puntaje de Gleason se calcula al sumar los dos grados de las células cancerosas que componen las áreas más grandes en la muestra de tejido de la biopsia. El puntaje de Gleason por lo general va de 6 a 10. Cuanto más bajo es el puntaje de Gleason, más se parecen las células cancerosas a las células normales, y es más probable que se multipliquen y diseminen de forma lenta. El puntaje de Gleason se usa para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento y determinar el pronóstico (desenlace).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2018-11-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
