<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045718">
  <TermName>hysterectomy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(HIS-teh-REK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Surgery to remove the uterus, and sometimes surrounding organs and tissues. There are several different types of hysterectomy. When only the uterus is removed, it is called a partial hysterectomy. When the uterus and cervix are removed, it is called a total hysterectomy. When the uterus, cervix, part of the vagina, and a wide area of ligaments and tissues around these organs are removed, it is called a radical hysterectomy. These procedures may be done through the vagina (with no incisions in the abdomen) or through an incision (cut) in the abdomen. </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707136" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hysterectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707135" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;histerectomía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>histerectomía</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cirugía para extirpar el útero y, en ocasiones, los órganos y tejidos que lo rodean. Hay varios tipos de histerectomía. Cuando solo se extirpa el útero, se  llama histerectomía parcial. Cuando se extirpan el útero y el cuello uterino, se llama histerectomía total. Cuando se extirpan el útero, el cuello uterino, parte de la vagina y una extensa área de ligamentos y tejidos alrededor de estos órganos, se llama histerectomía radical. Estos procedimientos se pueden realizar a través de la vagina (sin hacer cortes en el abdomen) o a través de una incisión (corte) en el abdomen.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-12-29</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
