<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045746"><TermName>laparoscopic-assisted colectomy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LA-puh-ruh-SKAH-pik-uh-SIS-ted koh-LEK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Surgery done with the aid of a laparoscope to remove all or part of the colon through several small incisions made in the wall of the abdomen. A laparoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing. It may also have a tool to remove tissue to be checked under a microscope for signs of disease. The laparoscope is inserted through one opening to guide the surgery. Surgical instruments are inserted through the other openings to perform the surgery. When only part of the colon is removed, it is called a partial colectomy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707179" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;laparoscopic-assisted colectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707180" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colectomía laparoscópica&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>colectomía laparoscópica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cirugía realizada con la ayuda de un laparoscopio para extraer todo el colon o una parte del mismo a través de varios cortes pequeños en la pared del abdomen. Un laparoscopio es un instrumento delgado con forma de tubo que tiene una luz y un lente para observar. A veces también tiene una herramienta para extraer tejido, que se estudia para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad. El laparoscopio se introduce en el cuerpo a través de un orificio y los otros instrumentos quirúrgicos se introducen por otros orificios. El procedimiento se llama colectomía parcial cuando se extrae solo una parte del colon. También se llama colectomía asistida por laparoscopia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2006-10-03</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
