<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045751"><TermName>LH-RH</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A hormone made by a part of the brain called the hypothalamus. LH-RH causes the pituitary gland in the brain to make and secrete the hormones luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH). In men, these hormones cause the testicles to make testosterone. In women, they cause the ovaries to make estrogen and progesterone. Also called GnRH, gonadotropin-releasing hormone, LHRH, and luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>LH-RH</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hormona elaborada por una parte del encéfalo que se llama hipotálamo. La hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante (LH-RH) hace que la hipófisis elabore y libere la hormona luteinizante  (LH) y la hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH). En los hombres, estas hormonas hacen que los testículos produzcan testosterona. En las mujeres, estas hormonas hacen que los ovarios produzcan estrógeno y progesterona. También se llama GnRH, hormona liberadora de gonadotropina, hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante y LHRH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-03-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/breast-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal-seno" UseWith="es">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de seno</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
