<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045769"><TermName>triptorelin pamoate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TRIP-toh-REH-lin PAM-oh-ayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced prostate cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Triptorelin pamoate initially causes the pituitary gland to make more luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), temporarily increasing testosterone levels in men. With continued use, triptorelin pamoate lowers the amount of LH and FSH the pituitary gland releases, leading to a drop in testosterone levels. Triptorelin pamoate may slow or stop the growth of cancer cells that need testosterone to grow. It is a type of luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist. Also called Trelstar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707212" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;triptorelin pamoate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707213" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pamoato de triptorelina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pamoato de triptorelina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se  usa para el tratamiento del cáncer de próstata avanzado. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Al principio, el pamoato de triptorelina hace que la hipófisis produzca más hormona luteinizante (LH) y hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH), lo que aumenta de forma temporal la concentración de testosterona en los hombres. Con el uso continuo, reduce la cantidad de LH y FSH que libera la hipófisis, lo que causa una caída en la concentración de testosterona. El pamoato de triptorelina en ocasiones reduce o detiene la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan testosterona para su desarrollo. Es un tipo de agonista de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante (LHRH). También se llama Trelstar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2025-01-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
