<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045762">
  <TermName>lymph node</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(limf node)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A small bean-shaped structure that is part of the body’s immune system. Lymph nodes filter substances that travel through the lymphatic fluid, and they contain lymphocytes (white blood cells) that help the body fight infection and disease. There are hundreds of lymph nodes found throughout the body. They are connected to one another by lymph vessels. Clusters of lymph nodes are found in the neck, axilla (underarm), chest, abdomen, and groin. For example, there are about 20-40 lymph nodes in the axilla. Also called lymph gland.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707200" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymph node&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707201" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ganglio linfático&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000661751" type="image/jpeg" alt="Lymphatic system; drawing shows the lymph vessels and lymph organs, including the lymph nodes, tonsils, thymus, spleen, and bone marrow. Also shown is the small intestine (one site of mucosal-associated lymphoid tissue). There are also two pullouts: one showing a close up of the inside structure of a lymph node and the attached artery, vein, and lymph vessels with arrows showing how the lymph (clear, watery fluid) moves into and out of the lymph node, and another showing a close up of bone marrow with blood cells." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">The lymph system is part of the body's immune system and is made up of tissues and organs that help protect the body from infection and disease. These include the tonsils, adenoids (not shown), thymus, spleen, bone marrow, lymph vessels, and lymph nodes. Lymph tissue is also found in many other parts of the body, including the small intestine. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000664393" type="image/jpeg" alt="Sistema linfático. Dibujo de una mujer adulta en el que se observan los vasos y ganglios linfáticos del cuerpo y otros órganos del sistema linfático, como las amígdalas, el timo, el bazo y la médula ósea, así como el tejido linfoide asociado a mucosas que se encuentra en el intestino delgado. En la parte superior izquierda, se observa una ampliación de la estructura interna de un ganglio linfático con una arteria, una vena y vasos linfáticos con flechas que señalan la forma en que la linfa (líquido claro) entra y sale del ganglio linfático. En la parte inferior derecha, en una ampliación del hueso del muslo, se observa la médula ósea con células sanguíneas." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El sistema linfático es una parte del sistema inmunitario y se compone de tejidos y órganos que ayudan a proteger el cuerpo de infecciones y enfermedades. Estos tejidos y órganos son las amígdalas, las adenoides (no se muestran en el dibujo), el timo, el bazo y la médula ósea, los vasos y los ganglios linfáticos. El tejido linfático también se encuentra en muchas otras partes del cuerpo, como el intestino delgado.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>ganglio linfático</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Estructura en forma de frijol que forma parte del sistema inmunitario. Los ganglios linfáticos filtran las sustancias que el líquido linfático transporta y contienen linfocitos (glóbulos blancos) que ayudan a combatir infecciones y enfermedades. En todo el cuerpo hay cientos de ganglios linfáticos conectados entre sí por los vasos linfáticos.  Se encuentran grupos de ganglios linfáticos en el cuello, la axila, el tórax, el abdomen y la ingle. Por ejemplo, en la axila hay entre 20 y 40 ganglios linfáticos. También se llama linfonódulo, nódulo linfático y nódulo linfoide.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-18</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
