<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045771">
  <TermName>malignancy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(muh-LIG-nun-see)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term for
          diseases in which abnormal cells divide without control and
          can invade nearby tissues. Malignant cells
          can also spread to other parts of the body through the
          blood and lymph systems. There are several main types of
          malignancy. Carcinoma is a
          malignancy that begins in the skin or
          in tissues that line or cover internal organs. Sarcoma is a
          malignancy that begins in bone,
          cartilage, fat, muscle, blood vessels, or other connective
          or supportive tissue. Leukemia is a
          malignancy that begins in blood-forming
          tissue, such as the bone marrow, and causes too many
          abnormal blood cells to be made. Lymphoma and multiple
          myeloma are malignancies that begin in the
          cells of the immune system. Central nervous system cancers
          are malignancies that begin in the tissues of
          the brain and spinal cord. Also called cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707215" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;malignancy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707214" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia maligna&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>neoplasia maligna</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que describe las
enfermedades en las que hay células anormales que se
multiplican sin control e invaden los tejidos cercanos. Es
posible que las células de las neoplasias malignas también
se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo a través de los
sistemas sanguíneo y linfático. Hay varios tipos de
neoplasias malignas. El carcinoma
es una neoplasia maligna que empieza en la
piel o en los tejidos que revisten o cubren los órganos
internos. El sarcoma empieza en el hueso, el cartílago, la
grasa, el músculo, los vasos sanguíneos u otro tejido
conjuntivo o de sostén. La leucemia afecta los tejidos
donde se forman las células sanguíneas, como la médula
ósea, y hace que se produzcan muchas células sanguíneas
anormales. El linfoma y el mieloma múltiple afectan las
células del sistema inmunitario. Las neoplasias malignas
del sistema nervioso central empiezan en los tejidos del
encéfalo y la médula espinal. También se llama cáncer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-06-10</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/understanding/what-is-cancer">What
Is Cancer? </RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/naturaleza/que-es/">¿Qué
es el cáncer?</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
