<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045784">
  <TermName>menstrual cycle</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MEN-stroo-ul SY-kul)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The monthly cycle of hormonal changes from the beginning of one menstrual period to the beginning of the next. During the monthly menstrual cycle, the lining of the uterus thickens to prepare for pregnancy. If pregnancy does not occur, estrogen and progesterone hormone levels begin falling. Very low levels of estrogen and progesterone tell the body to begin menstruation (the monthly shedding of blood and tissue from the lining of the uterus). The menstrual cycle usually lasts about 28 days, but this can vary from person to person. It normally starts during puberty and ends at menopause.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707238" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;menstrual cycle&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707239" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ciclo menstrual&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ciclo menstrual</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Secuencia mensual de cambios hormonales que empiezan el primer día de un período menstrual y terminan justo antes del siguiente período. Durante el ciclo menstrual, el tejido que reviste el útero aumenta de grosor en preparación para un posible embarazo. Si no se produce el embarazo, las concentraciones hormonales de estrógeno y progesterona comienzan a disminuir y cuando bajan lo suficiente, le indican al cuerpo que debe comenzar la menstruación (desprendimiento y eliminación normal de sangre y del tejido que reviste el útero). El ciclo menstrual suele durar alrededor de 28 días, pero esto varía de una persona a otra. Por lo general, comienza en la pubertad y termina con la menopausia. También se llama ciclo sexual femenino.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-03-07</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
