<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045796">
  <TermName>myelosuppressive therapy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MY-eh-loh-suh-PREH-siv THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Treatment that stops or slows the growth of blood-forming cells in the bone marrow. Myelosuppressive therapies, such as chemotherapy and radiation therapy, kill normal cells and cancer cells in the bone marrow. This lowers the number of normal red blood cells, white blood cells, and platelets in the blood and bone marrow. Myelosuppressive therapy may be given before a bone marrow or stem cell transplant. It may also be used to treat some blood conditions, such as polycythemia vera (a disease in which there are too many red blood cells in the bone marrow and blood).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707256" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;myelosuppressive therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707257" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia mielodepresora&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>terapia mielodepresora</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tratamiento que impide o hace más lento el crecimiento de células  productoras de sangre en la médula ósea. Las terapias mielodepresoras, como la quimioterapia y la radioterapia, destruyen células normales y células cancerosas en la médula ósea. Esto disminuye el número de glóbulos rojos, glóbulos blancos y plaquetas en la sangre y médula ósea. La terapia mielodepresora se puede administrar antes de un trasplante de médula ósea o de células madre, y también se utiliza para tratar ciertas afecciones de la sangre, como la policitemia vera (una enfermedad en la que hay demasiados glóbulos rojos en la médula ósea y sangre).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2016-09-01</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
