<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045815"><TermName>palliative therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PA-lee-uh-tiv THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Treatment given to help relieve the symptoms and reduce the suffering caused by cancer or other life-threatening diseases. Palliative therapy may help a person feel more comfortable, but it does not treat or cure the disease. For example, surgery, radiation therapy, or chemotherapy may be given to remove, shrink, or slow the growth of a tumor that is causing pain. Palliative therapy may be given with other treatments from the time of diagnosis until the end of life.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707290" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;palliative therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707291" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia paliativa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>terapia paliativa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tratamiento que se brinda para aliviar los síntomas y disminuir el sufrimiento causado por el cáncer y por otras enfermedades potencialmente mortales. Las terapias paliativas quizás ayuden a que las personas se sientan más cómodas, pero no tratan ni curan la enfermedad. Por ejemplo, es posible administrar  cirugía, radioterapia o quimioterapia para extirpar, reducir o hacer más lento el crecimiento de un tumor que  causa dolor. Las terapias paliativas para el cáncer se administran con otros tratamientos desde el momento del diagnóstico hasta la etapa final de la vida. También se llama tratamiento paliativo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2022-03-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/advanced-cancer/care-choices/palliative-care-fact-sheet">Palliative Care in Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/cancer-avanzado/opciones-de-cuidado/hoja-informativa-cuidados-paliativos">Cuidados paliativos durante el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping">Coping with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar">Cómo hacer frente al cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
