<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045851">
  <TermName>prostatectomy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PROS-tuh-TEK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Surgery to remove part or all of the prostate and some of the tissue around it, including the seminal vesicles (a gland that helps make semen). Nearby lymph nodes may also be removed. A prostatectomy may be done through an incision (cut) made in the wall of the lower abdomen or in the perineum (the area between the scrotum and anus). It may also be done using a laparoscope (a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and lens for viewing) or a special robotic system. An attempt is made to protect the nerves that control penile erection and the bladder from damage.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707338" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prostatectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707337" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prostatectomía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>prostatectomía</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cirugía para extirpar toda la próstata o parte de esta y algo del tejido que la rodea, como las vesículas seminales (glándulas que ayudas a producir el semen). A veces, también se extirpan los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. La prostatectomía se hace a través de una incisión (corte) en la pared del abdomen inferior o en el perineo (área entre el escroto y el ano), y en ocasiones se usa un laparoscopio (instrumento delgado en forma de tubo, con una luz y una lente para observar) o un sistema robótico especial. Durante esta cirugía se intentan proteger los nervios que controlan la erección del pene y evitar una lesión en la vejiga.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-06-22</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
