<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045887"><TermName>stage II cervical cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... SER-vih-kul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer has spread to the upper two-thirds of the vagina or to the tissue around the uterus. Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB, based on how far the cancer has spread. In stage IIA, cancer has spread from the cervix to the upper two-thirds of the vagina but has not spread to the tissue around the uterus. Stage IIA is divided into stages IIA1 and IIA2, based on the size of the tumor. In stage IIA1, the tumor is 4 centimeters or smaller. In stage IIA2, the tumor is larger than 4 centimeters. In stage IIB, cancer has spread from the cervix to the tissue around the uterus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707389" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II cervical cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707390" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000658904" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage II cervical cancer; drawing shows two cross-sections of the uterus, cervix, and vagina. The drawing on the left shows stages IIA1 and IIA2 cancer in the cervix that is 4 cm and has spread to the upper two-thirds of the vagina. The drawing on the right shows stage IIB cancer that has spread from the cervix to the tissue around the uterus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage II cervical cancer. In stages IIA1 and IIA2, cancer has spread from the cervix to the upper two-thirds of the vagina but has not spread to the tissue around the uterus. In stage IIA1, the cancer is 4 centimeters or smaller. In stage IIA2, the cancer is larger than 4 centimeters. In stage IIB, cancer has spread from the cervix to the tissue around the uterus.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000729743" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II. En la imagen se observan dos cortes transversales del útero, el cuello uterino y la vagina. En la imagen de la izquierda se muestra cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IIA1 y IIA2, con un tumor que mide 4 cm y se diseminó a los dos tercios superiores de la vagina. En la imagen de la derecha se muestra cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIB que se diseminó del cuello uterino al tejido que rodea el útero." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II. En los estadios IIA1 y IIA2, el cáncer se diseminó del cuello uterino a los dos tercios superiores de la vagina, pero no se diseminó al tejido que rodea el útero. En el estadio IIA1, el tumor mide 4 cm o menos. En el estadio IIA2, el tumor mide más de 4 cm. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se diseminó del cuello uterino al tejido que rodea el útero.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el estadio II, el cáncer se diseminó a los dos tercios superiores de la vagina o al tejido que rodea el útero. El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB, según hasta dónde se diseminó el cáncer. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se diseminó del cuello uterino a los dos tercios superiores de la vagina, pero no se diseminó al tejido que rodea el útero. El estadio IIA se divide en los estadios IIA1 y IIA2, según el tamaño del tumor. En el estadio IIA1, el tumor mide 4 cm o menos. En el estadio IIA2, el tumor mide más de 4 cm. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se diseminó del cuello uterino al tejido que rodea el útero.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-05-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810161" url="/types/cervical/stages">Cervical Cancer Stages</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810526" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/estadios">Estadios del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
