<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045888">
  <TermName>stage III cervical cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... SER-vih-kul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer has spread to the lower third of the vagina, and/or to the pelvic wall, and/or has caused kidney problems, and/or involves lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC, based on how far the cancer has spread. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread to the lower third of the vagina but has not spread to the pelvic wall. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to the pelvic wall and/or  the tumor has become large enough to block one or both ureters (tubes that connect the kidneys to the bladder)  or has caused one or both kidneys to get bigger or stop working. Stage IIIC is divided into stages IIIC1 and IIIC2, based on the spread of cancer to the lymph nodes. In stage IIIC1, cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the pelvis. In stage IIIC2, cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the abdomen near the aorta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707391" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III cervical cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707392" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000670190" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA cervical cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the cervix and vagina. Cancer is shown in the cervix and in the full length of the vagina." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIA cervical cancer. Cancer has spread to the lower third of the vagina but has not spread to the pelvic wall.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000670191" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB cervical cancer; drawing shows cancer in the cervix and pelvic wall. Also shown is cancer blocking the right ureter and an enlarged right ureter and right kidney. The uterus, bladder, and vagina are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIB cervical cancer. Cancer has spread to the pelvic wall and/or the tumor has become large enough to block one or both ureters or has caused one or both kidneys to get bigger or stop working.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800958" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIC cervical cancer; drawing shows stage IIIC1 cancer that has spread from the cervix to lymph nodes in the pelvis and stage IIIC2 cancer that has spread from the cervix to lymph nodes in the abdomen near the aorta." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIIC cervical cancer. In stage IIIC1, cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the pelvis. In stage IIIC2, cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the abdomen near the aorta.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000729744" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIA. En la imagen se observa un corte transversal del cuello uterino y la vagina. Se muestra cáncer en el cuello uterino y a todo lo largo de la vagina." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIA. El cáncer se diseminó al tercio inferior de la vagina, pero no se diseminó a la pared pélvica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000729746" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIB. En la imagen se observa cáncer en el cuello uterino y la pared pélvica. También se muestra cáncer que obstruye el uréter derecho, y agrandamiento del uréter y el riñón derechos. Además, se observan el útero, la vejiga y la vagina." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIB. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: el cáncer se diseminó a la pared pélvica; el tumor se agrandó y obstruye uno o ambos uréteres, o el tumor hace que uno o ambos riñones se agranden o no funcionen.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801647" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIC. En la imagen se observa cáncer en estadio IIIC1 que se diseminó desde el cuello uterino a los ganglios linfáticos de la pelvis, y cáncer en estadio IIIC2 que se diseminó desde el cuello uterino a los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen cercanos a la aorta." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIC. En el estadio IIIC1 el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos de la pelvis. En el estadio IIIC2, el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen cercanos a la aorta.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el estadio III, el cáncer se diseminó al tercio inferior de la vagina o a la pared pélvica, causó problemas de riñón o afectó los ganglios linfáticos.  El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC, según hasta dónde se diseminó el cáncer. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó al tercio inferior de la vagina, pero no se diseminó a la pared pélvica. En el estadio IIIB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: el cáncer se diseminó a la pared pélvica; el tumor se agrandó y obstruye uno o ambos uréteres (tubos que conectan los riñones con la vejiga), o hace que uno o ambos riñones se agranden o no funcionen. El estadio IIIC se divide en los estadios IIIC1 y IIIC2, según la forma en que se diseminó el cáncer a los ganglios linfáticos. En el estadio IIIC1, el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos de la pelvis. En el estadio IIIC2, el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen cercanos a la aorta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-01-06</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810161" url="/types/cervical/stages">Cervical Cancer Stages</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810526" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/estadios">Estadios del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
