<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045886">
  <TermName>stage I cervical cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... SER-vih-kul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer is found in the cervix only. Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB, based on the size of the tumor and the deepest point of tumor invasion. Stage IA is divided into stages IA1 and IA2, based on the deepest point of tumor invasion. In stage IA1, a very small amount of cancer that can only be seen with a microscope is found in the tissues of the cervix. The deepest point of tumor invasion is 3 millimeters or less. In stage IA2, a very small amount of cancer that can only be seen with a microscope is found in the tissues of the cervix. The deepest point of tumor invasion is more than 3 millimeters but not more than 5 millimeters. Stage IB is divided into stages IB1, IB2, and IB3, based on the size of the tumor and the deepest point of tumor invasion. In stage IB1, the tumor is 2 centimeters or smaller and the deepest point of tumor invasion is more than 5 millimeters. In stage IB2, the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 4 centimeters. In stage IB3, the tumor is larger than 4 centimeters.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707388" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I cervical cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707387" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000658902" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IA1 and IA2 cervical cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the cervix and vagina. An inset shows cancer cells in the cervix that can only be seen under a microscope. The cancer in stage IA1 is not more than 3 mm deep. The cancer in stage IA2 is more than 3 but not more than 5 mm deep." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IA1 and IA2 cervical cancer. A very small amount of cancer that can only be seen under a microscope is found in the tissues of the cervix. In stage IA1, the cancer is not more than 3 millimeters deep. In stage IA2, the cancer is more than 3 but not more than 5 millimeters deep.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000658903" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IB1 cervical cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the cervix and vagina and cancer in the cervix that is smaller than 2 cm. An inset shows cancer that is more than 5 mm deep. Also shown is a 2-cm scale that shows 10 mm is equal to 1 cm." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IB1 cervical cancer. The cancer is 2 centimeters or smaller and is more than 5 millimeters deep.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800957" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IB2 and IB3 cervical cancer; drawing shows two cross-sections of the cervix and vagina. The drawing on the left shows stage IB2 cancer in the cervix that is larger than 2 cm but not larger than 4 cm. The drawing on the right shows stage IB3 cancer in the cervix that is larger than 4 cm." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IB2 and IB3 cervical cancer. In stage IB2, the cancer is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 4 centimeters. In stage IB3, the cancer is larger than 4 centimeters. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000729741" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IA1 y IA2. En la imagen se observa un corte transversal del cuello uterino y la vagina. En el recuadro se muestran células cancerosas en el cuello uterino que solo se observan al microscopio. En el estadio IA1 el tumor se diseminó a una profundidad de 3 mm o menos. En el estadio IA2 el tumor se diseminó a una profundidad de más de 3 mm, pero no más de 5 mm." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IA1 y IA2. En los tejidos del cuello uterino se encuentra muy poco cáncer, que solo se observa al microscopio. En el estadio IA1, el tumor se diseminó a una profundidad de 3 mm o menos. En el estadio IA2, el tumor se diseminó a una profundidad de más de 3 mm, pero no más de 5 mm.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000729742" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IB1. En la imagen se observa un corte transversal del cuello uterino y la vagina, y se muestra cáncer en el cuello uterino que mide menos de 2 cm. En el recuadro se muestra cáncer que se diseminó a más de 5 mm de profundidad. También se observa una regla de 2 cm, y que 10 mm equivalen a 1 cm." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IB1. El tumor mide 2 cm o menos y se diseminó a más de 5 mm de profundidad.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801648" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IB2 y IB3. En la imagen se observan dos cortes transversales del cuello uterino y la vagina. En la imagen de la izquierda se muestra cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IB2, y el tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 4 cm. En la imagen de la derecha se muestra cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IB3, y el tumor mide más de 4 cm." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IB2 y IB3. En el estadio IB2, el tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 4 cm. En el estadio IB3, el tumor mide más de 4 cm.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio I</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el estadio I, el cáncer se encuentra solo en el cuello uterino. El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB, según el tamaño del tumor y la profundidad a la que este se diseminó. El estadio IA se divide en los estadios IA1 y IA2, según la profundidad a la que se disemina el tumor. En el estadio IA1, se encuentra muy poco cáncer (solo se observa al microscopio) en el tejido del cuello uterino. El tumor se diseminó a una profundidad de 3 mm o menos. En el estadio IA2, se encuentra muy poco cáncer (solo se observa al microscopio) en el tejido del cuello uterino. El tumor se diseminó a una profundidad de más de 3 mm, pero no más de 5 mm. El estadio IB se divide en los estadios IB1, IB2 y IB3, según el tamaño del tumor y la profundidad a la que este se diseminó. En el estadio IB1, el tumor mide 2 cm o menos y se diseminó a más de 5 mm de profundidad. En el estadio IB2, el tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 4 cm. En el estadio IB3, el tumor mide más de 4 cm.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2020-05-13</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810161" url="/types/cervical/stages">Cervical Cancer Stages</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810526" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/estadios">Estadios del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
