<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045901">
  <TermName>stage III ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... oh-VAYR-ee-un EH-pih-THEE-lee-ul fuh-LOH-pee-in ... PRY-mayr-ee PAYR-ih-toh-NEE-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes, or is primary peritoneal cancer, and has spread outside the pelvis to other parts of the abdomen and/or to nearby lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, one of the following is true: (1) cancer has spread to lymph nodes  behind the peritoneum (tissue that lines the abdominal wall and covers organs in the abdomen) only; or (2) cancer cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum (a fold of the peritoneum that surrounds the stomach and other organs in the abdomen). Cancer may have spread to nearby lymph nodes. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum, and the cancer in the peritoneum is 2 centimeters or smaller. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum. In stage IIIC, cancer has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum, and the cancer in the peritoneum is larger than 2 centimeters. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum or to the surface of the liver or spleen.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707417" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707418" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer epitelial de los ovarios en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000618030" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of stage IIIA shows cancer inside both ovaries that has spread to (a) lymph nodes behind the peritoneum and (b) the omentum. The small intestine, colon, fallopian tubes, uterus, and bladder are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">In stage IIIA, cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and (a) cancer has spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum only, or (b) cancer cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum. Cancer may have also spread to nearby lymph nodes.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000655351" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of stage IIIB shows cancer inside both ovaries that has spread to the omentum. The cancer in the omentum is 2 centimeters or smaller. An inset shows 2 centimeters is about the size of a peanut. Also shown are the small intestine, colon, fallopian tubes, uterus, bladder, and lymph nodes behind the peritoneum." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">In stage IIIB, cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum. The cancer in the omentum is 2 centimeters or smaller. Cancer may have also spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000655353" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of stage IIIC shows cancer inside both ovaries that has spread to the omentum. The cancer in the omentum is larger than 2 centimeters. An inset shows 2 centimeters is about the size of a peanut. Also shown are the small intestine, colon, fallopian tubes, uterus, bladder, and lymph nodes behind the peritoneum." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">In stage IIIC, cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum. The cancer in the omentum is larger than 2 centimeters. Cancer may have also spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum or to the surface of the liver or spleen (not shown).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000659000" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo del cáncer de ovario en estadio IIIA. Se observa el abdomen de una persona y en su interior se muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo marcados con la letra a y células cancerosas en el epiplón marcadas con la letra b. También se señalan el epiplón, el intestino delgado, el colon, una trompa de Falopio, el peritoneo, un ovario, el útero y la vejiga." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="es">En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios o en una o ambas trompas de Falopio y a) el cáncer se diseminó solo a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo, o b)  las células cancerosas que solo son visibles al microscopio, se diseminaron a la superficie del peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, como al epiplón. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000659004" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo del cáncer de ovario en estadio IIIB. Se observa el abdomen de una persona y en su interior se muestran ambos ovarios con cáncer. El cáncer se diseminó al epiplón donde el tumor mide 2 cm o menos; en un recuadro pequeño se compara el tamaño del tumor con el de un maní (cacahuete). También se señalan el epiplón, el intestino delgado, el colon, una trompa de Falopio, el peritoneo, un ovario, el útero y la vejiga." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios o en una o ambas trompas de Falopio y se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, como al epiplón; el cáncer en el epiplón mide 2 cm o menos. También es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000659006" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo del cáncer de ovario en estadio IIIC. Se observa el abdomen de una persona y en su interior se muestran ambos ovarios con cáncer. El cáncer se diseminó al epiplón donde el tumor mide más de 2 cm; en un recuadro pequeño se compara el tamaño del tumor con el de un maní (cacahuete). También se señalan el epiplón, el intestino delgado, el colon, una trompa de Falopio, el peritoneo, un ovario, el útero y la vejiga." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios o en una o ambas trompas de Falopio y se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, como al epiplón. El cáncer en el epiplón mide más de 2 cm. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo, o a la superficie del hígado o el bazo (no se muestra).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompas de Falopio y primario de peritoneo en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios o  en una o ambas trompas de Falopio, o es cáncer primario de peritoneo que se diseminó fuera de la pelvis a otras partes del abdomen o a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB, y  IIIC. En el estadio lllA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones:  1) el cáncer se diseminó solo a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del  peritoneo (tejido que reviste la pared abdominal y cubre órganos del abdomen);  2) las células cancerosas, que solo son visibles al microscopio, se diseminaron a la superficie del peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, como al epiplón (pliegue del peritoneo que rodea el estómago y otros órganos del abdomen).  Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. En el estadio lllB, el cáncer se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, como al epiplón, y el cáncer en el peritoneo mide 2 cm o menos. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás de peritoneo. En el estadio lllC, el cáncer se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, como al epiplón, y el cáncer del peritoneo mide más de 2 centímetros. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo, o a la superficie del  hígado o  el bazo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-07-05</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062963" url="/types/ovarian/patient/ovarian-epithelial-treatment-pdq">Ovarian Epithelial, Fallopian Tube, and Primary Peritoneal Cancers Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256785" url="/espanol/tipos/ovario/paciente/tratamiento-epitelial-ovario-pdq">Tratamiento de los cánceres epitelial de ovario, de trompas de Falopio y primario de peritoneo</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
