<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045962"><TermName>central venous access catheter</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SEN-trul VEE-nus AK-ses KA-theh-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to draw blood and give treatments, including intravenous fluids, drugs, or blood transfusions.  A thin, flexible tube is inserted into a vein, usually below the collarbone. It is guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava.   A needle is inserted into a port outside of the body to draw blood or give fluids.  A central venous access catheter may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks. There are several types of central venous access catheters.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707514" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;central venous access catheter&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707513" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;catéter central de acceso venoso&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000756806" type="image/jpeg" alt="Central venous catheter; drawing of a central venous catheter that goes from a vein below the right collarbone to a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. An inset shows a central venous catheter in the right side of the chest with a clear plastic dressing over it." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Central venous catheter. A central venous catheter is a thin, flexible tube that is inserted into a vein, usually below the right collarbone, and guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. It is used to give intravenous fluids, blood transfusions, chemotherapy, and other drugs. The catheter is also used for taking blood samples. It may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774006" type="image/jpeg" alt="Catéter venoso central. En el dibujo del tronco de un joven, se señala el corazón y la vena cava superior. Al lado derecho del corazón, se observa un catéter venoso central que va desde una vena debajo de la clavícula hasta la vena cava superior, que es una vena grande que se conecta con el corazón. En una ampliación, se muestra el catéter venoso central en el lado derecho del tórax cubierto por un apósito plástico transparente." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Catéter venoso central. Tubo delgado y flexible que se introduce en una vena, por lo general, debajo de la clavícula derecha, y se pasa hasta la vena cava superior, que es una vena grande que se conecta con el corazón. El catéter venoso central se usa para administrar líquidos intravenosos, transfusiones de sangre, quimioterapia y otros medicamentos. También se usa para extraer muestras de sangre. El catéter se puede dejar colocado durante semanas o meses para evitar la necesidad de pinchazos múltiples.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>catéter central de acceso venoso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para extraer sangre y administrar tratamientos, como líquidos intravenosos, medicamentos o transfusiones de sangre. Se introduce un tubo delgado y flexible en una vena, por lo general debajo de la clavícula. Luego se pasa el tubo hasta una vena grande en el lado superior derecho del corazón, llamada vena cava superior. Se introduce una aguja en un extremo del catéter fuera del cuerpo para extraer sangre o administrar líquidos. Un catéter central de acceso venoso en ocasiones se deja colocado durante semanas o meses para evitar los pinchazos múltiples. Hay varios tipos de catéteres centrales de acceso venoso. También se llama cánula venosa central, catéter venoso central y vía venosa central.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
