<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045989"><TermName>colposcopy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kol-POS-koh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a lighted, magnifying instrument called a colposcope is used to examine the cervix, vagina, and vulva. During colposcopy, an instrument called a speculum is inserted into the vagina to widen it so that the cervix can be seen more easily. A vinegar solution may be used to make abnormal tissue easier to see with the colposcope. Tissue samples may be taken using a spoon-shaped instrument called a curette and checked under a microscope for signs of disease. Colposcopy may be used to check for cancers of the cervix, vagina, and vulva, and changes that may lead to cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707549" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colposcopy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707550" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colposcopia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colposcopia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa un instrumento con una lente de aumento y una luz que se llama colposcopio a fin de examinar el cuello del útero, la vagina y la vulva. Durante la colposcopia, se coloca en la vagina un espéculo para abrirla y observar con mayor facilidad el cuello del útero.  A veces, se usa una solución de vinagre para ver mejor el tejido anormal con el colposcopio. Es posible extraer muestras de tejido con una herramienta en forma de cuchara que se llama cureta; las muestras se observan al microscopio para verificar si hay signos de enfermedad. La colposcopia se usa para encontrar cáncer en el cuello del útero, la vagina y la vulva, y cambios en el tejido que tal vez se conviertan en cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-01-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810192" url="/types/cervical/screening/abnormal-hpv-pap-test-results">HPV and Pap Test Results: Next Steps after an Abnormal Cervical Cancer Screening Test</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810505" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion/resultados-anormales-pruebas-vph-pap">Resultados anormales de las pruebas del VPH y de Pap para la detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
