<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045996">
  <TermName>mammography</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ma-MAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An imaging method that uses low-dose x-rays to create detailed pictures of the breast. It is used to detect cancer and other breast conditions. During the exam, the breasts are positioned one at a time between an x-ray plate and a plastic compression plate. Each breast is gently pressed between the plates to spread the breast tissue for a clearer image. Images are taken from different angles. Mammography is the most common screening test for breast cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707558" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mammography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707557" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mamografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000711008" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of a woman standing with her left breast pressed between two plates of a mammography machine. Behind her, a health professional uses an X-ray machine to take pictures of the breast. An inset shows the X-ray film image with an arrow pointed at abnormal tissue." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Mammography is an imaging test used to screen for and diagnose breast cancer. It can detect abnormal breast tissue, including cancer, sometimes before symptoms appear.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000749373" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo se observa una mujer de pie con la mama izquierda presionada entre dos placas de un mamógrafo.(máquina para hacer mamografías). Detrás de la mujer, una profesional de la salud utiliza una máquina de rayos X para obtener imágenes de la mama. En un recuadro, se muestra la imagen radiográfica y se señala con una flecha el tejido anormal." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="es">La mamografía es una prueba por imágenes que se usa para examinar la mama y diagnosticar el cáncer. Sirve para detectar tejido anormal en la mama, como cáncer, en ocasiones incluso antes de que aparezcan síntomas.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>mamografía</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Método de diagnóstico por imágenes en el que se utilizan rayos X de dosis baja con el fin de crear imágenes detalladas de la mama (seno). Se usa para detectar el cáncer y otras afecciones mamarias. Durante el examen, se coloca una de las mamas entre una placa de rayos X y una placa de compresión de plástico. La mama se presiona suavemente entre las placas para extender el tejido mamario y obtener imágenes  más nítidas desde diferentes ángulos. La mamografía es el examen de detección más común para el cáncer de mama. También se llama mastografía.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2025-05-07</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
