<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460127"><TermName>Ashkenazi Jews</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ASH-keh-NAH-zee jooz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of two major ancestral groups of Jewish people whose ancestors lived in France and Central and Eastern Europe, including Germany, Poland, and Russia. The other group is called Sephardic Jews and includes those whose ancestors lived in Spain, Portugal, North Africa, and the Middle East. Most Jewish people living in the United States are of Ashkenazi descent. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of two major ancestral groups of Jewish people whose ancestors lived in France and Central and Eastern Europe, including Germany, Poland, and Russia. The other group is called Sephardic Jews and includes those whose ancestors lived in Spain, Portugal, North Africa, and the Middle East. Most Jewish people living in the United States are of Ashkenazi descent. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736929" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Ashkenazi Jews&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802510" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;judíos asquenazíes&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>judíos asquenazíes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Uno de los dos principales grupos ancestrales de personas judías, cuyos antepasados vivieron en  Francia o Europa Central y Oriental, como  Alemania, Polonia y Rusia. El otro grupo es el de los judíos sefardíes, cuyos antepasados vivieron en España, Portugal, norte de África y Oriente Medio. La mayoría de los judíos que viven
           en los Estados Unidos son de ascendencia asquenazí.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Uno de los dos principales grupos ancestrales de personas judías, cuyos antepasados habitaron Francia o Europa Central y Oriental, como Alemania, Polonia y Rusia. El otro grupo es el de los judíos sefardíes, cuyos antepasados habitaron España, Portugal, norte de África y Oriente Medio. La mayoría de los judíos que residen en los Estados Unidos son de ascendencia asquenazí.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
