<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460151">
  <TermName>fluorescence in situ hybridization</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(floor-EH-sents in SY-too HY-brih-dih-ZAY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A laboratory method used to look at genes or chromosomes in cells and tissues. Pieces of DNA that contain a fluorescent dye are made in the laboratory and added to a cell or tissue sample. When these pieces of DNA bind to certain genes or areas on chromosomes in the sample, they light up when viewed under a microscope with a special light. FISH can be used to identify where a specific gene is located on a chromosome, how many copies of the gene are present, and any chromosomal abnormalities. It is used to help diagnose diseases, such as cancer, and help plan treatment. Also called FISH.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A technique used to identify the presence of specific chromosomes or chromosomal regions through hybridization (attachment) of fluorescently-labeled DNA probes to denatured chromosomal DNA. Examination through a microscope under fluorescent lighting detects the presence or absence of the colored hybridized signal, hence the presence or absence of the chromosome material. Also called FISH.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716967" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fluorescence in situ hybridization&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716966" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hibridación fluorescente in situ&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hibridación fluorescente in situ</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Técnica  de laboratorio que se usa para observar los genes o los cromosomas en las células y los tejidos. En el laboratorio, se preparan trozos de ADN con un tinte fluorescente que se agregan a una muestra de células o tejidos. Cuando se observan al microscopio con una luz especial, estos trozos de ADN brillan si se unen a genes o áreas específicas de los cromosomas en la muestra. La técnica FISH se puede usar para identificar la ubicación de un gen específico en un cromosoma, el número de copias del gen o cualquier anormalidad en los cromosomas. Sirve para diagnosticar enfermedades, como el cáncer, y para planificar el tratamiento. También se llama FISH e hibridación in situ con sondas fluorescentes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Técnica que se usa para identificar la presencia de cromosomas o regiones cromosómicas  específicas mediante la hibridación (unión) de sondas de ADN marcadas con fluorescencia al ADN cromosómico desnaturalizado. El examen al microscopio con luz fluorescente permite detectar la presencia o ausencia de la señal coloreada de la hibridación, y por lo tanto, la presencia o ausencia del material cromosómico. También se llama FISH e hibridación in situ con sondas fluorescentes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-07-23</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Fluorescence-In-Situ-Hybridization">Fluorescence In Situ Hybridization (FISH) (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Hibridacion-fluorescente-in-situ">Hibridación fluorescente in situ (FISH) (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
