<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460197">
  <TermName>mosaicism</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(moh-ZAY-ih-SIH-zum)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The occurrence of 2 or more cell lines with different genetic or chromosomal make-up, within a single individual or tissue.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which some cells or tissues in a person’s body have a different genetic or chromosomal makeup than those in the rest of the body. Mosaicism is caused by a genetic change that occurs during cell division. This can happen during embryo development or after birth. Mosaicism can affect a large number of cells or only a few cells. It may or may not cause disease. </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000736973" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mosaicism&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804230" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mosaicismo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mosaicismo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Presencia simultánea de dos o más líneas celulares con diferente composición genética o cromosómica en un solo individuo o tejido.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Anomalía en la que algunas células o tejidos tienen una composición genética o cromosómica diferente a la del resto del cuerpo. La causa del mosaicismo es un cambio genético que ocurre durante la división celular, ya sea durante el desarrollo embrionario (en el embarazo) o después del nacimiento. El mosaicismo puede afectar un gran número de células o solo unas pocas y no siempre produce enfermedad.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/001317.htm" UseWith="en">Mosaicism (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001317.htm" UseWith="es">Mosaicismo (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
