<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460208"><TermName>predisposing mutation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PREE-dih-SPOH-zing myoo-TAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A genetic alteration that increases an individual’s susceptibility or predisposition to a certain disease or disorder. When such a variant (or mutation) is inherited, development of symptoms is more likely, but not certain.  Also called deleterious mutation, disease-causing mutation, pathogenic variant, and susceptibility gene mutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A change in the DNA sequence of a gene that causes a person to have or be at risk of developing a certain genetic disorder or disease, such as cancer. Predisposing mutations can be inherited from a parent or occur during a person’s lifetime. Knowing if a person has a predisposing mutation may help prevent, diagnose, and treat diseases, such as cancer. Not everyone who has a predisposing mutation will develop the disease. Also called deleterious mutation, disease-causing mutation, pathogenic variant, and susceptibility gene mutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736981" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;predisposing mutation&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804237" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mutación predisponente&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mutación predisponente</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Alteración genética que aumenta la susceptibilidad o predisposición de la persona a padecer  ciertas enfermedades o trastornos. Cuando se hereda esta variante o mutación, es más probable que se presenten síntomas, aunque esto no es seguro. También se llama mutación causal de enfermedad, mutación deletérea, mutación en gen de susceptibilidad, variante de predisposición y variante patogénica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio en la secuencia de ADN de un gen que hace que una persona tenga, o esté en riesgo de presentar determinadas enfermedades o trastornos genéticos, como el cáncer. Es posible heredar una mutación predisponente de uno de los padres o que se produzca durante la vida de una persona. Conocer si una persona tiene una mutación predisponente tal vez ayude a prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar enfermedades, como el cáncer. No todas las personas que tienen una mutación predisponente presentarán la enfermedad. También se llama mutación causal de enfermedad, mutación deletérea, mutación en gen de susceptibilidad, variante de predisposición y variante patogénica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
