<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460201">
  <TermName>nucleotide</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(NOO-klee-oh-tide)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A building block for nucleic acids (the molecules inside cells that carry genetic information). Nucleotides are attached end-to-end to form the nucleic acids DNA and RNA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A molecule that is the basic building block of the nucleic acids DNA and RNA. A nucleotide is made up of a nitrogen-containing base (adenine, guanine, thymine, and cytosine in DNA, and adenine, guanine, uracil, and cytosine in RNA), a phosphate group, and a sugar molecule (deoxyribose in DNA, and ribose in RNA). DNA and RNA are polymers made up of many nucleotides.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000717049" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nucleotide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000717048" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nucleótido&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN. En la imagen se muestra un cromosoma, un nucleosoma, una histona, un gen y varios pares de bases nucleotídicas formadas por la unión de guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También se muestra una célula y su núcleo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Estructura del ADN. La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el interior del núcleo de una célula, donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos cadenas que se enroscan y forman un espiral parecido a una escalera de caracol que se llama hélice. Los cuatro componentes básicos del ADN son los nucleótidos: adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C). Los nucleótidos se unen entre sí (A con T y G con C) mediante enlaces químicos y forman pares de bases que conectan las dos cadenas de ADN. Los genes son pequeñas piezas de ADN que tienen información genética específica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN. En la imagen se muestra un cromosoma, un nucleosoma, una histona, un gen y varios pares de bases nucleotídicas formadas por la unión de guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También se observa una célula y su núcleo." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Estructura del ADN. La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el núcleo celular,  donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos cadenas que conforman una estructura helicoidal que se llama hélice. Los nucleótidos adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C) son los cuatro elementos fundamentales del ADN que forman pares de bases (A con T y G con C) mediante enlaces químicos que unen las dos cadenas del ADN. Los genes son segmentos pequeños de ADN que contienen información genética específica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>nucleótido</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Elemento fundamental de los ácidos nucleicos (las moléculas del interior de las células que transmiten información genética). Los nucleótidos están unidos por sus extremos para formar los ácidos nucleicos ADN y ARN. También se llama mononucleótido.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Molécula que constituye el componente básico de los ácidos nucleicos ADN y ARN. Un nucleótido está formado por una base nitrogenada (adenina, guanina, timina o citosina en el ADN; adenina, guanina, uracilo o citosina en el ARN), un grupo fosfato y una molécula de azúcar (desoxirribosa en el ADN; ribosa en el ARN). El ADN y el ARN son polímeros compuestos por muchos nucleótidos. También se llama mononucleótido.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2015-02-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Nucleotide">Nucleotide (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Nucleotido">Nucleótido (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
