<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046022">
  <TermName>adenoid cystic carcinoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(A-deh-noyd SIS-tik KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare type of cancer that begins in cells that line certain internal organs and make and release substances in the body, such as mucus, saliva, or other fluids. Adenoid cystic carcinoma occurs most often in the salivary glands, but it can also occur in other parts of the body, such as the voice box, windpipe, lacrimal gland (the gland that makes tears), breast, and uterus. Adenoid cystic carcinoma usually grows slowly. It tends to spread along the nerves to nearby tissue and in the blood.  In rare cases, it may spread to the lymph nodes or to other parts of the body, especially the lungs.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707600" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenoid cystic carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707599" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma adenoide quístico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma adenoide quístico</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo raro de cáncer que comienza en las células que revisten ciertos órganos internos. Estas células elaboran y liberan sustancias, como moco, saliva u otros líquidos. El carcinoma adenoide quístico se forma por lo general en las glándulas salivales, pero a veces se presenta en otras partes del cuerpo, como la laringe, la tráquea, la glándula lagrimal (glándula que produce las lágrimas), la mama y el útero. El carcinoma adenoide quístico, por lo común, es de crecimiento lento. Tiende a diseminarse, a través de los nervios, a los tejidos cercanos y a la sangre.  En raras ocasiones, se disemina a los ganglios linfáticos o a otras partes del cuerpo, en especial a los pulmones. También se llama adenocarcinoma quístico, carcinoma adenoquístico y carcinoma quístico adenoide.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2021-12-30</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
