<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460221"><TermName>translation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(trans-LAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In biology, the process by which a cell makes proteins using the genetic information carried in messenger RNA (mRNA). The mRNA is made by copying DNA, and the information it carries tells the cell how to link amino acids together to form proteins.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The process of
          synthesizing an amino acid sequence (protein product) from
          the messenger RNA (mRNA) code.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000717060" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;translation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000717061" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;traducción&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761782" type="image/jpeg" alt="Transcription and translation; the top part of the drawing shows transcription occurring in the nucleus of a cell: a piece of DNA that codes for a specific gene is copied into mRNA; bases in the copied DNA, adenine (A), cytosine (C), guanine (G), and thymine (T), form specific pairs with the bases in the mRNA, except adenine (A) in the DNA pairs with uracil (U) in the mRNA (also shown is a sequence of 3 bases called a codon in the mRNA); the mRNA then carries the genetic information from the DNA to the cytoplasm. The bottom part of the drawing shows translation occurring in the cytoplasm of a cell: the mRNA attaches to and passes through the ribosome; tRNA carries an amino acid to the ribosome, where it binds to a matching codon sequence in the mRNA; the amino acid joins with the other amino acids to form a growing protein chain; the completed protein is then released from the ribosome." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Transcription and translation are processes a cell uses to make all proteins the body needs to function from information stored in the sequence of bases in DNA. The four bases (C, A, T/U, and G in the figure) are the building blocks of DNA and RNA. During transcription, a piece of DNA that codes for a specific gene is copied into messenger RNA (mRNA) in the nucleus of the cell. The mRNA then carries the genetic information from the DNA to the cytoplasm, where translation occurs. During translation, proteins are made using the information stored in the mRNA sequence. The mRNA attaches to a structure called a ribosome that can read the genetic information. As the mRNA passes through the ribosome, another type of RNA called transfer RNA (tRNA) carries a protein building block called an amino acid to the ribosome. The tRNA carrying the amino acid binds to a matching sequence in the mRNA. As each tRNA binds to the mRNA strand, the amino acid it carried joins with the other amino acids to form a chain of amino acids. Once all of the amino acids coded for in the piece of mRNA have been linked, the completed protein is released from the ribosome. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761782" type="image/jpeg" alt="Transcription and translation; the top part of the drawing shows transcription occurring in the nucleus of a cell: a piece of DNA that codes for a specific gene is copied into mRNA; bases in the copied DNA, adenine (A), cytosine (C), guanine (G), and thymine (T), form specific pairs with the bases in the mRNA, except adenine (A) in the DNA pairs with uracil (U) in the mRNA (also shown is a sequence of 3 bases called a codon in the mRNA); the mRNA then carries the genetic information from the DNA to the cytoplasm. The bottom part of the drawing shows translation occurring in the cytoplasm of a cell: the mRNA attaches to and passes through the ribosome; tRNA carries an amino acid to the ribosome, where it binds to a matching codon sequence in the mRNA; the amino acid joins with the other amino acids to form a growing protein chain; the completed protein is then released from the ribosome." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_7"><Caption language="en">Transcription and translation are processes a cell uses to make all proteins the body needs to function from information stored in the sequence of bases in DNA. The four bases (C, A, T/U, and G in the figure) are the building blocks of DNA and RNA. During transcription, a piece of DNA that codes for a specific gene is copied into messenger RNA (mRNA) in the nucleus of the cell. The mRNA then carries the genetic information from the DNA to the cytoplasm, where translation occurs. During translation, proteins are made using the information stored in the mRNA sequence. The mRNA attaches to a structure called a ribosome that can read the genetic information. As the mRNA passes through the ribosome, another type of RNA called transfer RNA (tRNA) carries a protein building block called an amino acid to the ribosome. The tRNA carrying the amino acid binds to a matching sequence in the mRNA. As each tRNA binds to the mRNA strand, the amino acid it carried joins with the other amino acids to form a chain of amino acids. Once all of the amino acids coded for in the piece of mRNA have been linked, the completed protein is released from the ribosome. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791096" type="image/jpeg" alt="Transcripción y traducción. En la parte superior de la figura se observa la transcripción en el núcleo de la célula: una porción de ADN que codifica un gen específico se copia en un ARNm. Las bases del ADN copiado, adenina (A), citosina (C), guanina (G) y timina (T), forman pares específicos con las bases del ARNm; excepto la adenina (A) del ADN que forma par con el uracilo (U) del ARNm (también se muestra una secuencia de 3 bases en el ARNm que se llama codón). Luego, el ARNm lleva la información genética del ADN al citoplasma. En la parte inferior de la figura se muestra la traducción en el citoplasma de la célula: el ARNm se une al ribosoma y pasa a través de este, a su vez el ARNt lleva un aminoácido hacia el ribosoma en donde se une a un codón de la secuencia compatible de ARNm, este aminoácido se une a otros aminoácidos para formar una cadena de proteína que crece poco a poco hasta que la proteína completa se desprende del ribosoma." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="es">La transcripción y traducción son procesos que la célula usa para elaborar todas las proteínas que el cuerpo necesita para funcionar a partir de la información almacenada en las secuencias de bases del ADN. Las cuatro bases (C, A, T/U y G de la figura) son los bloques que componen el ADN y el ARN. Durante la transcripción, una porción de ADN que codifica un gen específico se copia  en un ARN mensajero (ARNm) en el núcleo de la célula. Luego, el ARNm lleva la información genética del ADN al citoplasma, en donde ocurre la traducción. Durante la traducción, se elaboran las proteínas usando la información almacenada en la secuencia de ARNm. El ARNm se une a una estructura llamada ribosoma que puede leer la información genética. A medida que el ARNm pasa a través del ribosoma, otro tipo de ARN llamado ARN de transferencia (ARNt) lleva hacia el ribosoma los bloques que forman las proteínas, llamado aminoácidos. El ARNt que lleva el aminoácido se une a una secuencia de ARNm compatible. A medida que cada ARNt se une con la cadena de ARNm, el aminoácido que lleva se enlaza con los otros aminoácidos para formar una cadena de aminoácidos. Cuando todos los aminoácidos codificados en una porción de ARNm se han unido, la proteína completa se desprende del ribosoma.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791096" type="image/jpeg" alt="Transcripción y traducción. En la parte superior de la figura se observa la transcripción en el núcleo de la célula: una porción de ADN que codifica un gen específico se copia en un ARNm. Las bases del ADN copiado, adenina (A), citosina (C), guanina (G) y timina (T), forman pares específicos con las bases del ARNm; excepto la adenina (A) del ADN que forma par con el uracilo (U) del ARNm (también se muestra una secuencia de 3 bases en el ARNm que se llama codón). Luego, el ARNm lleva la información genética del ADN al citoplasma. En la parte inferior de la figura se muestra la traducción en el citoplasma de la célula: el ARNm se une al ribosoma y pasa a través de este, a su vez el ARNt lleva un aminoácido hacia el ribosoma en donde se une a un codón de la secuencia compatible de ARNm, este aminoácido se une a otros aminoácidos para formar una cadena de proteína que crece poco a poco hasta que la proteína completa se desprende del ribosoma." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_9"><Caption language="es">La transcripción y traducción son procesos que la célula usa para elaborar todas las proteínas que el cuerpo necesita para funcionar, a partir de la información almacenada en las secuencias de bases del ADN. Las cuatro bases (C, A, T/U y G de la figura) son los bloques que componen el ADN y el ARN. Durante la transcripción, una porción de ADN que codifica un gen específico se copia  en un ARN mensajero (ARNm) en el núcleo de la célula. Luego, el ARNm lleva la información genética del ADN al citoplasma, en donde ocurre la traducción. Durante la traducción, se elaboran las proteínas usando la información almacenada en la secuencia de ARNm. El ARNm se une a una estructura llamada ribosoma que puede leer la información genética. A medida que el ARNm pasa a través del ribosoma, otro tipo de ARN llamado ARN de transferencia (ARNt) lleva hacia el ribosoma los bloques que forman las proteínas, llamado aminoácidos. El ARNt que lleva el aminoácido se une a una secuencia de ARNm compatible. A medida que cada ARNt se une con la cadena de ARNm, el aminoácido que lleva se enlaza con los otros aminoácidos para formar una cadena de aminoácidos. Cuando todos los aminoácidos codificados en una porción de ARNm se han unido, la proteína completa se desprende del ribosoma.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>traducción</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la biología, es el proceso por el cual una célula elabora proteínas usando la información genética que lleva el ARN mensajero (ARNm). El ARNm se produce al copiar el ADN y la información que lleva le indica a la célula cómo enlazar juntos los aminoácidos para formar proteínas.  También se llama traslación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso de síntesis de una secuencia de aminoácidos (producto proteico) a partir del código del RNA mensajero (mRNA). También se llama traslación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2017-09-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Translation">Translation (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Traduccion">Traducción (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
