<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046032">
  <TermName>echocardiography</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(EH-koh-KAR-dee-AH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that uses high-energy sound waves (ultrasound) to look at tissues and organs inside the chest. Echoes from the sound waves form a picture of the size, shape, and position of the heart on a computer screen (echocardiogram). The pictures can also show the parts of the inside of the heart, such as the valves, and the motion of the heart while it is beating. Echocardiography may be used to help diagnose heart problems, such as abnormal heart valves and heart rhythms, heart murmurs, and damage to the heart muscle from a heart attack. It may also be used to check for an infection on or around the heart valves, blood clots or tumors inside the heart, and fluid buildup in the sac around the heart.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708045" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;echocardiography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708046" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ecocardiografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ecocardiografía</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usan ondas de sonido de alta energía (ultrasónicas) para observar tejidos y órganos internos del pecho. Los ecos de las ondas de sonido forman una imagen del tamaño, la forma y la posición del corazón en una pantalla de computadora (ecocardiograma). Las imágenes también muestran partes del interior del corazón, como las válvulas, y el movimiento del corazón mientras está latiendo. Una ecocardiografía se usa para diagnosticar problemas cardíacos, como válvulas y ritmos anormales, soplos y daño en el músculo del corazón por un infarto. También se usa para determinar si hay una infección en las válvulas  cardíacas o alrededor de estas, coágulos de sangre o tumores dentro del corazón, o una acumulación de líquido en la bolsa que rodea este órgano.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2016-10-21</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
