<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046066"><TermName>monoclonal antibody</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MAH-noh-KLOH-nul AN-tee-BAH-dee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of protein that is made in the laboratory and can bind to certain targets in the body, such as antigens on the surface of cancer cells. There are many kinds of monoclonal antibodies, and each monoclonal antibody is made so that it binds to only one antigen. Monoclonal antibodies are being used in the diagnosis and treatment of many diseases, including some types of cancer. They can be used alone or to carry drugs, toxins, or radioactive substances directly to cancer cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708093" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;monoclonal antibody&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708094" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anticuerpo monoclonal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><EmbeddedVideo id="_3" ref="CDR0000801837" hosting="youtube" unique_id="dxnjAc-rqz8" language="en" audience="Patients" template="Video75NoTitle"><VideoTitle>How Monoclonal Antibodies Treat
          Cancer</VideoTitle><Caption language="en">How do  monoclonal antibodies work to treat cancer? This video shows how monoclonal antibodies, such as trastuzumab, pembrolizumab, and rituximab, block molecules cancer cells need to grow, flag cancer cells for destruction by the body’s immune system, or deliver harmful substances to cancer cells. </Caption></EmbeddedVideo><EmbeddedVideo id="_4" ref="CDR0000802012" hosting="youtube" unique_id="YvzxnnwZD9c" language="es" audience="Patients" template="Video75NoTitle"><VideoTitle>Tratamiento del cáncer con anticuerpos monoclonales</VideoTitle><Caption language="es">¿Cómo funcionan los anticuerpos monoclonales para tratar el cáncer?  En este video se explica cómo los anticuerpos monoclonales como el trastuzumab, el pembrolizumab y el rituximab bloquean moléculas que las células cancerosas necesitan para multiplicarse, marcan células cancerosas para que el sistema inmunitario las destruya o transportan sustancias que dañan estas células.</Caption></EmbeddedVideo><SpanishTermName>anticuerpo monoclonal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de proteína elaborada en
el laboratorio que se une a ciertas dianas en el
cuerpo, como los antígenos de la superficie de las células
cancerosas. Hay muchos tipos de anticuerpos monoclonales, y cada anticuerpo monoclonal se produce para unirse a un antígeno específico único. Los anticuerpos monoclonales se usan para el diagnóstico y tratamiento de muchas enfermedades, incluso algunos tipos de cáncer. Se
utilizan solos o para
transportar medicamentos, toxinas o sustancias radiactivas
directamente a las células cancerosas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-11-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/immunotherapy/monoclonal-antibodies">Monoclonal
Antibodies</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/inmunoterapia/anticuerpos-monoclonales">Anticuerpos
monoclonales</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
