<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046061"><TermName>pharynx</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FAYR-inx)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The hollow, muscular tube inside the neck that starts behind the nose and opens into the larynx and esophagus. It includes the nasopharynx (the upper part of the pharynx behind the nose), the oropharynx (the middle part of the pharynx), and the hypopharynx (the bottom part of the pharynx). The pharynx acts as a passageway for air to enter the larynx and lungs and food and liquid to enter the esophagus.  It also plays a role in speech. The pharynx is about 5 inches long, depending on body size.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708086" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pharynx&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708085" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;faringe&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713970" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the pharynx; drawing shows the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx. Also shown are the nasal cavity, oral cavity, hyoid bone, larynx, esophagus, and trachea." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the pharynx. The pharynx is a hollow, muscular tube inside the neck that starts behind the nose and opens into the larynx and esophagus. The three parts of the pharynx are the nasopharynx, oropharynx, and hypopharynx.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732292" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la faringe. En el dibujo se observan la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe. También se muestran la cavidad nasal, la cavidad oral, el hioides, la laringe, el esófago y la tráquea." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la faringe. La faringe es un tubo muscular hueco dentro del cuello que comienza detrás de la nariz y se comunica con la laringe y el esófago. Las tres partes de la faringe son la nasofaringe, la orofaringe y la hipofaringe.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>faringe</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tubo muscular hueco dentro del cuello que comienza detrás de la nariz y se comunica con la laringe y el esófago. Incluye la nasofaringe (parte superior de la faringe detrás de la nariz), la orofaringe (parte media de la faringe) y la hipofaringe (parte inferior de la faringe). La faringe es un conducto por donde pasa el aire a la laringe y los pulmones,  y pasan  los alimentos y bebidas al esófago. También cumple una función en el habla. Mide cerca de 5 pulgadas de largo, dependiendo del tamaño de la persona.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2023-06-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/head-and-neck">Head and Neck Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello">Cáncer de cabeza y cuello</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
