<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046078">
  <TermName>continuous hyperthermic peritoneal perfusion</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(kon-TIN-yoo-us HY-per-THER-mik PAYR-ih-toh-NEE-ul per-FYOO-zhun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A treatment used during surgery in which a heated solution containing anticancer drugs is infused directly into the abdominal cavity through a thin tube. After removal of as much tumor tissue as possible with surgery, continuous hyperthermic peritoneal perfusion is given to kill any remaining tumor cells. It is most often used to treat cancers that have spread to the peritoneum (the lining of the abdominal cavity). Also called CHPP, HIPEC, and hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708110" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;continuous hyperthermic peritoneal perfusion&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708109" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;perfusión peritoneal hipertérmica continua&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>perfusión peritoneal hipertérmica continua</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tratamiento que se usa durante una cirugía para aplicar medicamentos contra el cáncer directamente en la cavidad abdominal. Después de extirpar la mayor cantidad posible de tejido tumoral durante la cirugía, se coloca un tubo delgado en la cavidad abdominal por donde se hace pasar una solución caliente que contiene los medicamentos contra el cáncer. La perfusión peritoneal hipertérmica continua se administra para destruir cualquier célula tumoral que haya quedado. Se utiliza con más frecuencia para el tratamiento de cánceres que se diseminaron al peritoneo (tejido que reviste la cavidad abdominal). También se llama CHPP, HIPEC y quimioterapia intraperitoneal hipertérmica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-08-05</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
