<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046091"><TermName>xeroderma pigmentosum</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ZEER-oh-DER-ma pig-men-TOH-sum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare inherited disorder marked by an extreme sensitivity to ultraviolet light, such as from the sun, and a high risk of developing cancer. The signs and symptoms of xeroderma pigmentosum are usually seen in children by age 2 years. Affected children may develop a severe blistering sunburn after a short time in the sun, freckling of the skin, dry skin, and changes in skin color in sun-exposed areas. They may also develop eye problems and problems with the nervous system. People with xeroderma pigmentosum have a very high risk of developing skin cancer, usually by age 10 years, and other types of cancer, including cancers of the eyes, brain, and, in smokers, the lungs. Xeroderma pigmentosum is caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes involved in repairing damaged DNA. Also called XP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707659" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;xeroderma pigmentosum&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;xeroderma pigmentoso&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>xeroderma pigmentoso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro caracterizado por una extrema sensibilidad a los rayos ultravioleta, como los del sol, y un riesgo alto de cáncer. Los signos y síntomas del xeroderma pigmentoso a menudo se observan a los 2 años de edad. Es posible que estos niños sufran quemaduras graves y ampollas después de exponerse al sol por periodos cortos; además, la piel expuesta se vuelve pecosa, seca y cambia de color. A veces,  también tienen alteraciones en la vista y el sistema nervioso. Las personas con esta afección tienen un riesgo muy alto de presentar cáncer de piel, por lo general a los 10 años de edad, así como otros tipos de cáncer,  como cáncer de ojo, de encéfalo  y, en el caso de los fumadores, de pulmón. La causa del xeroderma pigmentoso son mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que participan en la reparación del daño al ADN. También se llama xeroderma pigmentario, xerodermia pigmentosa y XP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7910/xeroderma-pigmentosum">Xeroderma pigmentosum (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/xeroderma-pigmentosum/">Xeroderma pigmentosum (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13707/xeroderma-pigmentoso">Xeroderma pigmentoso (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001467.htm">Xerodermia pigmentosa (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
