<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046101"><TermName>stage III hypopharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... HY-poh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor (1) is larger than 4 centimeters or has spread to the larynx (voice box) or the mucosa (inner lining) of the esophagus. Cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor. The affected lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor. The affected lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller. Cancer is also found (a) in only one area of the hypopharynx and/or the tumor is 2 centimeters or smaller; or (b) in more than one area of the hypopharynx or in a nearby area, or the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 4 centimeters and has not spread to the larynx.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III hypopharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de hipofaringe en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de hipofaringe en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el estadio III, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor mide más de 4 cm o se diseminó a la laringe o la mucosa (revestimiento interior) del esófago. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor. El ganglio linfático afectado mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado de la cabeza o el cuello que el tumor. El ganglio linfático afectado mide 3 cm o menos. Además, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) se encuentra cáncer solo en un área de la hipofaringe y el tumor mide 2 cm o menos; b) se encuentra cáncer en más de un área de la hipofaringe o en un área cercana a esta, o el tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 4 cm, y no se diseminó a la laringe.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-09-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258014" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/hypopharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Hypopharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256820" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-hipofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de hipofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
