<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046129">
  <TermName>genetic marker</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(jeh-NEH-tik MAR-ker)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A specific sequence of DNA at a known location on a chromosome. There are many genetic markers on each chromosome. Genetic markers and genes that are close to each other on a chromosome are usually inherited (passed from parent to child) together. This may help researchers find a gene near a marker that may cause a certain disease or trait within a family. Examples of genetic markers are single polymorphism nucleotides (SNPs) and microsatellites.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A sequence of DNA with a known physical location on a chromosome. Genetic markers and genes that are close to each other on a chromosome tend to be inherited together. Genetic markers vary between individuals to the extent that they can be used to help find a nearby gene causing a certain disease or trait within a family. Examples of genetic markers are single polymorphism nucleotides (SNPs), restriction fragment length polymorphisms (RFLPs), variable number of tandem repeats (VNTRs), microsatellites, and copy number variants (CNVs). Genetic markers may or may not have a known function.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707719" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genetic marker&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707718" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;marcador genético&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>marcador genético</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Secuencia específica de ADN para la que se conoce su ubicación en un cromosoma. Hay muchos marcadores genéticos en cada cromosoma. Por lo general, los marcadores genéticos y los genes que están cerca entre sí en un cromosoma se heredan (pasan de padres a hijos) juntos . A veces, esto ayuda a los investigadores a encontrar un gen cerca de un marcador que quizás sea la causa de determinada enfermedad o rasgo en una familia. Los polimorfismos de nucleótido simple (SNP) y los microsatélites son ejemplos de marcadores genéticos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Secuencia de ADN para la que se conoce su ubicación en un cromosoma. Los marcadores genéticos y los genes que están cerca entre sí en un cromosoma tienden a heredarse juntos. Los marcadores genéticos varían entre las personas, hasta el punto de que es posible utilizarlos para ayudar a encontrar un gen cercano causal de determinada enfermedad o rasgo en una familia. Algunos ejemplos de marcadores genéticos son los   polimorfismos de nucleótido simple (SNP), los polimorfismos de longitud de los fragmentos de restricción (RFLP), las repeticiones en tándem de número variable (VNTR), los microsatélites y las variaciones en el número de copias (CNV). Es posible que los marcadores genéticos tengan o no una función conocida.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2016-09-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Genetic-Marker">Genetic Marker (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Marcador-genetico">Marcador genético (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
