<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046122">
  <TermName>stage III vulvar cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... VUL-ver KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The tumor is any size and has spread to the upper two-thirds of the urethra, the upper two-thirds of the vagina, the inner lining of the bladder or rectum, or to any number of lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, cancer is found in lymph nodes in the groin that are not larger than 5 millimeters. In stage IIIB, cancer is found in lymph nodes in the groin that are larger than 5 millimeters. In stage IIIC, cancer is found in lymph nodes in the groin and has extended through the outer covering of the lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707708" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III vulvar cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vulva en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de vulva en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a los dos tercios superiores de la uretra, los dos tercios superiores de la vagina, el revestimiento interno de la vejiga o el recto, o hasta los ganglios linfáticos. El estadio III se divide en los estadios  IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, se encuentra cáncer en ganglios linfáticos de la ingle, y estos miden 5 mm o menos. En el estadio IIIB, se encuentra cáncer en ganglios linfáticos de la ingle, y estos miden más de 5 mm. En el estadio IIIC, se encuentra cáncer en ganglios linfáticos de la ingle y el cáncer se diseminó a la superficie externa de los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2022-01-13</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000419665" url="/types/vulvar/patient/vulvar-treatment-pdq">Vulvar Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000452963" url="/espanol/tipos/vulva/paciente/tratamiento-vulva-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de vulva</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
