<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046128"><TermName>genetic testing</TermName><TermPronunciation>(jeh-NEH-tik TES-ting)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory method that looks for changes in genes, gene expression, or chromosomes in a person’s cells or tissues. Genetic testing may be done to look for inherited changes in a person's genes that may be a sign that the person has an increased risk of developing a specific disease or condition or of having a child or other family member with the disease or condition. This type of genetic testing is called germline testing. Genetic testing is also done on tumor tissue to look for genetic changes in the cancer cells. These changes occur during a person’s lifetime and are not inherited from a parent. This type of genetic testing, called somatic testing, is done to learn more about the cancer, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working.  Also called genetic analysis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707717" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genetic testing&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707716" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba genética&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba genética</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método de laboratorio con  el que se buscan cambios en los genes, en la expresión de los genes o en los cromosomas de las células o tejidos de una persona.  Las pruebas genéticas se hacen para encontrar cambios hereditarios en los genes que podrían ser un signo de aumento del riesgo de presentar una enfermedad o afección específica, de transmitir  (pasar) este cambio a los hijos e hijas, o de tener familiares con la misma enfermedad o afección. Este tipo de  o de la línea germinal. Las pruebas genéticas también se hacen en tejidos tumorales para identificar cambios genéticos en las células cancerosas. Estos cambios ocurren durante la vida de la persona y no son heredados del padre o la madre. Este tipo de  y son útiles para ayudar a comprender mejor el cáncer, planificar el tratamiento o determinar qué tan bien está funcionando el tratamiento. También se llama análisis genético y examen genético.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-11-01</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/risk-assessment-pdq" UseWith="en">Cancer Genetics Risk Assessment and Counseling (Health Professional Version)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/evaluacion-del-riesgo-pdq" UseWith="es">Evaluación del riesgo de cáncer y asesoramiento genético (Versión para profesionales de salud)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
