<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046131">
  <TermName>craniopharyngioma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KRAY-nee-oh-fuh-RIN-jee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, benign (not cancer) brain tumor that usually forms near the pituitary gland and the hypothalamus. Craniopharyngiomas are slow-growing and do not spread to other parts of the brain or to other parts of the body.  However, they may grow and press on nearby parts of the brain, including the pituitary gland, hypothalamus, optic chiasm, optic nerves, and fluid-filled spaces in the brain. This may cause problems with growth, vision, and making certain hormones. Craniopharyngiomas usually occur in children and young adults.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707723" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;craniopharyngioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707722" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;craneofaringioma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000803629" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the inside of the brain showing where craniopharyngiomas may form. A pullout shows a tumor between the hypothalamus and the optic chiasm. Also shown is the optic nerve, the pituitary gland, and the sphenoid sinus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Craniopharyngiomas are rare brain tumors that usually form near the pituitary gland and the hypothalamus. They are benign (not cancer) and do not spread to other parts of the brain or to other parts of the body. However, they may grow and press on nearby parts of the brain, including the pituitary gland, optic chiasm, and optic nerve. Craniopharyngiomas usually occur in children and young adults.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000803763" type="image/jpeg" alt="Imagen del interior del encéfalo en la que se muestra dónde se forman los craneofaringiomas. En el recuadro se observa un tumor entre el hipotálamo y el quiasma óptico. También se muestran el nervio óptico, la hipófisis y el seno esfenoidal." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Los craneofaringiomas son tumores de encéfalo raros que a menudo se forman cerca de la hipófisis y del hipotálamo. Son benignos (no cancerosos) y no se diseminan a otras partes del encéfalo o del cuerpo. Sin embargo, es posible que crezcan y presionen partes cercanas del encéfalo, como la hipófisis, el quiasma óptico o el nervio óptico. Los craneofaringiomas por lo general se presentan en niños y adultos jóvenes.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>craneofaringioma</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor de encéfalo benigno (no canceroso) y raro, que a menudo se forma cerca de la hipófisis y el hipotálamo. Los craneofaringiomas crecen lentamente y no se diseminan a otras partes del encéfalo o del cuerpo. Sin embargo, estos tumores pueden crecer y presionar partes cercanas del encéfalo, como la hipófisis, el hipotálamo, el quiasma óptico, los nervios ópticos y los espacios llenos de líquido del encéfalo. Esto puede causar problemas de crecimiento, visuales y de producción de ciertas hormonas. Los craneofaringiomas, por lo general, se presentan en niños y adultos jóvenes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2021-01-05</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000574137" url="/types/brain/patient/child-cranio-treatment-pdq">Childhood Craniopharyngioma </RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000632970" url="/espanol/tipos/cerebro/paciente/tratamiento-craneo-infantil-pdq">Craneofaringioma infantil</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
