<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046133"><TermName>cervix</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vix)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The lower, narrow end of the uterus (womb) that connects the uterus to the vagina (birth canal). The cervix allows fluids, such as menstrual blood, to pass from the uterus into the vagina. It also widens during the birth of a baby. The cervix has two main parts, the ectocervix and the endocervix. The ectocervix is the outer part of the cervix that can be seen during a pelvic exam. The endocervix is the inner part of the cervix that forms a canal that connects the vagina to the uterus. The area where the endocervix and ectocervix come together is called the squamocolumnar junction (also called the transformation zone). Most abnormal cell changes and cervical cancers begin in the squamous cells (thin, flat-looking cells under a microscope) of the squamocolumnar junction.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707727" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervix&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707726" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cuello uterino&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000609921" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the female reproductive system; drawing shows the uterus, myometrium (muscular outer layer of the uterus), endometrium (inner lining of the uterus), ovaries, fallopian tubes, cervix, and vagina." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the female reproductive system. The organs in the female reproductive system include the uterus, ovaries, fallopian tubes, cervix, and vagina. The uterus has a muscular outer layer called the myometrium and an inner lining called the endometrium. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000810405" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the anatomy of the cervix showing the internal OS, endocervical canal, endocervix, ectocervix, and external OS. The uterus and vagina are also shown. There is also a pullout that shows a close up of the squamocolumnar junction (the area where the endocervix and ectocervix meet) and the cells that line the endocervix and ectocervix." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the cervix. The cervix is the lower, narrow end of the uterus that connects the uterus to the vagina. It is made up of the internal OS (the opening between the cervix and the upper part of the uterus), the endocervix (the inner part of the cervix that forms the endocervical canal), the ectocervix (the outer part of the cervix that opens into the vagina) and the external OS (the opening between the cervix and vagina). The area where the endocervix and ectocervix meet is called the squamocolumnar junction, which contains both glandular cells (column-shaped cells that make mucus) from the endocervix and squamous cells (thin, flat cells) from the ectocervix. The squamocolumnar junction is sometimes  referred to as the transformation zone.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000650412" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del aparato reproductor femenino. En el dibujo de una mujer adulta se señalan el útero, el miometrio, que es la capa muscular externa del útero; el endometrio, que es la capa de tejido interno que reviste el útero; los ovarios, las trompas de Falopio, el cuello uterino y la vagina." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del aparato reproductor femenino. Los órganos del aparato reproductor femenino incluyen el útero, los ovarios, las trompas de Falopio, el cuello uterino y la vagina. El útero tiene una capa muscular externa llamada miometrio y una capa de tejido interno llamada endometrio.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812204" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo se observan las aracterísticas anatómicas del cuello uterino. Se muestran el orificio interno, el conducto endocervical, el endocérvix, el ectocérvix y el orificio externo. También se observan el útero y la vagina. Además, en un recuadro se muestra una vista de cerca de la unión escamocolumnar (área donde el endocérvix se une al ectocérvix) y las células que revisten el endocérvix y el ectocérvix." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Características anatómicas del cuello uterino. El cuello uterino es la porción final, inferior y estrecha del útero que conecta al útero con la vagina. Está formado por el orificio interno (abertura entre el cuello uterino y la parte superior del útero), el endocérvix (parte interna del cuello uterino que forma el conducto endocervical), el ectocérvix (parte externa del cuello uterino que se conecta con la vagina) y el orificio externo (abertura entre el cuello uterino y la vagina). El área donde el endocérvix se une al ectocérvix se llama unión escamocolumnar, y contiene células glandulares (células en forma de columna que elaboran moco) del endocérvix y células escamosas (células delgadas y planas) del ectocérvix. La unión escamocolumnar también se conoce como zona de transformación.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cuello uterino</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Extremo final y estrecho del útero (matriz) que conecta el útero y la vagina (canal del parto). El cuello uterino permite que los fluidos, como la sangre menstrual, pasen del útero a la vagina, y se ensancha durante el parto. El cuello uterino consta de dos partes principales: el ectocérvix y el endocérvix. El ectocérvix es la parte externa del cuello uterino que se ve durante un examen pélvico. El endocérvix es la parte interna del cuello uterino que forma un canal que conecta la vagina con el útero. El área donde se unen el endocérvix y el ectocérvix se llama unión escamocolumnar (también recibe el nombre de zona de transformación). La mayoría de los cambios celulares anormales y cánceres de cuello uterino comienzan en las células escamosas (células delgadas y de aspecto plano al microscopio) de la unión escamocolumnar. También se llama cérvix uterino y cuello del útero.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2023-07-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810146" url="/types/cervical">What Is Cervical Cancer?</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810430" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino">¿Qué es el cáncer de cuello uterino?</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
