<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046179">
  <TermName>stage II nasopharyngeal cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...NAY-zoh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>One of the following is true: (1) cancer has spread to one or more lymph nodes on one side of the neck and/or to one or more lymph nodes on one or both sides of the back of the throat. The affected lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller. Cancer is found in the nasopharynx only, or has spread from the nasopharynx to the oropharynx and/or to the nasal cavity,  or is found only in the lymph nodes in the neck.  The cancer cells in the lymph nodes are infected with Epstein-Barr virus (a virus linked to nasopharyngeal cancer); or  (2) cancer has spread to the parapharyngeal space (area near the pharynx, between the base of the skull and the lower jaw) and/or to nearby muscles. Cancer may have also spread to one or more lymph nodes on one side of the neck and/or to one or more lymph nodes on one or both sides of the back of the throat. The affected lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707792" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II nasopharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707793" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el estadio II, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de un lado del cuello, o a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados de la parte posterior de la garganta. Los ganglios afectados miden 6 cm o menos. El cáncer solo se encuentra en la nasofaringe o se diseminó de la nasofaringe a la orofaringe o la cavidad nasal; o el cáncer solo se encuentra en los ganglios linfáticos del cuello. Las células cancerosas en los ganglios linfáticos están infectadas por el virus de Epstein-Barr (un virus que se relaciona con el cáncer de nasofaringe). 2) El cáncer se diseminó al espacio parafaríngeo (área cerca de la faringe, entre la base del cráneo y la mandíbula inferior) o a los músculos cercanos. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de un lado del cuello, o a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados de la parte posterior de la garganta. Los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden 6 cm o menos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2019-04-10</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062966" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/nasopharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Nasopharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256817" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-nasofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de nasofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
