<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046171"><TermName>screening</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SKREE-ning)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Checking for disease in individuals who have no symptoms. Since screening may find diseases at an early stage, there may be a better chance of curing the disease. Screening may also include genetic testing to check for an individual's risk of developing an inherited disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Checking for disease when there are no symptoms. Since screening may find diseases at an early stage, there may be a better chance of curing the disease. Examples of cancer screening tests are the mammogram (for breast cancer), colonoscopy (for colon cancer), and the Pap test and HPV tests (for cervical cancer). Screening can also include doing a genetic test to check for a person’s risk of developing an inherited disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707780" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;screening&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707781" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;detección sistemática&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>detección sistemática</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Verificación de la presencia de una enfermedad cuando no hay síntomas. Dado que la detección sistemática permite encontrar enfermedades en estadio temprano, es posible que la probabilidad de curar la enfermedad sea mayor. Algunos ejemplos de exámenes de detección del cáncer son la mamografía (para el cáncer de mama), la colonoscopia (para el cáncer de colon), o la prueba de Papanicolaou y las pruebas del VPH (para el cáncer de cuello uterino).  A veces, la detección sistemática también incluye pruebas genéticas para determinar el riesgo de una persona de presentar una enfermedad hereditaria. También se llama cribado, cribaje, despistaje, pesquisa, pesquisaje, tamizado y tamizaje.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Verificación de la presencia de una enfermedad cuando no hay síntomas. Dado que  la detección sistemática permite encontrar enfermedades en estadio temprano, es posible que la probabilidad de curar la enfermedad sea mayor. A veces, la detección sistemática también incluye pruebas genéticas para determinar el riesgo de una persona de presentar una enfermedad hereditaria. También se llama cribado, cribaje, despistaje, pesquisa, pesquisaje, tamizado y tamizaje.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2018-01-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/screening">Cancer Screening</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq/information-summaries/screening">PDQ® Cancer Information Summaries: Screening/Detection (Testing for Cancer)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/deteccion">Exámenes de detección del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq/sumarios-de-informacion/deteccion">Sumarios del PDQ® de información sobre el cáncer: Exámenes de detección de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
