<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046181"><TermName>stage IV nasopharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...NAY-zoh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV nasopharyngeal cancer is divided into stages IVA and IVB. In stage IVA, (1) cancer has spread to the brain, the cranial nerves, the hypopharynx, the salivary gland in the front of the ear, the bone around the eye, and/or the soft tissues of the jaw. Cancer may have also spread to one or more lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck and/or the back of the throat. The affected lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer has spread to one or more lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck. The affected lymph nodes are larger than 6 centimeters and/or are found in the lowest part of the neck. In stage IVB, cancer has spread beyond the lymph nodes in the neck to distant lymph nodes, such as those between the lungs, below the collarbone, or in the armpit or groin, or to other parts of the body, such as the lung, bone, or liver.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707796" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV nasopharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707797" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA y IVB. En el estadio IVA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó al encéfalo, los nervios del cráneo, la hipofaringe, las glándulas salivales delante de los oídos, el hueso que rodea los ojos o el tejido blando de la mandíbula. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuello, o a la parte posterior de la garganta. Los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden 6 cm o menos. 2) El cáncer se diseminó a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuello. Los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden más de 6 cm o se encuentran en la parte más inferior del cuello. En el estadio IVB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó fuera de los ganglios linfáticos del cuello a ganglios linfáticos lejanos, como los que  están entre los pulmones, debajo de la clavícula, en la axila o la ingle. 2) El cáncer se diseminó a otras partes partes del cuerpo, como los pulmones, los huesos o el hígado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2019-04-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062966" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/nasopharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Nasopharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256817" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-nasofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de nasofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
