<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046215"><TermName>acute nonlymphocytic leukemia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-KYOOT non-LIM-foh-SIH-tik loo-KEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A fast-growing cancer in which too many myeloblasts (a type of immature white blood cell) are found in the bone marrow and blood. Acute nonlymphocytic leukemia usually gets worse quickly if it is not treated. It can spread outside the blood to other parts of the body, including the lymph nodes, spleen, liver, central nervous system (brain and spinal cord), skin, gums, and testicles. Acute nonlymphocytic leukemia is most common in older adults.  Also called acute myelogenous leukemia, acute myeloid leukemia, AML, and ANLL.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707844" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acute nonlymphocytic leukemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707845" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leucemia no linfocítica aguda&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>leucemia no linfocítica aguda</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer de crecimiento rápido por el que se encuentran demasiados mieloblastos (tipo de glóbulo blanco inmaduro) en la médula ósea y la sangre. La leucemia no linfocítica aguda, por lo general, empeora rápido si no se trata. A veces se disemina fuera de la sangre a otras partes del cuerpo, como los ganglios linfáticos, el bazo, el hígado, el sistema nervioso central (encéfalo y médula espinal), la piel, las encías y los testículos. La leucemia no linfocítica aguda es más común en adultos mayores. También se llama leucemia mielógena aguda, leucemia mieloide aguda, leucemia no linfoblástica aguda, LMA y LNLA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-12-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/leukemia">Leukemia</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/leucemia">Leucemia</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
