<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046235"><TermName>pernicious anemia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(per-NIH-shus uh-NEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which the body is unable to properly absorb vitamin B12, leading to a lower-than-normal number of red blood cells in the body. Vitamin B12 binds to a protein in the stomach called intrinsic factor. This allows vitamin B12 to be absorbed in the small intestine and then released into the bloodstream. Pernicious anemia occurs when there is too little intrinsic factor to bind enough vitamin B12 for it to be used by the body to make red blood cells. In most cases, this happens when the body’s immune system attacks the intrinsic factor protein or the cells in the lining of the stomach that make it. It may also occur in people with atrophic gastritis, a condition marked by chronic inflammation and thinning of the inner lining of the stomach. If not treated, pernicious anemia can lead to serious problems, including damage to the nervous system. People with pernicious anemia may have an increased risk of stomach cancer, gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors, or some other types of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707882" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pernicious anemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707881" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anemia perniciosa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>anemia perniciosa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que el cuerpo es incapaz de absorber de forma correcta la vitamina B12, lo que produce un número de glóbulos rojos inferior al normal. La vitamina B12 se une a una proteína del estómago llamada factor intrínseco. Esto permite que la vitamina B12 se absorba en el intestino delgado y luego se libere en el torrente sanguíneo. La anemia perniciosa se produce cuando hay muy poco factor intrínseco que fije suficiente vitamina B12 para que el cuerpo la utilice en la elaboración de glóbulos rojos. En la mayoría de los casos, esto ocurre cuando el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo ataca a la proteína del factor intrínseco o a las células del revestimiento del estómago que la elaboran. También es posible que se presente en personas con gastritis atrófica, una enfermedad caracterizada por la inflamación crónica y el adelgazamiento del revestimiento interno del estómago. Si no se trata, la anemia perniciosa puede producir problemas graves, como daño al sistema nervioso. Las personas con anemia perniciosa quizás tengan un mayor riesgo de presentar cáncer de estómago, tumores neuroendocrinos gastrointestinales o algunos otros tipos de cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2023-06-23</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
