<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046246">
  <TermName>pelvis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PEL-vus)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The bones between the lower abdomen and upper thighs that connect the spine to the legs. The pelvis supports upper body weight, aids balance and walking, and protects the bladder, reproductive organs, colon, and rectum. The pelvis can also describe the pelvic region, or the area of the body below the abdomen that contains the hip bones, bladder, and rectum. In females, it also contains the vagina, cervix, uterus, fallopian tubes, and ovaries. In males, it also contains the prostate and seminal vesicles.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707904" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pelvis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000707903" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pelvis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816808" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing showing the anatomy of the male pelvis (left panel) and female pelvis (right panel). Both panels show the pelvis, rectum, hip joint, and bladder. Also shown are the seminal vesicles and prostate (left panel), and the vagina, cervix, uterus, ovaries, and fallopian tubes (right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">The pelvis is the area of the body below the abdomen that contains the hip bones, bladder, and rectum. In females, it also contains the vagina, cervix, uterus, fallopian tubes, and ovaries. In males, it also contains the prostate and seminal vesicles.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817880" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo de dos paneles se observan las características anatómicas de la pelvis y se señalan la pelvis, el recto, la articulación de la cadera y la vejiga. En el panel de la izquierda se muestra la pelvis de un hombre y se señalan las vesículas seminales y la próstata. En el panel de la derecha se muestra la pelvis de una mujer y se señalan la vagina, el cuello uterino, los ovarios y las trompas de Falopio." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">La pelvis es el área del cuerpo debajo del abdomen donde se encuentran los huesos ilíacos (huesos de la cadera), la vejiga y el recto. En los hombres, la pelvis también contiene la próstata y las vesículas seminales. En las mujeres, la pelvis también contiene la vagina, el cuello uterino, las trompas de Falopio y los ovarios.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>pelvis</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Huesos que se encuentran entre el abdomen inferior y la parte superior de los muslos que conectan la columna vertebral con las piernas. La pelvis sostiene el peso de la parte superior del cuerpo, ayuda al equilibrio y a caminar, y protege la vejiga, los órganos reproductivos, el colon y el recto. El término pelvis a veces también describe la región pélvica, o el área del cuerpo debajo del abdomen   que contiene los huesos ilíacos de la cadera, la vejiga y el recto. En las mujeres, también contiene la vagina, el cuello uterino, el útero, las trompas de Falopio y los ovarios. En los hombres, contiene la próstata y las vesículas seminales.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2025-04-08</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
