<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046259"><TermName>oncogene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ON-koh-jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A mutated (changed) form of a type of gene called a proto-oncogene, which is involved in normal cell growth and division. When a proto-oncogene is changed so that too many copies are made or it becomes more active than normal, it is called an oncogene. Oncogenes may cause normal cells to become cancer cells and grow in the body. Mutations that lead to the conversion of proto-oncogenes to oncogenes usually occur during a person’s lifetime and are not inherited from a parent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707923" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oncogene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707924" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oncogén&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>oncogén</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma mutada (cambiada) de un tipo de gen llamado protooncogén. El protooncogén participa en la multiplicación y división celular normal. Cuando este gen cambia, por ejemplo, cuando se hacen demasiadas copias o presenta una mayor actividad a la usual, se le llama oncogén. Es posible que los oncogenes causen que las células normales se conviertan en células cancerosas que se multiplican en el cuerpo. Las mutaciones que producen la conversión de protooncogenes a oncogenes, por lo general, ocurren durante la vida de una persona y no se heredan de los padres.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2022-07-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Oncogene">Oncogene (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Oncogen">Oncogén (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
