<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046282"><TermName>monocyte</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MAH-noh-site)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of immune cell that is made in the bone marrow and travels through the blood to tissues in the body where it becomes a macrophage or a dendritic cell. Macrophages surround and kill microorganisms, ingest foreign material, remove dead cells, and boost immune responses. During inflammation, dendritic cells boost immune responses by showing antigens on their surface to other cells of the immune system. A monocyte is a type of white blood cell and a type of phagocyte.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707967" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;monocyte&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707968" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;monocito&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000503952" type="image/jpeg" alt="Blood cells; drawing shows six types of white blood cells (monocytes, lymphocytes, neutrophils, eosinophils, basophils, and macrophages), a red blood cell (erythrocyte), and platelets." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Blood cells. Blood contains many types of cells: white blood cells (monocytes, lymphocytes, neutrophils, eosinophils, basophils, and macrophages), red blood cells (erythrocytes), and platelets. Blood circulates through the body in the arteries and veins.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000553586" type="image/jpeg" alt="Células sanguíneas; el dibujo muestra seis tipos de glóbulos blancos (monolitos, linfocitos, neutrófilos, eosinófilos, basófilos y macrófagos), un glóbulo rojo (eritrocito) y plaquetas." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Células sanguíneas. La sangre contiene muchos tipos de células: glóbulos blancos (monolitos, linfocitos, neutrófilos, eosinófilos, basófilos y macrófagos), glóbulos rojos (eritrocitos) y plaquetas. La sangre circula por el cuerpo a través de las arterias y las venas.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>monocito</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de célula inmunitaria que se elabora en la médula ósea y viaja por la sangre hasta los tejidos del cuerpo, donde se convierte en un macrófago o una célula dendrítica.   Los macrófagos rodean y destruyen los microorganismos, ingieren el material extraño, eliminan las células muertas y estimulan las respuestas inmunitarias.   Durante un proceso inflamatorio, las células dendríticas estimulan las respuestas inmunitarias al llevar los antígenos en su superficie y presentarlos a otras células del sistema inmunitario. Un monocito es un tipo de glóbulo blanco y de fagocito.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-05-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
