<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046345">
  <TermName>internal radiation therapy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(in-TER-nul RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Internal radiation therapy is a form of radiation therapy where a sealed radioactive source is inserted into a body cavity, into a tumor directly, into tissue, or applied to the surface. This delivers a very high dose locally with a rapid fall-off of dose in the surrounding tissue.  Internal radiation therapy can be done using several high-dose insertions (high-dose rate or HDR), leaving the source in place for many hours (low-dose rate or LDR), or leaving the source in permanently. Pulsed-dose rate (PDR) internal radiation therapy is an internal radiation therapy technique that combines the advantages of HDR technology of dose optimization and radiation safety with radiobiological advantages of LDR internal radiation therapy.</DefinitionText>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of radiation therapy in which a source of radiation is put inside the body. Brachytherapy is a type internal radiation therapy that involves placing radioactive implants, such as pellets, seeds, ribbons, wires, needles, balloons, or capsules, in the body, directly into or near the tumor. Systemic radiation therapy is a type of internal radiation therapy that uses a source of radiation that is swallowed or injected into the body and travels through the blood, finding and killing tumor cells throughout the body.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708580" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;internal radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708579" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia interna&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>radioterapia interna</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma de radioterapia para la que se coloca una fuente de radiación en el interior del cuerpo. La braquiterapia es un tipo de radioterapia interna en la que se administra la radiación en el cuerpo colocando implantes radioactivos, como gránulos, semillas, cintas, alambres, agujas, globos o cápsulas directamente en el tumor o cerca de este. La radioterapia sistémica es otro tipo de radioterapia interna en la que se  utiliza una fuente de radiación que se ingiere o se inyecta en el cuerpo y viaja por la sangre, para encontrar y destruir las células tumorales en todo el organismo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma de radioterapia  para la que se usa una fuente sellada de radiación que se introduce en una cavidad corporal, directamente en un tumor, en el tejido o se aplica sobre una superficie. Con este procedimiento se administra locamente una dosis muy alta de radiación que disminuye rápido en el tejido circundante.  La  radioterapia interna se administra mediante varios implantes de dosis altas, un solo implante que se  deja en el lugar durante muchas horas (tasa de dosis bajas), o un implante permanente. La radioterapia interna de dosis pulsada  es una técnica que combina las ventajas de los implantes de dosis altas (optimización de la dosis e inocuidad)  con las ventajas radiobiológicas de la radioterapia interna de tasa de dosis bajas.</DefinitionText>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2025-03-27</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/radiation-therapy/brachytherapy?redirect=true">Brachytherapy to Treat Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/radioterapia/interna">Braquiterapia para tratar el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
