<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000463717">
  <TermName>medication</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MEH-dih-KAY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A dosage form that contains one or more active and/or inactive ingredients. Medications come in many dosage forms, including tablets, capsules, liquids, creams, and patches. They can also be given in different ways, such as by mouth, by infusion into a vein, or by drops that are put into the ear or eye. The form with the active ingredient is used to prevent, diagnose, treat, or relieve symptoms of a disease or abnormal condition. A medication that does not contain an active ingredient and is used in research studies is called a placebo.   Also called drug product.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716586" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medication&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716587" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicamento&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>medicamento</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Formulación  que contiene uno o más principios activos así como ingredientes inactivos. Los medicamentos se fabrican en diferentes presentaciones, como comprimidos, cápsulas, líquidos, cremas y parches. Se administran de diferentes maneras, entre ellas, por la boca, mediante infusión en una vena o como gotas que se aplican en los oídos o los ojos. La formulación que contiene el fármaco (principio activo) se usa para prevenir, diagnosticar, tratar o aliviar los síntomas de una enfermedad o afección. Un medicamento que no contiene un principio activo y que se usa en los estudios de investigación se llama placebo. También se llama producto farmacéutico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-05-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-02-09</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
