<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000463725">
  <TermName>nutrition therapy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(noo-TRIH-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A nutrition-based treatment plan to help manage or treat certain health conditions. These include diabetes, heart disease, kidney disease, digestive system problems, overweight, obesity, malnutrition, and cancer. Nutrition therapy includes assessing a person’s nutrition status, identifying their nutritional and dietary needs and goals, and developing a nutrition care plan. The nutrition care plan may involve changes in a person’s diet, counseling to support behavioral and lifestyle changes, or receiving nutrients through intravenous or tube feeding. Also called medical nutrition therapy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716947" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nutrition therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716946" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia nutricional&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>terapia nutricional</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Plan de tratamiento nutricional para ayudar a controlar o tratar ciertos problemas de salud, como diabetes, enfermedades cardíacas, enfermedades renales, problemas del aparato digestivo, sobrepeso, obesidad, desnutrición y cáncer. La terapia nutricional consiste en evaluar el estado nutricional de una persona, identificar sus necesidades y objetivos nutricionales y desarrollar un plan de atención. Esto puede incluir cambios en la alimentación (dieta), asesoramiento para llevar adelante cambios de hábitos y estilo de vida, o recibir nutrientes mediante alimentación intravenosa o enteral (por sonda). También se llama dietoterapia, terapia nutricional médica y tratamiento nutricional.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-05-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-08-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/nutrition">Nutrition During Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/nutricion" UseWith="es">Nutrición durante el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
