<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046384"><TermName>germline mutation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(JERM-line myoo-TAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A mutation in a reproductive cell (egg or sperm) that is in the DNA of every cell in the offspring's body. A mutation contained within the germline can be passed from parent to offspring and is, therefore, hereditary. Also called germline variant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene change in a body's reproductive cell (egg or sperm) that becomes incorporated into the DNA of every cell in the body of the offspring. Germline mutations are passed on from parents to offspring. Also called germline variant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708648" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;germline mutation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708647" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mutación de la línea germinal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mutación de la línea germinal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Mutación  que se encuentra en una célula reproductora (óvulo o espermatozoide) y que está presente en el ADN de todas las células de la descendencia. Una mutación de la línea germinal pasa del progenitor a su descendencia, por lo tanto, es hereditaria. También se llama mutación germinal, mutación hereditaria y variante de la línea germinal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio en un gen de una célula reproductora (óvulo o espermatozoide) que se añade al ADN de todas las células del cuerpo de los hijos de ambos sexos. Las mutaciones de la línea germinal pasan de progenitores (madre o padre) a hijos de ambos sexos. También se llama mutación germinal, mutación hereditaria y variante de la línea germinal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition></GlossaryTerm>
