<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046391"><TermName>genetic</TermName><TermPronunciation>(jeh-NEH-tik)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Having to do with genes. Most genes are sequences of DNA that contain information for making specific RNA molecules or proteins that perform important functions in a cell. The information in genes is passed down from parent to child. Sometimes, certain changes in genes can affect a person’s risk of disease, such as cancer. These changes may be inherited or they may occur with age or exposure to environmental factors, such as diet, exercise, drugs, and chemicals.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genetic&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genético&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>genético</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Relacionado con  los genes. La mayoría de los genes son secuencias de ADN que contienen información para producir moléculas de ARN o proteínas específicas que tienen funciones importantes en una célula. La información en los genes pasa de padres a hijos. A veces, ciertos cambios en los genes afectan el riesgo de una persona de enfermar; por ejemplo, de cáncer. Estos cambios se pueden heredar o se pueden presentar con la edad o la exposición a factores ambientales como la alimentación, el ejercicio, los medicamentos y las sustancias químicas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2017-09-08</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics">The Genetics of Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica">Genética del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
