<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046401"><TermName>fiber</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FY-ber)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In food, fiber is a type of carbohydrate found in plant foods that the body cannot digest. Fiber comes in two forms: soluble fiber and insoluble fiber. Soluble fiber dissolves in water and can help lower cholesterol and blood sugar levels. Soluble fiber is found in apples, bananas, oats, peas, black beans, lima beans, Brussels sprouts, and avocados. Insoluble fiber does not dissolve in water and helps move food through the digestive system, relieving or preventing constipation. Insoluble fiber is found in whole wheat flour, bran, nuts, seeds, and the skins of many fruits and vegetables. Eating foods rich in fiber may help with weight loss and reduce the risk of heart disease and some types of cancer. In body tissues, fiber refers to long thread-like cells, such as muscle fibers or nerve fibers.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708673" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fiber&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fibra&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>fibra</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En la alimentación, la fibra es un tipo de carbohidrato que se encuentra en los alimentos de origen vegetal y que el cuerpo no puede digerir. Se presenta en dos formas: la fibra soluble y la fibra insoluble. La fibra soluble se disuelve en agua y es posible que ayude a reducir las concentraciones de colesterol y glucosa (azúcar) en sangre. Este tipo de fibra alimentaria se encuentra en las manzanas, las bananas, la avena, los guisantes (arvejas), los frijoles negros, las habas (judías), las coles de Bruselas y los aguacates. La fibra insoluble no se disuelve en agua y ayuda a que los alimentos pasen por el tubo digestivo, lo que alivia o previene el estreñimiento. Este tipo de fibra se encuentra en la harina de trigo  integral, el salvado, los frutos secos, las semillas, y en la cáscara de muchas frutas, verduras y hortalizas. Consumir alimentos ricos en fibra, en ocasiones, ayuda a perder peso y a reducir el riesgo de enfermedades cardíacas, así como ciertos tipos de cáncer. En los tejidos del cuerpo, la fibra se refiere al tejido compuesto de células filiformes (con forma de hilo largo), como las fibras musculares o las fibras nerviosas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-08-01</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/healthy-eating/fiber-helps-diabetes.html" UseWith="en">Fiber: The Carb That Helps You Manage Diabetes (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/dietaryfiber.html" UseWith="en">Dietary Fiber (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/dietaryfiber.html">Fibra en la dieta (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
