<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046432">
  <TermName>ependymoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(eh-PEN-dih-MOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of glioma that begins in ependymal cells, which line the fluid-filled spaces in the brain and spinal cord and make cerebrospinal fluid. Ependymomas can form anywhere in the brain or spinal cord, but they usually form in the lower back part of the brain in children and in the spinal cord in adults. These tumors can occur at any age but are more common in young children. They can be low grade or high grade, determined by how abnormal the tumor cells look under a microscope and how quickly the tumor is likely to grow,  spread, and come back after treatment. Most ependymomas are low grade, meaning they tend to grow and spread within the brain and spinal cord slowly. They rarely spread outside the brain and spinal cord. Childhood ependymomas often come back after treatment. Also called ependymal tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708728" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ependymoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708727" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ependimoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000757890" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the inside of the brain showing the lateral ventricle, third ventricle, fourth ventricle, and the passageways between the ventricles (with cerebrospinal fluid shown in blue). Also shown are the cerebrum, cerebellum, brain stem (pons and medulla), and spinal cord." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Anatomy of the inside of the brain showing the lateral ventricle, third ventricle, fourth ventricle, and the passageways between the ventricles (with cerebrospinal fluid shown in blue). Also shown are the cerebrum, cerebellum, brain stem (pons and medulla), and spinal cord.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000759348" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo del interior de la cabeza de un niño donde se señalan diferentes partes del encéfalo: un ventrículo lateral, el tercer ventrículo, el cuarto ventrículo y las vías entre los ventrículos que contienen líquido cefalorraquídeo en azul. También se observa el cerebro, el cerebelo, la médula espinal y dos partes del tronco encefálico: la protuberancia y el bulbo raquídeo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Anatomía del interior del encéfalo. En este dibujo del interior de la cabeza de un niño, se señala un ventrículo lateral, el tercer ventrículo, el cuarto ventrículo y las vías entre los ventrículos que contienen líquido cefalorraquídeo en azul.  También se observa el cerebro, el cerebelo, la médula espinal y dos partes del tronco encefálico: la protuberancia y el bulbo raquídeo.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>ependimoma</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de glioma que comienza en las células ependimarias, que revisten los espacios llenos de líquido del encéfalo y la médula espinal y producen líquido cefalorraquídeo. Se forman en cualquier parte del encéfalo (tumor cerebral) o la médula espinal, pero suelen hacerlo en la parte posterior inferior del encéfalo en los niños y en la médula espinal en los adultos. Estos tumores aparecen a cualquier edad, pero son más frecuentes en niños pequeños. Son de grado bajo o de grado alto, lo que se determina por el aspecto anormal de las células tumorales al microscopio y la rapidez con que el tumor puede crecer, diseminarse y reaparecer después del tratamiento. La mayoría de los ependimomas son de bajo grado, lo que significa que suelen crecer y diseminarse de forma lenta dentro del encéfalo y la médula espinal y rara vez se extienden fuera de estos órganos. Los ependimomas infantiles suelen reaparecer después del tratamiento. También se llama tumor ependimario.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2024-06-12</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000813718" url="/types/brain/patient/childhood-ependymoma">Childhood Ependymoma</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/rare-brain-spine-tumor/tumors/ependymoma" UseWith="en">Ependymoma: Diagnosis and Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000813719" url="/espanol/tipos/cerebro/paciente/ependimoma-infantil">Ependimoma infantil</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/rare-brain-spine-tumor/espanol/tumores/ependimoma" UseWith="es">Ependimoma</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
