<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046457"><TermName>craniotomy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KRAY-nee-AH-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An operation in which a small hole is made in the skull or a piece of bone from the skull is removed to show part of the brain. A craniotomy may be done to remove a brain tumor or a sample of brain tissue. It may also be done to remove blood or blood clots from the brain, relieve pressure in the brain after an injury or stroke, repair a skull fracture or brain aneurysm (a bulge in a blood vessel wall), or treat other brain conditions. The piece of bone that is removed from the skull is usually put back in place after the surgery has been done.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708768" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;craniotomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708769" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;craneotomía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000680519" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of a craniotomy showing a section of the scalp that has been pulled back to remove a piece of the skull; the dura covering the brain has been opened to expose the brain. The layer of muscle under the scalp is also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Craniotomy:  An opening is made in the skull and a piece of the skull is removed to show part of the brain.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709151" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen de una craneotomía se observa que se levantó una sección del cuero cabelludo para extraer una pieza del cráneo; se abrió la duramadre que cubre el cerebro para exponer el cerebro. También se muestra la capa de músculo debajo del cuero cabelludo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Craneotomía. Se hace una abertura en el cráneo y se extrae una pieza del cráneo para exponer una parte del cerebro.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>craneotomía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Operación en la que se hace un pequeño orificio en el cráneo o se extrae una pequeña pieza del mismo para exponer parte del encéfalo, como el cerebro. La craneotomía se realiza para extraer un tumor o una muestra de tejido encefálico. También se realiza para extraer sangre o coágulos de la cabeza y para aliviar la presión intracraneal después de un traumatismo o de un accidente cerebrovascular. A veces se usa para reparar fracturas del cráneo, un aneurisma dentro de la cabeza (dilatación de la pared de un vaso sanguíneo) o como tratamiento de otras afecciones del encéfalo. Con frecuencia, la pieza del cráneo que se extrae se vuelve  a poner en su sitio después de la cirugía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2022-08-25</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
