<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046476"><TermName>cell</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sel)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In biology, the smallest unit that can live on its own and that makes up all living organisms and the tissues of the body. A cell has three main parts: the cell membrane, the nucleus, and the cytoplasm. The cell membrane surrounds the cell and controls the substances that go into and out of the cell. The nucleus is a structure inside the cell that contains the nucleolus and most of the cell’s DNA. It is also where most RNA is made. The cytoplasm is the fluid inside the cell. It contains other tiny cell parts that have specific functions, including the Golgi complex, the mitochondria, and the endoplasmic reticulum. The cytoplasm is where most chemical reactions take place and where most proteins are made. The human body has more than 30 trillion cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708802" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cell&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708803" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;célula&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761780" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a cell containing organelles, including the nucleus (contains DNA), the nucleolus, Golgi complex, mitochondria, and endoplasmic reticulum. Also shown are the cell membrane and a membrane receptor." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Parts of a cell.  A cell is surrounded by a membrane, which has receptors on the surface. A cell has several small structures inside it, including the nucleus, mitochondria, endoplasmic reticulum, and Golgi complex. These all have specific functions in the cell. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765321" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la ilustración, se muestra una célula con sus organelos, como el núcleo (contiene ADN), el nucléolo, el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. También se muestran la membrana celular y un receptor de membrana." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Partes de una célula. La célula está rodeada por una membrana, con receptores en la superficie; además,  tiene varias estructuras pequeñas en su interior, como el núcleo, las mitocondrias, el retículo endoplasmático y el  aparato de Golgi. Estas desempeñan funciones específicas en la célula.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>célula</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el ámbito de la biología, es la unidad más
pequeña que puede vivir por sí sola. Forma todos los
organismos
vivos y los tejidos del
cuerpo. Las tres partes principales de la
célula son la membrana celular, el núcleo y el citoplasma.
La membrana celular rodea la célula y controla las
sustancias que entran y salen. Dentro de la célula está el
núcleo que contiene el nucléolo y la mayor parte del ADN celular, además es donde se produce casi todo el ARN. El citoplasma
es el   líquido del interior de la célula
que contiene otros elementos diminutos con
funciones específicas, como el aparato de Golgi, las
mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. En el citoplasma ocurren la mayoría de
las reacciones químicas, y también es donde se elaboran la mayoría de las proteínas. El cuerpo humano tiene más de 30 billones de
células.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-11-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
