<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046470">
  <TermName>chromosome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KROH-muh-some)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Part of a cell that contains genetic information. Except for sperm and eggs, all human cells contain 46 chromosomes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A structure found inside the nucleus of a cell. A chromosome is made up of proteins and DNA organized into genes. Each cell normally contains 23 pairs of chromosomes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708792" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chromosome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000708793" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cromosoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN. En la imagen se muestra un cromosoma, un nucleosoma, una histona, un gen y varios pares de bases nucleotídicas formadas por la unión de guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También se muestra una célula y su núcleo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Estructura del ADN. La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el interior del núcleo de una célula, donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos cadenas que se enroscan y forman un espiral parecido a una escalera de caracol que se llama hélice. Los cuatro componentes básicos del ADN son los nucleótidos: adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C). Los nucleótidos se unen entre sí (A con T y G con C) mediante enlaces químicos y forman pares de bases que conectan las dos cadenas de ADN. Los genes son pequeñas piezas de ADN que tienen información genética específica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN. En la imagen se muestra un cromosoma, un nucleosoma, una histona, un gen y varios pares de bases nucleotídicas formadas por la unión de guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También se observa una célula y su núcleo." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Estructura del ADN. La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el núcleo celular,  donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos cadenas que conforman una estructura helicoidal que se llama hélice. Los nucleótidos adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C) son los cuatro elementos fundamentales del ADN que forman pares de bases (A con T y G con C) mediante enlaces químicos que unen las dos cadenas del ADN. Los genes son segmentos pequeños de ADN que contienen información genética específica.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cromosoma</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Parte de la célula que contiene información genética. Casi todas las células humanas contienen 46 cromosomas, excepto los espermatozoides y los óvulos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Estructura que se encuentra en el interior del núcleo celular formada por proteínas y ADN organizados en genes. Por lo habitual, una  célula normal contiene 23 pares de cromosomas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2015-02-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Chromosome">Chromosome (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.genome.gov/es/genetics-glossary/Cromosoma">Cromosoma (Instituto Nacional de Investigación del Genoma Humano)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
