<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046488"><TermName>carcinoma in situ</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which abnormal cells that look like cancer cells under a microscope are found only in the place where they first formed and haven’t spread to nearby tissue. At some point, these cells may become cancerous and spread into nearby normal tissue. There are many different types of carcinoma in situ depending on the type of tissue in which it began. These include adenocarcinoma in situ (of the cervix, lungs, and gastrointestinal tract), ductal carcinoma in situ (of the breast), and squamous cell carcinoma in situ (of the skin, mouth, and larynx). Also called stage 0 disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708823" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708822" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761914" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing showing layers of tissue, including the outer tissue layer, muscle layers, connective tissue, and inner tissue layer. The left panel shows carcinoma in situ (abnormal cells) in the inner tissue layer. The right panel shows cancer cells spreading from the inner tissue layer to the connective tissue and muscle layers." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Carcinoma in situ (CIS) is a group of abnormal cells that are found only in the place where they first formed in the body (see left panel). These abnormal cells may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue (see right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765320" type="image/jpeg" alt="Carcinoma in situ. En la imagen se observan dos paneles que muestran capas de tejido: la capa de tejido externo, las capas musculares, el tejido conjuntivo y la capa de tejido interna. En el panel izquierdo, se observa carcinoma in situ (células anormales) en la capa de tejido interna. En el panel derecho, se observan células cancerosas que se diseminan de la capa de tejido interno al tejido conjuntivo y las capas musculares." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">El carcinoma  in situ (CIS) es un grupo de células anormales que solo se encuentran en el primer lugar donde se formaron en el cuerpo (panel izquierdo). Es posible que estas células anormales se vuelvan cancerosas y se diseminen al tejido normal cercano (panel derecho).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>carcinoma in situ</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que se encuentran células anormales, que parecen células cancerosas, al microscopio solo en el lugar donde se formaron y que todavía no se diseminaron al tejido cercano. Es posible que en algún momento estas células se vuelvan cancerosas y se diseminen al tejido normal cercano. Hay muchas clases diferentes de carcinoma in situ según el tipo de tejido donde empezaron; entre ellas, el adenocarcinoma in situ (de cuello uterino, pulmón y tubo digestivo), el carcinoma ductal in situ (de mama) y el carcinoma de células escamosas in situ (de piel, boca y laringe). También se llama enfermedad en estadio 0.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2022-07-07</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
