<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046609"><TermName>supportive care</TermName><TermPronunciation>(suh-POR-tiv kayr)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Care given to improve the quality of life of people who have an illness or disease by preventing or treating, as early as possible, the symptoms of the disease and the side effects caused by treatment of the disease. Supportive care includes physical, psychological, social, and spiritual support for patients and their families. There are many types of supportive care. Examples include pain management, nutritional support, counseling, exercise, music therapy, meditation, and palliative care. Supportive care may be given with other treatments from the time of diagnosis until the end of life.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708486" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;supportive care&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708485" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cuidados médicos de apoyo&quot;" language="es" id="_9"/><SpanishTermName>cuidados médicos de apoyo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Atención que se brinda para mejorar la calidad de vida de las personas que padecen una enfermedad o dolencia mediante la prevención o el tratamiento lo antes posible, de los síntomas de la enfermedad y los efectos secundarios provocados por el tratamiento. Los cuidados de apoyo incluyen el apoyo físico, psicológico, social y espiritual a los pacientes y sus familias. Hay muchos tipos de cuidados de apoyo. Algunos ejemplos son el tratamiento del dolor, el apoyo nutricional, el asesoramiento, el ejercicio, la musicoterapia, la meditación y los cuidados paliativos. Desde el momento del diagnóstico hasta el final de la vida, es posible administrar los cuidados de apoyo junto con otros tratamientos. También se llama tratamiento de apoyo, tratamiento de soporte y tratamiento de sostén.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq/information-summaries/supportive-care" UseWith="en">PDQ® Cancer Information Summaries: Supportive and Palliative Care</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq/sumarios-de-informacion/cuidados-medicos-apoyo">Sumarios del PDQ® de información sobre el cáncer: Cuidados médicos de apoyo y cuidados paliativos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
