<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046636"><TermName>tumor marker</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TOO-mer MAR-ker)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance
          found in tissue, blood, bone marrow, or other body fluids
          that may be a sign of cancer or certain benign (noncancer)
          conditions. Many tumor markers are proteins made by both
          normal cells and cancer cells, but they are made in higher
          amounts by cancer cells. Genetic changes in tumor tissue,
          such as gene mutations, patterns of gene expression, and
          other changes in tumor DNA or RNA, are also being used as
          tumor markers. A tumor marker may be used with other tests
          to help diagnose cancer. It may also be used to help plan
          treatment, give a likely prognosis, and find out how well
          treatment is working or if cancer has come back. Examples
          of tumor markers include CA-125 (in ovarian cancer),
          estrogen receptor and progesterone receptor (in breast
          cancer), CEA (in colon cancer), PCA3 mRNA and PSA (in
          prostate cancer), and EGFR gene mutation (in non-small cell
          lung cancer).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709841" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor marker&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709842" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;marcador tumoral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>marcador tumoral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que se encuentra en
tejidos, sangre, médula ósea u otros líquidos del cuerpo, y
que a veces es un signo de cáncer o determinadas afecciones
benignas (no cancerosas). Muchos marcadores tumorales son
proteínas elaboradas por células normales y cancerosas,
pero que se producen en cantidades más altas en las células
cancerosas. Además, también se usan como marcadores
tumorales los cambios genéticos en el tejido tumoral, como
las mutaciones en genes, las formas de expresión de genes y
otros cambios en el ADN o ARN del tumor. Es posible usar un
marcador tumoral con otras pruebas para ayudar a
diagnosticar el cáncer. Los marcadores también son útiles
para planificar el tratamiento, dar un pronóstico y
determinar la eficacia de un tratamiento o si el cáncer
regresó. Los ejemplos de marcadores tumorales son el CA-125
(cáncer de ovario), los receptores de estrógeno y
progesterona (cáncer de mama), el ACE (cáncer de colon), el
ARNm de PCA3 y el PSA (cáncer de próstata), y la mutación
en el gen <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName> (cáncer de pulmón de
células no pequeñas).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2020-01-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/diagnosis/tumor-markers-fact-sheet">Tumor
Markers</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/hoja-informativa-marcadores-de-tumores">Marcadores
tumorales</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
