<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046658">
  <TermName>second primary cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SEH-kund PRY-mayr-ee KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term used to describe a new primary cancer that occurs in a person who has had cancer in the past. Second primary cancers may occur months or years after the original (primary) cancer was diagnosed and treated. Certain types of cancer treatment, such as chemotherapy and radiation therapy, may increase the risk of a second primary cancer. Having certain inherited gene mutations (changes) and being exposed to certain cancer-causing substances, such as tobacco smoke, may also increase the risk of a second primary cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709884" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;second primary cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709883" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;segundo cáncer primario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>segundo cáncer primario</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que se usa para describir un nuevo cáncer primario que se presenta en una persona con antecedentes de cáncer. Es posible que los segundos cánceres primarios aparezcan meses o años después del diagnóstico y tratamiento del cáncer original (primario). Ciertos tipos de tratamiento del cáncer, como la quimioterapia y la radioterapia, quizás aumenten el riesgo de un segundo cáncer primario. Tener ciertas mutaciones (cambios) heredadas en los genes y  haber estado expuesto a ciertas sustancias que producen cáncer, como el humo del tabaco, también aumenta el riesgo de un segundo cáncer primario.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2016-09-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000044457" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">secondary cancer</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000044457" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">cáncer secundario</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
