<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046679">
  <TermName>aldesleukin</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AL-des-LOO-kin)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with melanoma or renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer) that has spread to other parts of the body.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Aldesleukin is a form of interleukin-2 that is made in the laboratory.  Aldesleukin increases the activity and growth of white blood cells called T lymphocytes and B lymphocytes, which may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Aldesleukin is a type of cytokine and a type of immunomodulating agent. Also called Proleukin and recombinant human interleukin-2.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709917" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aldesleukin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709918" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aldesleucina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>aldesleucina</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con melanoma o carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón) que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. La aldesleucina es una forma de interleucina-2 que se produce en el laboratorio. La aldesleucina aumenta la actividad y la formación de glóbulos blancos llamados linfocitos T y B. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. La aldesleucina es un tipo de citocina y de inmunomodulador.  También se llama interleucina 2 humana genotecnológica y Proleukin.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2021-06-03</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000596071" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/aldesleukin">Aldesleukin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
