<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046692"><TermName>trichothiodystrophy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TRIH-koh-thy-oh-DIS-truh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited genetic disorder marked by short, dry hair that breaks easily and has a light- and dark-colored striped (tiger-tail) pattern when looked at under a microscope. There are many other signs and symptoms of trichothiodystrophy that begin in infancy and vary from person to person. About half of all people with trichothiodystrophy also have an extreme sensitivity to sunlight and may develop a severe blistering sunburn after a short time in the sun. Other signs and symptoms may include learning and developmental delays, shorter-than-average height, recurrent infections, dry, scaly skin, and abnormalities of the nails, eyes, and bones. Trichothiodystrophy is associated with mutations (changes) in several genes and is inherited in an autosomal recessive manner.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709936" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trichothiodystrophy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709935" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tricotiodistrofia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802195" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an autosomal recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their four children: an unaffected father (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene on a chromosome pair; an unaffected mother (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter with two normal genes; an unaffected son (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; and an affected son with two mutated genes." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Autosomal recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child. A genetic condition can occur when the child inherits one copy of a mutated (changed) gene from each parent. The parents of a child with an autosomal recessive condition usually do not have the condition. Unaffected parents are called carriers because they each carry one copy of the mutated gene and can pass it to their children.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802815" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia autosómica recesiva en una familia conformada por padre, madre y cuatro hijos: se muestran un par de cromosomas con un gen mutado y un gen normal en el padre no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en la madre no afectada (portadora); dos genes normales en una hija no afectada; un gen mutado y un gen normal en un hijo no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en una hija no afectada (portadora) y dos genes mutados en un hijo afectado." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">La herencia autosómica recesiva es una de las formas en que un rasgo o una afección genética pasa de padres a hijos. El niño presenta la afección genética cuando hereda dos copias de un gen mutado (cambiado), una del padre y otra de la madre. Por lo general, la madre y el padre no presentan la afección que se hereda de manera autosómica recesiva. Se dice que la madre y el padre no afectados son portadores porque cada uno tiene una copia del gen mutado que puede pasar a sus hijos. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>tricotiodistrofia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético hereditario raro. Se caracteriza por cabello corto, seco y quebradizo, que presenta un patrón de rayas claras y oscuras (cola de tigre) cuando se observa al microscopio. Hay muchos otros signos y síntomas de la tricotiodistrofia que comienzan en la infancia y varían de una persona a otra. Alrededor de la mitad de las personas con esta afección tienen también sensibilidad extrema a la luz solar y pueden presentar quemaduras solares graves con ampollas tras una breve exposición al sol. Otros signos y síntomas quizás incluyan retrasos en el aprendizaje y el desarrollo, estatura inferior a la media, infecciones recurrentes, piel seca y escamosa, así como alteraciones en las uñas, los ojos y los huesos. La tricotiodistrofia se relaciona con mutaciones (cambios) en varios genes que se heredan de manera autosómica recesiva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
