<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046727">
  <TermName>stage II malignant pleural mesothelioma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(...muh-LIG-nunt PLOOR-ul MEH-zoh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer (1) is found in the inside lining of the chest wall on one side of the chest. On the same side of the chest, cancer may also be found in one or more of the following: the thin layer of tissue that covers the lung; the thin layer of tissue that covers the organs between the lungs; and/or the thin layer of tissue that covers the top of the diaphragm. Cancer has spread to lymph nodes along the center of the chest on the same side of the chest as the tumor; or (2) is found in the inside lining of the chest wall, and in each of the thin layers of tissue that cover the lung, the organs between the lungs, and the top of the diaphragm on one side of the chest. On the same side of the chest, cancer has also spread into the diaphragm and/or lung tissue. Cancer has spread to lymph nodes along the center of the chest on the same side of the chest as the tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709999" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II malignant pleural mesothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000709998" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesotelioma pleural maligno en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mesotelioma pleural maligno en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer 1) se encuentra en el revestimiento interno de la pared torácica de un lado del tórax. En el mismo lado del tórax, es posible que también se encuentre cáncer en uno o más de los siguientes sitios: la capa delgada de tejido que recubre el pulmón, la capa delgada de tejido que recubre los órganos que están entre los pulmones o la capa delgada de tejido que recubre la parte superior del diafragma. El cáncer se diseminó  a los ganglios linfáticos a lo largo del centro del tórax del mismo lado que el tumor; o 2) se encuentra en el revestimiento interno de la pared torácica y en cada una de las capas delgadas de tejido que recubren el pulmón, los órganos que están entre los pulmones, y la parte superior del diafragma de un lado del tórax. En el mismo lado del tórax, el cáncer también se diseminó al diafragma, el tejido del pulmón o ambos. El cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos a lo largo del centro del tórax del mismo lado que el tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2018-07-30</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000269299" url="/types/mesothelioma/patient/mesothelioma-treatment-pdq">Malignant Mesothelioma Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433305" url="/espanol/tipos/mesotelioma/paciente/tratamiento-mesotelioma-pdq">Tratamiento del mesotelioma maligno</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
