<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046749"><TermName>granulocyte colony-stimulating factor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GRAN-yoo-loh-SITE KAH-luh-nee-STIM-yoo-LAY-ting FAK-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used under the brand names Neupogen, Zarxio, and Nivestym to treat neutropenia (a lower-than-normal number of white blood cells), prevent infection, and prepare the blood for the collection of certain types of blood cells, and under the brand name Granix to treat neutropenia. Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor is used in patients who have certain cancers and neutropenia caused by some types of chemotherapy and in patients who have severe chronic neutropenia that is not caused by cancer treatment. It is also used before an autologous stem cell transplant. Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor helps the bone marrow make more white blood cells. It is a type of colony-stimulating factor. Also called filgrastim and G-CSF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710027" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;granulocyte colony-stimulating factor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710028" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;factor estimulante de colonias de granulocitos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>factor estimulante de colonias de granulocitos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa bajo las marcas comerciales Neupogen, Zarxio y Nivestym para el tratamiento de la neutropenia (afección por la que hay menos glóbulos blancos que lo normal), la prevención de infecciones y la preparación de la sangre para la recolección de ciertos tipos de glóbulos sanguíneos.  También se usa bajo la marca comercial Granix para el tratamiento de la neutropenia. El factor estimulante de colonias de granulocitos se utiliza en pacientes con determinados cánceres y una neutropenia causada por algunos tipos de quimioterapia. Además, se usa en pacientes con neutropenia crónica grave que no es causada por un tratamiento del cáncer. Asimismo, se utiliza antes de un trasplante autógeno de células madre. El factor estimulante de colonias de granulocitos ayuda a que la médula ósea produzca más glóbulos blancos. Es un tipo de factor estimulante de colonias. También se llama filgrastim y G-CSF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2021-05-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000641058" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/filgrastim">Filgrastim</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
