<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046751"><TermName>external beam radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of radiation therapy that uses a machine outside the body to send high-energy radiation beams toward the area of the body with cancer. It is used to treat many types of cancer. It may also be used to shrink tumors to treat pain and other problems caused by the tumor, such as trouble breathing or loss of bowel and bladder control. Also called external radiation therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710029" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;external-beam radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710030" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia de haz externo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732668" type="image/jpeg" alt="External-beam radiation therapy of the brain; drawing shows a patient lying on a table under a machine that is used to aim high-energy radiation. An inset shows a mesh mask that helps keep the patient's head from moving during treatment. The mask has pieces of white tape with small ink marks on it. The ink marks are used to line up the radiation machine in the same position before each treatment." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">External-beam radiation therapy of the brain. A machine is used to aim high-energy radiation. The machine can rotate around the patient, delivering radiation from many different angles. A mesh mask helps keep the patient’s head from moving during treatment. Small ink marks are put on the mask. The ink marks are used to line up the radiation machine in the same position before each treatment.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732667" type="image/jpeg" alt="External-beam radiation therapy of the head and neck; drawing shows a patient lying on a table under a machine that is used to aim high-energy radiation at the cancer. An inset shows a mesh mask that helps keep the patient's head and neck from moving during treatment. The mask has pieces of white tape with small ink marks on it. The ink marks are used to line up the radiation machine in the same position before each treatment." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="en">External-beam radiation therapy of the head and neck. A machine is used to aim high-energy radiation at the cancer. The machine can rotate around the patient, delivering radiation from many different angles to provide highly conformal treatment. A mesh mask helps keep the patient’s head and neck from moving during treatment. Small ink marks are put on the mask. The ink marks are used to line up the radiation machine in the same position before each treatment.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732668" type="image/jpeg" alt="Radioterapia de haz externo del encéfalo; el dibujo muestra un paciente acostado sobre una mesa debajo de una máquina que se usa para enfocar radiación de alta energía. El recuadro muestra una máscara de malla que ayuda a inmovilizar la cabeza del paciente durante el tratamiento. La máscara tiene pedazos de cinta blanca con pequeñas marcas de tinta. Las marcas de tinta se utilizan para alinear la máquina de radiación en la misma posición antes de cada tratamiento." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Radioterapia de haz externo del encéfalo. Se utiliza una máquina para enfocar radiación de alta energía. La máquina puede rotar alrededor del paciente, liberando energía desde muchos ángulos diferentes. Una máscara de malla ayuda a inmovilizar la cabeza del paciente durante el tratamiento. Se trazan pequeñas marcas   de tinta en la máscara. Las marcas de tinta se utilizan para alinear la máquina de radiación en la misma posición antes de cada tratamiento.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732667" type="image/jpeg" alt="Radioterapia de haz externo de la cabeza y el cuello; el dibujo muestra un paciente acostado sobre una mesa debajo de una máquina que se usa para enfocar radiación de alta energía en el cáncer. El recuadro muestra una máscara de malla que ayuda a inmovilizar la cabeza y el cuello del paciente durante el tratamiento. La máscara tiene pedazos de cinta blanca con pequeñas marcas de tinta. Las marcas de tinta se utilizan para alinear la máquina de radiación en la misma posición antes de cada tratamiento." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Radioterapia de haz externo de la cabeza y el cuello. Se utiliza una máquina para enfocar radiación de alta energía en el cáncer. La máquina puede rotar alrededor del paciente, liberando energía desde muchos ángulos diferentes para proporcionar un tratamiento altamente conformado. Una máscara de malla ayuda a inmovilizar la cabeza y el cuello del paciente durante el tratamiento. Se trazan pequeñas marcas de tinta en la máscara. Las marcas de tinta se utilizan para alinear la máquina de radiación en la misma posición antes de cada tratamiento.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>radioterapia de haz externo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia para la que se usa una máquina fuera del cuerpo con el fin de enviar haces de rayos de alta energía hacia el área del cuerpo donde está el cáncer. Se usa para el tratamiento de muchos tipos de cáncer. También es posible utilizarla para reducir el tamaño del tumor con el fin de controlar el dolor y otros problemas causados por este, como la dificultad para respirar o la pérdida de control de los esfínteres. También se llama radioterapia externa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2025-03-27</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/radiation-therapy/external-beam?redirect=true">External Beam Radiation Therapy for Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/radioterapia/haz-externo">Radioterapia de haz externo para el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
