<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046755"><TermName>chronic myeloid leukemia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KRAH-nik MY-eh-loyd loo-KEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An indolent (slow-growing) cancer in which too many myeloblasts are found in the blood and bone marrow. Myeloblasts are a type of immature blood cell that makes white blood cells called myeloid cells. Chronic myeloid leukemia may get worse over time as the number of myeloblasts increases in the blood and bone marrow. This may cause fever, fatigue, easy bleeding, anemia, infection, a swollen spleen, bone pain, or other signs and symptoms. Chronic myeloid leukemia is usually marked by a chromosome change called the Philadelphia chromosome, in which a piece of chromosome 9 and a piece of chromosome 22 break off and trade places with each other. It usually occurs in older adults and rarely occurs in children. Also called chronic granulocytic leukemia, chronic myelogenous leukemia, and CML.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710035" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chronic myeloid leukemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710036" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leucemia mieloide crónica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>leucemia mieloide crónica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer de crecimiento lento (indolente) por el que se encuentran demasiados mieloblastos en la sangre y la médula ósea. Los mieloblastos son un tipo de célula sanguínea inmadura que se convierten en células mieloides, un tipo de glóbulos blancos. Es posible que la leucemia mieloide crónica empeore con el tiempo a medida que aumenta la cantidad de mieloblastos en la sangre y la médula ósea. Esto quizás produzca fiebre, fatiga, sangrado fácil, anemia, infecciones, hinchazón del bazo, dolor de huesos, u otros signos y síntomas. En este tipo de leucemia a menudo se encuentra un cambio cromosómico llamado cromosoma Filadelfia, en el que se rompe una parte del cromosoma 9 y una parte del cromosoma 22 e intercambian lugares. Suele presentarse en adultos mayores y es poco frecuente en los niños. También se llama leucemia granulocítica crónica, leucemia mielocítica crónica, leucemia mielógena crónica y LMC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2016-08-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/leukemia">Leukemia</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/leucemia">Leucemia</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
