<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046756">
  <TermName>barium swallow</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BAYR-ee-um SWAH-loh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A series of x-ray pictures of the upper gastrointestinal (GI) tract, including the throat, esophagus, stomach, and the first part of the small intestine  (duodenum). The x-ray pictures are taken after the patient drinks a liquid that contains barium sulfate (a silver-white metallic compound). The barium sulfate coats and outlines the inner walls of the upper GI tract so they can be seen on the x-ray pictures. Also called upper gastrointestinal series and upper GI series.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000710038" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;barium swallow&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000710037" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;estudio con ingesta de bario&quot;" language="es" id="_9"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000430686" type="image/jpeg" alt="Barium swallow; drawing shows barium liquid flowing down the esophagus and into the stomach. The barium coats and outlines the inside of the esophagus and stomach. The inset x-ray image shows a narrowing at the end of the esophagus caused by cancer." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Barium swallow for esophageal cancer. The patient drinks a liquid that contains barium (a silver-white metallic compound). The barium coats and outlines the inside of the esophagus and stomach. This allows abnormal areas, such as esophageal cancer, to be seen on x-rays.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000681324" type="image/jpeg" alt="Barium swallow; drawing shows barium liquid flowing down the esophagus and into the stomach. The barium coats and outlines the inside of the esophagus and stomach. Also shown is cancer in the stomach." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="en">Barium swallow for stomach cancer. The patient drinks a liquid that contains barium (a silver-white metallic compound). The barium coats and outlines the inside of the esophagus and stomach. This allows abnormal areas, such as stomach cancer, to be seen on x-rays. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000747240" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estudio con ingesta de bario. En el dibujo se observa bario líquido que pasa por el esófago hasta el estómago. El bario recubre y resalta el interior del esófago y el estómago. En la radiografía del recuadro se muestra un estrechamiento al final del esófago a causa del cáncer." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Estudio con ingesta de bario para el cáncer de esófago. El paciente bebe un líquido que contiene bario (compuesto metálico de color blanco plateado). El bario recubre y resalta el interior del esófago y el estómago. Esto permite que las áreas anormales, como el cáncer de esófago, se vean en radiografías.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000688543" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estudio con ingesta de bario. En el dibujo se observa el tronco y la cabeza de un hombre mayor. Además, se ve bario líquido que pasa por el esófago hasta el estómago. El bario recubre y resalta el interior del esófago y el estómago. También se observa cáncer de estómago." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Estudio con ingesta de bario para el cáncer de estómago. El paciente bebe un líquido que contiene bario (compuesto metálico de color blanco plateado). El bario recubre y resalta el interior del esófago y el estómago. Esto permite que las áreas anormales, como el cáncer de estómago, se vean en radiografías.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>estudio con ingesta de bario</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Serie de radiografías del tubo digestivo superior, incluye la garganta, el esófago, el estómago y el duodeno (la primera parte del intestino delgado).   Las radiografías se toman después de que el paciente bebe un líquido que contiene sulfato de bario (compuesto metálico de color blanco plateado). El sulfato de bario recubre y resalta el contorno de las paredes internas del tubo digestivo superior para que sea posible observarlas en las radiografías. También se llama estudio con papilla baritada, estudio con trago de bario, serie del tubo digestivo superior, tránsito baritado y tránsito digestivo superior.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2023-09-13</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
