<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046771">
  <TermName>cutaneous T-cell lymphoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(kyoo-TAY-nee-us … lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of cancer that begins in T cells (a type of white blood cell) and affects the skin. There are several different types of cutaneous T-cell lymphomas. Most are marked by an itchy, scaly, red rash that can thicken or form tumors on the skin, or by skin redness all over the body. The lymph nodes may also be swollen. Cutaneous T-cell lymphomas usually grow slowly, but some may grow quickly and spread to the lymph nodes or to other organs, such as the spleen or liver. They usually occur in middle-aged or older men. The most common types of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma are mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome.  Cutaneous T-cell lymphoma is a type of non-Hodgkin lymphoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000710055" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cutaneous T-cell lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000710056" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma cutáneo de células T&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>linfoma cutáneo de células T</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer que comienza en las células T (tipo de glóbulo blanco) y afecta la piel. Hay tipos diferentes de linfomas cutáneos de células T. La mayoría se caracterizan por un sarpullido rojo, escamoso, con picazón que a veces produce engrosamiento o tumores en la piel. También causa enrojecimiento de toda la piel del cuerpo. En ocasiones, se produce inflamación de  los ganglios linfáticos. Los linfomas cutáneos de células T suelen ser de crecimiento lento, pero algunos crecen rápido y se diseminan a los ganglios linfáticos u otros órganos, como el bazo o el hígado. Por lo general, se presentan en hombres de edad mediana o avanzada. Los tipos más comunes de este linfoma son la micosis fungoide y el síndrome de Sézary. El linfoma cutáneo de células T es un tipo de linfoma no Hodgkin. También se llama linfoma cutáneo de linfocitos T.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateLastModified>2021-12-30</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258022" url="/types/lymphoma/patient/mycosis-fungoides-treatment-pdq">Mycosis Fungoides (Including Sézary Syndrome) Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433316" url="/espanol/tipos/linfoma/paciente/tratamiento-micosis-fungoide-pdq">Tratamiento de la micosis fungoide (incluso el síndrome de Sézary)</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
