<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000468803">
  <TermName>immunity</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ih-MYOO-nih-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, the immune system’s way of protecting the body against an infectious disease. The three types of immunity are innate, adaptive, and passive. Innate immunity includes barriers, such as skin and mucous membranes, that keep harmful substances from entering the body. It is the first response of the body’s immune system to a foreign substance. Adaptive immunity occurs in response to being infected with or vaccinated against a microorganism. The body makes an immune response, which can prevent future infection with the microorganism. Adaptive immunity can last a person’s entire life. Passive immunity occurs when a person receives antibodies to a disease rather than making them through his or her own immune system. Passive immunity provides immediate protection but only lasts a few weeks or months.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716801" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;immunity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716800" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inmunidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>inmunidad</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el ámbito de la medicina, es la forma en que el sistema inmunitario protege el cuerpo contra las enfermedades causadas por infecciones. Los tres tipos de inmunidad son innata, adaptativa y pasiva. La inmunidad innata incluye barreras, como la piel y las membranas mucosas, que evitan la entrada de sustancias dañinas en el cuerpo. Este tipo de inmunidad es la primera respuesta del sistema inmunitario contra una sustancia extraña. La inmunidad adaptativa se produce como  respuesta del cuerpo a una infección o vacunación contra un microorganismo, de manera que se previenen futuras infecciones por el mismo microorganismo. Es posible que la inmunidad adaptativa dure toda la vida.  La inmunidad pasiva se presenta cuando una  persona recibe anticuerpos contra una enfermedad, en lugar de producirlos  en su sistema inmunitario. La protección de la inmunidad pasiva es inmediata, pero solo dura pocas semanas o meses.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-08-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-09-16</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
