<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000479005"><TermName>Kepivance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KEH-puh-vants)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to prevent and treat severe oral mucositis (mouth sores).  It is used in patients with blood cancer who are being treated with high-dose chemotherapy and radiation therapy followed by an autologous stem cell transplant. It is also being studied in the prevention and treatment of common side effects in other types of cancer. Kepivance is a form of human keratinocyte growth factor that is made in the laboratory.  It binds to certain receptors on the surface of cells in the lining of the mouth, stomach, and intestines. This may help protect healthy tissue from some of the side effects caused by certain types of cancer treatment. Kepivance is a type of cytoprotective agent. Also called palifermin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716807" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Kepivance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716806" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Kepivance&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Kepivance</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para la prevención y el tratamiento de la mucositis oral (llagas en la boca) grave. Se utiliza en pacientes con cáncer de la sangre que reciben dosis altas de quimioterapia y radioterapia seguidas de un trasplante de células madre autógeno. También está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de efectos secundarios comunes de otros tipos de cáncer. Kepivance es una forma de factor de crecimiento de queratinocitos humanos que se produce en el laboratorio. Se une a ciertos receptores en la superficie de las células que revisten la boca, el estómago y los intestinos. Es posible que esto ayude a proteger el tejido sano de algunos de los efectos secundarios causados por ciertos tipos de tratamientos del cáncer. Kepivance es un tipo de citoprotector. También se llama palifermina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-04-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-07-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000492043" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/palifermin">Palifermin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
