<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000479002">
  <TermName>dermoid cyst</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(DER-moyd sist)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of tumor that contains a cyst filled with tissues that are normally found in the outer layers of the skin, including sweat and oil glands. These may also contain elements of hair and teeth. Dermoid cysts can form anywhere in the body, but they usually form in the ovary, testes, the skin of the head, neck, face, or lower back, or in the central nervous system. Dermoid cysts are benign (not cancer) and tend to grow slowly. They are present at birth but may not be found until later in life. Dermoid cysts are a type of germ cell tumor called a mature teratoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716634" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dermoid cyst&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716635" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;quiste dermoide&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>quiste dermoide</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de tumor que contiene un quiste lleno de tejidos que se suelen encontrar en las capas externas de la piel, como las glándulas sudoríparas y sebáceas. A veces, estos tumores también  contienen porciones de pelo o dientes. Los quistes dermoides se forman en cualquier lugar del cuerpo, pero a menudo surgen en el ovario, el testículo, la piel de la cabeza, el cuello, la cara o la región lumbar; o en el sistema nervioso central. Los quistes dermoides son benignos (no cancerosos) y casi siempre crecen despacio. Están presentes en el momento del nacimiento, pero es posible que no se encuentren hasta después. Los quistes dermoides son un tipo de tumor de células germinativas que se llama teratoma maduro.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-04-14</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
