<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000482355">
  <TermName>stage 0 penile carcinoma in situ</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... PEE-nile KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage 0 is divided into stages 0is and 0a. In stage 0is, abnormal cells are found on the surface of the skin of the penis. These abnormal cells  form growths that may become cancer and spread into nearby normal tissue. Stage 0is is also called penile intraepithelial neoplasia. In stage 0a, squamous cell cancer that does not spread is found on the surface of the skin of the penis or on the underneath surface of the foreskin of the penis. Stage 0a is also called noninvasive localized squamous cell carcinoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716541" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage 0 penile carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000716540" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de pene in situ en estadio 0&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma de pene in situ en estadio 0</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio 0 se divide en los estadios 0is y 0a. En el estadio 0is, se encuentran células anormales en la superficie de la piel del pene. Estas células anormales forman bultos que a veces se vuelven cancerosos y se diseminan al tejido normal cercano. El estadio 0is también se llama neoplasia intraepitelial de pene. En el estadio 0a, el cáncer de células escamosas que no se disemina se encuentra en la superficie de la piel del pene o en la superficie interna del prepucio del pene. El  estadio 0a también se llama carcinoma de células escamosas localizado no invasivo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-07-23</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000438960" url="/types/penile/patient/penile-treatment-pdq">Penile Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000502300" url="/espanol/tipos/pene/paciente/tratamiento-pene-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pene</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
