<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000492235">
  <TermName>Sutent</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SOO-tent)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of gastrointestinal stromal tumors, pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors, or renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer).  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Sutent blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Sutent is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent.  Also called SU011248, SU11248, and sunitinib malate.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718253" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Sutent&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718252" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Sutent&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Sutent</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para
el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de tumores de estroma gastrointestinal, tumores neuroendocrinos de páncreas o carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Sutent bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que también prevenga la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Sutent es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas.  También se llama malato de sunitinib, SU011248 y SU11248.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-06-26</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-06-11</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000491976" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/sunitinibmalate">Sunitinib Malate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
