<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000496506">
  <TermName>surveillance</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ser-VAY-lents)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, the ongoing evaluation of an individual who has an increased risk of developing a disease or who has a disease that appears to be clinically stable or not progressing. Surveillance is also used to find early signs that a disease has come back. In public health, surveillance may also refer to the ongoing systematic collection and analysis of information about the incidence, prevalence, morbidity, survival, and mortality related to a disease or health-related event in a certain group of people.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, closely watching a patient’s condition but not treating it unless there are changes in test results. Surveillance is also used to find early signs that a disease has come back. It may also be used for a person who has an increased risk of a disease, such as cancer. During surveillance, certain exams and tests are done on a regular schedule. In public health, surveillance may also refer to the ongoing collection of information about a disease, such as cancer, in a certain group of people. The information collected may include where the disease occurs in a population and whether it affects people of a certain gender, age, or ethnic group. </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718349" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;surveillance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718348" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vigilancia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>vigilancia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En medicina, la observación detallada del estado de un paciente sin administrar un tratamiento, a menos que se produzcan cambios en los resultados de las pruebas. La vigilancia también se usa para detectar signos tempranos de que una enfermedad volvió. Además, es posible utilizarla con una persona que tenga un mayor riesgo de presentar una enfermedad, como el cáncer. Durante la vigilancia, se realizan determinados exámenes y pruebas de forma regular. En el ámbito de la salud pública, la vigilancia también se refiere a la recopilación continua de información sobre una enfermedad, como el cáncer, en un grupo de personas específico. Es posible que la información recopilada incluya  dónde se produce la enfermedad en una población y si afecta a personas de un determinado sexo, edad o grupo étnico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En medicina, la observación  continua de una persona que tiene un riesgo mayor de presentar una enfermedad o que tiene una enfermedad que parece clínicamente estable o que no progresa. La vigilancia también se utiliza para encontrar signos tempranos de la reaparición de una enfermedad. En el ámbito de la salud pública, la vigilancia además se refiere  a la recopilación constante y sistemática, así como al análisis, de información sobre la incidencia, prevalencia, morbilidad, supervivencia y mortalidad de una enfermedad, o un evento que tenga que ver con la salud, de un determinado grupo de personas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-10-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2014-07-31</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
