<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000505945">
  <TermName>Rituxan</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(rih-TUK-sun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient rituximab and is used alone or with other drugs to treat adults and children aged 6 months and older  with certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma, adults with chronic lymphocytic leukemia, and children aged 6 months and older  with B-cell acute leukemia. It is used in patients whose cancer is CD20 positive. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Rituxan binds to a protein called CD20, which is found on B cells (a type of white blood cell) and some types of cancer cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Rituxan is a type of monoclonal antibody.  </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718057" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Rituxan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718056" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Rituxan&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Rituxan</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo rituximab y se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos y  niños de 6 meses o más con ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B, adultos con leucemia linfocítica crónica y niños de 6 meses o más con leucemia aguda de células B. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer es positivo para CD20. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. Rituxan se une a una proteína llamada CD20, que se encuentra en las células B (tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Rituxan es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-08-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-05-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495778" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/rituximab">Rituximab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
