<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000507517"><TermName>Aldara</TermName><TermPronunciation>(al-DAR-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient imiquimod and is used to treat certain skin conditions. Aldara is used to treat superficial basal cell skin cancer and actinic keratosis (a skin condition that may become cancer) in adults who have a normal immune system. It is also used to treat genital warts or perianal warts in adults and in children aged 12 years or older. Aldara may help the immune system kill abnormal cells, including cancer cells. It is a type of immunomodulating agent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718645" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Aldara&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718644" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Aldara&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Aldara</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo imiquimod y se usa para el tratamiento de ciertas afecciones de la piel. Aldara se utiliza para el tratamiento del cáncer de piel de células basales superficial y la queratosis actínica (afección de la piel que a veces se vuelve cancerosa) en adultos con un sistema inmunitario normal. También se usa para el tratamiento de las verrugas genitales o perianales en adultos y niños de 12 años o más. Es posible que Aldara ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células anormales, como las células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inmunomodulador.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-06-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495327" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/imiquimod">Imiquimod</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
