<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000507639">
  <TermName>Sterile Talc Powder</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(STAYR-il ... POW-der)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A mist or powdered form of the mineral magnesium silicate that is used to prevent malignant pleural effusions from coming back. Malignant pleural effusion is a condition in which cancer causes an abnormal collection of fluid in the space between the lung and chest wall. When Sterile Talc Powder is given through a tube inserted into the pleural space, it causes the space to close up so fluid cannot collect there. Sterile Talc Powder is a type of sclerosing agent. Also called Sclerosol Intrapleural Aerosol, Steritalc, and talc.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Sterile Talc Powder&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718710" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;polvo estéril de talco&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>polvo estéril de talco</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento en polvo o en aerosol que contiene el mineral silicato de magnesio y que se usa para prevenir que vuelvan los derrames pleurales malignos. Un derrame pleural maligno es una afección por la que el cáncer hace que se acumule líquido en el espacio entre los pulmones y la pared del tórax. Cuando el polvo estéril de talco  se administra por un tubo que se coloca en el espacio pleural, hace que el espacio se cierre lo que evita la acumulación de líquido. El polvo estéril de talco es un tipo de esclerosante. También se llama aerosol intrapleural de Sclerosol, Steritalc y talco.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-07-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495779" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/talc">Talc</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
