<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000507751">
  <TermName>protein-bound paclitaxel</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PROH-teen-bownd PA-klih-TAK-sil)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of the anticancer drug paclitaxel that is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of breast cancer, non-small cell lung cancer, and pancreatic cancer. Protein-bound paclitaxel may have fewer side effects and work better than other forms of paclitaxel.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Protein-bound paclitaxel stops cancer cells from growing and dividing and may kill them.   It is a type of taxane. Also called ABI-007, Abraxane, nanoparticle paclitaxel, and paclitaxel albumin-stabilized nanoparticle formulation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718763" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;protein-bound paclitaxel&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718764" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;paclitaxel fijado a proteínas&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>paclitaxel fijado a proteínas</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma del medicamento contra el cáncer paclitaxel que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer de mama, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas y cáncer de páncreas. El paclitaxel fijado a una proteína tal vez produzca menos efectos secundarios, y sea más eficaz que otras formas de paclitaxel.  También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El paclitaxel fijado a una proteína detiene el crecimiento y la multiplicación de las células cancerosas y es posible que las destruya. Es un tipo de taxano. También se llama ABI-007, Abraxane, formulación de nanopartículas de paclitaxel estabilizadas con albúmina, nanopartícula de paclitaxel y paclitaxel unido a albúmina.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-12-22</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495323" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/nanoparticlepaclitaxel">Paclitaxel Albumin-stabilized Nanoparticle Formulation</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
