<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000508688"><TermName>Iressa</TermName><TermPronunciation>(i-REH-suh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat non-small cell lung cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and has certain mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName> gene. It is used in patients whose cancer has not already been treated with other anticancer therapy.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Iressa blocks certain proteins made by the <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName> gene, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Iressa is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called gefitinib and ZD1839.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718218" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Iressa&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718217" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Iressa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Iressa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y que tiene ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName>. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer no se ha tratado con otra terapia contra el cáncer. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Iressa bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan del gen <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName>, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que también prevenga la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Iressa es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama gefitinib y ZD1839.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-06-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495775" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/gefitinib">Gefitinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
