<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512909"><TermName>stage IVB lip and oral cavity cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... OR-ul KA-vih-tee KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVB, the tumor (1) has spread to one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters; or (2) has spread to one lymph node that is larger than 3 centimeters, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor, and cancer has spread through the outside covering of the lymph node into nearby connective tissue; or (3) has spread to one lymph node of any size on the opposite side of the neck as the primary tumor, and cancer has spread through the outside covering of the lymph node into nearby connective tissue; or (4) has spread to multiple lymph nodes anywhere in the neck, and cancer has spread through the outside covering of any lymph node into nearby connective tissue; or (5) has spread further into the muscles or bones needed for chewing, or to the part of the sphenoid bone behind the upper jaw, and/or to the carotid artery near the base of the skull. Cancer may have also spread to one or more lymph nodes of any size, anywhere in the neck.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718360" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVB lip and oral cavity cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718359" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral en estadio IVB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral en estadio IVB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático que mide más de 6 cm. 2) El tumor se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático que mide más de 3 cm del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el cáncer atravesó la capa externa del ganglio linfático al tejido conjuntivo cercano. 3) El tumor se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático de cualquier tamaño que está en el cuello del lado contrario al tumor primario; el cáncer atravesó la capa externa del ganglio linfático y se diseminó al tejido conjuntivo cercano. 4) El tumor se diseminó a varios ganglios linfáticos en cualquier parte del cuello; el cáncer atravesó la capa externa de cualquiera de los ganglios linfáticos y se diseminó al tejido conjuntivo cercano. 5) El tumor se diseminó más adentro a los músculos o los huesos que se usan para masticar, o a la parte del hueso esfenoides detrás del maxilar superior o la arteria carótida cerca de la base del cráneo. También es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de cualquier tamaño en cualquier parte del cuello.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-09-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258017" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/lip-mouth-treatment-pdq">Lip and Oral Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000486932" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-labio-boca-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral en adultos</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
