<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512926">
  <TermName>stage III Merkel cell carcinoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(stayj ... MER-kul sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III Merkel cell cancer is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, (1) the tumor may be any size and may have spread to nearby connective tissue, muscle, cartilage, or bone. A lymph node cannot be felt during a physical exam but cancer is found in the lymph node by sentinel lymph node biopsy or after the lymph node is removed and checked under a microscope for signs of cancer; or (2) a swollen lymph node is felt during a physical exam and/or seen on an imaging test. When the lymph node is removed and checked under a microscope for signs of cancer, cancer is found in the lymph node. The place where the cancer began is not known. In stage IIIB, the tumor may be any size and (1) may have spread to nearby connective tissue, muscle, cartilage, or bone. A swollen lymph node is felt during a physical exam and/or seen on an imaging test. When the lymph node is removed and checked under a microscope for signs of cancer, cancer is found in the lymph node; or (2) cancer is in a lymph vessel between the primary tumor and lymph nodes that are near or far away. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718368" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III Merkel cell carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718367" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, 1) el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible  que se haya diseminado al tejido conjuntivo, el músculo, el cartílago o el hueso cercanos. No se siente un ganglio linfático durante el examen físico, pero se encuentra cáncer en la biopsia de ganglio linfático centinela o después de que se saca el ganglio linfático y se examina al microscopio en busca de signos de cáncer;  o 2) se siente un ganglio linfático hinchado durante el examen físico o se ve en una prueba por imagen. Se encuentra cáncer en el ganglio linfático cuando se saca y se examina al microscopio en busca de signos de cáncer. El lugar donde comienza el cáncer no se conoce. En el  estadio IIIB, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y 1) es posible que se haya diseminado al tejido conjuntivo, el músculo, el cartílago y el hueso cercanos. Se siente un ganglio linfático hinchado durante el examen físico o se ve  en una prueba por imagen. Se encuentra cáncer en el ganglio linfático cuando se saca y se examina al microscopio en busca de signos de cáncer; o 2) hay cáncer en un vaso linfático entre el tumor primario y los ganglios linfáticos cercanos o lejanos. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-01-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000441548" url="/types/skin/patient/merkel-cell-treatment-pdq">Merkel Cell Carcinoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000470863" url="/espanol/tipos/piel/paciente/tratamiento-celulas-de-merkel-pdq">Tratamiento del carcinoma de células de Merkel</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
