<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512908"><TermName>stage IVA lip and oral cavity cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... OR-ul KA-vih-tee KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, the tumor  (1) is larger than 4 centimeters and the deepest point of tumor invasion is greater than 10 millimeters; or cancer has spread to the outer surface of the upper or lower jawbone, into the maxillary sinus, or to the skin of the face. The cancer may have spread to one lymph node that is 3 centimeters or smaller, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor; or (2) is any size or cancer has spread to the outer surface of the upper or lower jawbone, into the maxillary sinus, or to the skin of the face. Cancer has spread (a) to one lymph node that is 3 centimeters or smaller, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor, and cancer has spread through the outside covering of the lymph node into nearby connective tissue; or (b) to one lymph node that is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor; or (c) to multiple lymph nodes that are not larger than 6 centimeters, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor; or (d) to multiple lymph nodes that are not larger than 6 centimeters, on the opposite side of the neck as the primary tumor or on both sides of the neck.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718579" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVA lip and oral cavity cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718581" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral en estadio IVA&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral en estadio IVA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1)  El tumor mide más de 4 cm y se diseminó a más de 10 mm de profundidad,  o el cáncer se diseminó a la superficie externa del maxilar superior o inferior (mandíbula), dentro de los senos paranasales maxilares o a la piel de la cara. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático que mide 3 cm o menos del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario. 2) El tumor es de cualquier tamaño o el cáncer se diseminó a la superficie externa del maxilar superior o inferior (mandíbula), dentro de los senos paranasales maxilares o a la piel de la cara. Además, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático que mide 3 cm o menos del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el cáncer atravesó la capa externa del ganglio linfático y se diseminó al tejido conjuntivo cercano; b) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático que mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 6 cm, del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; c) el cáncer se diseminó a varios ganglios linfáticos que no miden más de 6 cm  del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; d) el cáncer se diseminó a varios ganglios linfáticos que no miden más de 6 cm y están en el cuello del lado contrario al tumor primario o en ambos lados del cuello.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-09-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258017" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/lip-mouth-treatment-pdq">Lip and Oral Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000486932" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-labio-boca-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral en adultos</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
