<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000514453"><TermName>mediastinoscope</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEE-dee-uh-STY-noh-skope)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A thin, tube-like instrument used to examine the tissues and lymph nodes in the area between the lungs. These tissues include the heart and its large blood vessels, trachea, esophagus, and bronchi. The mediastinoscope has a light and a lens for viewing and may also have a tool to remove tissue. It is inserted into the chest through a cut above the breastbone.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718172" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mediastinoscope&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718171" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mediastinoscopio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466554" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopy; shows mediastinoscope with light and lens inserted into the chest through an incision above the breastbone. Drawing shows right and left lungs, trachea, and lymph nodes. Inset shows anterior mediastinotomy (Chamberlain procedure) with incision beside the breastbone." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Mediastinoscopy. A mediastinoscope is inserted into the chest through an
incision above the breastbone to look for abnormal areas between the
lungs. A mediastinoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light
and a lens for viewing. It may also have a cutting tool. Tissue samples
may be taken from lymph nodes on the right side of the chest and checked
under a microscope for signs of cancer. In an anterior mediastinotomy
(Chamberlain procedure), the incision is made beside the breastbone to
remove tissue samples from the lymph nodes on the left side of the
chest.
</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000494346" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopia. En la imagen se observa un mediastinoscopio con una lente y una luz. El mediastinoscopio se introduce en el tórax a través de una incisión por encima del esternón. Se observan el pulmón derecho e izquierdo, la tráquea y los ganglios linfáticos. En el recuadro se muestra una mediastinotomía (procedimiento de Chamberlain)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Mediastinoscopia. Se realiza una incisión (corte) por encima del esternón y se introduce un mediastinoscopio en el tórax para determinar si hay áreas anormales entre los pulmones. Un mediastinoscopio es un instrumento delgado en forma de tubo, con una luz y una lente para observar. A veces tiene una herramienta para cortar. Se toman muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos del lado derecho del tórax para observarlas al microscopio y verificar si hay signos de cáncer. En una mediastinotomía anterior (procedimiento de Chamberlain), se hace una incisión junto al esternón para extraer muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos del lado izquierdo del tórax.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>mediastinoscopio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Instrumento delgado en forma de tubo que se usa para examinar los tejidos y los ganglios linfáticos del área entre los pulmones. Estos tejidos incluyen el corazón y sus vasos sanguíneos principales, la tráquea, el esófago y los bronquios. El mediastinoscopio tiene una luz y una lente para observar, y a veces tiene una herramienta para extirpar tejido. Se introduce a través de una incisión (corte) que se hace por encima del esternón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-02-12</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
