<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000522475"><TermName>IL-1-alpha</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... AL-fuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a group of related proteins made by leukocytes (white blood cells) and other cells in the body. IL-1-alpha, one form of IL-1, is made mainly by one type of white blood cell, the macrophage, and helps another type of white blood cell, the lymphocyte, fight infections. It also helps leukocytes pass through blood vessel walls to sites of infection and causes fever by affecting areas of the brain that control body temperature. The other form of IL-1, IL-1-beta, acts the same as IL-1-alpha. IL-1-alpha made in the laboratory is used as a biological response modifier to boost the immune system in cancer therapy. IL-1-alpha is a type of cytokine.  Also called IL-1-alfa, interleukin-1-alfa, and interleukin-1-alpha.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718109" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;IL-1-alpha&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><SpanishTermName>IL-1-α</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una de las proteínas elaboradas por los leucocitos (glóbulos blancos) y otras células del cuerpo.   La IL-1-α es un tipo de IL-1 que  se produce principalmente en los macrófagos (tipo de glóbulo blanco) para ayudar a los linfocitos (otro tipo de glóbulo blanco) a combatir infecciones.   También ayuda a  que los leucocitos pasen a través de las paredes de los vasos sanguíneos y lleguen a los sitios donde hay infección; además, produce fiebre porque afecta zonas del cerebro que controlan la temperatura. La otra forma de IL-1, la IL-1-β, actúa igual que la IL-1-α. En el laboratorio se produce IL-1-α para usarla como modificador de la respuesta biológica y estimular el sistema inmunitario durante el tratamiento del cáncer. La IL-1-α es un tipo de citocina. También se llama IL-1-alfa, interleucina-1-alfa e interleuquina-1-alfa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-11-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-10-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
