<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000522913"><TermName>IMRT</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>IMRT is a 3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy  planning and delivery tool that shapes the radiation dose distribution and minimizes the dose to normal structures. IMRT implies inverse planning algorithms (i.e., the physician determines radiation treatment parameters to maximize dose to the target and minimize dose to normal tissues, and the planning algorithm maximizes the adherence to these parameters by modifying the beam spatially and/or temporally).  Spatial and temporal beam modification is often achieved by dynamically moving multi-leaf collimators. IMRT can also be achieved via custom-made beam compensators, which are derived from inverse planning algorithms. A novel way to deliver IMRT is tomotherapy, in which a bank of collimated leaves shutter open and closed while rotating around the patient in a spiral manner. The unifying principle of all IMRT planning and delivery methods is inverse planning.  IMRT results in a greater deposition of low doses to normal tissue, which may increase the risk of second malignancies.  Also called intensity-modulated radiation therapy.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of 3-dimensional radiation therapy that uses computer-generated images to show the size and shape of the tumor. Thin beams of radiation of different intensities are aimed at the tumor from many angles. This type of radiation therapy reduces the damage to healthy tissue near the tumor. Also called intensity-modulated radiation therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>RTIM</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>La RTIM es un método de planificación y administración de la radioterapia conformada tridimensional (RTC-3D) que permite dar forma  a la distribución de la dosis de radiación y minimizar la dosis dirigida a las estructuras normales. Para la RTIM se emplean algoritmos de planificación inversa (es decir, el médico determina los parámetros del tratamiento de radiación para potenciar la dosis dirigida al sitio de tratamiento y reducir al mínimo la dosis dirigida a los tejidos normales, además el algoritmo de planificación permite aumentar el cumplimiento de los parámetros al modificar el haz de forma espacial o temporal).   La modificación  espacial o temporal del haz a menudo se logra mediante el movimiento dinámico de los colimadores multiláminas.  La RTIM también se administra  mediante el uso de compensadores de haces hechos a medida a partir de algoritmos de planificación inversa. La tomoterapia es una forma novedosa de administrar la RTIM para la que se usa un banco de láminas colimatadas que se abren y cierran, a la vez que rotan alrededor del paciente como un espiral.  La planificación inversa es el principio unificador de  todos los métodos de  planificación y administración de RTIM.  Este tipo de radioterapia libera dosis bajas al tejido normal, lo que quizás aumente el riesgo de segundas neoplasias malignas. También se llama radioterapia de intensidad modulada.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia tridimensional que usa imágenes creadas por una computadora para mostrar el tamaño y la forma de un tumor. Se dirigen hacia el tumor haces delgados de radiación de diferentes intensidades y desde muchos ángulos. Este tipo de radioterapia reduce el daño al tejido sano que está cerca del tumor. También se llama radioterapia de intensidad modulada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-11-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2006-11-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
