<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000523283"><TermName>anti-IL-6 chimeric monoclonal antibody</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AN-tee ... ky-MEER-ik MAH-noh-KLOH-nul AN-tee-BAH-dee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat a rare condition called multicentric Castleman disease in patients who do not have HIV or human herpesvirus 8. It is also being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer and other conditions. Anti-IL-6 chimeric monoclonal antibody binds to a protein called interleukin-6 (IL-6), which is made by some white blood cells and other cells in the body. Anti-IL-6 chimeric monoclonal antibody may help reduce inflammation and stop the growth of cancer cells or abnormal blood cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody.  Also called cCLB8, CNTO 328, siltuximab, and Sylvant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718451" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anti-IL-6 chimeric monoclonal antibody&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718450" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anticuerpo monoclonal quimérico anti-IL-6&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>anticuerpo monoclonal quimérico anti-IL-6</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar una afección rara que se llama enfermedad de Castleman multicéntrica en pacientes que no tienen el virus de la inmunodeficiencia humana (VIH) ni el virus del herpes humano 8. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer y otras afecciones. El anticuerpo monoclonal quimérico anti-IL-6 se une a una proteína llamada interleucina-6 (IL-6), elaborada por algunos glóbulos blancos y otras células del cuerpo. Es posible que el anticuerpo monoclonal quimérico anti-IL-6 ayude a reducir la inflamación e impida la formación de células cancerosas o de células sanguíneas anormales. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama cCLB8, CNTO 328, siltuximab y Sylvant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-12-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-08-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000760470" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/siltuximab">Siltuximab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
