<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000523438">
  <TermName>fibroadenoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FY-broh-a-deh-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) tumor that most often forms in the breast and is made up of fibrous (connective) tissue and glandular tissue. A fibroadenoma is usually painless. It often feels like a hard, round lump with a smooth, well-defined border that moves easily under the skin of the breast. Fibroadenomas may go away on their own or may need to be removed. They often get smaller after menopause. Fibroadenomas are the most common type of benign breast tumor. They can occur at any age but are more common in younger women. Most fibroadenomas do not increase the risk of breast cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fibroadenoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000718528" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fibroadenoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>fibroadenoma</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso) que se forma con más frecuencia en las mamas (senos) y que se compone de tejido fibroso (conjuntivo) y tejido glandular. El fibroadenoma por lo general no duele. A menudo, se siente como un bulto duro y redondo con un borde liso y bien definido que se mueve con facilidad debajo de la piel de la mama. A veces, los fibroadenomas desaparecen solos y otras veces se deben extirpar. Suelen encogerse después de la menopausia. Los fibroadenomas son los tumores benignos de mama más comunes. Es posible que aparezcan a cualquier edad, pero son más frecuentes en mujeres jóvenes. La mayoría de los fibroadenomas no aumentan el riesgo de cáncer de mama. También se llama adenofibroma y adenoma fibroso.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-01-16</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-08-09</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
