<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000531118"><TermName>CIN</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe abnormal cells that are found on the surface of the cervix when a biopsy is done. CIN is usually caused by infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). CIN is not cancer but may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue. It is graded on a scale of 1 to 3, based on how abnormal the cells look under a microscope and how much of the cervical tissue is affected. For example, CIN 1 has slightly abnormal cells and is less likely to become cancer than CIN 2 or CIN 3. CIN is sometimes called cervical dysplasia. Also called cervical intraepithelial neoplasia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734601" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CIN&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>NIC</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que se usa para indicar que en una biopsia se encontraron células anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. Por lo general, la NIC se debe a una infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). La NIC no es cancerosa, pero a veces se vuelve cancerosa y se disemina al tejido normal cercano. Se clasifica mediante una escala de 1 a 3,  según cuán anormales se vean las células al microscopio y cuánto tejido del cuello uterino se encuentre afectado. Por ejemplo, la NIC 1 tiene células que se ven un poco anormales y es menos probable que se vuelva cancerosa que la NIC 2 o la NIC 3. En ocasiones, la NIC se llama displasia de cuello uterino o displasia cervical. También se llama CIN, neoplasia intraepitelial cervical y NICU.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-19</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-10-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810192" url="/types/cervical/screening/abnormal-hpv-pap-test-results">HPV and Pap Test Results: Next Steps after an Abnormal Cervical Cancer Screening Test</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810505" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion/resultados-anormales-pruebas-vph-pap">Resultados anormales de las pruebas del VPH y de Pap para la detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
