<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000534234"><TermName>charged-particle radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PAR-tih-kul RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Charged particles (such as protons and carbon ions) can be used to deliver therapeutic radiation. A proton is the charged nucleus of a hydrogen atom (hydrogen atom minus an electron).  Standard radiation therapy is delivered with a linear accelerator (LINAC) that delivers photon therapy (akin to high energy light), while protons and other charged particles are generated from a cyclotron. The difference between charged-particle and photon irradiation is that charged particles stop abruptly in the tissue (Bragg peak), so there is less exit dose through normal tissue. A disadvantage of charged-particle radiation therapy is the greater neutron exposure compared with essentially none using photons, and thus the benefit of protons in reducing radiation-associated malignancies is not known and controversial. Proton therapy can be used to deliver intensity-modulated radiation therapy, stereotactic radiation therapy, or stereotactic radiosurgery.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of external radiation therapy that uses a special machine to make invisible, high-energy particles (protons or helium ions) that kill cancer cells. This type of radiation may cause less damage to nearby healthy tissue than radiation therapy with high-energy x-rays.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718701" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;charged-particle radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718700" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia con partículas cargadas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radioterapia con partículas cargadas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Las partículas con carga eléctrica (como los protones y los iones de carbono) se pueden usar para la administración de radiación terapéutica.  Un protón  es el núcleo cargado de un átomo de hidrógeno (un átomo de hidrógeno que pierde un electrón).   La radioterapia estándar se administra con un acelerador lineal (LINAC) que libera terapia con fotones (similar a la luz de alta energía), mientras que los protones y otras partículas cargadas se generan en un ciclotrón.  La diferencia entre la irradiación con partículas cargadas y la irradiación con fotones es que la partículas cargadas se detienen de manera repentina en el tejido (pico de Bragg), de manera que sale menos dosis a través del tejido normal.  Una desventaja de la terapia con partículas cargadas  es la mayor exposición de neutrones en comparación con los fotones, que no producen esta exposición; por lo tanto no se conoce el beneficio de los protones para reducir las neoplasias malignas relacionadas con la radiación y este tema es polémico.  La terapia con protones se usa para administrar radioterapia de intensidad modulada, radioterapia estereotáctica y radiocirugía estereotáctica.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia externa en la que se usa una máquina especial para producir partículas invisibles de alta energía (protones o iones de helio) que destruyen las células cancerosas. Este tipo de radiación ocasiona menos daño al tejido sano cercano que la radioterapia con rayos X de alta energía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-07-06</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
