<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000535555"><TermName>ipilimumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ih-pih-LIH-myoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that binds to the protein CTLA-4 to help immune cells kill cancer cells better and is used to treat many different types of cancer. These include cancers that have certain mutations (changes) in genes involved in DNA repair. Ipilimumab is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of colorectal cancer, esophageal cancer, hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), malignant pleural mesothelioma, melanoma, non-small cell lung cancer, and renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ipilimumab may block CTLA-4 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called MDX-010 and Yervoy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718436" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ipilimumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718435" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ipilimumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ipilimumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se une a la proteína CTLA-4 para ayudar a las células inmunitarias a destruir más células cancerosas, y que se usa para el tratamiento de muchos tipos diferentes de cáncer. Entre ellos, los cánceres que tienen ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en los genes que participan en la reparación del ADN. El ipilimumab se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de esófago, carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), mesotelioma pleural maligno, melanoma, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas y carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Es posible que el ipilimumab bloquee CTLA-4 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama MDX-010 y Yervoy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-02-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-11-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000698294" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ipilimumab">Ipilimumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
