<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000538635">
  <TermName>axitinib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AK-sih-TIH-nib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs to treat advanced renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer). It is used in patients whose cancer has not already been treated or whose cancer has not gotten better after treatment with one other systemic therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Axitinib blocks proteins called growth factor receptors, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow.  Axitinib is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called Inlyta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000703904" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;axitinib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000703903" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;axitinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>axitinib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento del carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón) avanzado. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer todavía no se trató o no  mejoró con otra terapia sistémica. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El axitinib bloquea unas proteínas llamadas receptores de factores de crecimiento, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que también prevenga la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de  inhibidor de
tirosina–cinasas. También se llama Inlyta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-10-04</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-06-11</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000724471" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/axitinib">Axitinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
