<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000556486"><TermName>deleterious mutation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DEH-leh-TEER-ee-us myoo-TAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A genetic alteration that increases an individual’s susceptibility or predisposition to a certain disease or disorder. When such a variant (or mutation) is inherited, development of symptoms is more likely, but not certain.  Also called disease-causing mutation, pathogenic variant, predisposing mutation, and susceptibility gene mutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A change in the DNA sequence of a gene that causes a person to have or be at risk of developing a certain genetic disorder or disease, such as cancer. Deleterious mutations can be inherited from a parent or occur during a person’s lifetime. Knowing if a person has a deleterious mutation may help prevent, diagnose, and treat diseases, such as cancer. Not everyone who has a deleterious mutation will develop the disease. Also called disease-causing mutation, pathogenic variant, predisposing mutation, and susceptibility gene mutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736913" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deleterious mutation&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804258" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mutación deletérea&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mutación deletérea</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Alteración genética que aumenta la susceptibilidad o predisposición de la persona a padecer  ciertas enfermedades o trastornos. Cuando se hereda esta variante o mutación, es más probable que se presenten síntomas, aunque esto no es seguro. También se llama mutación causal de enfermedad, mutación dañina, mutación en gen de susceptibilidad, mutación nociva, mutación perjudicial, mutación predisponente y variante patogénica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio en la secuencia de ADN de un gen que hace que una persona tenga, o esté en riesgo de presentar determinadas enfermedades o trastornos genéticos, como el cáncer. Es posible heredar una mutación deletérea de uno de los padres o que se produzca durante la vida de una persona. Conocer si una persona tiene una mutación deletérea tal vez ayude a prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar enfermedades, como el cáncer. No todas las personas que tienen una mutación deletérea presentarán la enfermedad. También se llama mutación causal de enfermedad, mutación dañina, mutación en gen de susceptibilidad, mutación nociva, mutación perjudicial, mutación predisponente y variante patogénica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-06-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
