<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000556495"><TermName>variant of uncertain significance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VAYR-ee-unt … un-SER-tin sig-NIH-fih-kunts)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A variation in a genetic sequence for which the association with disease risk is unclear.  Also called unclassified variant, variant of unknown significance, and VUS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A change in a gene’s DNA sequence that has an unknown effect on a person’s health. There is usually not enough information about a variant of uncertain significance to know whether it increases a person’s risk of developing a disease, such as cancer. Also called unclassified variant, variant of unknown significance, and VUS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000737003" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;variant of uncertain significance&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804261" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;variante de significación incierta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>variante de significación incierta</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio en la secuencia de ADN de un gen cuyo efecto en la salud no se conoce. Por lo general, no hay suficiente información sobre una variante de significación incierta como para saber si aumenta el riesgo de una persona de presentar una enfermedad, como el cáncer. También se llama variante de significado incierto, variante sin clasificar y VSI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Variación en la secuencia genética que no tiene una asociación definida con el riesgo de presentar una enfermedad. También se llama variante de significado incierto, variante sin clasificar y VSI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-06-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
