<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560136"><TermName>doxorubicin hydrochloride liposome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DOK-soh-ROO-bih-sin HY-droh-KLOR-ide LY-poh-some)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of the anticancer drug doxorubicin that is contained inside very tiny, fat-like particles and is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of ovarian cancer, AIDS-related Kaposi sarcoma, and multiple myeloma. Doxorubicin hydrochloride liposome  may have fewer side effects and work better than other forms of doxorubicin hydrochloride. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Doxorubicin hydrochloride liposome is a type of anthracycline antibiotic and a type of topoisomerase inhibitor. Also called Doxil and liposomal doxorubicin hydrochloride.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720852" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;doxorubicin hydrochloride liposome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720853" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;liposoma de clorhidrato de doxorrubicina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>liposoma de clorhidrato de doxorrubicina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma del medicamento anticanceroso doxorrubicina que se empaca en partículas diminutas parecidas  a la grasa, y que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer de ovario, sarcoma de Kaposi relacionado con el SIDA y mieloma múltiple. Es posible que el liposoma de clorhidrato de doxorrubicina produzca menos efectos secundarios y tal vez sea más eficaz que otras formas de clorhidrato de doxorrubicina. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El liposoma de clorhidrato de doxorrubicina es un antibiótico de tipo antraciclina y es un tipo de inhibidor de la topoisomerasa. También se llama clorhidrato de doxorrubicina liposomal y Doxil.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-07-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000544235" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/doxorubicin-hydrochloride-liposome">Doxorubicin Hydrochloride Liposome</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
