<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560661">
  <TermName>CIN 3</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A cervical biopsy finding that means severely abnormal cells were found on the surface of the cervix. CIN 3 is usually caused by infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). CIN 3 is not cancer but may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue if not treated. Treatment for CIN 3 may include cryotherapy, laser therapy, loop electrosurgical procedure (LEEP), or cone biopsy to remove or destroy the abnormal tissue. CIN 3 is sometimes called high-grade or severe dysplasia. Also called cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 3.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000734561" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CIN 3&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>NIC 3</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Hallazgo de una biopsia cervical que indica la presencia de células muy anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. Por lo general, la causa de la NIC 3 es la infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). La NIC 3 no es cancerosa, pero si no se trata, a veces, se vuelve cancerosa y se disemina al tejido normal cercano. El tratamiento de esta lesión incluye la crioterapia, la terapia láser, la escisión electroquirúrgica con asa y la biopsia de cono para extirpar o destruir el tejido anormal. En ocasiones, se llama displasia de alto grado o displasia grave. También se llama CIN 3, neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 3 y NICU 3.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-09-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-11-03</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810192" url="/types/cervical/screening/abnormal-hpv-pap-test-results">HPV and Pap Test Results: Next Steps after an Abnormal Cervical Cancer Screening Test</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810505" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion/resultados-anormales-pruebas-vph-pap">Resultados anormales de las pruebas del VPH y de Pap para la detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
