<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000561319">
  <TermName>autophagy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(aw-TAH-fuh-jee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A process by
          which a cell breaks down and destroys old, damaged, or
          abnormal proteins and other substances in its cytoplasm
          (the fluid inside a cell). The breakdown products are then
          recycled for important cell functions, especially during
          periods of stress or starvation. Autophagy also helps
          destroy bacteria and viruses that cause infection and may
          prevent normal cells from becoming cancer cells. Once
          cancer has formed, autophagy may protect the cancer cells
          by providing extra nutrients to them or by keeping
          anticancer drugs or other substances from destroying them.
          Autophagy may also affect the body’s immune response
          against viruses, bacteria, and cancer
          cells.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720483" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;autophagy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720482" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;autofagia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>autofagia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proceso por el que la célula descompone y destruye proteínas viejas, dañadas o anormales, y otras sustancias en su citoplasma (líquido en el interior de la célula). Los productos de la descomposición  se reciclan para funciones celulares importantes, en especial durante períodos de estrés o   ayuno. La autofagia también ayuda a destruir virus y bacterias que causan infección y quizás impida que las células normales se vuelvan cancerosas. Una vez que el cáncer se formó, es posible que la autofagia proteja a las células cancerosas brindando nutrientes o impidiendo que los medicamentos contra el cáncer u otras sustancias, las destruyan. La autofagia   quizás afecte la respuesta inmunitaria contra los virus, las bacterias y las células cancerosas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-11-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-08-23</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
