<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000561720">
  <TermName>signaling pathway</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SIG-nuh-ling …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Describes a
          series of chemical reactions in which a group of molecules
          in a cell work together to control a cell function, such as
          cell division or cell death. A cell receives signals from
          its environment when a molecule, such as a hormone or
          growth factor, binds to a specific protein receptor on or
          in the cell. After the first molecule in the pathway
          receives a signal, it activates another molecule. This
          process is repeated through the entire signaling pathway
          until the last molecule is activated and the cell function
          is carried out. Abnormal activation of signaling pathways
          may lead to diseases, such as cancer. Drugs are being
          developed to target specific molecules involved in these
          pathways. These drugs may help keep cancer cells from
          growing.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;signaling pathway&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vía de señalización&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>vía de señalización</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Descripción de una serie de
reacciones químicas en las que
un grupo de
moléculas de la célula
trabajan juntas
para controlar las funciones celulares, como la
multiplicación o la destrucción celular. Las células
reciben señales del entorno cuando una molécula (como una
hormona o factor de crecimiento) se une a una proteína
específica llamada receptor sobre la célula o dentro de
ella. Después de que la primera molécula de la vía de
señalización recibe la señal, se activa otra molécula y este
proceso se repite durante toda la vía de señalización hasta
que la última molécula se activa y cumple con la función
celular. La activación anormal de las vías de señalización
quizás produzca enfermedades, como el cáncer. Se están
elaborando medicamentos que actúan sobre moléculas
específicas que participan en estas vías. Estos
medicamentos quizás eviten la multiplicación de células
cancerosas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-11-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-01-23</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
