<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000562765">
  <TermName>dual energy x-ray absorptiometry</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... EH-ner-jee ... ub-SORP-shee-AH-meh-tree)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that measures the amount of calcium and other minerals in a bone by passing x-rays with two different energy levels through the bone. A dual energy x-ray absorptiometry shows the strength and thickness of a bone and is usually done in the lower spine, hip, lower arm, wrist, fingers, and heel. It is used to diagnose osteoporosis (a condition of lower bone density), to see how well osteoporosis treatments are working, and to predict how likely the bones are to break. A dual energy x-ray absorptiometry also measures fat and muscle composition in specific parts of the body, such as the arms, legs, and pelvis. Also called BMD scan, bone densitometry, bone mineral density scan, DEXA scan, and DXA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000721101" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dual energy x-ray absorptiometry&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000721102" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;absorciometría de rayos X de energía dual&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/>
  <SpanishTermName>absorciometría de rayos X de energía dual</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento que mide la cantidad de calcio y otros minerales que hay en un hueso al pasar rayos X con dos grados diferentes de energía a través de él. Además, la absorciometría de rayos X de energía dual muestra la fuerza y el grosor de un hueso y suele realizarse en la parte inferior de la columna vertebral, la cadera, el antebrazo, la muñeca, los dedos y el talón. Asimismo, se usa para diagnosticar la osteoporosis (afección por la que disminuye la densidad de los huesos), con el fin de ver cómo funcionan los tratamientos contra la osteoporosis y para predecir la probabilidad de que los huesos se rompan. Este procedimiento también mide la composición de la grasa y los músculos en partes específicas del cuerpo, como los brazos, las piernas o la pelvis. También se llama absorciometría dual de rayos X, densitometría ósea, DEXA, DO, DXA, prueba de la densidad mineral ósea y radioabsorciometría de doble energía.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-08-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-03-15</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
