<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000564157"><TermName>cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul SKWAY-mus IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cervical biopsy finding that means slightly abnormal cells were found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1 is usually caused by infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1 is not cancer and usually goes away on its own without treatment, but sometimes it can become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1 is sometimes called low-grade or mild dysplasia. Also called CIN 1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720814" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720815" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hallazgo de una biopsia cervical que indica la presencia de células un poco anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. Por lo general, la causa de la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1 es la infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1 no es cancerosa y es frecuente que desaparezca sin tratamiento, pero a veces se vuelve cancerosa y se disemina al tejido normal cercano. En ocasiones, se llama displasia de bajo grado o displasia leve. También se llama neoplasia intraepitelial cervicouterina escamosa de grado 1, neoplasia intraepitelial escamosa de cuello uterino de grado 1 y NIC 1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-08-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-11-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810192" url="/types/cervical/screening/abnormal-hpv-pap-test-results">HPV and Pap Test Results: Next Steps after an Abnormal Cervical Cancer Screening Test</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810505" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion/resultados-anormales-pruebas-vph-pap">Resultados anormales de las pruebas del VPH y de Pap para la detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
