<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000572255">
  <TermName>dexrazoxane hydrochloride</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(DEX-ruh-ZOK-sane HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat severe side effects caused by certain types of anticancer drugs. It is used under the brand names Totect and Zinecard to reduce heart damage in women who are receiving doxorubicin for breast cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is also used under the brand name Totect to treat the toxic effects of an anticancer drug that leaks from a vein into surrounding tissue and causes tissue damage.  Dexrazoxane hydrochloride is also being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. It is a type of cardioprotective agent, a type of chemoprotective agent, and a type of topoisomerase inhibitor. Dexrazoxane is the active ingredient of dexrazoxane hydrochloride.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720796" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dexrazoxane hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720797" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de dexrazoxano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de dexrazoxano</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de los efectos secundarios graves de ciertos tipos de medicamentos contra el cáncer. Se usa bajo las marcas comerciales Totect y Zinecard con el fin de reducir el daño en el corazón de mujeres que reciben doxorrubicina para un cáncer de mama que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También se utiliza bajo la marca comercial Totect para tratar los efectos tóxicos que se producen cuando un medicamento contra el cáncer sale de una vena y daña los tejidos cercanos. Además, el clorhidrato de dexrazoxano está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Es un tipo de cardioprotector, de quimioprotector y de inhibidor de la topoisomerasa. El dexrazoxano es el principio activo del clorhidrato de dexrazoxano. También se llama hidrocloruro de dexrazoxano.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2007-10-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-03-26</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000570125" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/dexrazoxanehydrochloride">Dexrazoxane Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
