<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000589395"><TermName>cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2/3</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul SKWAY-mus IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cervical biopsy finding that means a mix of moderately abnormal and severely abnormal cells were found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2/3 has features of both CIN 2 and CIN 3. It is usually caused by infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2/3 is not cancer but may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue if not treated. Treatment for cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2/3 may include cryotherapy, laser therapy, loop electrosurgical procedure (LEEP), or cone biopsy to remove or destroy the abnormal tissue. Also called CIN 2/3.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721105" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2/3&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721106" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2 y 3&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2 y 3</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hallazgo de una biopsia cervical que indica la presencia de células moderadamente anormales  y células muy anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. Esta neoplasia comparte características de dos tipos de neoplasias intraepiteliales cervicales escamosas, de grado  2 y de grado 3. Por lo general, esta neoplasia se forma como resultado de   la infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH), y aunque no es cancerosa, si  no se  trata, a veces, se vuelve cancerosa y se disemina al tejido normal cercano. El tratamiento incluye la crioterapia, la terapia láser, la escisión electroquirúrgica con asa y la  biopsia de cono para extirpar o destruir el tejido anormal. También se llama neoplasia intraepitelial cervicouterina de grado 2/3, neoplasia intraepitelial de cuello uterino de grado 2/3 y NIC 2 y 3.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-03-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-11-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810192" url="/types/cervical/screening/abnormal-hpv-pap-test-results">HPV and Pap Test Results: Next Steps after an Abnormal Cervical Cancer Screening Test</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810505" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion/resultados-anormales-pruebas-vph-pap">Resultados anormales de las pruebas del VPH y de Pap para la detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
