<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000597170">
  <TermName>signal transduction</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SIG-nul tranz-DUK-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The process by which a cell responds to substances outside the cell through signaling molecules found on the surface of and inside the cell. Most molecules that lead to signal transduction are chemical substances, such as hormones, neurotransmitters, and growth factors, that bind to a specific protein receptor (signaling molecule) on or in a cell. The signals are then passed from one molecule to another inside the cell, which results in a specific cell response, such as cell division or cell death. Signal transduction is important for cells to grow and work normally. Cells that have abnormal signaling molecules may become cancer cells. Also called cell signaling.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720974" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;signal transduction&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720975" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;transducción de la señal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>transducción de la señal</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proceso por el que la célula responde a sustancias del exterior de la célula mediante moléculas de señalización que están en la superficie de la célula o dentro de ella. La mayoría de las moléculas  que participan en la transducción de la señal son sustancias químicas, como hormonas, neurotransmisores y factores de crecimiento que se unen a proteínas específicas llamadas receptores (moléculas de señalización) sobre la célula o dentro de ella. Las señales pasan de una molécula  a otra en el interior de la célula, lo que produce una respuesta celular específica, como multiplicación o destrucción celular. La  transducción de la señal es importante para el  crecimiento y funcionamiento celular normal. Las células que tienen moléculas de señalización celular anormales a veces se vuelven células cancerosas. También se llama señalización celular, transducción de señales y transmisión de señales.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2008-05-30</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-01-23</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
