<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000600466"><TermName>methylnaltrexone bromide</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEH-thul-nal-TREK-sone BROH-mide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to relieve constipation caused by the use of opioids (pain killers that are like morphine). It is used in adults with pain caused by cancer or treatment for cancer or by other advanced disease. Methylnaltrexone bromide binds to opioid receptors outside the brain and may block the side effects of opioid drugs without affecting their ability to relieve pain. Methylnaltrexone bromide is a type of peripheral opioid receptor antagonist. Also called Relistor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720631" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;methylnaltrexone bromide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720630" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bromuro de metilnaltrexona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>bromuro de metilnaltrexona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para
aliviar el estreñimiento que provoca el uso de opioides (analgésicos similares a la morfina). Se utiliza en adultos que reciben opoides para el dolor que causa el cáncer o su tratamiento o debido a otras enfermedades en estadio avanzado. El bromuro de metilnaltrexona se une a los receptores de opioides fuera del encéfalo y es posible que bloquee los efectos secundarios de los opioides sin afectar su capacidad de aliviar el dolor. El bromuro de metilnaltrexona es un tipo de antagonista del receptor periférico de opioides. También se llama Relistor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-07-18</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-07-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000786562" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/methylnaltrexonebromide">Methylnaltrexone Bromide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
