<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000612891">
  <TermName>stage III ovarian low malignant potential tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… oh-VAYR-ee-un...muh-LIG-nunt poh-TEN-shul TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The tumor is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes, or is primary peritoneal cancer, and has spread outside the pelvis to other parts of the abdomen and/or to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum (the tissue that lines the abdominal wall and covers most of the organs in the abdomen). Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, one of the following is true: (1) the tumor has spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum only; or (2) tumor cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum (a fold of the peritoneum that surrounds the stomach and other organs in the abdomen). The tumor may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum. In stage IIIB, the tumor has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum, and the tumor in the peritoneum is 2 centimeters or smaller. The tumor may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum. In stage IIIC, the tumor has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, such as the omentum, and the tumor in the peritoneum is larger than 2 centimeters. The tumor may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum or to the surface of the liver or spleen. Also called stage III ovarian borderline tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000720667" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III ovarian low malignant potential tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor de ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio III</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El tumor se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios, o  en una o ambas trompas de Falopio, o es cáncer primario de peritoneo que se diseminó fuera de la pelvis a otras partes del abdomen o a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo (tejido que reviste la pared abdominal y recubre la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen). El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB, y  IIIC. En el estadio lllA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones:  1) el tumor se diseminó solo a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del  peritoneo;  2) las células cancerosas, que solo son visibles al microscopio, se diseminaron a la superficie del peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, por ejemplo, al epiplón (pliegue del peritoneo que rodea el estómago y otros órganos del abdomen).  Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo. En el estadio lllB, el tumor se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, por ejemplo,  al epiplón, y el tumor en el peritoneo mide 2 cm o menos. Es posible que el tumor se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás de peritoneo. En el estadio lllC, el tumor se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis, por ejemplo, al epiplón, y el tumor en el peritoneo mide más de 2 centímetros. Es posible que el tumor se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo, o a la superficie del  hígado o  el bazo. También se llama tumor limítrofe de ovario en estadio III.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2008-08-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2025-03-12</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062968" url="/types/ovarian/patient/ovarian-low-malignant-treatment-pdq">Ovarian Borderline Tumors Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256839" url="/espanol/tipos/ovario/paciente/tratamiento-ovario-bajo-potencial-maligno-pdq">Tratamiento de los tumores limítrofes de ovario</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
