<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000613891"><TermName>[18F]-labeled substance P antagonist receptor quantifier</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… LAY-buld SUB-stunts P an-TA-guh-nist reh-SEP-ter KWAN-tih-FY-er)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A radiolabeled substance being studied in PET imaging of the brain. It is also being studied as a way to find where cancer cells have spread in patients with pancreatic cancer. It binds to cell receptors for substance P, also known as neurokinin-1, which is found on nerve cells and on some types of cancer cells, such as pancreatic cancer cells. [18F]-labeled substance P antagonist receptor quantifier is a type of PET radioligand and a type of radiolabeled neurokinin-1 receptor antagonist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720864" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;[18F]-labeled substance P antagonist receptor quantifier&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720865" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;[18F]-cuantificador del receptor del antagonista de la sustancia P marcado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>[18F]-cuantificador del receptor del antagonista de la sustancia P marcado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia radiomarcada en estudio para su uso en imágenes del encéfalo obtenidas mediante TEP. También está en estudio para detectar la diseminación de células cancerosas en pacientes con cáncer de páncreas. Se une a los receptores celulares de la neurocinina-1 y la sustancia P, que se encuentran en las células nerviosas y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, como las células del cáncer de páncreas. El [18F]-cuantificador del receptor del antagonista de la sustancia P marcado es un tipo de radioligando de TEP y de antagonista del receptor de  neurocinina-1 radiomarcado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-09-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-01-13</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
