<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000615419">
  <TermName>SCID</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disease that is marked by a lack of B lymphocytes (white blood cells that make antibodies and help fight infections) and a lack of T lymphocytes (white blood cells that attack virus-infected cells, foreign cells, and cancer cells). Patients with this disease have a high risk of developing viral, bacterial, and fungal infections. Also called severe combined immunodeficiency disease.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000734742" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;SCID&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>IDCG</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Enfermedad hereditaria rara que se caracteriza por la falta de linfocitos B (glóbulos blancos que elaboran anticuerpos y ayudan a luchar contra las infecciones) y  linfocitos T (glóbulos blancos que atacan a las células infectadas por virus, células extrañas y células cancerosas). Los pacientes con esta enfermedad tienen un riesgo alto de contraer infecciones por virus, bacterias y hongos. También se llama EICG y enfermedad de inmunodeficiencia combinada grave.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2008-09-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7628/severe-combined-immunodeficiency">Severe combined immunodeficiency (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13312/inmunodeficiencia-combinada-grave">Inmunodeficiencia combinada grave (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
