<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000616128"><TermName>granisetron hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(gra-NIH-seh-tron HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to prevent nausea and vomiting caused by chemotherapy and radiation therapy and to prevent and treat nausea and vomiting after surgery in adults. Granisetron hydrochloride blocks the action of a chemical called serotonin, which binds to certain nerves and may trigger nausea and vomiting. Blocking serotonin may help lessen nausea and vomiting. Granisetron hydrochloride is a type of antiemetic and a type of serotonin receptor antagonist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721169" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;granisetron hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721170" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de granisetrón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de granisetrón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para prevenir las náuseas y los vómitos que causan la quimioterapia y la radioterapia. También se usa en adultos para prevenir y tratar las náuseas y los vómitos después de una cirugía. El clorhidrato de granisetrón bloquea la acción de la sustancia química serotonina, que se une a ciertos nervios,   y quizás provoque náuseas y vómitos. Es posible que el bloqueo de la serotonina ayude a disminuir las náuseas y los vómitos. El clorhidrato de granisetrón es un tipo de antagonista del receptor de serotonina y un antiemético. También se llama hidrocloruro de granisetrón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-10-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-07-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000793696" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/granisetronhydrochloride">Granisetron Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
