<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000618614">
  <TermName>risk ratio</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… RAY-shee-oh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A measure of the risk of a certain event happening in one group compared to the risk of the same event happening in another group. In cancer research, risk ratios are used in prospective (forward looking) studies, such as cohort studies and clinical trials. A risk ratio of one means there is no difference between two groups in terms of their risk of cancer, based on whether or not they were exposed to a certain substance or factor, or how they responded to two treatments being compared. A risk ratio of greater than one or of less than one usually means that being exposed to a certain substance or factor either increases (risk ratio greater than one) or decreases (risk ratio less than one) the risk of cancer, or that the treatments being compared do not have the same effects. Also called relative risk.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722527" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;risk ratio&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722528" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cociente de riesgos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cociente de riesgos</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medida del riesgo de que suceda algo en determinado grupo de personas que se compara con otro grupo. En el campo de la investigación del cáncer, el cociente de riesgos (CR) se usa en los estudios prospectivos (seguimiento hacia el futuro), como los estudios de cohorte y los ensayos clínicos. Un CR igual a 1 significa que no hay diferencia en el riesgo de cáncer entre los dos grupos a partir de la exposición o la ausencia de exposición a un factor determinado (por ejemplo, exposición a una sustancia), o según la respuesta a tratamientos en estudio que se comparan entre sí. Un CR mayor o menor a 1 significa que la exposición a cierto factor aumenta (CR &gt;1) o disminuye (CR &lt;1) el riesgo de contraer cáncer, o que hay diferencias en el efecto de los tratamientos en estudio. También se llama razón de riesgos y riesgo relativo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2008-10-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
