<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000618610"><TermName>odds ratio</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… RAY-shee-oh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A measure of the odds of an event happening in one group compared to the odds of the same event happening in another group. In cancer research, odds ratios are most often used in case-control (backward looking) studies to find out if being exposed to a certain substance or other factor increases the risk of cancer. For example, researchers may study a group of individuals with cancer (cases) and another group without cancer (controls) to see how many people in each group were exposed to a certain substance or factor. They calculate the odds of exposure in both groups and then compare the odds. An odds ratio of one means that both groups had the same odds of exposure and, therefore, the exposure probably does not increase the risk of cancer. An odds ratio of greater than one means that the exposure may increase the risk of cancer, and an odds ratio of less than one means that the exposure may reduce the risk of cancer. Also called relative odds.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722520" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;odds ratio&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722519" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oportunidad relativa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>oportunidad relativa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medida de la posibilidad de que una situación suceda en un grupo, en comparación con la posibilidad de que la misma situación suceda en otro grupo. En la investigación del cáncer, la oportunidad relativa se utiliza con mayor frecuencia en los estudios de casos y controles (en los que se observa el pasado) para determinar si la exposición a cierta sustancia u otro factor aumenta el riesgo de cáncer. Por ejemplo, los investigadores estudian un grupo de personas  con cáncer (casos), lo comparan con otro grupo de personas sin cáncer (controles o testigos) y determinan cuántas personas de cada grupo estuvieron expuestas a cierta sustancia o factor. Luego calculan la posibilidad de exposición en cada grupo y las comparan. Una oportunidad relativa igual a 1 significa que la posibilidad de exposición fue igual en ambos grupos y, por consiguiente, la exposición probablemente no aumenta el riesgo de cáncer. Una oportunidad relativa mayor que 1 significa que la exposición quizás aumente el riesgo de cáncer y una oportunidad relativa menor que 1 significa que la exposición quizás reduce el riesgo de cáncer. También se llama cociente de probabilidad, probabilidad relativa, razón de momios, razón de posibilidades, razón de probabilidades y razón de productos cruzados.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-10-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
