<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000628802">
  <TermName>eltrombopag olamine</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(el-TROM-boh-pag OH-luh-meen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat thrombocytopenia (a low blood platelet count) in adults and children with chronic immune thrombocytopenic purpura that did not get better with other treatment. Eltrombopag olamine is also used to treat severe aplastic anemia. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Eltrombopag olamine binds to the thrombopoietin receptor, which causes the bone marrow to make more platelets. It is a type of thrombopoietin receptor agonist. Also called Promacta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722495" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eltrombopag olamine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722496" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eltrombopag olamina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>eltrombopag olamina</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de la trombocitopenia (concentración baja de plaquetas en la sangre) en adultos y en determinados niños con púrpura trombocitopénica inmunitaria crónica que no mejoró con otros tratamientos. El eltrombopag olamina también se usa para tratar la anemia aplásica grave. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. El eltrombopag olamina se une al receptor de
la trombopoyetina y hace que la médula ósea elabore más plaquetas. Es un tipo de agonista del receptor de la trombopoyetina. También se llama Promacta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2008-12-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-05-18</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000626822" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/eltrombopagolamine">Eltrombopag Olamine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
