<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000632152"><TermName>daunomycin hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DAW-noh-MY-sin HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that comes from the bacterium <ScientificName>Streptomyces coeruleorubidus</ScientificName> and is  used with other drugs as remission induction therapy to treat adults with acute myeloid leukemia and adults and children with acute lymphoblastic leukemia. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Daunomycin hydrochloride blocks a certain enzyme needed for cell division and DNA repair and may kill cancer cells. It is a type of anthracycline antibiotic and a type of topoisomerase inhibitor. Daunorubicin is the active ingredient of daunorubicin hydrochloride. Also called daunorubicin hydrochloride.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000723110" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;daunomycin hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000723111" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de daunomicina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de daunomicina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se obtiene de la bacteria <ScientificName>Streptomyces coeruleorubidus</ScientificName> y se usa con otros medicamentos como terapia de inducción a la remisión durante el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia mieloide aguda, y el tratamiento de adultos y niños con leucemia linfoblástica aguda. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de daunomicina bloquea cierta enzima necesaria para la multiplicación celular y la reparación del ADN, y es posible que destruya células cancerosas. Es un antibiótico de tipo antraciclina y un tipo de
inhibidor de la topoisomerasa. La daunorrubicina es el principio activo del clorhidrato de daunorrubicina. También se llama clorhidrato de daunorrubicina e hidrocloruro de daunomicina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-02-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000649927" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/daunorubicinhydrochloride">Daunorubicin Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
