<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000634125">
  <TermName>premature menopause</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PREE-muh-CHOOR MEH-nuh-pawz)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which the ovaries stop working and menstrual periods stop before age 40. This can cause fertility problems and symptoms of menopause. There are two types of premature menopause, primary and secondary. Primary premature menopause means that the ovaries do not function normally. This may be because they have been removed by surgery, or it may be caused by some cancer treatments and certain diseases or genetic conditions. In secondary premature menopause, the ovaries are normal but there is a problem getting hormone signals to them from the brain. This is usually caused by diseases of the pituitary gland or hypothalamus. Some women with premature menopause sometimes have menstrual periods and may be able to have children. Also called early menopause, ovarian failure, and ovarian insufficiency.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000723098" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;premature menopause&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000723099" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;menopausia prematura&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>menopausia prematura</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que los ovarios dejan de funcionar y se detiene la menstruación antes de los 40 años. Esto puede causar problemas de reproducción y síntomas de menopausia.  Hay dos tipos de menopausia prematura: primaria y secundaria. Cuando se presenta menopausia prematura primaria los ovarios no funcionan de manera normal; es posible que esto se deba a que los ovarios se extirparon mediante cirugía o por efecto de algunos tratamientos contra el cáncer, y determinadas enfermedades o afecciones genéticas.  En la menopausia prematura secundaria, los ovarios son normales, pero tienen un problema para recibir las señales hormonales que les llegan desde el encéfalo. Por lo general, las causas son enfermedades de la hipófisis o el hipotálamo. En ocasiones, algunas mujeres con menopausia prematura tienen periodos menstruales y pueden tener hijos. También se llama insuficiencia del ovario, insuficiencia ovárica y menopausia precoz.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2009-02-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-women" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Girls and Women with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-mujeres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en las mujeres con cáncer: niñas y adultas</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
