<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635457"><TermName>HIPAA</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HIH-puh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A 1996 U.S. law that allows workers and their families to keep their health insurance when they change or lose their jobs. The privacy rule of the HIPAA protects the privacy of a person’s health information and keeps it from being misused. It gives people the right to receive and review their health records and to choose with whom their health care providers and health insurance companies share their information (including friends, family members, and caregivers). The law also includes standards for setting up and maintaining secure electronic health records. Also called Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act and Kassebaum Kennedy Act.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722748" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HIPAA&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722747" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HIPAA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>HIPAA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Ley de los Estados Unidos de 1996 que permite al trabajador y su familia conservar su seguro médico cuando cambia de trabajo o queda desempleado.   La norma de confidencialidad de la Ley de Portabilidad y Responsabilidad de Seguros Médicos (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act, HIPAA) protege los datos médicos personales y evita su uso indebido. Otorga a la persona el derecho a solicitar y examinar su historia clínica e indicar a los proveedores de atención de la salud y las compañías aseguradoras a quiénes pueden divulgar esta información (incluso amigos, parientes y cuidadores). La ley también fija normas de seguridad para establecer y mantener los registros electrónicos sobre la salud de la persona. También se llama Ley de Portabilidad y Responsabilidad de Seguros Médicos y Ley Kassebaum Kennedy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-02-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
