<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635764">
  <TermName>5-fluorouracil</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(5-FLOOR-oh-YOOR-uh-sil)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug given as an injection to treat cancers of the breast, colon, rectum, stomach, and pancreas and as a cream to treat actinic keratosis (a skin condition that may become cancer) and certain types of basal cell skin cancer. It is used under the brand names Carac, Tolak, Efudex, and Fluoroplex to treat actinic keratosis. It is also used under the brand name Efudex to treat basal cell skin cancer. 5-fluorouracil is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. It stops cells from making DNA and may kill cancer cells. 5-fluorouracil is a type of antimetabolite. Also called 5-FU and fluorouracil.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722856" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;5-fluorouracil&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722855" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;5-fluorouracilo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>5-fluorouracilo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se administra por inyección para el tratamiento de cánceres de mama, colon, recto, estómago y páncreas. Además, se usa en forma de crema para el tratamiento de la queratosis actínica (afección de la piel que en ocasiones se vuelve cáncer) y ciertos tipos de cáncer de piel de células basales. Para la queratosis actínica, se usa bajo las marcas comerciales Carac, Tolak, Efudex y Fluoroplex, y para  el cáncer de piel de células basales, se usa bajo la marca comercial  Efudex.  El 5-fluorouracilo también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras enfermedades y tipos de cáncer.  Impide que las células elaboren ADN y es posible que destruya células cancerosas.  El 5-fluorouracilo es un tipo de antimetabolito.  También se llama 5-FU y fluorouracilo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2009-02-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-12-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000537894" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/fluorouracil">Fluorouracil Injection </RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000778112" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/fluorouracil-topical">Fluorouracil (Topical)</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
