<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000637711"><TermName>EZN-2285</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat acute lymphoblastic leukemia in children and young adults aged 1 month to 21 years.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  EZN-2285 is made up of the enzyme L-asparaginase that is linked to a substance called SC-PEG, which makes the drug stay in the body longer. L-asparaginase comes from the bacterium <ScientificName>E. coli</ScientificName> and breaks down the amino acid asparagine. This may stop the growth of cancer cells that need asparagine to grow. EZN-2285  is a type of  protein synthesis inhibitor. Also called Asparlas, calaspargase pegol, and SC-PEG E. coli L-asparaginase.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>EZN-2285</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de la leucemia linfoblástica aguda en niños y adultos jóvenes (1 mes a 21 años de edad). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. EZN-2285 contiene la enzima L-asparaginasa unida a una sustancia llamada SC-PEG que permite que el medicamento permanezca más tiempo en el cuerpo. La L-asparaginasa se obtiene de la bacteria <ScientificName>E. coli</ScientificName> y su función es descomponer el aminoácido asparagina.    Es posible que de esta manera se detenga la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan asparaginasa para multiplicarse. EZN-2285 es un tipo de inhibidor de la síntesis de proteínas. También se llama Asparlas, calaspargasa pegol y L-asparaginasa de E. coli con SC-PEG.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-03-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000796477" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/calaspargasepegol-mknl">Calaspargase Pegol-mknl</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
