<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000639508">
  <TermName>leptomeningeal carcinoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LEP-toh-meh-NIN-jee-ul KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A serious condition in which cancer cells spread from the original (primary) tumor to the meninges (the thin layers of tissue that cover and protect the brain and spinal cord). This can cause the meninges to become inflamed and cerebrospinal fluid and pressure to build up in the brain. Leptomeningeal carcinoma can happen in many types of cancer, but it is most common in people with breast cancer, lung cancer, or melanoma. Also called carcinomatous meningitis, leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, leptomeningeal metastasis, meningeal carcinomatosis, meningeal metastasis, and neoplastic meningitis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722728" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leptomeningeal carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722727" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma leptomeníngeo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma leptomeníngeo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección grave por la que las células cancerosas se diseminan desde el tumor original (primario) a las meninges (capas delgadas de tejido que cubren y protegen el encéfalo y la médula espinal). Esto produce inflamación de las meninges y acumulación del líquido cerebroespinal de manera que aumenta la presión dentro del encéfalo. El carcinoma leptomeníngeo se puede presentar en muchos tipos de cáncer, pero es más común en las personas con cáncer de mama, cáncer de pulmón o  melanoma. También se llama carcinomatosis leptomeníngea, carcinomatosis meníngea, meningitis carcinomatosa, meningitis neoplásica, metástasis en las leptomeninges y metástasis en las meninges.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2009-03-30</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-05-05</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
