<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000639749">
  <TermName>Afinitor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(uh-FIH-nih-tor)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient everolimus and is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of breast cancer, kidney cancer, and pancreatic, lung, and gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors.  Afinitor is also used to treat a type of benign kidney tumor called renal angiomyolipoma and a type of benign brain tumor called subependymal giant cell astrocytoma in patients who have tuberous sclerosis. Afinitor blocks a protein involved in cell division, which may help keep abnormal cells, including cancer cells, from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Afinitor is a type of kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722800" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Afinitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000722799" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Afinitor&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Afinitor</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo everólimus y se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de determinados tipos de cáncer de mama, cáncer de riñón, tumores de páncreas, tumores de pulmón y tumores neuroendocrinos gastrointestinales. Afinitor también se usa para el tratamiento de un tipo de tumor benigno de riñón llamado angiomiolipoma renal  y un tipo de tumor benigno de encéfalo llamado astrocitoma subependimario de células gigantes en pacientes con esclerosis tuberosa. Afinitor bloquea una proteína que participa en la división celular, lo que tal vez ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso las células cancerosas. Es posible que además impida la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Afinitor es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas y de inhibidor de la angiogénesis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2009-04-03</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-05-18</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000640318" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/everolimus">Everolimus</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
