<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000640046"><TermName>lymphostatic elephantiasis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lim-foh-STA-tik EH-luh-fun-TY-uh-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A chronic condition marked by extreme swelling in an arm, leg, or other part of the body caused by a buildup of lymph in the tissues. The skin of the affected area usually feels hard and thick and may be darker in color. There may also be decreased mobility in the affected area. Lymphostatic elephantiasis can occur when lymph vessels or nodes become damaged or blocked, which affects the flow of lymph in the body. This is most commonly caused by cancer or cancer treatment, such as surgery or radiation therapy. Lymphostatic elephantiasis is considered the most advanced stage of lymphedema. Also called stage III lymphedema.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722969" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphostatic elephantiasis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722968" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;elefantiasis linfostática&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>elefantiasis linfostática</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección crónica caracterizada por una hinchazón excesiva en un brazo, pierna u otra parte del cuerpo; la causa es la acumulación de linfa en los tejidos.  Por lo general, la piel del área afectada se siente dura y gruesa, además de tener un color más oscuro. También es posible que haya menos movilidad en esa zona. La elefantiasis linfostática ocurre cuando los vasos o los ganglios linfáticos se dañan o bloquean, lo que afecta al flujo de la linfa por el cuerpo. Las causas más frecuentes son el cáncer o  los tratamientos como la cirugía o la radioterapia. La elefantiasis linfostática se considera el estadio más avanzado del linfedema. También se llama linfedema en estadio III.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-07-02</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-03-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
