<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000641943"><TermName>Cowden disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOW-den dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare inherited disorder marked by the presence of many benign (not cancer) growths called hamartomas and an increased risk of cancer. Hamartomas form in different parts of the body, especially the skin, mouth, and gastrointestinal tract. Other benign tumors may also occur in the thyroid, breast, uterus, soft tissue, and brain. Other signs and symptoms include a larger-than-average head, abnormal skin changes, blood vessel problems, autism spectrum disorder, and learning and developmental delays. People with Cowden disease have an increased risk of developing certain types of cancer, including melanoma and cancers of the breast, thyroid, endometrium, kidney, colon, and rectum. Cowden disease is usually caused by mutations (changes) in the PTEN gene. Also called Cowden syndrome and multiple hamartoma syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722876" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cowden disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722875" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad de Cowden&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad de Cowden</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro que se caracteriza por  la formación de muchos  tumores benignos (no cancerosos) llamados hamartomas y un aumento del riesgo de cáncer. Los hamartomas se forman en diferentes partes del cuerpo, sobre todo en la piel, la boca y el tubo digestivo. A veces, también se forman tumores benignos en la tiroides, la mama, el útero, el tejido blando y el encéfalo. Otros signos y síntomas incluyen una cabeza más grande que lo normal, cambios anormales en la piel, problemas en los vasos sanguíneos, trastornos del espectro autista, y retrasos en el aprendizaje y el desarrollo. Las personas con este trastorno tienen más riesgo de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el melanoma y  los cánceres de mama, tiroides, endometrio, riñón, colon y recto. Por lo general, la causa de la enfermedad de Cowden son  mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>PTEN</GeneName>. También se llama síndrome de Cowden y síndrome de hamartoma múltiple.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-10-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6202/cowden-syndrome">Cowden syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/cowden-syndrome/">Cowden syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13194/sindrome-de-cowden">Síndrome de Cowden (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
