<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000644330">
  <TermName>recombinant interferon alfa-2b</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ree-KOM-bih-nunt in-ter-FEER-on AL-fuh …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with AIDS-related Kaposi sarcoma, hairy cell leukemia, certain types of follicular lymphoma or melanoma, genital warts or perianal warts, or chronic hepatitis B or C. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer and other conditions.  Recombinant interferon alfa-2b is a form of interferon alfa (a substance normally made by cells in the immune system) that is made in the laboratory.  It is a type of cytokine and a type of immunomodulating agent. Also called IFN alpha-2B, interferon alfa-2b, and Intron A.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000726079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;recombinant interferon alfa-2b&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000726078" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;interferón alfa 2b recombinante&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>interferón alfa 2b recombinante</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento en adultos con sarcoma de Kaposi relacionado con el SIDA, leucemia de células pilosas, ciertos tipos de linfoma folicular o melanoma, verrugas genitales, verrugas perianales y hepatitis B o C crónica. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer y otras afecciones. El interferón alfa 2b recombinante es una forma de interferón alfa (sustancia que normalmente se produce en las células del sistema inmunitario) que se elabora en el laboratorio. Es un tipo de citocina y de inmunomodulador. También se llama IFN alfa 2B, interferón alfa 2b e Intron A.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2009-10-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-06-02</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000744420" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/recombinant-interferon-alfa-2b">Recombinant Interferon Alfa-2b</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
