<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000648595">
  <TermName>Syk kinase inhibitor R-935788</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(sik KY-nays in-HIH-bih-ter …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat thrombocytopenia (a low blood platelet count) in adults with chronic immune thrombocytopenia (ITP) that did not get better with other treatment. ITP is a condition in which platelets are destroyed by the immune system. Syk kinase inhibitor R-935788 is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. It blocks an enzyme called Syk, which may help keep the immune system from destroying platelets.  Syk kinase inhibitor R-935788 is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called fostamatinib disodium, R788 sodium, and Tavalisse.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000726159" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Syk kinase inhibitor R-935788&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000726158" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de la cinasa Syk R-935788&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>inhibidor de la cinasa Syk R-935788</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de la trombocitopenia (concentración baja de plaquetas) en adultos con trombocitopenia inmunitaria crónica que no mejoró con otro tratamiento. La trombocitopenia inmunitaria es una afección por la que el sistema inmunitario destruye las plaquetas. El inhibidor de la cinasa Syk R-935788 también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. Bloquea una enzima llamada Syk, lo que quizás ayude a evitar que el sistema inmunitario destruya las plaquetas. El inhibidor de la cinasa Syk R-935788 es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama fostamatinib disódico, inhibidor de la quinasa Syk  R-935788, R788 sódico y Tavalisse.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2010-01-11</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-10-21</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
