<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000652256"><TermName>KRAS gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAY-ras jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene that makes a protein that is involved in cell signaling pathways that control cell growth, cell maturation, and cell death. The natural, unchanged form of the gene is called wild-type <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName>.  Mutated (changed) forms of the <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName> gene have been found in some types of cancer, including non-small cell lung cancer, colorectal cancer, and pancreatic cancer. These changes may cause cancer cells to grow and spread in the body. Knowing whether a patient’s tumor has a wild-type or mutated <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName> gene may help plan cancer treatment.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725949" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;KRAS gene&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725948" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen KRAS&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen KRAS</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una proteína que participa en las vías de señalización celular que controlan la multiplicación, la maduración y la destrucción de las células. La forma natural inalterada del gen se llama <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName> natural. Se han encontrado formas mutadas (cambiadas) del  gen <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName> en algunos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas, el cáncer colorrectal y el cáncer de páncreas. Es posible que estos cambios estimulen la multiplicación de las células y su diseminación por el cuerpo. Saber si el tumor de un paciente tiene una forma mutada o natural del gen <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName> quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento del cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-08-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-11-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
