<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000655176"><TermName>ASC-US</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A finding of abnormal cells in the tissue that lines the outer part of the cervix. ASC-US is the most common abnormal finding in a Pap test. It may be a sign of infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) or other types of infection, such as a yeast infection. It may also be a sign of inflammation, low hormone levels (in menopausal women), or a benign (not cancer) growth, such as a cyst or polyp. More testing, such as an HPV test or another Pap test, may be needed. Also called ASCUS and atypical squamous cells of undetermined significance.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>ASC-US</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hallazgo de células anormales en el tejido que reviste la parte exterior del cuello uterino. Las ASC-US son el hallazgo anormal más común en una prueba de Pap. A veces, este hallazgo es un signo de infección por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) o por otro tipo de microorganismo, como un hongo. Es posible que también indiquen inflamación, concentraciones bajas de hormonas (en mujeres menopáusicas), o la presencia de una masa benigna (no cancerosa), como un quiste o un pólipo. Este resultado a menudo señala la necesidad de hacer otras pruebas, como la de VPH. También se llama ASCUS y células escamosas atípicas de significado indeterminado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-11-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-07-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810192" url="/types/cervical/screening/abnormal-hpv-pap-test-results">HPV and Pap Test Results: Next Steps after an Abnormal Cervical Cancer Screening Test</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810505" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion/resultados-anormales-pruebas-vph-pap">Resultados anormales de las pruebas del VPH y de Pap para la detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
