<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658059"><TermName>pancreatic function test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik FUNK-shun …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test used to measure the ability of the pancreas to respond to a hormone called secretin. Secretin causes the pancreas, liver, and stomach to release substances that help digest food. During a pancreatic function test, a tube is inserted through the nose or throat into the stomach and small intestine. Secretin is given to the patient by injection into a vein. After a certain amount of time, samples of fluid are taken from the small intestine through the tube and sent to a lab to test for a response. A pancreatic function test may be used to help diagnose problems that affect the pancreas, such as pancreatitis, cystic fibrosis, and a type of pancreatic tumor called a gastrinoma. Also called secretin stimulation test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725863" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancreatic function test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725862" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba del funcionamiento pancreático&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba del funcionamiento pancreático</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba que se usa para medir la capacidad del páncreas de responder a una hormona que se llama secretina. La secretina hace que el páncreas, el hígado y el estómago liberen sustancias que ayudan a digerir los alimentos. Durante una prueba del funcionamiento pancreático, se introduce un tubo por la nariz o la garganta hacia el estómago y el intestino delgado. La secretina se administra al paciente mediante una inyección en una vena. Después de cierto tiempo, se toman muestras de líquido del intestino delgado a través de un tubo y se envían al laboratorio para evaluar la respuesta. A veces, se usa una prueba del funcionamiento pancreático para ayudar a diagnosticar problemas que afectan el páncreas, como la pancreatitis, la fibrosis quística y un tipo de tumor pancreático que se llama gastrinoma.  También se llama prueba de estimulación con secretina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2016-08-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
