<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000661196"><TermName>methemoglobinemia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MET-hee-moh-GLOH-bih-NEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which a higher-than-normal amount of methemoglobin is found in the blood. Methemoglobin is a form of hemoglobin that cannot carry oxygen.  In methemoglobinemia, tissues cannot get enough oxygen. Symptoms may include headache, dizziness, fatigue, shortness of breath, nausea, vomiting, rapid heartbeat, loss of muscle coordination, and blue-colored skin. Methemoglobinemia can be caused by injury or being exposed to certain drugs, chemicals, or foods. It can also be an inherited condition.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726339" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;methemoglobinemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726338" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;metahemoglobinemia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>metahemoglobinemia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que hay una cantidad más alta que lo normal de metahemoglobina en la sangre. La metahemoglobina es una forma de hemoglobina que no puede transportar oxígeno, de manera que no llega suficiente oxígeno a los tejidos.   Los síntomas de la metahemoglobinemia incluyen dolor de cabeza, mareo, cansancio, falta de aliento, náuseas, vómitos, latidos cardíacos rápidos, pérdida de coordinación muscular y piel de color azul.   Es posible que la causa  de esta afección sea una lesión o la exposición a ciertos medicamentos, sustancias químicas o alimentos.   A veces, la metahemoglobinemia es hereditaria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-31</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/methemoglobinemia-beta-globin-type/">Methemoglobinemia, beta-globin type (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/2659/congenital-methemoglobinemia">Hereditary methemoglobinemia (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000562.htm">Metahemoglobinemia (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
