<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000662024"><TermName>Rothmund-Thomson syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ROT-moond-TOM-sun SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that affects many parts of the body, especially the skin, eyes, bones, hair, and teeth. The main sign or symptom is a red blistering rash on the face that begins in early infancy. Over time, the rash can spread to the arms, legs, and buttocks and cause patchy skin coloring, areas of thin skin, and small clusters of blood vessels under the skin. Other signs and symptoms include slow growth and shorter-than-average height; little or no hair, including eyelashes and eyebrows; abnormalities of the nails, teeth, and bones; gastrointestinal problems; and blood problems. People with Rothmund-Thomson syndrome have an increased risk of developing cancer at an early age, especially osteosarcoma (a type of bone cancer), basal cell skin cancer, and squamous cell skin cancer. Rothmund-Thomson syndrome may be caused by a mutation (change) in the RECQL4 gene. Also called poikiloderma congenitale and RTS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Rothmund-Thomson syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725776" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Rothmund-Thomson&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Rothmund-Thomson</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro que afecta muchas partes del cuerpo, en especial la piel, los ojos, los huesos, el pelo y los dientes. La principal manifestación es una erupción roja y con ampollas en la cara que comienza durante la lactancia temprana. Con el tiempo, a veces la erupción se extiende por los brazos, las piernas y las nalgas, y causa manchas oscuras, áreas de adelgazamiento de la piel y pequeños grupos de vasos sanguíneos debajo de la piel. Otros signos y síntomas incluyen crecimiento lento y estatura más baja que el promedio; calvicie o escaso pelo, incluso en las pestañas y las cejas; malformaciones de las uñas, los dientes y los huesos; problemas digestivos y de la sangre. Las personas con síndrome de Rothmund-Thomson tienen un riesgo más alto de presentar cáncer a una edad temprana, sobre todo, osteosarcoma (tipo de cáncer de hueso), cáncer de células basales de la piel  y cáncer de células escamosas de la piel. Es posible que la causa de este síndrome sea una  mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>RECQL4</GeneName>. También se llama poiquilodermia congénita y RTS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-04-07</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-02-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/4392/rothmund-thomson-syndrome">Rothmund-Thomson syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/rothmund-thomson-syndrome/">Rothmund-Thomson syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
