<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666196">
  <TermName>absolute risk</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AB-soh-loot risk)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A measure of the risk of a certain event happening. In cancer research, absolute risk is the likelihood that a person who is free of a specific type of cancer at a given age will develop that cancer over a certain period of time. For example, a woman 35 years of age, with no known risk factors for breast cancer, has an absolute risk of getting breast cancer over a lifetime of 90 years of about 13%, meaning she has a 1 in 8 chance of developing breast cancer. This also means the chance that she will never have breast cancer is about 87%, or 7 in 8. </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000725802" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;absolute risk&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000725801" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;riesgo absoluto&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>riesgo absoluto</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medida del riesgo de que se presente una situación determinada. En el campo de la  investigación del cáncer, el riesgo absoluto es la probabilidad de que una persona, que no tiene un tipo específico de cáncer a cierta edad, presente ese cáncer en un tiempo determinado.   Por ejemplo, una mujer de 35 años, sin factores de riesgo de cáncer de mama conocidos, que viva 90 años tiene un riesgo absoluto de presentar cáncer de mama a lo largo de su vida cercano al 13 %, lo que significa que tiene una probabilidad de 1 entre 8 de presentar cáncer de mama. También significa que la probabilidad de que nunca tenga cáncer de mama es de alrededor del 87 %, o de 7 entre 8.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-10-06</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
