<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666663"><TermName>Bloom-Torre-Machacek syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... TOR-ay-muh-HA-chek SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder marked by shorter than average height, a narrow face, a red skin rash that occurs on sun-exposed areas of the body, and an increased risk of cancer. The rash usually occurs on the face, arms, and back of the hands. Small clusters of enlarged blood vessels may appear in the rash and in the eyes. Other signs and symptoms include patches of skin that may be lighter or darker than the skin around them, a small jaw and large ears, a high-pitched voice, fertility problems, learning problems, and other growth and developmental problems. People with this disorder have an increased risk of diabetes, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, and frequent ear and lung infections. They also have an increased risk of developing cancer at an early age, especially squamous cell skin cancer, leukemia, lymphoma, and gastrointestinal tract cancer. Bloom-Torre-Machacek syndrome is caused by a mutation (change) in the BLM gene that causes cells to have abnormal breaks in the chromosomes. Also called Bloom syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725986" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Bloom-Torre-Machacek syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725987" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Bloom-Torre-Machacek&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Bloom-Torre-Machacek</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro que se caracteriza por estatura más baja que el promedio, cara estrecha, erupción roja en la piel expuesta al sol y mayor riesgo de cáncer. La erupción se suele observar en la cara, los brazos y el dorso de las manos. A veces, aparecen pequeños grupos de vasos sanguíneos dilatados en la zona de la erupción y en los ojos. Otros signos y síntomas incluyen manchas en la piel (más claras o más oscuras que la piel que las rodea), mandíbula pequeña, orejas grandes, voz aguda, problemas de fertilidad, dificultades con el aprendizaje, el crecimiento y el desarrollo. Este trastorno aumenta el riesgo  de diabetes, enfermedad pulmonar obstructiva crónica e infecciones frecuentes en los oídos y los pulmones. Además, aumenta el riesgo de cáncer a una edad temprana, en especial, cáncer de células escamosas de piel, leucemia, linfoma y cáncer de tubo digestivo. La causa del síndrome de Bloom-Torre-Machacek es una mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>BLM </GeneName> que produce rupturas anormales en los cromosomas de las células. También se llama síndrome de Bloom.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-02-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/915/bloom-syndrome">Bloom syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/bloom-syndrome/">Bloom syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
