<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666670">
  <TermName>Blackfan–Diamond anemia</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BLAK-fan-DY-uh-mund uh-NEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A very rare disorder in which the bone marrow doesn’t make enough red blood cells. It is usually seen in the first year of life.  Patients may have deformed thumbs and other physical problems. They also have an increased risk of leukemia and sarcoma, especially osteosarcoma (bone cancer). Patients with Blackfan–Diamond anemia may have a mutation (change) in one of the genes that make proteins found in the cell’s ribosomes. Also called congenital hypoplastic anemia, congenital pure red cell aplasia, DBA, Diamond-Blackfan anemia, erythrogenesis imperfecta, and inherited erythroblastopenia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000725996" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Blackfan–Diamond anemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000725997" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anemia de Blackfan–Diamond&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>anemia de Blackfan–Diamond</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno muy raro por el que la médula ósea no produce suficientes glóbulos rojos. Suele presentarse durante el primer año de vida. A veces, los pacientes tienen pulgares  deformes y otros problemas físicos. También presentan un riesgo más alto de leucemia y sarcoma, en especial de osteosarcoma (cáncer de hueso). Es posible que los pacientes con anemia de Blackfan–Diamond tengan una mutación (cambio) en uno de los genes que dan origen a  las proteínas de los ribosomas de la célula. También se llama ADB, anemia de Diamond-Blackfan, anemia hipoplásica congénita, aplasia pura de células rojas congénita, eritroblastopenia hereditaria, eritrogénesis imperfecta y síndrome de Blackfan-Diamond.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6274/diamond-blackfan-anemia">Diamond-Blackfan anemia (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/diamond-blackfan-anemia/">Diamond-Blackfan anemia (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12933/anemia-de-diamond-blackfan">Anemia de Diamond-Blackfan (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
