<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000669655"><TermName>bone marrow aspiration and biopsy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(bone MAYR-oh AS-pih-RAY-shun ... BY-op-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in
          which a small sample of bone marrow (soft, sponge-like
          tissue in the center of most bones) and bone is removed. A
          small area of skin and the surface of the bone underneath
          are numbed with an anesthetic. Then a special wide needle
          is pushed into the bone. A sample of liquid bone marrow is
          removed with a syringe attached to the needle. The syringe
          is then removed and the needle is rotated to remove a
          sample of the bone and the bone marrow. Both the bone
          marrow and bone samples are sent to a laboratory to be
          looked at under a microscope.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bone marrow aspiration and biopsy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726530" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aspiración de la médula ósea y biopsia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000554337" type="image/jpeg" alt="Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy; drawing shows a patient lying face down on a table and a bone marrow needle being inserted into the hip bone. An inset shows a close up of the needle being inserted through the skin and hip bone into the bone marrow." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy. After a small area of skin is numbed, a long, hollow needle is inserted through the patient's skin and hip bone into the bone marrow. A sample of bone marrow and a small piece of bone are removed for examination under a microscope.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000584849" type="image/jpeg" alt="Aspiración de la médula ósea y biopsia; el dibujo muestra a un paciente acostado boca abajo en una camilla y una aguja para médula ósea que se inserta en el hueso de la cadera. El recuadro muestra la aguja para médula ósea que se inserta a través de la piel hasta la médula ósea del hueso de la cadera." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Aspiración  de la médula ósea y biopsia. Después de adormecer un área pequeña de la piel, se inserta una aguja para médula ósea en el hueso de la cadera del paciente. Se extraen muestras de sangre, hueso y médula ósea para examinarlas bajo un microscopio.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>aspiración de la médula ósea y biopsia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento
mediante el cual se extrae una muestra de hueso y de médula
ósea (tejido esponjoso y suave que se encuentra en el
centro de la mayoría de los huesos). Se adormece con un anestésico un área
pequeña de la piel y de la superficie del hueso. Luego, se introduce y empuja hacia el hueso una aguja
especial ancha. Se extrae una muestra de la médula ósea
líquida con una jeringa adherida a la aguja. Después, se quita
la jeringa y se hace rotar la aguja para extraer una
muestra de hueso y de médula ósea. Estas muestras se envían
a un laboratorio para observarlas al
microscopio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-07-07</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
