<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000670006"><TermName>common hepatic duct</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAH-mun heh-PA-tik dukt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tube that carries bile from the liver. The common hepatic duct starts where the right and left hepatic ducts join outside the liver and ends where a duct from the gallbladder joins it to form the common bile duct.  It is part of the biliary system.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;common hepatic duct&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725673" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;conducto hepático común&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000659742" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the extrahepatic bile ducts; drawing shows the extrahepatic bile ducts, including the common hepatic duct (perihilar region) and the common bile duct (distal region). Also shown are the liver, right and left hepatic ducts, gallbladder, cystic duct, pancreas, ampulla of Vater, and small intestine." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the extrahepatic bile ducts. Extrahepatic bile ducts are small tubes that carry bile from the liver and gallbladder to the small intestine.  They are made up of the common hepatic duct (perihilar region) and the common bile duct (distal region). Bile is made in the liver and flows through the common hepatic duct and the cystic duct to the gallbladder, where it is stored. When food is being digested,  bile is released from the gallbladder and flows through the common bile duct, pancreas, and ampulla of Vater into the small intestine.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000668855" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de las vías biliares extrahepáticas. En el dibujo se señalan las vías biliares extrahepáticas, que abarcan el conducto hepático común, en la región perihiliar, y el conducto colédoco en la región distal. También se muestran el hígado, los conductos hepáticos izquierdo y derecho, la vesícula biliar, el conducto cístico, el páncreas, la ampolla de Vater y una parte del intestino delgado. En la parte superior izquierda del dibujo se observa el tronco de una persona adulta y se señala la ubicación del hígado, la vesícula biliar y las vías biliares dentro del cuerpo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de las vías biliares extrahepáticas. Las vías biliares extrahepáticas son conductos (tubos) pequeños que transportan bilis desde el hígado y la vesícula biliar hasta el intestino delgado. Abarcan el conducto hepático común (región perihiliar) y el conducto colédoco (región distal). El hígado produce la bilis, que fluye por el conducto hepático común y el conducto cístico hasta la vesícula biliar, donde se almacena. Durante el proceso de digestión de los alimentos, la vesícula biliar libera bilis que fluye por el conducto colédoco, atraviesa el páncreas, y sale por la ampolla de Vater hacia el intestino delgado.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>conducto hepático común</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tubo que transporta la bilis desde el hígado. El conducto hepático común, empieza fuera del hígado donde se unen los conductos hepáticos derecho e izquierdo, y termina donde se une con el conducto cístico, que viene de la vesícula biliar, para formar el conducto colédoco. El conducto hepático común forma parte del sistema biliar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-07-07</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-06-23</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
