<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000670002">
  <TermName>BRAF (V600E) kinase inhibitor RO5185426</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… KY-nays in-HIH-bih-ter …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used to treat Erdheim-Chester disease (a very rare type of histiocytosis) and advanced melanoma that have a certain mutation (change) in the 
      <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>
       gene. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. BRAF (V600E) kinase inhibitor RO5185426 blocks certain proteins made by the mutated 
      <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>
       gene, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of kinase inhibitor. Also called PLX4032, RG7204, vemurafenib, and Zelboraf.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000725671" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;BRAF (V600E) kinase inhibitor RO5185426&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000725672" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de la cinasa BRAF (V600E) RO5185426&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>inhibidor de la cinasa BRAF (V600E) RO5185426</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de  la enfermedad de Erdheim-Chester (tipo muy raro de histiocitosis) y el melanoma en estadio avanzado que tiene cierta mutación (cambio) en el gen 
      <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>
      . También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El inhibidor de la cinasa BRAF (V600E) RO5185426  bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan del gen 
      <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>
       mutado, lo que tal vez ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas. También se llama PLX4032, RG7204, vemurafenib y Zelboraf.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2010-07-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-09-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000709542" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/vemurafenib">Vemurafenib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
