<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000682415"><TermName>stage IB non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage I non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IA and IB. In stage IB, the tumor is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 4 centimeters. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes; OR the tumor is 4 centimeters or smaller and one or more  of the following is found: (1) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (2) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (3) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has developed pneumonitis. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727570" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IB non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727569" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000794784" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing of stage IB lung cancer; the panel on the left shows a tumor (larger than 3 cm but not larger than 4 cm) in the right lung. Also shown are the pleura and diaphragm. The panel on the right shows a primary tumor (4 cm or smaller) in the left lung and cancer in (a) the left main bronchus and (b) the inner membrane covering the lung (inset). Also shown is (c) part or all of the lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation). The carina and a rib (inset) are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IB lung cancer. The tumor is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 4 centimeters. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes; OR the tumor is 4 centimeters or smaller. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes and one or more of the following is found: (a) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (b) cancer has spread to the inner membrane that covers the lung; and/or (c) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation of the lung).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798545" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IB. Se observan dos imágenes. En la imagen de la izquierda, se observa un tumor en el pulmón derecho que mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 4 cm. También se muestran la pleura y el diafragma. En la imagen de la derecha, se observa un tumor primario en el pulmón izquierdo que mide 4 cm o menos; además, se observan las siguientes situaciones: a) cáncer en el bronquio principal izquierdo; b) cáncer en la membrana interna que recubre el pulmón (recuadro inferior); c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón). También se observan la carina y, en el  recuadro inferior, una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IB. Se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 4 cm, y el cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos. 2) El tumor mide 4 cm o menos, el cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos y se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: a) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana interna que recubre el pulmón; c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB. En el estadio IB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 4 cm, y el cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos. 2) El tumor mide 4 cm o menos, y se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre el pulmón; todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis. El cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-07-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-06-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956" url="/types/lung/patient/non-small-cell-lung-treatment-pdq">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766" url="/espanol/tipos/pulmon/paciente/tratamiento-pulmon-celulas-no-pequenas-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
