<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000682421"><TermName>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIB, the tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and cancer has spread to lymph nodes above the collarbone on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor or to any lymph nodes on the opposite side of the chest as the primary tumor. Also, one or more of the following may be found: (1) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (2) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (3) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has developed pneumonitis; OR the tumor may be any size and cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are around the trachea or aorta, or where the trachea divides into the bronchi. Also, one or more of the following is found: (1) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe or a different lobe of the lung with the primary tumor; and/or (2) cancer has spread to any of the following: the membrane that lines the inside of the chest wall, the chest wall, the nerve that controls the diaphragm, the outer layer of tissue of the sac around the heart, the trachea, carina, esophagus, breastbone or backbone, diaphragm, heart, major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart (aorta or vena cava), or the nerve that controls the larynx (voice box).

</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727574" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727573" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000521915" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB lung cancer (1); drawing shows a primary tumor (5 cm or smaller) in the left lung and cancer in lymph nodes above the collarbone on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor and in lymph nodes on the opposite side of the chest as the primary tumor. Also shown is cancer that has spread to (a) the left main bronchus and (b) the membrane covering the lung. Also shown is (c) part or all of the lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation). The carina, pleura, and a rib (inset) are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB lung cancer (1). The primary tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and cancer has spread to lymph nodes above the collarbone on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor or to any lymph nodes on the opposite side of the chest as the primary tumor. Also, one or more of the following may be found: (a) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (b) cancer has spread to the inner membrane that covers the lung; and/or (c) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has pneumonitis (inflammation of the lung).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000682124" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB lung cancer (2); drawing shows a primary tumor in the left lung and (a) a separate tumor in a different lobe of the lung with the primary tumor. Also shown is cancer in lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are around the trachea or where the trachea divides into the bronchi. Also shown is (b) cancer that has spread to the following: the chest wall and the lining of the chest wall and lung, the nerve that controls the voice box, the trachea, the carina, the esophagus, the breastbone, the diaphragm, the nerve that controls the diaphragm, the aorta and vena cava, the heart, and the sac around the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB lung cancer (2). The tumor may be any size and cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are around the trachea or aorta (not shown), or where the trachea divides into the bronchi.  Also, one or more of the following is found: (a) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe or a different lobe of the lung with the primary tumor; and/or (b) cancer has spread to any of the following: the chest wall or the membrane that lines the inside of the chest wall, the nerve that controls the voice box, the trachea, the carina, the esophagus, the breastbone or backbone (not shown), the diaphragm, the nerve that controls the diaphragm, the heart, the major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart (aorta or vena cava), or the outer layer of tissue of the sac around the heart.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000537607" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIB (Parte 1). En la imagen se observan un tumor primario que mide 5 cm o menos en el pulmón izquierdo, y ganglios linfáticos cancerosos encima de la clavícula del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario y en el lado contrario al tumor primario. También se observan las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana que recubre el pulmón; c) todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón). Además, se muestran la carina, la pleura y, en un recuadro, una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIB (Parte 1). El tumor primario mide 5 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos encima de la clavícula del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario o a cualquiera de los ganglios linfáticos del lado contrario al tumor primario. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos:

a) el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; b) el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre el pulmón; c)
todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis (inflamación del pulmón).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000686830" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIB (Parte 2). En la imagen se observa un tumor primario en el pulmón izquierdo y a) un tumor separado en otro lóbulo del pulmón con el tumor primario. También se muestran ganglios linfáticos cancerosos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están alrededor de la tráquea o donde la tráquea se divide para formar los bronquios. También se observa que el cáncer se diseminó a los siguientes sitios: la pared torácica y la membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica, el nervio que controla la laringe, la tráquea, la carina, el esófago, el esternón, el diafragma, el nervio que controla el diafragma, la aorta, la vena cava, el corazón y el pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIIB (Parte 2). El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos están alrededor de la tráquea o la aorta (no se muestra), o donde la tráquea se divide para formar los bronquios. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos:

a) hay uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario o en otro lóbulo; b)
el cáncer se diseminó a alguno de los siguientes sitios:
la pared torácica o la membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica,
el nervio que controla la laringe, la tráquea, la carina, el esófago, el esternón o la columna vertebral (no se muestra), el diafragma, el nervio que controla el diafragma, el corazón, los vasos sanguíneos principales que entran o salen del corazón (aorta o vena cava) o la capa más externa del pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor mide 5 cm o menos, y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos encima de la clavícula del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario o a cualquiera de los ganglios linfáticos del lado contrario al tumor. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre el pulmón; todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis. 2) El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos se encuentran alrededor de la tráquea o la aorta, o donde la tráquea se divide para formar los bronquios. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos:  hay uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario o en  otro lóbulo; el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica, la pared torácica, el nervio que controla el diafragma, la capa más externa del pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón), la tráquea, la carina, el esófago, el esternón, la columna vertebral, el diafragma, el corazón, los vasos sanguíneos principales que entran o salen del corazón (la aorta o la vena cava), o el nervio que controla la laringe.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-07-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-06-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956" url="/types/lung/patient/non-small-cell-lung-treatment-pdq">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766" url="/espanol/tipos/pulmon/paciente/tratamiento-pulmon-celulas-no-pequenas-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
