<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000682419">
  <TermName>stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage II non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIB, the tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and cancer has spread to the lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are in the lung or near the bronchus. Also, one or more of the following may be found: (1) cancer has spread to the main bronchus, but has not spread to the carina; and/or (2) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (3) part of the lung or the whole lung has collapsed or has developed pneumonitis; OR cancer has not spread to lymph nodes and one or more of the following is found: (1) the tumor is larger than 5  centimeters but not larger than 7 centimeters; and/or (2) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung as the primary tumor; and/or (3) cancer has spread to any of the following: the membrane that lines the inside of the chest wall, the chest wall, the  nerve that controls the diaphragm, and/or the outer layer of tissue of the sac  around the heart.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000727572" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000727571" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000682110" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIB lung cancer (1); drawing shows a primary tumor (5 cm or smaller) in the right lung and cancer in lymph nodes in the same lung as the primary tumor. Also shown are the trachea, main bronchus, pleura, and diaphragm." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIB lung cancer (1). The primary tumor is 5 centimeters or smaller and cancer has spread to the lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The lymph nodes with cancer are in the lung or near the bronchus.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795027" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIB lung cancer (2); drawing shows (a) a primary tumor (larger than 5 cm but not larger than 7 cm) in the left lung (top inset) and (b) a separate tumor in the same lobe of the lung as the primary tumor. Also shown is cancer that has spread to (c) the chest wall and the membranes covering the lung and chest wall (middle inset); (d) the nerve that controls the diaphragm; and (e) the sac around the heart (bottom inset). The pleura, diaphragm, heart, and a rib (middle inset) are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IIB lung cancer (2). Cancer has not spread to lymph nodes and one or more of the following is found: (a) the primary tumor is larger than 5 centimeters but not larger than 7 centimeters; and/or (b) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung as the primary tumor; and/or cancer has spread to any of the following: (c) the chest wall and/or the membrane that lines the inside of the chest wall, (d) the nerve that controls the diaphragm, and/or (e) the outer layer of tissue of the sac around the heart.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000686747" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIB (Parte 1). En la imagen se muestran un tumor primario que mide 5 cm o menos en el pulmón derecho, y ganglios linfáticos cancerosos en el mismo pulmón que el tumor primario. También se observan la tráquea, el bronquio principal, la pleura y el diafragma." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIB (Parte 1). El tumor primario mide 5 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos se encuentran en el pulmón o cerca del bronquio.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798547" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIB (Parte 2). En la imagen se observa lo siguiente: a) un tumor primario que mide más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm en el pulmón izquierdo (recuadro superior); b) un tumor separado en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario. También se observa cáncer que se diseminó a los siguientes sitios: c) la pared torácica, la membrana que recubre el pulmón y la membrana que reviste la pared torácica (recuadro intermedio); d) el nervio que controla el diafragma; e) el pericardio (recuadro inferior). Además, se muestran la pleura, el diafragma, el corazón y en el recuadro intermedio, una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón en estadio IIB  (Parte 2). El cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos y se presentan uno o más de los siguientes casos:

a) el tumor primario mide más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm; b)
hay uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario.
También es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a alguno de los siguientes sitios:
c) la pared torácica o la membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica; d) el nervio que controla el diafragma; e) la capa más externa del pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIB</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El tumor mide 5 cm o menos y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del tórax que el tumor primario. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos se encuentran en el pulmón o cerca del bronquio. Además, se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: el cáncer se diseminó al bronquio principal, pero no a la carina; el cáncer se diseminó a la capa más interna de la membrana que recubre el pulmón; todo el pulmón o una parte de este se desinfló o presenta neumonitis. 2) El cáncer no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos y se encuentran uno o más de los siguientes casos: el tumor mide más de 5  cm, pero no más de 7 cm; hay uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón que el tumor primario; el cáncer se diseminó a la membrana que reviste el interior de la pared torácica, la pared torácica, el nervio que controla el diafragma o la capa más externa del pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2010-07-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-06-18</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956" url="/types/lung/patient/non-small-cell-lung-treatment-pdq">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766" url="/espanol/tipos/pulmon/paciente/tratamiento-pulmon-celulas-no-pequenas-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
