<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000683344">
  <TermName>Costello syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KOS-teh-loh SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare genetic disorder that is caused by a mutation (change) in the 
      <GeneName>HRAS</GeneName>
       gene. Costello syndrome is marked by shorter-than-average height, unusual facial features, extra folds of skin (especially on the neck, hands, and feet), loose joints, heart problems, and learning and developmental delays. People with Costello syndrome may develop small, non-cancerous wart-like growths called papillomas around the nose, mouth, or anus. They also have an increased risk of developing certain types of cancer, especially rhabdomyosarcoma (a type of soft tissue tumor) and neuroblastoma (cancer that forms from immature nerve cells).    
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000727927" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Costello syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000727926" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Costello&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Costello</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno genético raro que se produce por una mutación (cambio) en el gen 
      <GeneName>HRAS</GeneName>
      . El síndrome de Costello se caracteriza por una estatura más baja que  la normal, rasgos faciales inusuales, pliegues en la piel (en especial en el cuello, las manos y los pies), articulaciones flojas, problemas cardíacos, y retrasos en el aprendizaje y el desarrollo.   Las personas con síndrome de Costello en ocasiones presentan pequeñas verrugas no cancerosas, llamadas papilomas, alrededor de la nariz, la boca o el ano. También tienen un mayor riesgo de presentar  ciertos tipos de cáncer, en especial rabdomiosarcoma (tipo de tumor de tejido blando) y neuroblastoma (cáncer que se forma a partir de células nerviosas inmaduras).
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-01-10</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/1550/costello-syndrome">Costello syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/costello-syndrome/">Costello syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13010/sindrome-de-costello">Síndrome de Costello (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
