<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000687145"><TermName>cancer treatment vaccine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAN-ser TREET-ment vak-SEEN)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment that helps the body’s immune system recognize and destroy cancer cells. A cancer treatment vaccine may be made from a patient’s own tumor cells, from their dendritic cells (a type of immune cell), or from certain proteins or other molecules found on the cancer cells of many people with that cancer. Another type of cancer treatment vaccine is made from a virus that infects and breaks down cancer cells. Cancer treatment vaccines are being used to treat certain types of prostate cancer and melanoma. They are also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Cancer treatment vaccines are a type of immunotherapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cancer treatment vaccine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727710" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vacuna de tratamiento contra el cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vacuna de tratamiento contra el cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento que ayuda a que el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo reconozca y destruya las células cancerosas. Para elaborar una vacuna de tratamiento contra el cáncer se obtienen del paciente células tumorales o células dendríticas (tipo de célula inmunitaria), o  se usan determinadas proteínas u otras moléculas de las células cancerosas de muchas personas con el mismo tipo de cáncer. Otro tipo de vacuna de tratamiento contra el cáncer se produce a partir de virus que infectan y destruyen las células cancerosas. Las vacunas de tratamiento contra el cáncer se usan para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer de próstata y el melanoma, y se estudia su uso en otros tipos de cáncer. Estas vacunas se emplean en un tipo de inmunoterapia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-10-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-04-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/immunotherapy/cancer-treatment-vaccines">Cancer Treatment Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/inmunoterapia">Inmunoterapia para tratar el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
