<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000689078"><TermName>medical history</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEH-dih-kul HIH-stuh-ree)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A record of information about a person’s health. A personal medical history may include information about allergies, illnesses, surgeries, immunizations, and results of physical exams and tests. It may also include information about medicines taken and health habits, such as diet and exercise. A family medical history includes health information about a person’s close family members (parents, grandparents, children, brothers, and sisters). This includes their current and past illnesses. A family medical history may show a pattern of certain diseases in a family. Also called health history.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733308" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medical history&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733309" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;antecedentes médicos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>antecedentes médicos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Registro con información sobre la salud de una persona.   Los antecedentes médicos personales pueden incluir información acerca de las alergias, las enfermedades, las cirugías, las inmunizaciones y los resultados de los exámenes físicos y las pruebas.   A veces, también incluyen información de los medicamentos que tomó la persona, y sus hábitos de salud, como el régimen de alimentación y el ejercicio.   Los antecedentes médicos familiares incluyen información sobre la salud de los familiares cercanos (padres, abuelos, hijos y hermanos).   Esto incluye sus enfermedades actuales y pasadas.   Es posible que los antecedentes médicos familiares indiquen la forma cómo se presentan ciertas enfermedades en una familia.   También se llama antecedentes de salud.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-12-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-06-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
