<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000689097">
  <TermName>integrative medicine</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(IN-teh-gray-tiv MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An approach to medical care that recognizes the benefit of combining conventional (standard) therapies (such as drugs and surgery) with complementary therapies (such as acupuncture and yoga) that have been shown to be safe and effective. For example, acupuncture may be used with certain drugs to help lessen cancer pain or nausea and vomiting. Integrative medicine tries to address the physical, emotional, social, spiritual, and environmental factors that can affect a person’s health and well-being.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733333" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;integrative medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733332" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina integral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>medicina integral</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Método de atención médica en el que se reconoce el beneficio de combinar los tratamientos convencionales (estándar), como los medicamentos y la cirugía, con las terapias complementarias, como la acupuntura y el yoga, que demostraron ser seguras y eficaces. Por ejemplo, es posible usar la acupuntura con ciertos medicamentos para ayudar a reducir el dolor del cáncer, las náuseas y los vómitos. La medicina integral intenta atender los factores físicos, emocionales, sociales, espirituales y ambientales que a veces afectan la salud y el bienestar de las personas. También se llama medicina integradora y medicina integrativa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-08-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-07-07</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
