<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000689414">
  <TermName>Children's Oncology Group</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… on-KAH-loh-jee …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A large group
          of researchers, hospitals, and cancer centers that get
          support from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) to study
          childhood cancers. The main goal of the
          Children's Oncology Group is to conduct clinical
          trials that test new ways to prevent, diagnose, and treat
          cancer in children and adolescents. These clinical trials
          also include supportive care and childhood cancer
          survivorship studies. The Children's Oncology Group
          has hospitals and cancer centers in the United States,
          Canada, Europe, Australia, and New Zealand. It is part of
          the National Clinical Trials Network
          (NCTN). Also called COG.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733121" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Children's Oncology Group&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733120" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Children's Oncology Group&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Children's Oncology Group</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Grupo numeroso de investigadores, hospitales y centros oncológicos que obtienen apoyo del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI) para estudiar el cáncer infantil. El objetivo principal del Children's Oncology Group es llevar a cabo ensayos clínicos en los que se prueban nuevas formas de prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar el cáncer en niños y adolescentes. Estos ensayos clínicos también  incluyen estudios sobre cuidados médicos de apoyo y de supervivencia del cáncer infantil. El Children's Oncology Group tiene hospitales y centros oncológicos en los Estados Unidos, Canadá, Europa, Australia y Nueva Zelanda. Es parte de la Red Nacional de Ensayos Clínicos (National Clinical Trials Network, NCTN). También se llama COG.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-08-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-06-26</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
