<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000690361"><TermName>Xgeva</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ex-JEE-vuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient denosumab and is used to prevent or treat certain bone problems. Xgeva is used to prevent  bone problems caused by multiple myeloma or by solid tumors that have spread to the bone. It is also used in certain patients to treat giant cell tumor of the bone that cannot be removed by surgery, and to treat hypercalcemia that is caused by cancer and did not get better after treatment with bisphosphonates. Xgeva binds to a protein called RANKL, which keeps RANKL from binding to another protein called RANK on the surface of certain bone cells, including bone cancer cells. This may help keep bone from breaking down and cancer cells from growing.  Xgeva may also prevent the loss of calcium from the bones. It is a type of monoclonal antibody.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727540" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Xgeva&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727539" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Xgeva&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Xgeva</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el ingrediente activo denosumab, que se usa para prevenir o tratar ciertos problemas óseos. Xgeva se usa para prevenir los problemas óseos causados por el mieloma múltiple o los tumores sólidos que se diseminaron al hueso. También se utiliza en algunos pacientes para el tratamiento del tumor óseo de células gigantes que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía, y para la hipercalcemia que causa el cáncer y que no mejoró con bisfosfonatos. Xgeva se une a una proteína llamada RANKL e impide que RANKL se una a otra proteína llamada RANK en la superficie de ciertas células óseas, como las células del cáncer de hueso. Esto quizás impida el deterioro de los huesos y la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que Xgeva también prevenga la pérdida de calcio en los huesos. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-12-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-08-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000689968" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/denosumab">Denosumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
