<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000694852"><TermName>serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sayr-uh-TOH-nin-NOR-eh-pih-NEH-frin ree-UP-tayk in-HIH-bih-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of drug that is used to treat depression and some other conditions. Serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors stop or delay substances called serotonin and norepinephrine from being reabsorbed in the brain, which leaves more of them available for the brain to use. Raising serotonin and norepinephrine levels can help regulate mood and relieve depression and chronic pain. Serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors include drugs such as duloxetine and venlafaxine. Also called SNRI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733265" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733266" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de la recaptación de serotonina y norepinefrina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor de la recaptación de serotonina y norepinefrina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de la depresión y otras afecciones. Los inhibidores de la recaptación de serotonina y norepinefrina impiden o retrasan la reabsorción en el encéfalo de unas  sustancias llamadas serotonina y norepinefrina, que quedan disponibles en más cantidad para que el encéfalo las utilice. El aumento de la concentración de  serotonina y norepinefrina a veces ayuda a regular el estado de ánimo, así como a aliviar la depresión y el dolor crónico. Los inhibidores de la recaptación de serotonina y norepinefrina incluyen medicamentos como la duloxetina y la venlafaxina. También se llama inhibidor de la recaptación de serotonina y noradrenalina e IRSN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-04-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-12-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
