<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000700147">
  <TermName>radical trachelectomy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(RA-dih-kul TRAY-kee-LEK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Surgery to remove the cervix, nearby tissue, and the upper part of the vagina. Lymph nodes in the pelvis may also be removed. After the cervix is removed, the uterus is attached to the remaining part of the vagina. A special stitch  or band is placed on the uterus to help keep the uterus closed during a pregnancy. Because the uterus, fallopian tubes, and ovaries are not removed, a radical trachelectomy may be done to treat a person with early-stage cervical cancer who wants to become pregnant in the future. Also called radical cervicectomy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733099" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radical trachelectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802514" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervicectomía uterina radical&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cervicectomía uterina radical</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cirugía para extirpar el cuello uterino, el tejido cercano y la parte superior de la vagina. En ocasiones también se extirpan los ganglios linfáticos de la pelvis. Después de que se extirpa el cuello uterino, el útero se une con la parte que queda de la vagina. Se coloca una sutura o banda especial en el útero para ayudar a mantenerlo cerrado durante el embarazo. Debido a que no se extraen el útero, las trompas de Falopio ni los ovarios, es posible realizar una cervicectomía uterina radical para tratar a una persona con cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio temprano que quiera quedar embarazada en el futuro. También se llama cervicectomía radical y traquelectomía radical.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-06-03</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-12-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-women" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Girls and Women with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-mujeres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en las mujeres con cáncer: niñas y adultas </RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
