<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000700509">
  <TermName>Zytiga</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(zy-TEE-guh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat prostate cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. Zytiga is used under the brand name Zytiga    to treat patients whose cancer is castration resistant (has not responded to treatments that lower testosterone levels) or whose cancer is high risk and castration sensitive (has responded to treatments that lower testosterone levels). It is also used under the brand name Yonsa to treat patients whose cancer is castration resistant. Zytiga is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It lowers the amount of androgens (male hormones), such as testosterone, made by the body. This may stop the growth of cancer cells that need androgens to grow. Zytiga is a type of antiandrogen.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000732946" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zytiga&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000732945" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zytiga&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Zytiga</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento del cáncer de próstata que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. El acetato de abiraterona  se usa bajo la marca comercial Zytiga para tratar a los pacientes con un cáncer resistente a la castración (que no respondió a los tratamientos que disminuyen las concentraciones de testosterona) o un cáncer de riesgo alto sensible a la castración (que respondió a los tratamientos que disminuyen las concentraciones de testosterona).  También se usa bajo la marca comercial Yonsa para el tratamiento de los pacientes cuyo cáncer es resistente a la castración. Además,  está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El acetato de abiraterona disminuye la cantidad de andrógenos (hormonas masculinas, como la testosterona), que elabora el cuerpo, lo que quizás impida la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan  andrógenos para multiplicarse.  El acetato de abiraterona es un tipo de antiandrógeno.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-05-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-10-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000700207" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/abirateroneacetate">Abiraterone Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
