<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000701525">
  <TermName>carcinomatous lymphangitis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KAR-sih-NOH-muh-tus LIM-fan-JY-tis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A serious condition in which cancer cells spread from the original (primary) tumor to the lymph vessels (the thin tubes that carry lymph and white blood cells through the body’s lymph system). The cancer cells build up in the lymph vessels, which causes them to become blocked. Carcinomatous lymphangitis usually occurs in the lungs. It can happen in many types of cancer, but it is most common in people with cancers of the breast, lung, colon, stomach, pancreas, or prostate. Also called lymphangitic carcinomatosis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733383" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinomatous lymphangitis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733384" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfangitis carcinomatosa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>linfangitis carcinomatosa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección grave por la que las células cancerosas se diseminan desde el tumor original (primario) a los vasos linfáticos (tubos delgados que transportan la linfa y los glóbulos blancos por el sistema linfático del cuerpo). Las células cancerosas se acumulan en los vasos linfáticos y causan obstrucción. La linfangitis carcinomatosa suele presentarse en los pulmones. Esta afección se relaciona con muchos tipos de cáncer, pero es más común en personas con cáncer de mama, pulmón, colon, estómago, páncreas o próstata. También se llama carcinomatosis linfangítica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-10-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-05-05</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
