<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000702085">
  <TermName>MEN2 syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare, genetic disorder that affects the endocrine glands and can cause tumors in the thyroid gland, parathyroid glands, and adrenal glands. The affected endocrine glands may make high levels of hormones, which can lead to other medical problems such as high blood pressure and kidney stones. MEN2 syndrome is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
      , and is divided into three subtypes (MEN2A, MEN2B, and FMTC).  People with all subtypes of MEN2 syndrome have an increased risk of medullary thyroid cancer, pheochromocytoma, and parathyroid gland cancer. Also called MEN2, multiple endocrine adenomatosis type 2, and multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2 syndrome.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000732986" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;MEN2 syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000732985" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de NEM2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813290" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing shows parts of the body affected by MEN2 syndrome, including the thyroid gland, parathyroid glands, and adrenal gland. There are also two insets: one showing the back view of the thyroid gland with the four pea-sized parathyroid glands, and the other showing the inner part of the adrenal gland called the adrenal medulla." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Multiple endocrine neoplasia 2 (MEN2) syndrome is a rare, inherited disorder that affects the endocrine glands or organs. MEN2 syndrome usually causes thyroid gland, parathyroid gland, or adrenal gland tumors. The tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813447" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo se observan las partes del cuerpo afectadas por el síndrome de NEM2, como las glándulas tiroidea, paratiroideas y suprarrenales. Además hay dos recuadros: en uno se muestra una vista posterior de la glándula tiroidea con las cuatro glándulas paratiroideas del tamaño de una arveja, y en el otro se muestra la parte interna de la glándula suprarrenal llamada médula suprarrenal." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple 2 (NEM2) es un trastorno hereditario raro que afecta las glándulas u órganos endocrinos. Por lo general, el síndrome de NEM2 produce tumores en las glándulas tiroidea, paratiroideas o suprarrenales. Es posible que los tumores sean benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de NEM2</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno genético raro  que afecta las glándulas endocrinas y causa tumores en las glándulas tiroidea, paratiroideas y suprarrenales. Es posible que las glándulas endocrinas afectadas produzcan concentraciones altas de hormonas, lo que conlleva otros problemas médicos, como presión arterial alta y cálculos renales. La causa del síndrome de NEM2 es una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
      . Hay tres subtipos de esta enfermedad (NEM2A, NEM2B y CTMF), y todos acarrean un riesgo más alto de presentar cáncer de tiroides medular, feocromocitoma y cáncer de glándula paratiroidea. También se llama adenomatosis endocrina múltiple de tipo 2, NEM2, síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple de tipo 2 y síndrome MEN2.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-10-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-08-22</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/3830/men2">Multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2 (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/multiple-endocrine-neoplasia/">Multiple endocrine neoplasia (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000399.htm">Neoplasia endocrina múltiple (NEM) II (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000799404" url="/types/multiple-endocrine-neoplasia/patient-child-men-syndromes-treatment-pdq">Childhood Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia (MEN) Syndromes Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000800622" url="/espanol/tipos/neoplasia-endocrina-multiple/paciente-tratamiento-sindromes-nem-infantil-pdq">Tratamiento de los síndromes de neoplasia endocrina múltiple infantiles</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
