<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000703578"><TermName>recombinant human papillomavirus quadrivalent vaccine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ree-KOM-bih-nunt HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus KWAH-drih-VAY-lent vak-SEEN)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A vaccine that is no longer available in the United States but is still used in other countries to protect against infection with four types of human papillomavirus (HPV). Recombinant human papillomavirus quadrivalent vaccine is used in females and males aged 9 to 26 years to protect against low-risk HPV types 6 and 11, which cause most genital warts, and against high-risk HPV types 16 and 18, which cause most precancerous lesions and cancers of the cervix, vagina, vulva, and anus. Recombinant human papillomavirus quadrivalent vaccine may also prevent HPV-related cancers of the penis and oropharynx.  Also called Gardasil.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732883" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;recombinant human papillomavirus quadrivalent vaccine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732884" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vacuna recombinante tetravalente contra el virus del papiloma humano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vacuna recombinante tetravalente contra el virus del papiloma humano</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Vacuna que ya no se consigue en los Estados Unidos, pero que todavía se usa en otros países para prevenir la infección por 4 tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). La vacuna recombinante tetravalente contra el virus del papiloma humano se usa en mujeres y hombres de 9 a 26 años con el fin de prevenir la infección por los tipos 6 y 11 de VPH de riesgo bajo que producen la mayoría de las verrugas genitales. También protege contra los tipos 16 y 18 de VPH de riesgo alto que producen la mayoría de las lesiones precancerosas y los cánceres de cuello uterino, vagina, vulva y ano. Es posible que la vacuna recombinante tetravalente contra el virus del papiloma humano además prevenga el cáncer de pene y el cáncer de orofaringe relacionados con el VPH. También se llama Gardasil y vacuna tetravalente contra el VPH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-07-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-02-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000658589" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/recombinant-HPV-quadrivalent-vaccine">Recombinant Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Quadrivalent Vaccine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-vaccine-fact-sheet">Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/hoja-informativa-vacuna-vph">Vacunas contra el virus del papiloma humano (VPH)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
