<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000710949">
  <TermName>Xalkori</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(zal-KOR-ee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used to treat certain types of ALK-positive inflammatory myofibroblastic tumors in adults and children aged 1 year and older, ALK-positive systemic anaplastic large cell lymphoma in young adults and children aged 1 year and older, and ALK-positive or ROS1-positive non-small cell lung cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Xalkori blocks certain proteins made by the 
      <GeneName>ALK </GeneName>
       and 
      <GeneName>ROS1</GeneName>
       genes, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called crizotinib.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733080" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Xalkori&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Xalkori&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Xalkori</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de tumores miofibroblásticos inflamatorios positivos para ALK en adultos y en niños de 1 año o más, linfoma anaplásico de células grandes sistémico positivo para ALK en adultos jóvenes y en niños de 1 año o más, y cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas positivo para ALK o positivo para ROS1.  También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Xalkori bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan de los genes 
      <GeneName>ALK</GeneName>
       y 
      <GeneName>ROS1</GeneName>
      , lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama crizotinib.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-10-04</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-07-21</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000710816" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/crizotinib">Crizotinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
