<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000716287">
  <TermName>controlled substance</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(kun-TROLD SUB-stunts)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug or other substance that is tightly controlled by the government because it may be abused or cause addiction. The control applies to the way the substance is made, used, handled, stored, and distributed. Controlled substances include opioids, stimulants, depressants, hallucinogens, and anabolic steroids. Controlled substances with known medical use, such as morphine, Valium, and Ritalin, are available only by prescription from a licensed medical professional. Other controlled substances, such as heroin and LSD, have no known medical use and are illegal in the United States.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000734747" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;controlled substance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000734748" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sustancia controlada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sustancia controlada</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento u otra sustancia que el gobierno somete a control estricto debido a su capacidad de producir dependencia, abuso o adicción. Se controla la producción, el uso, la manipulación, el almacenamiento y la distribución de la sustancia. Los ejemplos de sustancias controladas son opioides, estimulantes, depresores, alucinógenos y esteroides anabolizantes.   Las sustancias controladas que tienen utilidad médica reconocida, como la morfina, Valium y Ritalin,  solo se consiguen con una receta médica de un profesional autorizado.   Otras sustancias controladas, como la heroína y el LSD, no tienen uso médico conocido y son ilegales en los Estados Unidos. También se llama droga.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-02-23</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
