<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000718943"><TermName>Jakafi</TermName><TermPronunciation>(JA-kah-fy)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of primary myelofibrosis (MF), post-polycythemia vera MF, post-essential thrombocythemia MF, or polycythemia vera, and adults and children aged 12 years and older with acute or chronic graft-versus-host disease. It is also being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer.  Jakafi blocks a protein called JAK, which may help keep abnormal blood cells or cancer cells from growing. It may also lower the body’s immune response. Jakafi is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called ruxolitinib phosphate.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732903" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Jakafi&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732902" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Jakafi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Jakafi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de mielofibrosis primaria,   mielofibrosis pospolicitemia vera,  mielofibrosis postrombocitosis esencial, o policitemia vera. También se usa en adultos y en niños de 12 años o más con enfermedad de injerto contra huésped aguda o crónica. Además,  está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Jakafi bloquea una proteína llamada JAK, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células sanguíneas anormales o de células cancerosas. Es posible que también reduzca la respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo. Jakafi es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama fosfato de ruxolitinib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-12-02</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000717928" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ruxolitinibphosphate">Ruxolitinib Phosphate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
