<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000720215">
  <TermName>stage I esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... ee-SAH-fuh-JEE-ul SKWAY-mus sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB, depending on where the cancer has spread. In stage IA, cancer has spread into the mucosa layer or thin muscle layer of the esophagus wall. The cancer cells are grade 1 or the grade is not known. Grade 1 cancer cells look more like normal cells under a microscope and grow and spread more slowly than grade 2 and 3 cancer cells.  In stage IB, cancer has spread (1) into the mucosa layer, thin muscle layer, or submucosa layer of the esophagus wall. The cancer cells are any grade or the grade is not known; or (2) into the thick muscle layer of the esophagus wall. The cancer cells are grade 1. </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733190" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I esophageal squamous cell carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000733191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células escamosas de esófago en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752730" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IA squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus; drawing shows the esophagus and stomach. An inset shows grade 1 cancer cells or cancer cells of an unknown grade in the mucosa layer and thin muscle layer of the esophagus wall. Also shown are the submucosa layer, thick muscle layer, and connective tissue layer of the esophagus wall. The lymph nodes are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IA squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus. Cancer has spread into the mucosa layer or thin muscle layer of the esophagus wall. The cancer cells are grade 1 or the grade is not known.  Grade 1 cancer cells look more like normal cells under a microscope and grow and spread more slowly than grade 2 and 3 cancer cells.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752731" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IB squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus; drawing shows the esophagus and stomach. A two-panel inset shows the layers of the esophagus wall: the mucosa layer, thin muscle layer, submucosa layer, thick muscle layer, and connective tissue layer. The lymph nodes are also shown. The left panel shows cancer cells that are any grade or of an unknown grade in the mucosa layer, thin muscle layer, and submucosa layer. The right panel shows grade 1 cancer cells in the mucosa layer, thin muscle layer, submucosa layer, and thick muscle layer." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IB squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus. Cancer has spread into the mucosa layer, thin muscle layer, or submucosa layer of the esophagus wall. The cancer cells are any grade or the grade is not known; OR cancer has spread into the thick muscle layer of the esophagus wall. The cancer cells are grade 1. Grade 1 cancer cells look more like normal cells under a microscope and grow and spread more slowly than grade 2 and 3 cancer cells.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000765180" type="image/jpeg" alt="Carcinoma de células escamosas de esófago en estadio IA. En la imagen se observan el esófago y el estómago. En una ampliación, se muestran células cancerosas en la mucosa y la capa muscular delgada de la pared del esófago. Las células cancerosas son de grado 1 o grado desconocido. Además, se observan la submucosa, la capa muscular gruesa y el tejido conjuntivo de la pared del esófago. También se muestran ganglios linfáticos." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="es">Carcinoma de células escamosas de esófago en estadio IA. El cáncer se diseminó a la mucosa o la capa muscular delgada de la pared del esófago. Las células cancerosas son de grado 1 o grado desconocido. Las células cancerosas de grado 1 se ven más como las células normales al microscopio, y se multiplican y diseminan más despacio que las células cancerosas de grados 2 y 3.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000765181" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de esófago de células escamosas en estadio IB. En la imagen se observan el esófago y el estómago. En una ampliación de dos paneles, se muestran las capas de la pared del esófago: la mucosa, la capa muscular delgada, la submucosa, la capa muscular gruesa y el tejido conjuntivo. También se muestran ganglios linfáticos. En el panel izquierdo, se observan células cancerosas de cualquier grado o de grado desconocido en la mucosa, la capa muscular delgada y la submucosa. En el panel derecho, se observan células cancerosas de grado 1 en la mucosa, la capa muscular delgada, la submucosa y la capa muscular gruesa." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de esófago de células escamosas en estadio IB. El cáncer se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: 1) La mucosa, la capa muscular delgada o la submucosa de la pared del esófago. Las células cancerosas son de cualquier grado o de grado desconocido. 2) La capa muscular gruesa de la pared del esófago. Las células escamosas son de grado 1. Las células cancerosas de grado 1 se ven más como las células normales al microscopio, y se multiplican y diseminan más despacio que las células cancerosas de grados 2 y 3.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células escamosas de esófago en estadio I</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText> El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB, según el lugar donde se diseminó el cáncer. En el estadio IA, el cáncer se diseminó a la mucosa o a la capa muscular delgada de la pared del esófago; las células cancerosas son de grado 1 o grado desconocido; las células cancerosas de grado 1 se ven más como las células normales al microscopio, y  se multiplican y se diseminan más despacio que las células cancerosas de grados 2 y 3. En el estadio IB, el cáncer se diseminó a uno de los siguientes sitios: 1) la mucosa, la capa muscular delgada o la submucosa de la pared del esófago; las células cancerosas son de cualquier grado o de grado desconocido; 2) la capa muscular gruesa de la pared del esófago; las células cancerosas son de grado 1.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2011-12-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-06-26</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062960" url="/types/esophageal/patient/esophageal-treatment-pdq">Esophageal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256773" url="/espanol/tipos/esofago/paciente/tratamiento-esofago-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de esófago</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
