<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000730162"><TermName>actinomycin D</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AK-tih-noh-MY-sin …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that comes from the bacterium <ScientificName>Streptomyces parvulus</ScientificName> and is used alone or with other drugs to treat adults and children with Ewing sarcoma, gestational trophoblastic tumor,  rhabdomyosarcoma, Wilms tumor, or certain types of testicular cancer and adults with certain types of solid tumors. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Actinomycin D damages the cell’s DNA and may kill cancer cells. It is a type of antineoplastic antibiotic. Also called Cosmegen and dactinomycin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738131" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;actinomycin D&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738132" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;actinomicina D&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>actinomicina D</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se obtiene de la bacteria <ScientificName>Streptomyces parvulus</ScientificName> y se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos y niños con sarcoma de Ewing, tumor trofoblástico gestacional, rabdomiosarcoma, tumor de Wilms o ciertos tipos de cáncer de testículo. Además, se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de tumores sólidos en adultos. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. La actinomicina D  daña el ADN de la célula y es posible que destruya células cancerosas. Es un tipo de antibiótico antineoplásico. También se llama Cosmegen y dactinomicina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-06-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000720376" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/dactinomycin">Dactinomycin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
