<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000732564"><TermName>fertility preservation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fer-TIH-lih-tee PREH-zer-VAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of procedure used to help keep a person’s ability to have children. A fertility preservation procedure is done before a medical treatment that may cause infertility, such as radiation therapy or chemotherapy. Examples of fertility preservation procedures include sperm banking, egg freezing, in vitro fertilization with embryo freezing, and certain types of surgery for cervical and ovarian cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740981" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fertility preservation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740980" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;preservación de la fecundidad&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>preservación de la fertilidad</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de procedimiento que se usa para ayudar a mantener la capacidad de una persona de tener hijos.   Un procedimiento de preservación de la fertilidad se realiza antes de un tratamiento médico que puede causar esterilidad, como radioterapia o quimioterapia.   Ejemplos de procedimientos de preservación de la fertilidad incluyen el almacenamiento de espermatozoides, la congelación de óvulos, la fecundación in vitro con congelamiento de embriones y ciertos tipos de cirugía para el cáncer de cuello uterino y de ovario. También se llama conservación de la fertilidad y preservación de la fecundidad.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-08-15</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-men">Fertility Issues in Boys and Men with Cancer </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-women">Fertility Issues in Girls and Women with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-hombres">Cuestiones de fecundidad en los hombres con cáncer: niños y adultos </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-mujeres">Cuestiones de fecundidad en las mujeres con cáncer: niñas y adultas </RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
