<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000732562"><TermName>tumor marker test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TOO-mer MAR-ker ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test that measures the amount of substances called tumor markers in tissue, blood, urine, or other body fluids. Most tumor markers are proteins made by both normal cells and cancer cells, but they are made in higher amounts by cancer cells. Genetic changes in tumor tissue, such as gene mutations, patterns of gene expression, and other changes in tumor DNA, are also being used as tumor markers. A tumor marker test is usually done with other tests, such as biopsies or imaging, to help diagnose some types of cancer. It may also be used to help plan treatment or find out how well treatment is working, give a likely prognosis, or find out if cancer has come back or spread to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740979" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor marker test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740978" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba de marcadores tumorales&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba de marcadores tumorales</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba para medir la cantidad de sustancias conocidas como marcadores tumorales en los tejidos, la sangre, la orina u otros líquidos del cuerpo. La mayoría de los marcadores tumorales son elaborados tanto por las células normales como por las células cancerosas, pero las células cancerosas los producen en cantidades más altas. También se utilizan como marcadores tumorales los cambios genéticos en el tejido tumoral, como las mutaciones de genes, el perfil de expresión de genes y otros cambios en el ADN del tumor. Las pruebas de marcadores tumorales suelen hacerse junto con otras pruebas, como biopsias o  imágenes, para ayudar a diagnosticar algunos tipos de cáncer. Además, estas pruebas son útiles para planificar el tratamiento, determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz, dar un pronóstico, y averiguar si el cáncer volvió o se diseminó  a otras partes del cuerpo. También se llama prueba de biomarcadores tumorales.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-08-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-08-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/biomarker-testing-cancer-treatment">Biomarker Testing for Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/pruebas-de-biomarcadores-tratamiento-cancer">Pruebas de biomarcadores para el tratamiento de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
