<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000736223"><TermName>stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer on the eyelid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... non-MEH-luh-NOH-muh skin KAN-ser ... I-lid)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB.  In stage IIIA, the tumor may be any size and may have spread to the edge of the eyelid where the lashes are, to the connective tissue in the eyelid, or to the full thickness of the eyelid, or to the eye, eye socket, sinuses, tear ducts, or brain, or to the tissues that support the eye. Cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor and the node is 3 centimeters or smaller. In stage IIIB, the tumor may be any size and may have spread to the edge of the eyelid where the lashes are, to the connective tissue in the eyelid, or to the full thickness of the eyelid, or to the eye, eye socket, sinuses, tear ducts, or brain, or to the tissues that support the eye. Cancer has spread to (1) one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor and the node is larger than 3 centimeters; or (2) more than one lymph node on the opposite side of the body as the tumor or on both sides of the body.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738138" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer on the eyelid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738137" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel no melanoma de párpado en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel no melanoma de párpado en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que se haya diseminado al borde del párpado donde están las pestañas, al tejido conjuntivo del párpado o a todo el grosor del párpado, o al ojo, la órbita, los senos paranasales, los conductos lagrimales o el encéfalo, o a los tejidos que sostienen el ojo. El cáncer se diseminó a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor y el ganglio mide 3 cm o menos. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y tal vez se diseminó al borde del párpado donde están las pestañas, al tejido conjuntivo del párpado o a todo el grosor del párpado, o al ojo, la órbita, los senos paranasales, los conductos lagrimales o el encéfalo, o a los tejidos que sostienen el ojo. El cáncer se diseminó 1) a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor y el ganglio mide más de 3 cm; o 2) a más de un ganglio linfático del lado del cuerpo contrario al tumor o a ambos lados del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-06-28</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2018-08-09</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258035" url="/types/skin/patient/skin-treatment-pdq">Skin Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256809" url="/espanol/tipos/piel/paciente/tratamiento-piel-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de piel</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
