<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000737122">
  <TermName>Oncotype DX breast cancer assay</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ON-koh-tipe … brest KAN-ser A-say)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A lab test that is used to help predict whether breast cancer will come back or spread to other parts of the body. The test looks at the activity level of 21 different genes in breast cancer tissue of people with early-stage (stage I, II, or IIIA) invasive breast cancer that is estrogen receptor (ER) positive, HER2 negative, and is either node-negative or has spread to 1 to 3 lymph nodes. If the test shows that there is a high risk that the cancer will spread or come back, treatment with chemotherapy may be needed to lower the risk. Also called 21-gene signature.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743000" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Oncotype DX breast cancer assay&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743001" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;análisis de cáncer de mama Oncotype DX&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>análisis de cáncer de mama Oncotype DX</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio que se usa para ayudar a pronosticar si el cáncer de mama se diseminará a otras partes del cuerpo o volverá. Mediante esta prueba se analiza la actividad de 21 genes en el tejido de mama canceroso de personas con cáncer de mama invasivo en estadio temprano (estadio I, II o IIIA) que es positivo para receptores de estrógeno (ER), negativo para HER2 y que no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos, o que se diseminó a 3 o menos ganglios linfáticos. Si el resultado de la prueba indica que hay un riesgo alto de que el cáncer se disemine o vuelva, a veces se necesita tratamiento con quimioterapia para reducir el riesgo. También se llama análisis de 21 genes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-10-15</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-12-15</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000785682" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">Oncotype DX ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) assay</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000785682" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">ensayo Oncotype DX para el carcinoma ductal in situ (CDIS)</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
