<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000737131">
  <TermName>MammaPrint</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MA-muh-print)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A lab test that is used to help predict whether breast cancer will come back or spread to other parts of the body. The test looks at the activity level of 70 different genes in breast cancer tissue of people with early-stage (stage I, II, or IIIA) invasive breast cancer that is less than 5 cm and is either node-negative or has spread to 1 to 3 lymph nodes. If the test shows that there is a high risk that the cancer will spread or come back, treatment with chemotherapy may be needed to lower the risk. Also called 70-gene signature.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743025" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;MammaPrint&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743024" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;MammaPrint&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>MammaPrint</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio que se usa para ayudar a pronosticar si el cáncer de mama se diseminará a otras partes del cuerpo o volverá. Mediante esta prueba se analiza la actividad de 70 genes en el tejido de mama canceroso de personas con cáncer de mama invasivo en estadio temprano (estadio I, II o IIIA) que no se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos  o que se diseminó a 3 o menos ganglios linfáticos. Si el resultado de la prueba indica que hay un riesgo alto de que el cáncer se disemine o vuelva, a veces se necesita tratamiento con quimioterapia para reducir el riesgo. También se llama análisis de 70 genes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-10-15</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-12-15</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/lista-marcadores-tumorales" UseWith="es">Marcadores tumorales más comunes</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
