<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000738000">
  <TermName>c-erbB-2 positive</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… PAH-zih-tiv)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Describes cells that have a protein called HER2 on their surface. In normal cells, HER2 helps control cell growth. Cancer cells that make too much HER2 may grow more quickly and are more likely to spread to other parts of the body. Checking to see if a cancer is c-erbB-2 positive may help plan treatment, which may include drugs that kill c-erbB-2-positive cancer cells. Cancers that may be c-erbB-2 positive include breast, bladder, pancreatic, ovarian, and stomach cancers. Also called HER2 positive and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 positive.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743006" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;c-erbB-2 positive&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743007" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;positiva para c-erbB-2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>positiva para c-erbB-2</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Característica de una célula que tiene una proteína llamada HER2 en su superficie. En las células normales, HER2 ayuda a controlar la multiplicación celular. Es posible que las células cancerosas que producen demasiada HER2  se multipliquen más rápido y es más probable que se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo. Saber si un cáncer es positivo para c-erbB-2 quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento, incluso con medicamentos que destruyen las células positivas para HER2. Los tipos de cáncer que a veces son positivos para c-erbB-2 incluyen el cáncer de mama, vejiga, páncreas, ovario y estómago. También se llama positiva para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano y positiva para HER2.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-10-31</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-11-19</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
