<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739944"><TermName>Afinitor Disperz</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-FIH-nih-tor DIS-perz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient everolimus and is used to treat a type of benign brain tumor called subependymal giant cell astrocytoma and certain types of seizures in patients who have tuberous sclerosis.  Afinitor Disperz blocks a protein involved in cell division, which may help keep abnormal cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It may also help prevent or treat seizures in some patients. Afinitor Disperz is a type of kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742098" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Afinitor Disperz&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742097" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Afinitor Disperz&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Afinitor Disperz</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo everólimus y se usa para el tratamiento de un tipo de tumor benigno de encéfalo llamado astrocitoma subependimario de células gigantes  y ciertos tipos de convulsiones en pacientes con esclerosis tuberosa. Afinitor Disperz bloquea una proteína que participa en la división celular, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células anormales. Además, tal vez impida la formación de los vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es posible que también  ayude a prevenir o tratar las convulsiones en algunos pacientes. Afinitor Disperz es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas y de inhibidor de la angiogénesis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-09-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-05-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000640318" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/everolimus">Everolimus</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
