<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000740854"><TermName>hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee PAYR-uh-GANG-glee-OH-muh-FEE-oh-KROH-moh-sy-TOH-muh SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, genetic disorder marked by tumors called paragangliomas, which are found in paraganglia. Paraganglia are groups of nerve-like cells found near the adrenal glands and near blood vessels or nerves in the head, neck, chest, abdomen, and pelvis. Paragangliomas that form in the adrenal glands are called pheochromocytomas. Paragangliomas are usually benign (not cancer), but sometimes become malignant (cancerous).  People with hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma syndrome usually have more than one paraganglioma, and may have an increased risk of certain types of cancer, such as kidney cancer and thyroid cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745274" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745273" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de paraganglioma-feocromocitoma hereditario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de paraganglioma-feocromocitoma hereditario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético raro que se caracteriza por la formación de paragangliomas, un tipo de tumor que surge en los paraganglios.   Los paraganglios son grupos de células similares a las células nerviosas, que estan cerca de las glándulas suprarrenales y los vasos sanguíneos o nervios de la cabeza, el cuello, el tórax, el abdomen y la pelvis.   Los paragangliomas de las glándulas adrenales se llaman feocromocitomas. Estos tumores suelen ser benignos (no cancerosos), pero a veces se vuelven malignos (cancerosos).   Las personas con el síndrome hereditario de paraganglioma-feocromocitoma a menudo presentan más de un paraganglioma y es posible que tengan un riesgo más alto de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de riñón y el cáncer de tiroides.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-11-21</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/11984/hereditary-paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma">Hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/hereditary-paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma/">Hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
