<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000740896">
  <TermName>regorafenib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(REH-goh-RA-feh-nib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of colorectal cancer, gastrointestinal stromal tumors, and hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer).  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Regorafenib blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Regorafenib is a type of kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called Stivarga.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000742082" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;regorafenib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000742081" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;regorafenib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>regorafenib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer colorrectal, tumores de estroma gastrointestinal y carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El regorafenib bloquea ciertas proteínas,  lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que también prevenga la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. El regorafenib es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de inhibidor de cinasa. También se llama Stivarga.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-10-03</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-06-11</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000740826" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/regorafenib">Regorafenib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
