<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000741769">
  <TermName>precision medicine</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(pree-SIH-zhun MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of medicine that uses information about a person’s genes, proteins, environment, and lifestyle to prevent, diagnose, or treat disease. In cancer, precision medicine uses specific information about a person’s tumor to help make a diagnosis, plan treatment, find out how well treatment is working, or make a prognosis. Precision medicine may also be used to help determine a person’s risk of developing certain types of cancer. Examples of precision medicine include using targeted therapies to treat specific types of cancer, such as HER2-positive breast cancer, or using tumor marker testing to help diagnose cancer. Precision medicine is sometimes called personalized medicine.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000742989" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;precision medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000742988" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina de precisión&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/>
  <SpanishTermName>medicina de precisión</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Enfoque médico para el que se usa la información de los genes, las proteínas, el entorno y el estilo de vida de una persona con el fin de prevenir, diagnosticar o tratar una enfermedad. En la medicina de precisión para el cáncer, se utiliza información específica del tumor de una persona para facilitar el diagnóstico, planificar el tratamiento, evaluar la eficacia del tratamiento o dar un pronóstico. También se usa para determinar el riesgo de una persona de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer. Ejemplos de medicina de precisión son el uso de terapias dirigidas para el tratamiento de tipos específicos de cáncer, como el cáncer de mama  positivo para HER2, o el uso de pruebas de marcadores tumorales para facilitar el diagnóstico del cáncer. También se llama medicina individualizada y medicina personalizada de precisión.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-10-16</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-30</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/biomarker-testing-cancer-treatment">Biomarker Testing for Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/pruebas-de-biomarcadores-tratamiento-cancer">Pruebas de biomarcadores para el tratamiento de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
