<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000743916">
  <TermName>Cometriq</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(koh-MEH-trik)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient cabozantinib-s-malate and is used to treat progressive medullary thyroid cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Cometriq blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow.  Cometriq  is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746313" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cometriq&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746312" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cometriq&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Cometriq</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo (S)-malato de cabozantinib y que se usa para el tratamiento del cáncer de tiroides medular progresivo que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Cometriq bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que además impida la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Cometriq es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas y de inhibidor de la angiogénesis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-12-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-01-27</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000743644" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/cabozantinib-s-malate">Cabozantinib-S-Malate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
