<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000743915">
  <TermName>cabozantinib-s-malate</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KA-boh-ZAN-tih-nib ... MA-layt)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs under the brand name Cabometyx to treat certain types of differentiated thyroid cancer, hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), neuroendocrine tumors, and renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer). It is used under the brand name Cometriq to treat certain types of medullary thyroid cancer. Cabozantinib-s-malate is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Cabozantinib-s-malate is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746310" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cabozantinib-s-malate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746311" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;(S)-malato de cabozantinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>(S)-malato de cabozantinib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos bajo la marca comercial Cabometyx, para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer de tiroides diferenciado, carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), tumores neuroendocrinos y carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón). También se emplea bajo la marca comercial Cometriq para tratar ciertos tipos de cáncer de tiroides medular. Además, el  (S)-malato de cabozantinib está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Este medicamento bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás evite la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Asimismo, tal vez impida la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. El (S)-malato de cabozantinib es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas y de inhibidor de la angiogénesis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-12-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2025-05-07</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000743644" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/cabozantinib-s-malate">Cabozantinib-S-Malate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
