<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744186">
  <TermName>Iclusig</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(i-KLOO-sig)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of chronic myelogenous leukemia or Philadelphia chromosome–positive acute lymphoblastic leukemia. It is used in patients whose cancer is newly diagnosed, has the T315I mutation, or cannot be treated with other kinase inhibitors. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Iclusig blocks BCR::ABL1  and other proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Iclusig is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called ponatinib hydrochloride.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746321" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Iclusig&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746320" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Iclusig&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Iclusig</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de leucemia mielógena crónica o leucemia linfoblástica aguda positivos para el cromosoma Filadelfia. Se utiliza en pacientes con cáncer recién diagnosticado y que tiene la mutación T315I  o que no se puede tratar con otros inhibidores de tirosina–cinasas. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Iclusig bloquea la proteína BCR::ABL1 y otras proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas y las destruya. Es posible que además impida la formación de nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Iclusig es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama clorhidrato de ponatinib.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2012-12-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-10-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000744060" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ponatinibhydrochloride">Ponatinib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
