<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744618">
  <TermName>stage IIIA intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... IN-truh-AH-kyoo-ler MEH-luh-NOH-muh ... SIH-lee-ayr-ee BAH-dee ... KOR-oyd)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, the tumor (1) is size category 2 (12.1 to 18 millimeters wide and not more than 3 millimeters thick; or 9.1 to 15 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick; or not more than 12 millimeters wide and 6.1 to 9 millimeters thick) and has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is not more than 5 millimeters thick. The tumor may have spread to the ciliary body; or (2) is size category 3 (15.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick; or 12.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 6.1 to 9 millimeters thick; or  not more than 18 millimeters wide and 9.1 to 12 millimeters thick; or  not more than 15 millimeters wide and 12.1 to 15 millimeters thick) and has spread to the ciliary body; or (3) is size category 3 and has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is not more than 5 millimeters thick. The tumor has not spread to the ciliary body; or (4) is  size category 4 (more than 18 millimeters wide and may be any thickness; or 15.1 to 18 millimeters wide and more than 12 millimeters thick; or  not more than 15 millimeters wide and more than 15 millimeters thick) and is in the choroid only.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746286" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIA intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746287" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma ocular de cuerpo ciliar y coroides en estadio IIIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>melanoma ocular de cuerpo ciliar y coroides en estadio IIIA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, 1) el tamaño del tumor es de categoría 2  (mide de 12,1 a 18 mm de ancho y hasta 3 mm de grosor; o mide de 9,1 a 15 mm de ancho y de 3,1 a 6 mm de grosor; o mide hasta 12 mm de ancho y de 6,1 a 9 mm de grosor) y el tumor se diseminó a través de la esclerótica al exterior del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular mide hasta 5 mm de grosor. Es posible que el tumor se haya diseminado al cuerpo ciliar; o 2) el tamaño del tumor es de categoría 3 (mide de 15,1 a 18 mm de ancho y de 3,1 a 6  mm de grosor; o mide de 12,1 a 18 mm de ancho y de 6,1 a 9 mm de grosor; o mide hasta 18 mm de ancho y de 9,1 a 12 mm de grosor; o mide hasta 15 mm de ancho y de 12,1 a 15 mm de grosor) y el tumor se diseminó al cuerpo ciliar; o 3) el tamaño del tumor es de categoría 3  y el tumor se diseminó a través de la esclerótica al exterior del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular mide hasta 5 mm de grosor. El tumor no se diseminó al cuerpo ciliar; o 4) el tamaño del tumor es de categoría 4 (mide más de 18 mm de ancho y tiene cualquier grosor; o mide de 15,1 a 18 mm de ancho y más 12 mm de grosor; o mide hasta 15 mm de ancho y más de 15 mm de grosor) y el tumor se encuentra solo en la coroides.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-01-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-07-02</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258015" url="/types/eye/patient/intraocular-melanoma-treatment-pdq">Intraocular (Uveal) Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000537037" url="/espanol/tipos/ojo/paciente/tratamiento-melanoma-ocular-pdq">Tratamiento del melanoma ocular uveal</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
