<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744889">
  <TermName>stage IIIC intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... IN-truh-AH-kyoo-ler MEH-luh-NOH-muh ... SIH-lee-ayr-ee BAH-dee ... KOR-oyd)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIC, the tumor (1) is size category 4 (more than 18 millimeters wide and may be any thickness; or 15.1 to 18 millimeters wide and more than 12 millimeters thick; or  not more than 15 millimeters wide and more than 15 millimeters thick) and    has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is not more than 5 millimeters thick. The tumor has spread to the ciliary body; or (2) may be any size and has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is more than 5 millimeters thick.

</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746294" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIC intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000746295" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma ocular de cuerpo ciliar y coroides en estadio IIIC&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>melanoma ocular de cuerpo ciliar y coroides en estadio IIIC</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIC, 1) el tamaño del tumor es de categoría 4  (mide más de 18 mm de ancho y tiene cualquier grosor; o mide de 15,1 a 18 mm de ancho y más de 12 mm de grosor; o mide hasta 15 mm de ancho y más de 15 mm de grosor) y el tumor se diseminó a través de la esclerótica al exterior del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular mide hasta 5 mm de grosor. El tumor se diseminó al cuerpo ciliar; o 2) el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a través de la esclerótica al exterior del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular mide más 5 mm de grosor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-01-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2018-07-02</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258015" url="/types/eye/patient/intraocular-melanoma-treatment-pdq">Intraocular (Uveal) Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000537037" url="/espanol/tipos/ojo/paciente/tratamiento-melanoma-ocular-pdq">Tratamiento del melanoma ocular uveal</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
