<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000746427">
  <TermName>Pomalyst</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PAH-muh-list)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that is similar to thalidomide and is used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of multiple myeloma or Kaposi sarcoma.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Pomalyst may help the immune system kill cancer cells. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Pomalyst is a type of immunomodulating agent and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called CC-4047 and pomalidomide.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000749869" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Pomalyst&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000749868" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Pomalyst&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Pomalyst</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento similar a la talidomida, que se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de mieloma múltiple o sarcoma de Kaposi. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros  tipos de cáncer. Es posible que Pomalyst ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Asimismo, tal vez impida la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Pomalyst es un tipo de inmunomodulador y de antiangiogénico. También se llama CC-4047 y pomalidomida.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-02-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-06-03</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000746335" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/pomalidomide">Pomalidomide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
