<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748115">
  <TermName>G6PD deficiency</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… deh-FIH-shun-see)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An inherited disorder in which a person doesn’t have enough of an enzyme called G6PD that helps red blood cells work the way they should. In G6PD deficiency, the red blood cells break down when the body is exposed to infection, severe stress, or certain drugs, chemicals, or foods. This may lead to a condition called hemolytic anemia. This disorder is most common in African-American men and in men of Middle Eastern or Mediterranean descent. Also called glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752525" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;G6PD deficiency&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752526" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deficiencia de G6PD&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>deficiencia de G6PD</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario en el cual no hay suficiente cantidad de una enzima llamada G6PD, que ayuda a que los glóbulos rojos funcionen de manera apropiada. La deficiencia de G6PD hace que se destruyan los glóbulos rojos cuando el cuerpo presenta una infección, estrés intenso o se expone a ciertos medicamentos, productos químicos o alimentos.   A veces, esto produce una afección que se llama anemia hemolítica.   Este trastorno es más frecuente en los hombres afroamericanos y de ascendencia del Oriente Medio o del Mediterráneo. También se llama deficiencia de glucosa-6-fosfato–deshidrogenasa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-05-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6520/glucose-6-phosphate-dehydrogenase-deficiency">Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/glucose-6-phosphate-dehydrogenase-deficiency/">Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/g6pddeficiency.html">Deficiencia de glucosa-6-fosfato–deshidrogenasa (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
