<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748830">
  <TermName>Surgeon General</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SER-jun JEH-neh-rul)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The chief medical doctor and health educator for the United States. The mission of the U.S. Surgeon General is to give the public the best scientific information available on how to improve health and lower the risk of illness and injury. The U.S. Surgeon General oversees the U.S. Public Health Service and is chosen by the U.S. President. Each state public health agency and branch of the U.S. military also has its own Surgeon General. The office of the U.S. Surgeon General is part of the Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752621" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Surgeon General&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752620" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Director general de salud pública de los Estados Unidossanidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Director general de salud pública de los Estados Unidos</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Persona a cargo de la dirección de la salud pública y la educación sanitaria en los Estados Unidos. Su misión es proporcionar a la población la mejor información científica disponible sobre cómo mejorar la salud y reducir el riesgo de enfermedades y lesiones. El presidente de los Estados Unidos designa a la persona que ocupa este cargo, quien tiene la responsabilidad de supervisar el Servicio de Salud Pública de los Estados Unidos (USPHS). Cada agencia estatal de salud pública y cada rama de las fuerzas armadas del país también cuenta con una oficina de dirección de salud. La oficina del Director general de salud pública de los Estados Unidos forma parte del Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos (DHHS). También se llama Director general de sanidad de los Estados Unidos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-07-18</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
