<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000750209">
  <TermName>invasive ductal carcinoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(in-VAY-siv DUK-tul KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The most common type of invasive breast cancer. It begins in the lining of the milk ducts (thin tubes that carry milk from the lobules of the breast to the nipple) and spreads outside the ducts to surrounding normal tissue. Invasive ductal carcinoma can also spread through the blood and lymph systems to other parts of the body. Also called infiltrating ductal carcinoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752561" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;invasive ductal carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000752562" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma ductal invasivo&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000806270" type="image/jpeg" alt="Invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) of the breast; drawing shows a lobe, ducts, and fatty tissue in a cross section of the breast. An inset shows a normal duct and a duct with IDC and cancer cells spreading outside it." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) of the breast begins in the lining of a breast duct (milk duct) and spreads outside the duct to other tissues in the breast. It can also spread through the blood and lymph system to other parts of the body. IDC is the most common type of invasive breast cancer.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000807074" type="image/jpeg" alt="Carcinoma ductal invasivo de mama. En la imagen, se señala un lóbulo, unos conductos y el tejido graso en un corte transversal de la mama. En el recuadro, se observa un conducto normal y un conducto con carcinoma ductal invasivo donde las células cancerosas se diseminan fuera del conducto." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El carcinoma ductal invasivo de mama empieza en el revestimiento de los conductos galactóforos (conductos de la mama) y se disemina fuera de los conductos a otros tejidos de la mama. También se puede diseminar a otras partes del cuerpo a través de la sangre y el sistema linfático. Este es el tipo más común de cáncer de mama invasivo.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma ductal invasivo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo más común de cáncer de mama invasivo. Empieza en el revestimiento de los conductos galactóforos (tubos delgados que llevan la leche desde los lobulillos de la mama hasta el pezón)  y se disemina fuera de los conductos al tejido normal que los rodea. También es posible que se disemine a otras partes del cuerpo a través de la sangre y el sistema linfático. También se llama carcinoma canalicular invasivo, carcinoma ductal infiltrante y carcinoma ductal invasor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-07-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-12-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast  Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
