<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000752850"><TermName>HPV/Pap cotest</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a human papillomavirus (HPV) test and a Pap test are done at the same time to check for cervical cancer. The HPV test looks for DNA or RNA from certain high-risk types of HPV in samples of cells taken from the cervix. The Pap test checks for cervical cancer cells and cell changes that may lead to cervical cancer. The same cell sample may be used for both the HPV test and the Pap test. Women aged 30 to 65 years may have an HPV/Pap cotest every 5 years. Cotesting is more likely to find abnormal cells or cervical cancer than a Pap test alone is. Also called Pap/HPV cotest.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798048" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HPV/Pap cotest&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798046" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba conjunta del VPH y de Pap&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>prueba conjunta del VPH y de Pap</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento durante el cual se hacen dos pruebas al mismo tiempo, una prueba del virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y una prueba de Papanicolaou (Pap), para determinar si hay cáncer de cuello uterino. Con la prueba del VPH, se busca ADN o ARN de ciertos tipos de VPH de riesgo alto en muestras de células del cuello uterino. Con la prueba de Pap, se busca identificar células cancerosas de cuello uterino o cambios en las células que pueden causar este tipo de cáncer. A veces se usa la misma muestra de células para hacer ambas pruebas. Por lo general, se recomienda que las mujeres se hagan una prueba conjunta del VPH y de Pap cada 5 años. Es más probable encontrar células anormales o cáncer de cuello uterino con una prueba conjunta que con la prueba de Pap sola. También se llama prueba conjunta de Pap y del VPH y prueba conjunta del VPH y de Papanicolaou.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-11-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000810140" url="/types/cervical/screening">Cervical Cancer Screening</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000810456" url="/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/deteccion">Detección del cáncer de cuello uterino</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
