<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753087"><TermName>low-risk human papillomavirus</TermName><TermPronunciation>(loh-risk HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of human papillomaviruses (HPV) that can infect cells on the moist surfaces or inner lining of some organs and body cavities, such as the cervix, vagina, vulva, penis, anus, mouth, and throat, but rarely cause cancer. Low-risk human papillomavirus infections, most often HPV types 6 and 11, can cause warts on or around the genitals, anus, mouth, larynx, or other parts of the respiratory tract. Low-risk human papillomavirus is transmitted through intimate skin-to-skin contact, most often during vaginal, anal, or oral sex. It can also be transmitted during childbirth, but this is less common.   Also called low-risk HPV.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759274" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;low-risk human papillomavirus&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759275" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;virus del papiloma humano de riesgo bajo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>virus del papiloma humano de riesgo bajo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) que infectan las células de las superficies húmedas o del revestimiento interno de algunos órganos y cavidades corporales, como el cuello uterino, la vagina, la vulva, el pene, el ano, la boca o la garganta, pero que rara vez producen cáncer. Las infecciones por virus del papiloma humano de riesgo bajo, sobre todo por los tipos 6 y 11, pueden causar verrugas en, o alrededor de, los genitales, el ano, la boca, la laringe y   en otras áreas de las vías respiratorias. Los virus del papiloma humano de riesgo bajo se trasmiten por el contacto íntimo piel con piel, en especial durante las relaciones sexuales vaginales, anales u orales. El contagio también puede ocurrir durante el parto, pero es menos frecuente. También se llama virus del papiloma humano de bajo riesgo y VPH de riesgo bajo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-12-19</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-09-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-and-cancer">HPV and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-vaccine-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/vph-y-cancer?redirect=true">VPH y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
