<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753084">
  <TermName>high-risk human papillomavirus</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(hy-risk HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A group of cancer-causing human papillomaviruses (HPV). These viruses can infect the cells on the moist surfaces or inner lining of some organs and body cavities, such as the cervix, vagina, vulva, penis, anus, mouth, and throat. A long-lasting infection with a high-risk human papillomavirus type can cause cell changes that become cancer over time if not found and removed.  High-risk human papillomavirus can cause cancers of the cervix, anus, oropharynx, vagina, vulva, and penis. There are about 12 types of high-risk human papillomavirus, but HPV types 16 and 18 cause most HPV-related cancers. High-risk human papillomavirus is transmitted through intimate skin-to-skin contact, most often during vaginal, anal, or oral sex. Also called high-risk HPV.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000759268" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;high-risk human papillomavirus&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000759269" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;virus del papiloma humano de riesgo alto&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>virus del papiloma humano de riesgo alto</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Grupo de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) que causan cáncer. Estos virus infectan las células de las superficies húmedas o del revestimiento interno de algunos órganos y cavidades corporales, como el cuello uterino, la vagina, la vulva, el pene, el ano, la boca o la garganta. La infección duradera por un tipo de virus del papiloma humano de riesgo alto causa cambios en las células que, si no se encuentran y se extirpan, con el tiempo se vuelven cancerosos. Los virus del papiloma humano de riesgo alto pueden causar cánceres de cuello uterino, ano, orofaringe, vagina, vulva o pene. Existen 12 tipos de virus del papiloma humano de riesgo alto, pero los tipos 16 y 18 causan la mayoría de los cánceres relacionados con estos virus. Los virus del papiloma humano de riesgo alto se trasmiten por el contacto íntimo piel con piel, en especial durante las relaciones sexuales vaginales, anales u orales. También se llama virus del papiloma humano de alto riesgo y VPH de riesgo alto.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2013-12-19</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-09-25</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-and-cancer">HPV and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-vaccine-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/vph-y-cancer?redirect=true">El virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
