<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000754220"><TermName>hereditary cancer syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee KAN-ser SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of inherited disorder in which there is a higher-than-normal risk of certain types of cancer. Hereditary cancer syndromes are caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes passed from parents to children. In a hereditary cancer syndrome, certain patterns of cancer may be seen within families. These patterns include having several close family members (such as a mother, daughter, and sister) with the same type of cancer, developing cancer at an early age, or having two or more types of cancer develop in the same person. Examples of hereditary cancer syndromes are hereditary breast and ovarian cancer syndrome, Li-Fraumeni syndrome, Cowden syndrome, and Lynch syndrome. Also called family cancer syndrome and inherited cancer syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of inherited disorder in which there is a higher-than-normal risk of certain types of cancer. Hereditary cancer syndromes are caused by inherited genetic variants and may be associated with several clinical manifestations. Examples of hereditary cancer syndromes include Lynch syndrome and hereditary breast and ovarian cancer syndrome. Also called family cancer syndrome and inherited cancer syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759263" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary cancer syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759262" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de cáncer hereditario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de cáncer hereditario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de trastorno hereditario en el que hay un riesgo más alto que lo normal de ciertos tipos de cáncer. Los síndromes de cáncer hereditario obedecen a mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que se trasmiten de padres a hijos. En  estos síndromes se observa una distribución específica del cáncer en la familia. Por ejemplo, que se presente el mismo tipo de cáncer en varios familiares cercanos (como madre, hija y hermana), que aparezca cáncer a una edad temprana o que una persona tenga dos o más tipos de cáncer. Algunos ejemplos son el síndrome de cáncer de mama y ovario hereditario, el síndrome de Li-Fraumeni, el síndrome de Cowden y el síndrome de Lynch. También se llama síndrome de cáncer familiar, síndrome de cáncer heredado y síndrome hereditario de susceptibilidad al cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de trastorno hereditario que acarrea un riesgo más alto que lo normal de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer. La causa de los síndromes de cáncer hereditario son variantes genéticas hereditarias y es posible que  se asocien con múltiples manifestaciones clínicas. El síndrome de Lynch y el síndrome de cáncer de mama y ovario hereditario son ejemplos de este tipo de síndrome. También se llama síndrome de cáncer familiar, síndrome de cáncer heredado y síndrome hereditario de susceptibilidad al cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
