<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000757527">
  <TermName>hyper-CVAD regimen</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(HY-per ... REH-jih-men)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An abbreviation for a chemotherapy combination used to treat some types of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) and non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL). Hyper-CVAD regimen includes the drugs cyclophosphamide, vincristine sulfate, doxorubicin hydrochloride (Adriamycin), and dexamethasone. It also includes the drugs methotrexate and cytarabine.  It is given as hyperfractionated therapy, in which the total dose of the drugs is divided into small doses and given more than once a day. Also called hyper-CVAD.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000760850" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hyper-CVAD regimen&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000760849" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;régimen hiper-CVAD&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>régimen hiper-CVAD</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Nombre de una quimioterapia combinada que se usa para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de leucemia linfoblástica aguda (LLA)  y linfoma no Hodgkin (LNH). El régimen hiper-CVDA incluye los medicamentos ciclofosfamida, sulfato de vincristina, clorhidrato de doxorrubicina (Adriamycin) y dexametasona. También incluye los medicamentos metotrexato y citarabina. Se administra como terapia hiperfraccionada, de manera que la dosis total del medicamento se divide en dosis más pequeñas y se administra más de una vez por día. También se llama hiper-CVAD.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2014-03-05</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000757219" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/Hyper-CVAD">Hyper-CVAD</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
