<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000762782"><TermName>Beleodaq</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BEE-lee-oh-dak)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with peripheral T-cell lymphoma that has come back or has not gotten better with other treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Beleodaq blocks certain enzymes needed for cell division and may kill cancer cells. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow and may help make cancer cells easier to kill with other anticancer drugs. It is a type of histone deacetylase inhibitor, a type of antiangiogenesis agent, and a type of chemosensitizer. Also called belinostat and PXD101.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764454" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Beleodaq&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764453" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Beleodaq&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Beleodaq</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con linfoma de células T periféricas que volvió o no mejoró con otro tratamiento.  También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Beleodaq bloquea ciertas enzimas necesarias para la división celular y es posible que destruya células cancerosas.  Además, quizás impida el crecimiento de los vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer, y ayude a que sea más fácil  destruir las células cancerosas cuando se usan otros medicamentos contra el cáncer.  Es un tipo de antiangiogénico, de quimiosensibilizador y de inhibidor de la histona–desacetilasa. También se llama belinostat y PXD101.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-07-11</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000762728" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/belinostat">Belinostat</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
