<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000763024"><TermName>next-generation sequencing</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... JEH-neh-RAY-shun SEE-kwen-sing)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A high-throughput method used to determine a portion of the nucleotide sequence of an individual’s genome. This technique utilizes DNA sequencing technologies that are capable of processing multiple DNA sequences in parallel. Also called massively parallel sequencing and NGS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term that describes methods used in the lab to learn the order of building blocks (called nucleotides) for millions of DNA or RNA fragments at the same time. Computers are used to piece together the fragments in order to sequence a person or other organism’s entire DNA, large segments of DNA or RNA, or the DNA in specific types of cells from a sample of tissue.  Next-generation sequencing can also identify changes in certain areas of the genome or in specific genes.  There are many different types of next-generation sequencing methods, including whole-genome sequencing, whole-exome sequencing, multigene panel testing, and transcriptome sequencing. Next-generation sequencing may help researchers understand the cause of certain diseases, such as cancer. Also called massively parallel sequencing and NGS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764445" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;next-generation sequencing&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804294" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;secuenciación de última generación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>secuenciación de última generación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método de productividad elevada que se usa para determinar una porción de la secuencia de nucleótidos del genoma de un individuo. Para este método se utilizan técnicas de secuenciación del ADN que permiten procesar en paralelo múltiples secuencias de ADN. También se llama NGS, secuenciación de nueva generación, secuenciación de próxima generación y secuenciación masiva en paralelo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que describe los métodos que se usan en un laboratorio para conocer el orden de los componentes básicos (llamados nucleótidos) de millones de fragmentos de ADN y ARN al mismo tiempo. Se utilizan computadoras para juntar los fragmentos y secuenciar el ADN completo, segmentos grandes de ADN o ARN, o ADN de tipos específicos de células en una muestra de tejido de una persona u organismo. Con la secuenciación de última generación también es posible identificar cambios en ciertas áreas del genoma o en genes específicos. Hay diferentes métodos de secuenciación de última generación, como la secuenciación del genoma completo, la secuenciación del exoma completo, la prueba de genes múltiples y la secuenciación de transcriptomas. La secuenciación de última generación a veces ayuda a los investigadores a entender la causa de ciertas enfermedades, como el cáncer. También se llama NGS, secuenciación de nueva generación, secuenciación de próxima generación y secuenciación masiva en paralelo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-07-16</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
