<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000764137"><TermName>Aicardi syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ay-KAR-dee SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, genetic disorder marked by a lack of tissue connecting the left and right halves of the brain, seizures, lesions on the back of the eye (retina), and other brain and eye abnormalities. Other problems may include unusual facial features, defects of the hands, spine, and ribs, and developmental and gastrointestinal problems. When Aicardi syndrome occurs, it is almost always in a newborn girl. People with Aicardi syndrome have an increased risk of certain tumors, such as hepatoblastoma (a type of liver cancer) and choroid plexus tumors (a rare tumor that forms in the brain).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769380" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Aicardi syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769379" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Aicardi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Aicardi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético raro que se caracteriza por la falta del tejido que conecta las mitades izquierda y derecha del cerebro, convulsiones, lesiones en la retina (parte posterior del ojo), y otras alteraciones en el encéfalo y los ojos. Otras manifestaciones son rasgos faciales atípicos, defectos en las manos, la columna vertebral y las costillas, además de alteraciones digestivas y del desarrollo. El síndrome de Aicardi casi siempre afecta a niñas recién nacidas. Las personas afectadas tienen un mayor riesgo de ciertos tumores, como el hepatoblastoma (tipo de cáncer de hígado) y los tumores de plexo coroideo (tumor raro de encéfalo).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-07</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/5764/aicardi-syndrome">Aicardi syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/aicardi-syndrome/">Aicardi syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12500/sindrome-de-aicardi">Síndrome de Aicardi (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001664.htm">Síndrome de Aicardi (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
