<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000764540"><TermName>Keytruda</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kee-TROO-duh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that binds to the protein PD-1 to help immune cells kill cancer cells better and is used to treat many different types of cancer. These include cancers that express the protein PD-L1, that have certain mutations (changes) in genes involved in DNA repair, or that have a high number of tumor mutations. Keytruda is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of biliary tract cancer (including bile duct cancer and gallbladder cancer), breast cancer, cervical cancer, classic Hodgkin lymphoma, colorectal cancer, endometrial cancer, esophageal cancer, gastroesophageal junction cancer, head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (SCC), hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), malignant pleural mesothelioma, non-small cell lung cancer, primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma, renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer), skin cancer (SCC of the skin, Merkel cell carcinoma, and melanoma), stomach cancer, urothelial carcinoma (a type of bladder or urinary tract cancer), and other solid tumors. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Keytruda may block PD-1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called pembrolizumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766723" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Keytruda&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766722" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Keytruda&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Keytruda</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se une a la proteína PD-1 para ayudar a las células inmunitarias a  destruir más células cancerosas, y que se usa para el tratamiento de muchos tipos diferentes de cáncer. Entre ellos, los cánceres que  expresan la proteína PD-L1, que tienen ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en los genes que participan en la reparación del ADN o que tienen muchas mutaciones en el tumor. Keytruda se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer biliar (como el cáncer de vías biliares y de vesícula biliar), cáncer de mama, cáncer de cuello uterino, linfoma de Hodgkin clásico, cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de endometrio, cáncer de esófago, cáncer de unión gastroesofágica, carcinoma de células escamosas de cabeza y cuello, carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), mesotelioma pleural maligno, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas, linfoma mediastínico primario de células B grandes, carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón), cáncer  de piel (carcinoma de células escamosas de piel, carcinoma de células de Merkel y melanoma), cáncer de estómago, carcinoma urotelial (tipo de cáncer de vejiga o aparato urinario) y otros tumores sólidos. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Es posible que Keytruda bloquee PD-1 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama pembrolizumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-09-18</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-11-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000764622" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/pembrolizumab">Pembrolizumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">immune checkpoint inhibitor</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
