<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000767370">
  <TermName>lanreotide acetate</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(lan-REE-oh-tide A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that is similar to  somatostatin (a hormone made by the body) and is used to treat certain types of gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors, carcinoid syndrome, and acromegaly  (a condition in which the pituitary gland makes too much growth hormone). Lanreotide acetate may help stop the body from making extra amounts of certain hormones, including growth hormone, insulin, glucagon, and hormones that affect digestion. It may also help keep certain types of tumor cells from growing. Lanreotide acetate is a type of somatostatin analog. Also called Somatuline Depot.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000769337" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lanreotide acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000769336" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetato de lanreotida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>acetato de lanreotida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento similar a la somatostatina (hormona elaborada por el cuerpo) que se usa para  el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de tumores neuroendocrinos gastroenteropancreáticos, el síndrome carcinoide y la acromegalia (afección por la que la hipófisis elabora demasiada hormona del crecimiento). El acetato de lanreotida quizás ayude a impedir que el cuerpo elabore demasiada cantidad de determinadas hormonas,  como la hormona del crecimiento, la insulina, el glucagón y las hormonas que afectan la digestión. Además, es posible que impida la multiplicación de algunos tipos de células tumorales. El acetato de lanreotida es un tipo de análogo de la somatostatina. También se llama Somatulina Depot.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2014-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-10-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000767468" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/lanreotideacetate">Lanreotide Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
