<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000767620">
  <TermName>recombinant human papillomavirus nonavalent vaccine</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ree-KOM-bih-nunt HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus NOH-nuh-VAY-lent vak-SEEN)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A vaccine that is FDA-approved for use in females and males aged 9 to 45 years to protect against infection with nine types of human papillomavirus (HPV).  Recombinant human papillomavirus nonavalent vaccine protects against low-risk HPV types 6 and 11, which cause most genital warts, and against high-risk HPV types 16, 18, 31, 33, 45, 52, and 58, which cause most precancerous lesions and cancers of the cervix, vagina, vulva, anus, and head and neck, including the oropharynx. Recombinant human papillomavirus nonavalent vaccine may also prevent HPV-related cancer of the penis. Also called Gardasil 9.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000769331" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;recombinant human papillomavirus nonavalent vaccine&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000769330" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vacuna recombinante nonavalente contra el virus del papiloma humano&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>vacuna recombinante nonavalente contra el virus del papiloma humano</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Vacuna aprobada por la FDA para usar en mujeres y hombres de 9 a 45 años con el fin de prevenir la infección por 9 tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). La vacuna recombinante nonavalente contra el virus del papiloma humano protege contra los tipos 6 y 11 de VPH de riesgo bajo que producen la mayoría de las verrugas genitales. También protege contra los tipos 16, 18, 31, 33, 45, 52 y 58 de VPH de riesgo alto que causan la mayoría de las lesiones precancerosas y los cánceres de  cuello uterino, vagina, vulva, ano, y cabeza y cuello, incluso el cáncer de orofaringe. Es posible que la vacuna recombinante nonavalente contra el virus del papiloma humano también prevenga el cáncer de pene relacionado con el VPH. También se llama Gardasil 9 y vacuna nonavalente contra el VPH.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2014-12-29</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-02-15</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000767283" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/recombinant-HPV-nonavalent-vaccine">Recombinant Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Nonavalent Vaccine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-vaccine-fact-sheet">Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/hoja-informativa-vacuna-vph">Vacunas contra el virus del papiloma humano (VPH)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
