<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000767747"><TermName>nivolumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(nih-VOL-yoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that binds to the protein PD-1 to help immune cells kill cancer cells better and is used to treat many different types of cancer. These include cancers that express the protein PD-L1 or that have certain mutations (changes) in genes involved in DNA repair. Nivolumab is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of classic Hodgkin lymphoma, colorectal cancer, esophageal cancer, gastroesophageal junction cancer, head and neck squamous cell carcinoma, hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), malignant pleural mesothelioma, melanoma, non-small cell lung cancer, renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer), stomach cancer, and urothelial carcinoma (a type of bladder or urinary tract cancer). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Nivolumab may block PD-1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called Opdivo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771214" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nivolumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771213" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nivolumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>nivolumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se une a la proteína PD-1 para ayudar a las células inmunitarias a destruir más células cancerosas, y que se usa  para el tratamiento de muchos tipos diferentes de cáncer. Entre ellos, los cánceres que expresan la proteína PD-L1 o que tienen ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en los genes que participan en la reparación del ADN. El nivolumab se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de linfoma de Hodgkin clásico, cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de esófago, cáncer de unión gastroesofágica, carcinoma de células escamosas de cabeza y cuello, carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), mesotelioma pleural maligno, melanoma, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas, carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón), cáncer de estómago y carcinoma urotelial (tipo de cáncer de vejiga o de aparato urinario). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Es posible que el nivolumab bloquee PD-1 y ayude al
sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un
tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de
puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama Opdivo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-01-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-10-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000767749" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/nivolumab">Nivolumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">immune checkpoint inhibitor</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
