<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000771302"><TermName>CAR T-cell therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kar T-sel THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment in which a patient's T cells (a type of immune system cell) are changed in the laboratory so they will attack cancer cells. T cells are taken from a patient’s blood. Then the gene for a special receptor that binds to a certain protein on the patient’s cancer cells is added to the T cells in the laboratory. The special receptor is called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR). Large numbers of the CAR T cells are grown in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. CAR T-cell therapy is used to treat certain blood cancers, and it is being studied in the treatment of  other types of cancer. Also called chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774971" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CAR T-cell therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774972" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia de células T con CAR&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774647" type="image/jpeg" alt="CAR T-cell therapy; drawing of blood being removed from a vein in a patient’s arm to get T cells. Also shown is a special receptor called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) being made in the laboratory; the gene for CAR is inserted into the T cells and then millions of CAR T cells are grown. Drawing also shows the CAR T cells being given to the patient by infusion and binding to antigens on the cancer cells and killing them." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">CAR T-cell therapy. A type of treatment in which a patient’s T cells (a type of immune cell) are changed in the laboratory so they will bind to cancer cells and kill them. Blood from a vein in the patient’s arm flows through a tube to an apheresis machine (not shown), which removes the white blood cells, including the T cells, and sends the rest of the blood back to the patient. Then, the gene for a special receptor called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is inserted into the T cells in the laboratory. Millions of the CAR T cells are grown in the laboratory and then given to the patient by infusion. The CAR T cells are able to bind to an antigen on the cancer cells and kill them.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791284" type="image/jpeg" alt="Terapia de células T con CAR. En el dibujo se muestra que se extrae sangre de una vena del brazo de un paciente para obtener células T. También se muestra que se elabora en el laboratorio un receptor especial, que se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR); se añade a las células T el gen que produce el CAR y luego se reproducen millones de células T con CAR. Además, se muestra que el paciente recibe las células T con CAR mediante infusión, y que luego estas células se unen a los antígenos de las células cancerosas y las destruyen." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Terapia de células T con CAR. Tipo de tratamiento  en el que se modifican las células T (un tipo de célula inmunitaria) de un paciente en el laboratorio a fin de que se unan a las células cancerosas y las destruyan. La sangre de una vena del brazo del paciente pasa por un tubo hasta una máquina de  aféresis (no se muestra) que extrae los glóbulos blancos, incluso las células T, y devuelve el resto de la sangre al paciente. Luego,   en el laboratorio, el gen que produce un receptor especial, que se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR), se añade a las células T, y se reproducen millones de células T con CAR que el paciente recibe mediante infusión. Las células T   con CAR se unen a un antígeno de las células cancerosas y las destruyen.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>terapia de células T con CAR</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento en el que las células T (tipo de célula del sistema inmunitario) del paciente  se modifican en el laboratorio para que ataquen a las células cancerosas. Las células T se extraen de la sangre del paciente, y en el laboratorio, se les añade el gen de un receptor especial que se une a cierta proteína de las células cancerosas del paciente. Este receptor especial se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR). En el laboratorio se producen grandes cantidades de células T con CAR y se administran al paciente mediante infusión. La terapia de células T con CAR se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos cánceres de la sangre, y está en estudio  para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. También se llama terapia CAR-T, terapia celular CAR-T, terapia con células CAR-T, terapia de células T con receptor quimérico para el antígeno, terapia de linfocitos T con CAR y tratamiento con linfocitos T-CAR.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-07-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-05-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/immunotherapy/t-cell-transfer-therapy">T-cell Transfer Therapy</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/inmunoterapia/terapia-transferencia-de-celulas-t">Terapia de transferencia de células T</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
