<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000772584"><TermName>research advocate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(REE-serch AD-vuh-kut)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A person who serves as a link between patients and scientific researchers. Research advocates help patients understand scientific information and research findings that may help them.  They may also bring a patient perspective on research activities to scientific advisory boards and committees. For example, research advocates use their own experiences and the experiences of patients to work with researchers to help develop clinical trials that are safe and meet the needs of patients. They also help teach patients and their families about clinical trials and recruit patients to clinical trials.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774996" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;research advocate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774995" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;defensor de los participantes en investigación&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/><SpanishTermName>defensor de los participantes en investigación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Persona que sirve de vínculo entre pacientes e  investigadores.  Los defensores de los participantes en investigación ayudan a los pacientes a  entender la información científica y los hallazgos de las investigaciones que quizás los beneficien.  En ocasiones, también aportan a los consejos y comités asesores científicos la visión del paciente sobre las actividades relacionadas con la investigación.  Por ejemplo, los defensores de la investigación usan sus propias experiencias y las de los pacientes para colaborar con los investigadores con el fin de ayudar a diseñar ensayos clínicos inocuos y que responden a  las necesidades de los pacientes.  También informan a los pacientes y sus familias acerca de los ensayos clínicos y preseleccionan participantes para esos ensayos. También se llama defensor de pacientes en investigación y representante de los pacientes en investigación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-06-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-nci/organization/oar/research-advocacy">Research Advocacy at NCI</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
