<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000773135">
  <TermName>orphan drug designation</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(OR-fun … DEH-zig-NAY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A status given to certain drugs called orphan drugs, which show promise in the treatment, prevention, or diagnosis of orphan diseases. An orphan disease is a rare disease or condition that affects fewer than 200,000 people in the United States. Orphan diseases are often serious or life threatening. In 1983, the U.S. government passed a law, called the Orphan Drug Act, to give drug companies certain financial benefits for developing orphan drugs. This law is meant to help bring more drugs to patients with rare diseases.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776441" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;orphan drug designation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776440" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;designación de medicamento huérfano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>designación de medicamento huérfano</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Asignación que se otorga a ciertos medicamentos conocidos como medicamentos huérfanos que parecen prometedores para el tratamiento, prevención o diagnóstico de enfermedades huérfanas.  Se dice que una enfermedad o afección es huérfana o rara cuando afecta a menos de 200 000 personas en los Estados Unidos. Con frecuencia, estas enfermedades son graves o potencialmente mortales. En 1983, el gobierno de los Estados Unidos emitió una ley llamada Orphan Drug Act que proporciona a las compañías farmacéuticas ciertos beneficios financieros para la elaboración de medicamentos huérfanos. Esta ley tiene el propósito de ayudar en la distribución de más medicamentos a pacientes con enfermedades poco frecuentes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2015-08-13</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
