<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774376"><TermName>testicular sperm extraction</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tes-TIH-kyoo-ler spurm ek-STRAK-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which sperm cells are removed and either used right away to fertilize eggs or frozen for future infertility treatment.  Tissue is removed from the testicle through a small incision (cut) and looked at under a microscope in the laboratory to find sperm cells. Testicular sperm extraction may be useful for men who want to have children after having treatment that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Testicular sperm extraction is a type of sperm retrieval method. Also called TESE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776500" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;testicular sperm extraction&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776501" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extracción de espermatozoides del testículo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>extracción de espermatozoides del testículo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el cual se extraen espermatozoides para fecundar óvulos de manera inmediata, o para congelarlos y almacenarlos  con el fin de tratar la esterilidad en el futuro.  La extracción de espermatozoides del testículo suele ser útil  para los hombres que quieren tener hijos después de recibir un tratamiento que puede causar esterilidad, como ciertos tratamientos para el cáncer. La extracción de espermatozoides del testículo es un método para la extracción de espermatozoides. También se llama EET.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-men" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Boys and Men with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-hombres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en los hombres con cáncer: niños y adultos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
