<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774384"><TermName>follow-up care</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FAH-loh-up kayr)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Care given to a patient over time after finishing treatment for a disease. Follow-up care involves regular medical checkups,   which may include a physical exam, blood tests, and imaging tests. Follow-up care checks for health problems that may occur months or years after treatment ends, including the development of other types of cancer. Follow-up care is given after positive screening test results, such as a positive Pap test result. In cancer patients, one purpose of follow-up care is checking to see if the cancer has come back or has spread to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776510" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;follow-up care&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776509" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;atención de seguimiento&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>atención de seguimiento</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Atención que se brinda a un paciente a lo largo del tiempo después de terminar el tratamiento de una enfermedad. Incluye citas y revisiones médicas regulares, que pueden incluir exámenes físicos, análisis de sangre y pruebas de imágenes. Durante el seguimiento, se vigila la aparición de problemas de salud que se pueden presentar meses o años después de terminar el tratamiento, incluso otros tipos de cáncer. Este tipo de atención también se brinda cuando se recibe un resultado positivo en un examen de detección, como un resultado anormal en una prueba de Pap. En los pacientes de cáncer, uno de los propósitos de la atención de seguimiento es determinar si el cáncer volvió o se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También se llama control postratamiento, cuidado de seguimiento y seguimiento médico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping/survivorship/follow-up-care">Follow-Up Medical Care</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/supervivencia/cuidados-de-seguimiento">Atención médica de seguimiento</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
