<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774382">
  <TermName>ovarian tissue freezing</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(oh-VAYR-ee-un TIH-shoo FREE-zing)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The process of freezing ovarian tissue to save for future infertility treatment. Part or all of an ovary is removed, and the tissue that contains the eggs is cut into thin slices and frozen. The tissue may later be thawed and placed back into the woman’s body, usually on the remaining ovary.  Ovarian tissue freezing is a type of fertility preservation. It may be useful for women who want to have children after having treatment that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Also called ovarian tissue banking and ovarian tissue cryopreservation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776506" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ovarian tissue freezing&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776507" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;congelamiento de tejido ovárico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>congelamiento de tejido ovárico</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el cual se congela tejido de los ovarios  para usarlo en un futuro como tratamiento de la esterilidad. Se extrae el ovario completo o una parte de este, luego el tejido que contiene los óvulos se corta en láminas finas y se congela para almacenarlo. Este tejido se puede descongelar después para colocarlo en el cuerpo de la mujer, por lo general en el ovario que quedó.  El congelamiento de tejido ovárico es un tipo de preservación de la fertilidad. Puede ser útil para mujeres que quieren tener hijos luego de recibir un tratamiento que en ocasiones causa esterilidad, como ciertos tratamientos del cáncer. También se llama almacenamiento de tejido ovárico, congelación de tejido ovárico y criopreservación de tejido ovárico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-women" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Girls and Women with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-mujeres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en las mujeres con cáncer: niñas y adultas</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
