<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774492">
  <TermName>testicular tissue freezing</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(tes-TIH-kyoo-ler TIH-shoo FREE-zing)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A process being developed to freeze testicular tissue from boys who have not gone through puberty, to save for future infertility treatment. Tissue that contains cells that make sperm is removed from the testicles through a small incision (cut). It is then frozen and stored. At a later date, the tissue can be thawed to retrieve sperm. Testicular tissue freezing is being studied as a type of fertility preservation. It may be useful for young boys who are going to have treatments that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Also called testicular tissue banking and testicular tissue cryopreservation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776489" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;testicular tissue freezing&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776488" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;congelamiento de tejido testicular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>congelamiento de tejido testicular</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proceso, en fase de desarrollo, para congelar tejido de los testículos de varones jóvenes que no han llegado a la pubertad, a fin de  guardarlo para tratar la esterilidad en el futuro. Se extrae el tejido de los testículos que contiene las células de las que se forman los espermatozoides mediante una pequeña incisión (corte). Luego se congela, se almacena y, en una fecha posterior, se descongela para extraer los espermatozoides.   El congelamiento de tejido testicular está en estudio como un tipo de preservación de la fertilidad y puede ser útil para los varones jóvenes que recibirán tratamientos que en ocasiones causan esterilidad, como ciertos tipos de tratamientos del cáncer. También se llama almacenamiento de tejido testicular, congelación de tejido testicular y criopreservación de tejido testicular.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-men" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Boys and Men with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-hombres">Cuestiones de fecundidad en los hombres con cáncer: niños y adultos</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
