<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774531"><TermName>HER2 negative</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… NEH-guh-tiv)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes cells that have a small amount or none of a protein called HER2 on their surface. In normal cells, HER2 helps control cell growth. Cancer cells that are HER2 negative may grow more slowly and are less likely to recur (come back) or spread to other parts of the body than cancer cells that have a large amount of HER2 on their surface. Checking to see if a cancer is HER2 negative may help plan treatment.  Cancers that may be HER2 negative include breast, bladder, ovarian, pancreatic, and stomach cancers. Also called human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000777144" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HER2 negative&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000777145" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;negativa para HER2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>negativa para HER2</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Característica de una célula que no tiene una proteína llamada HER2 en su superficie, o que tiene poca cantidad de esta proteína. En las células normales, HER2 ayuda a controlar la multiplicación celular. Es posible que las células cancerosas negativas para HER2  se multipliquen más lento, y es menos probable que recidiven (vuelvan) o se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo. Saber si un cáncer es negativo para HER2 quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento. Entre los cánceres que a veces son negativos para HER2 se incluyen el cáncer de mama, vejiga, páncreas, ovario y estómago. También se llama negativa para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-10-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-11-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
