<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774532"><TermName>human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HYOO-mun eh-pih-DER-mul grothe FAK-ter reh-SEP-ter … NEH-guh-tiv)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes cells that have a small amount or none of a protein called HER2 on their surface. In normal cells, HER2 helps control cell growth. Cancer cells that are human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative may grow more slowly and are less likely to recur (come back) or spread to other parts of the body than cancer cells that have a large amount of HER2 on their surface. Checking to see if a cancer is human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative may help plan treatment.  Cancers that may be human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative include breast, bladder, ovarian, pancreatic, and stomach cancers. Also called HER2 negative.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000777146" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000777147" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;negativa para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>negativa para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Característica de una célula que no tiene una proteína llamada HER2 en su superficie, o que tiene poca cantidad de esta proteína. En las células normales, HER2 ayuda a controlar la multiplicación celular. Es posible que las células cancerosas negativas para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano  se multipliquen más lento, y es menos probable que recidiven (vuelvan) o se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo. Saber si un cáncer es negativo para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento. Entre los cánceres que a veces son negativos para el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano se incluyen el cáncer de mama, vejiga, páncreas, ovario y estómago. También se llama negativa para HER2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-10-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-11-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
