<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000775143">
  <TermName>trisomy 18</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(TRY-soh-mee …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A genetic disorder caused by having an extra chromosome 18 in some or all of the body’s cells. Trisomy 18 is marked by a low birth weight and certain abnormal features. These include a small, abnormally shaped head; a small jaw and mouth; clenched fists with overlapping fingers; and heart, lung, kidney, intestine, and stomach defects. Many babies with trisomy 18 die before birth or within the first month of life, but some children live for several years. Having trisomy 18 increases the risk of certain types of cancer, such as hepatoblastoma (a type of liver cancer) and Wilms tumor (a type of kidney cancer). Also called Edwards syndrome.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000777149" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trisomy 18&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000777148" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trisomía 18&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>trisomía 18</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno genético causado por tener un cromosoma 18 de más en todas las células del cuerpo o en algunas células. La trisomía 18 se caracteriza por peso bajo al nacer y ciertos rasgos inusuales, como una cabeza pequeña con una forma anormal; mandíbula y boca pequeñas; puños apretados con dedos superpuestos, y defectos en el corazón, los pulmones, los riñones, los intestinos y el estómago. Muchos bebés con trisomía 18 mueren antes de nacer o en el primer mes de vida, pero algunos niños viven durante varios años. La trisomía 18 aumenta el riesgo de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el hepatoblastoma (tipo de cáncer de hígado) y el tumor de Wilms (tipo de cáncer de riñón). También se llama síndrome de Edwards.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2015-11-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6321/edwards-syndrome">Trisomy 18 (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/trisomy-18/">Trisomy 18 (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001661.htm">Trisomía 18 (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
