<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000775581">
  <TermName>multigene test</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MUL-tee-jeen ...)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Genetic tests that use next-generation sequencing to test multiple genes simultaneously. Also called MGPT and multigene panel test.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A laboratory test in which many genes are studied in a sample of tissue. Multigene tests help find mutations (changes) in certain genes that may increase a person’s risk of a disease such as cancer. They may also look at the activity of certain genes in a sample of tissue. Multigene tests may be used to help plan treatment or help predict whether cancer will spread to other parts of the body or come back. Also called MGPT and multigene panel test.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776445" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;multigene test&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804311" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;análisis multigénico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>análisis multigénico</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio en la que se estudian muchos genes en una muestra de tejido. Los análisis multigénicos sirven para encontrar mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que quizás aumenten el riesgo de enfermedades como el cáncer. También permiten estudiar la actividad de ciertos genes en una muestra de tejido. Los análisis multigénicos a veces se usan para planificar el tratamiento o predecir si el cáncer se diseminará a otras partes del cuerpo o volverá. También se llama prueba de genes múltiples.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Pruebas genéticas que sirven para analizar de manera simultánea múltiples genes mediante secuenciación de última generación. También se llama prueba de genes múltiples.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2015-09-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-07-24</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/biomarker-testing-cancer-treatment" UseWith="en">Biomarker Testing for Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/risk-assessment-pdq" UseWith="en">Cancer Genetics Risk Assessment and Counseling (Health Professional Version)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/pruebas-de-biomarcadores-tratamiento-cancer" UseWith="es">Pruebas de biomarcadores para el tratamiento de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
