<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000776570">
  <TermName>irinotecan sucrosofate</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(I-rih-noh-TEE-kan soo-KROH-soh-fayt)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of the anticancer drug irinotecan hydrochloride that is contained inside very tiny, fat-like particles and is used with other drugs to treat adults with pancreatic cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients whose cancer has not been treated with other anticancer therapy or has gotten worse after treatment with gemcitabine hydrochloride. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Irinotecan sucrosofate may have fewer side effects and work better than other forms of irinotecan hydrochloride. Irinotecan sucrosofate blocks a certain enzyme needed for cell division and DNA repair, and it may kill cancer cells. It is a type of topoisomerase inhibitor and a type of camptothecin analog. Also called Onivyde and PEP02.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000777158" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;irinotecan sucrosofate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000777157" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sucrosofato de irinotecán&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sucrosofato de irinotecán</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma del medicamento contra el cáncer clorhidrato de irinotecán que se está contenido o encapsulado en partículas lipoides diminutas (liposomas). Se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de páncreas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se utiliza en pacientes que no han recibido otro tratamiento contra el cáncer o que empeoraron después de recibir clorhidrato de gemcitabina. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El sucrosofato de irinotecán quizás produzca menos efectos secundarios,  y es posible que sea más eficaz que otras formas del medicamento; además, bloquea una enzima necesaria para la multiplicación celular y la reparación del ADN, y es posible que destruya células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la topoisomerasa y un análogo de la camptotecina. También se llama Onivyde y PEP02.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2015-10-27</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-02-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000776561" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/irinotecan-hydrochloride-liposome">Irinotecan Sucrosofate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
