<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000776875"><TermName>cobimetinib fumarate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOH-bih-MEH-tih-nib FYOO-muh-rayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used alone to treat adults with a group of blood disorders called  histiocytic neoplasms and with vemurafenib to treat adults with melanoma that has spread or cannot be removed by surgery and has a certain mutation (change) in the <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> gene. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Cobimetinib fumarate blocks proteins called MEK1 and MEK2, which may help keep tumor cells from growing. It is a type of kinase inhibitor. Also called Cotellic.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000778407" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cobimetinib fumarate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000778406" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fumarato de cobimetinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>fumarato de cobimetinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa como monoterapia (sin otros medicamentos) para el tratamiento de un grupo de enfermedades de la sangre llamadas neoplasias histiocíticas. También se usa con el vemurafenib para el tratamiento de adultos con melanoma que se diseminó o que no es posible extirpar mediante cirugía, y  tiene determinada mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El fumarato de cobimetinib bloquea las proteínas MEK1 y MEK2, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células tumorales. Es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas. También se llama Cotellic.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-11-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-11-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000776883" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/cobimetinib">Cobimetinib Fumarate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
