<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000777080"><TermName>necitumumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NEH-sih-TOO-moo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with gemcitabine and cisplatin to treat squamous non-small cell lung cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients whose cancer has not been treated with other anticancer therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Necitumumab binds to a protein called epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), which is found on some types of cancer cells. Blocking this protein may help keep cancer cells from growing. Necitumumab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Portrazza.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000778419" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;necitumumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000778418" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;necitumumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>necitumumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con la gemcitabina y el cisplatino para tratar el cáncer de pulmón de  células no pequeñas y escamosas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se usa  en pacientes cuyo cáncer no se trató con otras terapias contra el cáncer. También está en estudio  para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El necitumumab  se une a una proteína llamada receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico (RFCE), que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. El bloqueo de esta proteína puede ayudar a impedir la formación de células cancerosas. El necitumumab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Portrazza.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-12-07</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000777166" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/necitumumab">Necitumumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
