<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000777025"><TermName>primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PRY-mayr-ee MEE-dee-uh-STY-nul larj ... sel lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An aggressive (fast-growing) type of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma (cancer of the immune system).  Primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma develops from B cells in the mediastinum (the area behind the breastbone). It may spread to organs and tissues such as the lungs, pericardium (sac around the heart), liver, gastrointestinal tract, ovaries, adrenal glands, and central nervous system. Most patients with primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma are women who are age 30 to 40 years but it may also occur in older children. Also known as primary mediastinal B-cell lymphoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780330" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780329" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma mediastínico primario de células B grandes&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma mediastínico primario de células B grandes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B (cáncer del sistema inmunitario) de crecimiento rápido (agresivo). El linfoma mediastínico primario de células B grandes se forma a partir de las células B del mediastino (área detrás del esternón). Es posible que se disemine a órganos y tejidos como los pulmones, el pericardio (membrana que rodea el corazón), el hígado, el tubo digestivo, los ovarios, las glándulas suprarrenales y el sistema nervioso central. La mayoría de los casos se presentan en mujeres de 30 a 40 años de edad, pero a veces se presenta en niños. También se llama linfoma mediastínico primario de células B, linfoma mediastínico primario de linfocitos B grandes y linfoma primario mediastinal de células B.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-03-14</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
