<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000777030">
  <TermName>CTLA-4</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A protein found on T cells (a type of immune cell) that helps keep the body’s immune responses in check.  When CTLA-4 is bound to another protein called B7, it helps keep T cells from killing other cells, including cancer cells. Some anticancer drugs, called immune checkpoint inhibitors, are used to block CTLA-4. When this protein is blocked, the “brakes” on the immune system are released and the ability of T cells to kill cancer cells is increased.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000776560" type="image/jpeg" alt="Immune checkpoint inhibitor; the panel on the left shows the binding of the T-cell receptor (TCR) to antigen and MHC proteins on the antigen-presenting cell (APC) and the binding of CD28 on the T cell to B7-1/B7-2 on the APC. It also shows the binding of B7-1/B7-2 to CTLA-4 on the T cell, which keeps the T cells in the inactive state. The panel on the right shows immune checkpoint inhibitor (anti-CTLA antibody) blocking the binding of B7-1/B7-2 to CTLA-4, which allows the T cells to be active and to kill tumor cells." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Immune checkpoint inhibitor. Checkpoint proteins, such as B7-1/B7-2 on antigen-presenting cells (APC) and CTLA-4 on T cells, help keep the body’s immune responses in check. When the T-cell receptor (TCR) binds to antigen and major histocompatibility complex (MHC) proteins on the APC and CD28 binds to B7-1/B7-2 on the APC, the T cell can be activated. However, the binding of B7-1/B7-2 to CTLA-4 keeps the T cells in the inactive state so they are not able to kill tumor cells in the body (left panel). Blocking the binding of B7-1/B7-2 to CTLA-4 with an immune checkpoint inhibitor (anti-CTLA-4 antibody) allows the T cells to be active and to kill tumor cells (right panel).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000777020" type="image/jpeg" alt="Inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. En el panel izquierdo, se observa la unión del receptor de la célula T (TCR) con el antígeno y las proteínas del complejo principal de histocompatibilidad (MHC) en la célula presentadora de antígeno, y la unión de CD28 en la célula T con B7-1/B7-2 en la célula presentadora de antígeno. También se muestra la unión de B7-1/B7-2 con CTLA-4 en la célula T, que mantiene inactivas a las células T. En el panel derecho, se observa un inhibidor de puntos de control (anticuerpo anti-CTLA) que impide la unión de B7-1/B7-2 con CTLA-4, lo que permite que las células T se activen y destruyan las células tumorales." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. Las proteínas de puntos de control, como B7-1/B7-2 en  las células presentadoras de antígeno y CTLA-4 en las células T, ayudan a mantener bajo control las reacciones inmunitarias. Cuando el receptor de las células T (TCR) se une al antígeno y a las proteínas del complejo principal de histocompatibilidad (MHC) en la célula presentadora de antígeno y  CD28 se une a B7-1/B7-2 en la célula presentadora de antígeno, es posible que se active la célula  T. Sin embargo, la unión de  B7-1/B7-2 con CTLA-4 mantiene las células T inactivas de manera que no pueden destruir las células tumorales del cuerpo (panel izquierdo). El bloqueo de la unión de  B7-1/B7-2 con CTLA-4 con un inhibidor de puntos de control (anticuerpo anti-CTLA-4) permite que la célula T se active y destruya las células tumorales (panel derecho).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>CTLA-4</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proteína que se encuentra en las células T (un tipo de célula inmunitaria) que ayuda al cuerpo a mantener bajo control las respuestas inmunitarias. Cuando CTLA-4 se une a otra proteína llamada B7, impide que las células T destruyan otras células, como las células cancerosas. Algunos medicamentos contra el cáncer, que se llaman inhibidores de puntos de control inmunitario, se usan para impedir la acción de  CTLA-4. Cuando se bloquea esta proteína, se sueltan los &quot;frenos&quot; del sistema inmunitario y aumenta la capacidad de las células T de destruir células cancerosas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-03-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-04-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">immune checkpoint inhibitor</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
