<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000777449"><TermName>Alecensa</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-leh-SEN-suh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of non-small cell lung cancer that are ALK positive. It used in patients whose cancer has spread to other parts of the body. It is also used to help keep cancer from coming back in patients whose cancer was removed by surgery. Alecensa is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Alecensa blocks certain proteins made by the <GeneName>ALK</GeneName> gene, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called alectinib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000778417" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Alecensa&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000778416" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Alecensa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Alecensa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas positivos para ALK. Se administra a pacientes cuyo cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También se utiliza para evitar que el cáncer vuelva en los pacientes que se sometieron a cirugía para extirparlo. Alecensa está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  Alecensa bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan a partir del gen <GeneName>ALK</GeneName>, lo que  quizás ayude a detener la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama alectinib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-12-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-04-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000777392" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/alectinib">Alectinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
