<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000778326">
  <TermName>restaging</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ree-STAY-jing)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A process used to find out the amount or spread of cancer in the body if it comes back or gets worse after treatment. Restaging may also be done to find out how the cancer responded to treatment. If restaging is done and a new stage is assigned, the new stage will be marked with an “r” in front of it to show that it’s different from the original stage. Usually, the  original stage stays the same, even if the cancer comes back or gets worse. The same tests that were done to diagnose the cancer are usually done again. Restaging helps doctors plan the best treatment for cancer that has come back or gotten worse.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000780344" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;restaging&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>reestadificación</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el que se examina el grado de diseminación del cáncer en el cuerpo y se averigua si el cáncer volvió o empeoró después del tratamiento.  La reestadificación también se hace para  determinar si el cáncer respondió al tratamiento. Si se hace una reestadificación y se asigna un  estadio nuevo, se anotará una &quot;r&quot; antes del estadio, lo que indica que el estadio es diferente del inicial. Por lo general,  el estadio original no cambia, aun si el cáncer regresa o empeora. Normalmente, se vuelve a realizar las mismas pruebas que se usaron para el diagnóstico del cáncer. La reestadificación permite que los médicos planeen el mejor tratamiento para el cáncer que volvió o empeoró.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-02-03</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
