<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000778643">
  <TermName>pain flare</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(payn flayr)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A sudden increase in pain that may occur in patients who already have chronic pain from cancer, arthritis, fibromyalgia, or other conditions. A pain flare usually lasts for a short time. During a pain flare, the level of pain may be severe but the type of pain and where it is in the body are usually the same as the patient’s chronic pain. Pain flares may occur with stress, illness, and certain activities, such as exercising or coughing, or when the dose of pain medicine that the patient is taking wears off. Pain flares are usually not a symptom of a new condition or a condition that has gotten worse. Also called breakthrough pain.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000780306" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pain flare&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000780305" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;crisis de dolor&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>crisis de dolor</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Aumento repentino del dolor que a veces presentan los pacientes que ya tienen un dolor crónico causado por cáncer, artritis, fibromialgia u otras afecciones. Por lo general, una crisis de dolor  dura poco tiempo, pero el dolor puede ser muy intenso; suele producirse en el mismo lugar del dolor crónico. Las causas de una crisis de dolor son estrés, enfermedades o actividades, como hacer ejercicio o toser. También aparece cuando pasa el efecto de la dosis del medicamento para controlar el dolor. Este tipo de dolor no suele ser un síntoma de un problema de salud nuevo ni de un empeoramiento de la afección del paciente. También se llama brote de dolor, dolor intercurrente, empeoramiento del dolor, exacerbación del dolor, reagudización del dolor y recrudecimiento del dolor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-03-29</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2016-08-15</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062845" url="/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/pain/pain-pdq">Cancer Pain</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/pain">Pain in People with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256654" url="/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/dolor/dolor-pdq">El dolor y el cáncer</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/dolor">Dolor</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
