<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000778725"><TermName>hemizygous</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HEH-mee-ZY-gus)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes an individual who has only one member of a chromosome pair or chromosome segment rather than the usual two. Hemizygosity is often used to describe X-linked genes in males who have only one X chromosome. This term is sometimes used in somatic cell genetics where cancer cell lines are often hemizygous for certain alleles or chromosomal regions.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term that describes a person who has only one copy of a gene rather than the usual two copies. Hemizygosity can occur under normal conditions. For example, because most males have one X chromosome and one Y chromosome, they are hemizygous for genes on those chromosomes. Hemizygosity can also occur under abnormal conditions, such as when two copies of a gene should be present but one is missing. For example, Turner syndrome occurs when a female inherits only one copy of the X chromosome instead of the usual two copies.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780348" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemizygous&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804317" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemicigótico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>hemicigótico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describe a un individuo que solo tiene un cromosoma del par de cromosomas normales, o que solo tiene un segmento cromosómico en lugar de los dos habituales. La hemicigosis a menudo se usa para  describir los genes ligados al cromosoma X en varones porque solo tienen un cromosoma X. Este término a veces se usa en el ámbito de la genética de las células somáticas para describir las líneas de células cancerosas que a menudo son hemicigóticas para determinados alelos  o regiones cromosómicas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que describe a las personas que solo tienen una copia de un gen, en lugar de las dos copias habituales. Es posible que la hemicigosis se presente en condiciones normales. Por ejemplo, como la mayoría de los hombres tienen un cromosoma X y un cromosoma Y, son hemicigóticos para los genes de esos cromosomas. La hemicigosis también ocurre en condiciones anormales, como cuando deberían estar presentes dos copias de un gen pero falta una. Por ejemplo, el síndrome de Turner se produce cuando una mujer hereda solo una copia del cromosoma X, en lugar de las dos copias habituales.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-02-08</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
