<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000779095"><TermName>liquid biopsy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LIH-kwid BY-op-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory test done on a sample of blood, urine, or other body fluid to look for cancer cells from a tumor or small pieces of DNA, RNA, or other molecules released by tumor cells into a person’s body fluids.  Liquid biopsy allows multiple samples to be taken over time, which may help doctors understand what kind of genetic or molecular changes are taking place in a tumor. A liquid biopsy may be used to help find cancer at an early stage. It may also be used to help plan treatment or to find out how well treatment is working or if cancer has come back.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780346" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;liquid biopsy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780345" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biopsia líquida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>biopsia líquida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio que se realiza en una muestra de sangre, orina u otro líquido corporal con el fin de  buscar células cancerosas en un tumor o  trozos pequeños de ADN, ARN u otras moléculas que las células tumorales liberan en los líquidos corporales. La posibilidad de tomar varias muestras a lo largo del tiempo permite que los equipos médicos comprendan la clase de cambios genéticos o moleculares que tienen lugar en un tumor. La biopsia líquida se puede utilizar para ayudar a encontrar un cáncer en estadio temprano. También es útil para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento, determinar su eficacia y averiguar si el cáncer volvió.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-03-29</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-12-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
