<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000779197"><TermName>melphalan hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEL-fuh-lan HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of multiple myeloma and uveal melanoma (a type of eye cancer). An infusion of one form of melphalan hydrochloride is used as palliative therapy to treat multiple myeloma in patients who cannot take melphalan by mouth. Other forms of melphalan hydrochloride are used under the brand name Evomela to prepare patients with multiple myeloma for a stem cell transplant and under the brand name Hepzato to treat adults with uveal melanoma that has spread to less than half of the liver and cannot be removed by surgery. Hepzato is given as an infusion directly into an artery that leads to the liver. Melphalan hydrochloride is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It may kill cancer cells by damaging their DNA and stopping them from dividing. Melphalan hydrochloride is a type of alkylating agent.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780324" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melphalan hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000780323" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de melfalán&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de melfalán</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de mieloma múltiple y melanoma uveal (tipo de cáncer de ojo). Un tipo de  clorhidrato de melfalán se administra mediante infusión como terapia paliativa para tratar el mieloma múltiple en pacientes que no pueden tomarlo por boca. Otros tipos de clorhidrato de melfalán se usan bajo el nombre comercial Evomela para preparar a los pacientes con mieloma múltiple que van a recibir un transplante de células madre. También se administra  bajo el nombre comercial Hepzato para el tratamiento de adultos con melanoma uveal que se diseminó a menos de la mitad del hígado, y que no se puede extirpar con cirugía. Hepzato se administra mediante infusión directamente en una arteria que transporta sangre al hígado. Además, el clorhidrato de melfalán está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Es posible que destruya células cancerosas al dañar su ADN e impedir que se multipliquen. Este medicamento es un tipo de alquilante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-03-02</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-08-22</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000779087" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/melphalan-hydrochloride">Melphalan Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
