<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000779585">
  <TermName>fecal impaction</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FEE-kul im-PAK-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A mass of dry, hard stool that cannot pass out of the colon or rectum. Fecal impaction may be caused by using laxatives too often, using certain types of pain medicines, little or no physical activity over a long period, diet changes, or constipation that is not treated. Signs and symptoms may include being unable to have a bowel movement, pain in the abdomen or back, problems urinating, and nausea and vomiting. Fecal impaction may also cause problems with circulation, the heart, or breathing.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782445" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fecal impaction&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782444" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;impactación fecal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815226" type="image/jpeg" alt="Fecal impaction; drawing showing a mass of dark brown stool in the last part of the colon and in the rectum. The stomach, small intestine, and anus are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Fecal impaction is a serious condition in which a mass of dry, hard stool blocks the colon or rectum. It  can be life threatening and requires immediate medical attention.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815996" type="image/jpeg" alt="Impactación fecal. En el dibujo se muestra una masa de heces de color marrón oscuro en la última parte del colon y en el recto. También se muestran el estómago, el intestino delgado y el ano." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">La impactación fecal es una afección grave en la que una masa de heces secas y duras bloquea el colon o el recto.  Esto puede poner en peligro la vida, por lo que requiere de atención médica inmediata.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>impactación fecal</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Masa de heces duras y secas que no puede salir del colon o del recto. Las posibles causas de esta afección son usar laxantes con mucha frecuencia, tomar ciertos tipos de analgésicos, hacer poca o ninguna actividad física por bastante tiempo, cambiar la alimentación o no tratar el estreñimiento. Los signos y síntomas incluyen incapacidad de evacuar, dolor en el abdomen o la espalda, dificultad para orinar, y náuseas o vómitos. La impactación fecal a veces también produce problemas circulatorios, cardíacos o respiratorios. También se llama impactación intestinal y retención fecal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-05-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-07-22</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/constipation" UseWith="en">Constipation and Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/estrenimiento" UseWith="es">Estreñimiento relacionado con el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
