<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000779580"><TermName>bowel obstruction</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BOW-ul ub-STRUK-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A partial or complete block of the small or large intestine that keeps food, liquid, gas, and stool from moving through the intestines in a normal way. Bowel obstructions may be caused by a twist in the intestines, hernias, inflammation, scar tissue from surgery, and certain types of cancer, such as cancers of the stomach, colon, and ovary. They may also be caused by conditions that affect the muscles of the intestine, such as paralysis. Signs and symptoms may include pain and swelling in the abdomen, constipation, diarrhea, vomiting, and problems passing gas. Most bowel obstructions occur in the small intestine. Also called intestinal obstruction.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782441" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bowel obstruction&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782440" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;obstrucción intestinal&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815602" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a large mass of dark brown stool in the large intestine caused by a tumor blockage. The tumor is at the end of the large intestine just before the rectum. Also shown are other parts of the digestive tract, including the stomach, small intestine, rectum, and anus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">A bowel obstruction is a serious condition that occurs when the small intestine or large intestine becomes blocked. The blockage stops food and stool from moving through the intestines. A bowel obstruction can be caused by certain cancers and cancer treatments.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000816205" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo del abdomen de una persona adulta se muestra una obstrucción intestinal, con una masa grande de materia fecal de color marrón oscuro en el intestino grueso causada por el bloqueo de un tumor. El tumor se encuentra en la porción final del intestino grueso justo antes del recto. También se señalan otras partes del tubo digestivo, como el estómago, el intestino delgado, el recto y el ano." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Una obstrucción intestinal es una afección grave que  se presenta cuando hay un bloqueo u oclusión en el intestino delgado o el intestino grueso.  La obstrucción impide que los alimentos y la material fecal se muevan a través de los intestinos.  La obstrucción intestinal a veces se debe a ciertos cánceres y tratamientos del cáncer.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>obstrucción intestinal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Bloqueo parcial o completo en el intestino delgado o el intestino grueso que impide el movimiento normal de los alimentos, los líquidos, los gases y la materia fecal. Las causas de las obstrucciones intestinales son, entre otras, una torsión del intestino, hernias, inflamación, cicatrices de una cirugía y ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de estómago, cáncer de colon y cáncer de ovario. En ocasiones también se deben a problemas en los músculos del intestino, como una parálisis. Los signos y síntomas son dolor e hinchazón o distensión en el abdomen, estreñimiento, diarrea, vómitos y problemas para expulsar el gas. La mayoría de las obstrucciones intestinales se producen en el intestino delgado. También se llama obturación intestinal y oclusión intestinal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-05-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-07-22</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/bowel-obstruction" UseWith="en">Bowel Obstruction and Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/obstruccion-intestinal" UseWith="es">Obstrucción intestinal relacionada con el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
