<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000779696">
  <TermName>testicular sperm aspiration</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(tes-TIH-kyoo-ler … AS-pih-RAY-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure in which a sample of sperm cells and tissue are removed from the testicle through a small needle attached to a syringe. The sperm is separated from the tissue and looked at under a microscope in the laboratory. It may then be used right away to fertilize eggs or frozen for future infertility treatment. Testicular sperm aspiration may be useful for men who have fertility problems caused by a blockage that keeps sperm from being ejaculated. This could be caused by previous vasectomy, certain genetic conditions, ejaculation problems, infection, or other conditions. It may also be useful for men who want to have children after having treatment that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Testicular sperm aspiration is a type of sperm retrieval method. Also called TESA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000781320" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;testicular sperm aspiration&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000781321" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aspiración de espermatozoides del testículo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>aspiración de espermatozoides del testículo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se saca una muestra de espermatozoides y tejido del testículo a través de  una aguja pequeña conectada a una jeringa. Los espermatozoides se separan del tejido y se observan al microscopio en el laboratorio. Se pueden usar de inmediato para fecundar óvulos o se pueden congelar para tratar la esterilidad en el futuro. La aspiración de espermatozoides del testículo puede ser útil para los hombres que tienen problemas de esterilidad producidos por un bloqueo que impide la eyaculación de los espermatozoides. Esto podría deberse a una vasectomía previa, ciertas afecciones genéticas, problemas de eyaculación, infecciones u otras afecciones. También podría ser útil para los hombres que quieran tener hijos después de someterse a un tratamiento que puede causar esterilidad, como ciertos tratamientos contra el cáncer. La aspiración de espermatozoides del testículo es un tipo de método de obtención de espermatozoides. También se llama AET.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-04-19</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2017-05-16</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
