<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000780219">
  <TermName>follow-up care plan</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FAH-loh-up kayr plan)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A detailed plan given to a patient after treatment ends, that contains a summary of the patient’s treatment, along with recommendations for follow-up care. In cancer, the plan is based on the type of cancer and the treatment the patient received. A follow-up care plan may include schedules for physical exams and medical tests to see if the cancer has come back or spread to other parts of the body. Getting follow-up care also helps check for health problems that may occur months or years after treatment ends, including other types of cancer. A follow-up care plan may also include information to help meet the emotional, social, legal, and financial needs of the patient.  It may include referrals to specialists and recommendations for a healthy lifestyle, such as changes in diet and exercise and quitting smoking. Also called survivorship care plan.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782438" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;follow-up care plan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782439" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;plan de atención de seguimiento&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>plan de atención de seguimiento</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Plan detallado que se entrega a un paciente después de terminar el tratamiento; contiene un resumen del tratamiento y recomendaciones para el seguimiento de la atención. En el caso del cáncer, el plan se basa en el tipo de cáncer y el tratamiento que recibió el paciente. Un plan de atención de seguimiento puede contener agendas para exámenes físicos y pruebas para determinar si el cáncer volvió o se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. La atención de seguimiento también ayuda a detectar problemas de salud que se pueden presentar meses o años después de terminar el tratamiento, incluso otros tipos de cáncer. Es posible que este plan de atención de seguimiento incluya información para ayudar a satisfacer las necesidades emocionales, sociales, legales y financieras del paciente. Asimismo, quizás contenga derivaciones a especialistas y recomendaciones para un estilo de vida saludable, como cambios en la dieta, ejercicio y dejar de fumar. También se llama plan de atención del sobreviviente.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-05-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2017-06-26</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping/survivorship/follow-up-care">Follow-Up Medical Care</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/supervivencia/cuidados-de-seguimiento">Cuidados médicos de seguimiento</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
