<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000780302"><TermName>gonadal shielding</TermName><TermPronunciation>(goh-NA-dul SHEEL-ding)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure used to help keep a person fertile by preventing damage to reproductive organs during radiation therapy. A protective shield is placed on the outside of the body to cover the area of the gonads (the testicles or ovaries) and other parts of the reproductive system during radiation therapy. For males, this would also include the prostate and penis. For females, it would also include the fallopian tubes, uterus, cervix, and vagina. Gonadal shielding is a type of fertility preservation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782422" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gonadal shielding&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782423" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;blindaje gonadal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>blindaje gonadal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se utiliza para conservar la capacidad reproductiva de una persona al prevenir los daños en los órganos genitales durante la administración de radioterapia. Se coloca una cubierta protectora en el exterior del cuerpo para cubrir el área de las gónadas (testículos u ovarios) y otras partes del aparato reproductor durante la radioterapia. En los hombres, la cubierta también protege la próstata y el pene. En las mujeres, además protege la trompas de Falopio, el útero, el cuello del útero y la vagina. El blindaje gonadal es un tipo de preservación de la fertilidad.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-06-02</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-women" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Girls and Women with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-men" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Boys and Men with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-mujeres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en las mujeres con cáncer: niñas y adultas </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-hombres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en los hombres con cáncer: niños y adultos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
