<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000780385">
  <TermName>ovarian transposition</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(oh-VAYR-ee-un tranz-poh-ZIH-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure used to help keep a woman fertile by preventing damage to the ovaries during radiation therapy. Before radiation therapy begins, one or both ovaries and fallopian tubes are separated from the uterus and attached to the wall of the abdomen away from where the radiation will be given. Ovarian transposition may be useful for women who want to have children after having radiation therapy that can cause infertility. It is a type of fertility preservation. Also called oophoropexy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782456" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ovarian transposition&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782457" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trasposición ovárica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>trasposición ovárica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se utiliza para ayudar a conservar la capacidad reproductiva de una mujer al prevenir el daño a los ovarios durante la administración de radioterapia. Antes de comenzar la radioterapia, uno o ambos ovarios y las trompas de Falopio se separan del útero y se unen a la pared del abdomen lejos del lugar que recibirá la radiación. La trasposición ovárica quizás sea útil para mujeres que quieren tener hijos después de recibir radioterapia, que en ocasiones causa esterilidad. Este procedimiento es un tipo de preservación de la fertilidad. También se llama ooforopexia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-06-02</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/fertility-women" UseWith="en">Fertility Issues in Girls and Women with Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/fecundidad-mujeres" UseWith="es">Cuestiones de fecundidad en las mujeres con cáncer: niñas y adultas</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
