<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000780537">
  <TermName>echocardiogram</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(EH-koh-KAR-dee-oh-gram)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A computer picture of the heart created by bouncing high-energy sound waves (ultrasound) off internal tissues or organs of the chest. Echocardiograms show the size, shape, and position of the heart. They also show the parts inside the heart, such as the valves, and the motion of the heart while it is beating. An echocardiogram may be used to help diagnose heart problems, such as abnormal heart valves and heart rhythms, damage to the heart muscle from a heart attack, and heart murmurs.  Echocardiograms can also show an infection on or around the heart valves, blood clots or tumors inside the heart, and fluid buildup in the sac around the heart.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784450" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;echocardiogram&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784451" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ecocardiograma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ecocardiograma</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Imagen del corazón creada por una computadora al hacer rebotar ondas sonoras de alta energía (ultrasónicas) en tejidos u órganos internos del pecho. Los ecocardiogramas muestran el tamaño, la forma y la posición del corazón, también muestran las partes internas de este órgano, como las válvulas, y el movimiento del corazón mientras está latiendo. Un ecocardiograma se suele usar para ayudar a diagnosticar problemas del corazón, como las válvulas y los ritmos cardíacos anormales, el daño en el músculo del corazón por un infarto del miocardio y los soplos cardíacos. En  los ecocardiogramas también se pueden observar infecciones en las válvulas del corazón o alrededor de estas, coágulos de sangre o tumores dentro del corazón, así como una acumulación de líquido en la bolsa que rodea este órgano.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-08-15</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
