<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000780700"><TermName>Cabometyx</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KA-boh-MEH-tix)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient cabozantinib-s-malate and is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer), and differentiated thyroid cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Cabometyx blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Cabometyx is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782429" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cabometyx&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782428" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cabometyx&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Cabometyx</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo (S)-malato de cabozantinib y que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón) y cáncer de tiroides diferenciado. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Cabometyx bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es posible que además impida la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Cabometyx es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas y de inhibidor de la angiogénesis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-05-09</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000743644" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/cabozantinib-s-malate">Cabozantinib-S-Malate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
