<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781206"><TermName>X-linked dominant inheritance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... linkt DAH-mih-nunt in-HAYR-ih-tunts)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>X-linked dominant inheritance refers to genetic conditions associated with mutations in genes on the X chromosome. A single copy of the mutation is enough to cause the disease in both males (who have one X chromosome) and females (who have two X chromosomes). In some conditions, the absence of a functional gene results in the death of affected males.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of the ways a genetic trait or condition caused by a  mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome can be passed down (inherited) from parent to child. In X-linked dominant inheritance, a genetic condition can occur when the child inherits one copy of a mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome from one parent. Daughters have a 50% chance of inheriting the mutated X-linked gene from their mother and a 100% chance of inheriting the mutated X-linked gene from their father. Sons have a 50% chance of inheriting the mutated X-linked gene from their mother and a 0% chance of inheriting the mutated X-linked gene from their father. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782419" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;X-linked dominant inheritance&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804320" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802197" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an X-linked dominant inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their children. The panel on the left shows an affected father (who only has one X chromosome) with a mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome; an unaffected mother (who has two X chromosomes) with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an affected daughter (who has two X chromosomes) with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an unaffected son (who only has one X chromosome) with a normal gene on the X chromosome. The panel on the right shows an unaffected father with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an affected mother with a normal gene on one X chromosome and a mutated gene on the other X chromosome; an unaffected daughter with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an unaffected son with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an affected daughter with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an affected son with a mutated gene on the X chromosome." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="en">X-linked dominant inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child through mutations (changes) in a gene on a single X chromosome. In females (who have two X chromosomes), a mutation in a gene on one of the X chromosomes is enough to cause the condition. In males (who only have one X chromosome), a mutation in the copy of the gene on the single X chromosome causes the condition. Fathers cannot pass X-linked dominant conditions to their sons, but all daughters of affected fathers will be affected with the condition and can pass it on to their children.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802197" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an X-linked dominant inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their children. The panel on the left shows an affected father (who only has one X chromosome) with a mutated (changed) gene on the X chromosome; an unaffected mother (who has two X chromosomes) with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an affected daughter (who has two X chromosomes) with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an unaffected son (who only has one X chromosome) with a normal gene on the X chromosome. The panel on the right shows an unaffected father with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an affected mother with a normal gene on one X chromosome and a mutated gene on the other X chromosome; an unaffected daughter with a normal gene on both X chromosomes; an unaffected son with a normal gene on the X chromosome; an affected daughter with a mutated gene on one X chromosome and a normal gene on the other X chromosome; and an affected son with a mutated gene on the X chromosome." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="en">X-linked dominant inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child through mutations (changes) in a gene on a single X chromosome. In females (who have two X chromosomes), a mutation in a gene on one of the X chromosomes is enough to cause the condition. In males (who only have one X chromosome), a mutation in the copy of the gene on the single X chromosome causes the condition. Fathers cannot pass X-linked dominant conditions to their sons, but all daughters of affected fathers will be affected with the condition and can pass it on to their children.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802816" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X en dos familias conformadas por padre, madre e hijos. En el lado izquierdo se muestran un padre afectado con un gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X); una madre no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X); una hija afectada con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X; un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X. En el lado derecho se muestra un padre no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una madre afectada con un gen normal en un cromosoma X y un gen mutado en el otro cromosoma X; una hija no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X; un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una hija afectada con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X y un hijo afectado con un gen mutado en el cromosoma X." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_5"><Caption language="es">La herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X es una de las formas en que un rasgo o afección genética pasa de padres a hijos cuando hay mutaciones (cambios) en un gen de un solo cromosoma X. En las mujeres, la presencia de una mutación en un gen de un solo cromosoma X es suficiente para causar la enfermedad (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X). En los hombres, la presencia de una mutación en un gen del único cromosoma X causa la enfermedad (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X). Los padres no pueden pasar a sus hijos varones una afección de herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X; pero todas las hijas de un padre afectado presentarán la afección y es posible que la pasen a sus hijos e hijas.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802816" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X en dos familias conformadas por padre, madre e hijos. En el lado izquierdo se muestran un padre afectado con un gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X); una madre no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X); una hija afectada con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X; un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X. En el lado derecho se muestra un padre no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una madre afectada con un gen normal en un cromosoma X y un gen mutado en el otro cromosoma X; una hija no afectada con un gen normal en cada uno de los cromosomas X; un hijo no afectado con un gen normal en el cromosoma X; una hija afectada con un gen mutado en un cromosoma X y un gen normal en el otro cromosoma X y un hijo afectado con un gen mutado en el cromosoma X." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8"><Caption language="es">La herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X es una de las formas en que un rasgo o afección genética pasa de padres a hijos cuando hay mutaciones (cambios) en un gen de un solo cromosoma X. En las mujeres, la presencia de una mutación en un gen de un solo cromosoma X es suficiente para causar la enfermedad (las mujeres tienen dos cromosomas X). En los hombres, la presencia de una mutación en un gen del único cromosoma X causa la enfermedad (los varones solo tienen un cromosoma X). Los padres no pueden pasar a sus hijos varones una afección de herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X; pero todas las hijas de un padre afectado presentarán la afección y es posible que la pasen a sus hijos e hijas.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Este tipo de herencia se refiere a las afecciones genéticas asociadas a mutaciones en el cromosoma X. Una sola copia de la mutación es suficiente para provocar la enfermedad en hombres (solo tienen un cromosoma X) y en mujeres (tienen dos cromosomas X). En algunas afecciones, la ausencia de un gen funcional produce la muerte de los varones afectados.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una de las formas en que se hereda (pasa de padres a hijos) un rasgo genético o una afección causada por un gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X. En la herencia dominante ligada al cromosoma X, la afección se puede presentar cuando el hijo o la hija  heredan una sola copia del gen mutado (cambiado) en el cromosoma X de la madre o el padre. Las hijas tienen una probabilidad del 50 % de heredar el gen mutado en el cromosoma  X de su madre y una probabilidad del  100 % de heredar el gen mutado en el cromosoma  X de su padre. Los hijos varones tienen una probabilidad del 50 % de heredar el gen mutado en el cromosoma X de su madre y una probabilidad del 0 %  de heredar el gen mutado en el cromosoma X de su padre.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-05-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
