<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781539">
  <TermName>juvenile nasopharyngeal angiofibroma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(JOO-veh-nile NAY-zoh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul AN-jee-oh-fy-BROH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) tumor that is made up of blood vessels and fibrous (connective) tissue. Juvenile nasopharyngeal angiofibromas form in the back of the nose and may spread to the upper part of the throat, the sinuses around the nose, the bone around the eyes, and rarely, to the brain. Signs and symptoms may include runny nose, nosebleeds, problems breathing through the nose, hearing loss, and easy bruising. Juvenile nasopharyngeal angiofibromas are most common in young men. They are a type of vascular tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784429" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;juvenile nasopharyngeal angiofibroma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784428" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;angiofibroma nasofaríngeo juvenil&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>angiofibroma nasofaríngeo juvenil</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso) formado por vasos sanguíneos y tejido fibroso (conjuntivo). Los angiofibromas nasofaríngeos juveniles aparecen en  la parte posterior de la nariz y a veces se diseminan a la parte superior de la garganta, los senos paranasales y los huesos que rodean los ojos; en muy pocas ocasiones se diseminan al cerebro.  Los signos y síntomas son secreción nasal, hemorragia nasal, dificultad para respirar por la nariz, sordera y tendencia a formar moretones. Los angiofibromas nasofaríngeos juveniles son más frecuentes en hombres jóvenes. Son un tipo de tumor vascular.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-01</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
