<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781543">
  <TermName>kaposiform hemangioendothelioma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(kuh-POH-zee-form hee-MAN-jee-oh-EN-doh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare blood vessel tumor that usually forms on the skin of the arms and legs, but may also form in deeper tissues, such as muscle and bone. Kaposiform hemangioendotheliomas may sometimes form in the lymph nodes, chest, abdomen, or bones.  They are fast growing and can spread to nearby tissue, but usually do not spread to other parts of the body. Signs and symptoms may include firm, painful areas of skin that look bruised; purple or brownish-red areas on the skin; easy bruising; anemia; and abnormal bleeding. Kaposiform hemangioendotheliomas are most common in infants and                young children. They are a type of vascular tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784433" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;kaposiform hemangioendothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784432" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemangioendotelioma kaposiforme&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hemangioendotelioma kaposiforme</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor de vasos sanguíneos muy infrecuente que, por lo general, se forma en la piel  de los brazos y las piernas, y a veces se forma en tejidos más profundos, como los músculos y los huesos. En ocasiones, los hemangioendoteliomas kaposiformes  se forman en los ganglios linfáticos, el pecho, el abdomen o los huesos. Estos tumores crecen rápido y, aunque se pueden diseminar al tejido cercano, por lo general no se suelen diseminar a otras partes del cuerpo. Los signos y síntomas son áreas de piel firmes y dolorosas que se ven como moretones; áreas de piel de color morado o marrón rojizo; tendencia a la formación de moretones;  anemia y hemorragias anormales. Los hemangioendoteliomas kaposiformes son más frecuentes en lactantes y niños pequeños. Son un tipo de tumor vascular.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-01</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
