<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781637">
  <TermName>spindle cell hemangioma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SPIN-dul sel hee-MAN-jee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) blood vessel tumor that forms on or under the skin. Spindle cell hemangiomas have cells called spindle cells that look long and slender under a microscope. These tumors are painful red-brown or bluish lesions that usually appear on the arms or legs. One or more lesions may form, and they can sometimes rupture (break open) and bleed. Spindle cell hemangiomas usually occur in young adults but can sometimes occur in children. They are a type of vascular tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784414" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;spindle cell hemangioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784415" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemangioma fusocelular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hemangioma fusocelular</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso) de los vasos sanguíneos que se forma en la piel o debajo de esta. Los hemangiomas fusocelulares  tienen células llamadas células fusiformes cuyo aspecto al microscopio es alargado y delgado. Estos tumores son lesiones de color marrón rojizo o azuladas   que son dolorosas y se suelen presentar en los brazos o las piernas. Es posible que se formen una o más lesiones y que a veces se rompan y sangren. Los hemangiomas fusocelulares habitualmente se presentan en adultos jóvenes, pero en ocasiones aparecen en niños. Son un tipo de tumor vascular. También se llama hemangioma de células fusiformes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-02</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
