<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781624"><TermName>epithelioid hemangioendothelioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-pih-THEE-lee-oyd hee-MAN-jee-oh-EN-doh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare blood vessel tumor that usually forms in the liver, lung, or bone, but it can also form on or in the skin. Epithelioid hemangioendotheliomas may be slow growing or fast growing and, in some people, may spread to other parts of the body very quickly. Signs and symptoms depend on where the tumor is in the body. On the skin, the tumor may be raised with round or flat, red-brown patches that feel warm. In the lung, the tumor can cause chest pain, trouble breathing, spitting up blood, and anemia. In the bone, the tumor can cause breaks. Epithelioid hemangioendotheliomas usually occur in adults, but can sometimes occur in children. They are a type of vascular tumor and a type of soft tissue sarcoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000784406" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epithelioid hemangioendothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000784407" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemangioendotelioma epitelioide&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>hemangioendotelioma epitelioide</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor raro de  los vasos sanguíneos que suele formarse en el hígado, el pulmón o el hueso, pero que también  se forma en la piel o en su superficie. Algunos  hemangioendoteliomas epitelioides son de crecimiento lento y otros son de crecimiento rápido y, en algunas personas, se diseminan con rapidez a otras partes del cuerpo. Los signos y síntomas dependen de la ubicación del tumor en el cuerpo. En la piel, el tumor a veces es elevado con manchas marrón rojizas, redondeadas o planas, y se siente caliente al tacto. En el pulmón, es posible que cause dolor en el tórax, dificultad para respirar, expectoración con sangre y anemia. En el hueso, quizás provoque fracturas. Por lo general, los hemangioendoteliomas epitelioides se presentan en adultos, pero en ocasiones se presentan en niños. Es un tipo de tumor vascular y de sarcoma de tejido blando.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-09-02</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
