<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781626">
  <TermName>Kasabach-Merritt syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KAS-uh-bak-MAYR-it SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare condition in which the blood is not able to clot and serious bleeding may occur. It occurs in some patients who have blood vessel tumors called tufted angiomas and kaposiform hemangioendotheliomas. These tumors usually form on the skin but may also form in deeper tissues, such as muscle and bone. The tumors may grow quickly and trap and destroy platelets, which are needed to form clots and stop bleeding. Kasabach-Merritt syndrome is most common in infants and young children.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784408" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Kasabach-Merritt syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784409" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Kasabach-Merritt&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Kasabach-Merritt</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección muy poco frecuente en la que la sangre no coagula y puede producir hemorragias graves. Se presenta en algunos pacientes que tienen tumores de vasos sanguíneos llamados angiomas en penacho y hemangioendoteliomas kaposiformes. Por lo general, estos tumores  se forman en la piel, pero también se pueden formar en tejidos profundos, como los músculos o los huesos. Es posible que los tumores crezcan rápido, y atrapen o destruyan las plaquetas que se necesitan para formar los coágulos y detener las hemorragias. El síndrome de  Kasabach-Merritt en más frecuente en lactantes y niños pequeños.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-02</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000774255" url="/types/soft-tissue-sarcoma/patient/child-vascular-tumors-treatment-pdq">Childhood Vascular Tumors</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000782396" url="/espanol/tipos/sarcoma-de-tejido-blando/paciente/tratamiento-tumores-vasculares-infantiles-pdq">Tratamiento de los tumores vasculares infantiles</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
