<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781619">
  <TermName>angiolymphoid hyperplasia with eosinophilia</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AN-jee-oh-LIM-foyd HY-per-PLAY-zhuh … EE-oh-SIH-noh-FIH-lee-uh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare benign (not cancer) tumor of small blood vessels surrounded by lymphocytes and eosinophils (types of white blood cells). Angiolymphoid hyperplasia with eosinophilia usually forms on or in the skin, especially the skin of the head, but can occur in other areas of the body, such as in bone. On the skin, it may appear as firm pink to red bumps that may be itchy or painful. If the tumor is in bone, it may cause swelling and pain. Angiolymphoid hyperplasia with eosinophilia is sometimes caused by injury and often comes back after treatment. Angiolymphoid hyperplasia with eosinophilia is most common in young and middle-aged adults. It is a type of vascular tumor. Also called epithelioid hemangioma and histiocytoid hemangioma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784386" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;angiolymphoid hyperplasia with eosinophilia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784387" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hiperplasia angiolinfoide con eosinofilia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hiperplasia angiolinfoide con eosinofilia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso) muy poco frecuente de los vasos sanguíneos pequeños que está rodeado de linfocitos y eosinófilos (tipos de glóbulos blancos).  La hiperplasia angiolinfoide con eosinofilia por lo general se forma en la piel o en su superficie, especialmente en la piel de la cabeza, aunque también se presenta en otras áreas del cuerpo, como en los huesos. Sobre la piel puede aparecer como bultos firmes rosados a rojos que pican o duelen. Si el tumor está en el hueso, es posible que produzca hinchazón y dolor. En ocasiones, la causa de la hiperplasia angiolinfoide con eosinofilia es un traumatismo y, a menudo, vuelve después del tratamiento.  La hiperplasia angiolinfoide con eosinofilia es más frecuente en adultos jóvenes y de mediana edad. Es un tipo de tumor vascular. También se llama hemangioma epitelioide y hemangioma histiocitoide.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-02</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
