<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781622">
  <TermName>composite hemangioendothelioma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(kum-PAH-zit hee-MAN-jee-oh-EN-doh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A blood vessel tumor that is made up of different types of cells and has features that are both benign (not cancer) and malignant (cancer). Composite hemangioendotheliomas usually form on or under the skin on the arms or legs. They may also form on the head, neck, or chest. Composite hemangioendotheliomas may spread to nearby lymph nodes, but usually do not spread to other parts of the body. They may come back in the same place after treatment. They are most common in adults. Composite hemangioendotheliomas are a type of vascular tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784404" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;composite hemangioendothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000784405" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemangioendotelioma compuesto&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hemangioendotelioma compuesto</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor de vasos sanguíneos que se forma a partir de varios tipos de células, y tiene características benignas (no canceroso) y malignas (canceroso). Por lo general, los hemangioendoteliomas compuestos  se forman en la piel o debajo de la piel de  los brazos o las piernas. También se forman en la cabeza, el cuello o el pecho. Aunque los hemangioendoteliomas compuestos   a veces se diseminan a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos, no se suelen diseminar a otras partes del cuerpo. Es posible que estos tumores reaparezcan en el mismo lugar después del tratamiento. Los hemangioendoteliomas compuestos son más frecuentes en adultos  y son un tipo de tumor vascular.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-02</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
