<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781880">
  <TermName>propranolol hydrochloride</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(proh-PRAN-uh-lol HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used under the brand name Hemangeol to treat infants 5 weeks to 5 months of age with infantile hemangioma (a benign blood vessel tumor) and under other brand names to treat high blood pressure, including before surgery in patients with pheochromocytoma, and many other conditions. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and some types of cancer. Propranolol hydrochloride blocks certain receptors on nerve cells and causes blood vessels to relax and widen. This improves blood flow and lowers blood pressure and heart rate. Propranolol hydrochloride may also help shrink certain types of vascular tumors. It is a type of beta blocker.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782451" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;propranolol hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000782450" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de propranolol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de propranolol</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se utiliza bajo la marca comercial Hemangeol para el tratamiento de lactantes de 5 semanas a 5 meses de edad con un hemangioma infantil (tumor benigno de los vasos sanguíneos). También se usa bajo otras marcas comerciales para el tratamiento de la presión arterial alta, incluso antes de una cirugía en los pacientes con un feocromocitoma, y muchas otras afecciones. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y algunos tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de propranolol bloquea ciertos receptores en las células nerviosas y hace que los vasos sanguíneos se relajen y dilaten. Esto mejora la circulación sanguínea y disminuye la presión arterial y la frecuencia cardíaca. Es posible que el clorhidrato de Propranolol también reduzca el tamaño de ciertos tipos de tumores vasculares. Es un tipo de betabloqueante. También se llama hidrocloruro de propranolol.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-06-27</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-07-29</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000781904" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/propranolol-hydrochloride">Propranolol Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
