<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781861"><TermName>beta-blocker</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BAY-tuh-BLAH-ker)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of drug
          that blocks the action of substances, such as adrenaline,
          on nerve cells and causes blood vessels to relax and dilate
          (widen). This allows blood to flow more easily and lowers
          blood pressure and the heart rate.
          Beta-blockers are used to treat
          high blood pressure, chest pain (angina), abnormal heart
          rate (arrhythmia), congestive heart failure, and several
          other conditions. They may also shrink certain types of
          vascular tumors, such as hemangiomas. Also called beta-adrenergic antagonist and beta-adrenergic blocking agent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785369" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;beta-blocker&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785370" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;betabloqueante&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>betabloqueante</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de medicamento que impide
la acción de sustancias, como la adrenalina, en las células
nerviosas y hace que los vasos sanguíneos se relajen y se
dilaten (ensanchen), lo que permite que la sangre fluya más
fácilmente y reduce la presión arterial y la frecuencia
cardíaca. Los betabloqueantes se usan para tratar la
presión arterial alta, el dolor en el pecho (angina de pecho),
el ritmo cardíaco anormal (arritmia), la insuficiencia
cardíaca congestiva y varias otras afecciones. También
pueden achicar ciertos tipos de tumores vasculares, como
los hemangiomas. También se llama antagonista adrenérgico beta, betabloqueador, bloqueador adrenérgico beta y bloqueante ß.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-09-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
