<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781844"><TermName>skin tag</TermName><TermPronunciation>(skin tag)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A small, benign skin growth that may have a stalk (peduncle). Skin tags most commonly appear on the neck, axillary, groin, and inframammary regions. Also called acrochordon.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A common benign (not cancer) skin growth that appears as a small, raised, brown or skin-colored bump that may have a short, narrow stalk. Skin tags usually occur in areas where the skin folds, such as the neck, armpit, inner thigh, and eyelid.  They are usually painless and do not grow or change but may become painful if rubbed or scratched. They most often occur in older adults and in people who are overweight or have diabetes. Also called acrochordon.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000782464" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;skin tag&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804322" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fibroma blando&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>fibroma blando</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor de piel benigno y pequeño que a veces es pediculado. Los fibromas blandos se forman con mayor frecuencia en la nuca, la axila, la ingle y la región inframamaria. También se llama acrocordón y papiloma cutáneo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor de piel benigno (no canceroso) frecuente, que surge como un bulto pequeño de color marrón o del color de la  piel, y a veces tiene  un tallo corto y delgado. Los fibromas blandos suelen presentarse en áreas donde hay pliegues de la piel, como la nuca, las axilas, la parte interior de los muslos y los párpados. Por lo general no duelen, no crecen ni cambian de color, pero a veces duelen cuando se frotan o raspan. Son más frecuentes en adultos mayores y en personas con sobrepeso o que tienen diabetes. También se llama acrocordón y papiloma cutáneo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-06-22</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
