<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781934"><TermName>Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(klih-PEL-tray-noh-NAY SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare disorder that affects the blood vessels, soft tissues, and bones. It may also affect the lymph vessels. Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome is marked by a port-wine stain (a red or purplish birthmark caused by swelling of small blood vessels near the surface of the skin), abnormal overgrowth of bone and soft tissue, and varicose veins or other abnormal veins. It usually affects the legs, but it can also affect the arms or trunk. Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome is present at birth.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785441" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785442" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Klippel-Trénaunay&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Klippel-Trénaunay</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno raro que afecta los vasos sanguíneos, los tejidos blandos y los huesos. A veces, también afecta los vasos linfáticos. El síndrome de Klippel-Trénaunay se caracteriza por una mancha en vino de Oporto (marca de nacimiento de color rojo o púrpura causada por la inflamación de los vasos sanguíneos pequeños cerca de la superficie de la piel), sobrecrecimiento anormal de los huesos y los tejidos blandos, además de várices y otras venas anormales. Suele afectar las piernas, pero también puede afectar los brazos o el tronco. Este síndrome está presente en el momento del nacimiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-09-23</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/3122/klippel-trenaunay-syndrome">Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/klippel-trenaunay-syndrome/">Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12255/sindrome-de-klippel-trenaunay">Síndrome de Klippel-Trénaunay (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000150.htm">Síndrome de Klippel-Trénaunay (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
