<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000781930"><TermName>Maffucci syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(muh-FOO-chee SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A very rare disorder that affects the skin and cartilage. It is marked by benign (not cancer) growths of cartilage in bones. These growths usually occur in the hands or feet, but may also occur in the skull, ribs, and spine. They may cause severely deformed bone, shortening of the arms or legs, broken bones, and other bone problems. Maffucci syndrome is also marked by hemangiomas (benign blood vessel tumors), most often in the skin. People with this syndrome have an increased risk of certain cancers, such as chondrosarcoma (cancer that forms in bone cartilage) or cancers of the ovary or liver. Maffucci syndrome is most common in young children.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785438" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Maffucci syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785437" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Maffucci&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Maffucci</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno muy raro que afecta la piel y el cartílago. Se caracteriza por tumores benignos (no cancerosos) de cartílago en los huesos. Estos tumores suelen observarse en las manos o los pies, pero también se encuentran en el cráneo, las costillas y la columna vertebral. Es posible que causen deformaciones graves en los huesos, acortamiento de los brazos o las piernas, fracturas y otros problemas óseos. El síndrome de Maffucci también se caracteriza por hemangiomas (tumores benignos de vasos sanguíneos), que suelen aparecer en la piel. Las personas con este síndrome tienen un aumento del riesgo de ciertos cánceres, como condrosarcoma (cáncer de cartílago óseo) y  cáncer de ovario o de hígado. El síndrome de Maffucci es más común en niños pequeños. También se llama enfermedad de Maffucci.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-09-23</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6958/maffucci-syndrome">Maffucci syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/maffucci-syndrome/">Maffucci syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
