<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782329"><TermName>DICER1 syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called DICER1. Having this mutation increases the risk of certain types of tumors, including tumors of the kidney, thyroid, ovary, cervix, testicle, brain, eye, and lining of the lung. The tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). A goiter (an enlarged thyroid) and polyps in the colon may also occur. Not all people who have a mutation in the DICER1 gene will develop tumors.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785443" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;DICER1 syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785444" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome DICER1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome DICER1</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro causado por una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama <GeneName>DICER1</GeneName>. Esta mutación aumenta el riesgo de ciertos tipos de tumores, como los tumores de riñón, tiroides, ovario, cuello del útero, testículo, encéfalo, ojo y revestimiento del pulmón. Es posible que los tumores sean benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). A veces, también se presenta bocio (tiroides agrandada) y pólipos en el colon. No todas las personas que tienen una mutación en el gen <GeneName>DICER1</GeneName> tendrán tumores.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-10-06</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10734/dicer1-related-pleuropulmonary-blastoma-cancer-predisposition-syndrome">DICER1-related pleuropulmonary blastoma cancer predisposition syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/dicer1-syndrome/">DICER1 syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
