<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782356"><TermName>cystic nephroma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SIS-tik neh-FROH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, benign (not cancer) kidney tumor made up of fluid-filled cysts. Cystic nephroma can occur in one or both kidneys. Signs and symptoms may include pain in the abdomen or back, a lump in the abdomen, blood in the urine, urinary tract infection, anemia, and fever. Cystic nephroma usually occurs in young children or middle-aged adults. Cystic nephroma may also be found in patients who have pleuropulmonary blastoma (a rare, fast-growing cancer that forms in the tissues of the lung and chest cavity). Some patients with cystic nephroma have a mutation (change) in a gene called DICER1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785357" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cystic nephroma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785358" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nefroma quístico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>nefroma quístico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor renal benigno (no canceroso) poco frecuente compuesto por quistes llenos de líquido. El nefroma quístico se presenta en uno o ambos riñones. Los signos y síntomas son dolor en el abdomen y la espalda, un bulto en el abdomen, sangre en la orina, infecciones en las vías urinarias, anemia y fiebre. El nefroma quístico se suele presentar en niños pequeños o adultos  de edad mediana. También se puede encontrar en pacientes de blastoma pleuropulmonar (cáncer poco frecuente de crecimiento rápido que se forma en los tejidos del pulmón y la cavidad del pecho). Algunos pacientes con nefroma quístico tienen una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama DICER1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-10-06</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
