<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782331">
  <TermName>pleuropulmonary blastoma familial cancer syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PLOOR-oh-PUL-muh-NAYR-ee blas-TOH-muh fuh-MIH-lee-ul KAN-ser SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that increases the risk of pleuropulmonary blastoma (a rare, fast-growing cancer that forms in the tissues of the lung and chest cavity). Pleuropulmonary blastoma familial cancer syndrome may cause cysts in the kidney and lung, thyroid problems, and cancers of the ovary, testicle, kidney, and soft tissue. It may also cause other cancers and benign (not cancer) conditions. This syndrome may be caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called DICER1.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785445" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pleuropulmonary blastoma familial cancer syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785446" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de blastoma pleuropulmonar familiar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de blastoma pleuropulmonar familiar</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario raro que aumenta el riesgo de presentar blastoma pleuropulmonar (cáncer raro de crecimiento rápido que se forma en los tejidos del pulmón y la cavidad torácica). El síndrome de blastoma pleuropulmonar familiar causa quistes en el riñón y el pulmón, problemas tiroideos y cáncer de ovario, testículo, riñón y tejido blando. A veces, también produce otros cánceres y afecciones benignas (no cancerosas). Es posible que la causa de este síndrome sea una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama 
      <GeneName>DICER1</GeneName>
      .
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-10-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10734/dicer1-related-pleuropulmonary-blastoma-cancer-predisposition-syndrome">DICER1-related pleuropulmonary blastoma cancer predisposition syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/dicer1-syndrome/">DICER1 syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
