<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782474">
  <TermName>infantile hemangiopericytoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(IN-fun-TILE hee-MAN-jee-oh-PAYR-ih-sy-TOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare type of soft tissue tumor that begins in cells that wrap around blood vessels. Infantile hemangiopericytomas may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). They usually occur in infants and young children but may also be found before birth by ultrasound. They can occur anywhere in the body, but usually occur in the arms, legs, pelvis, or head and neck. In children older than 1 year, infantile hemangiopericytomas are more likely to spread to other parts of the body, including the lymph nodes and lungs. Children younger than 1 year may have a better prognosis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785344" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;infantile hemangiopericytoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785345" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemangiopericitoma infantil&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hemangiopericitoma infantil</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de tumor de tejido blando poco frecuente que comienza en las células que envuelven los vasos sanguíneos. Los hemangiopericitomas infantiles pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). Por lo general, se presentan en lactantes y niños pequeños, pero también se pueden encontrar antes del nacimiento mediante una ecografía. Aparecen en cualquier parte del cuerpo, pero por lo general lo hacen en los brazos, las piernas, la pelvis, o la cabeza y el cuello. En los niños mayores de 1 año, es más probable que los hemangiopericitomas infantiles se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo, como los ganglios linfáticos y los pulmones. Es posible que los niños menores de 1 año tengan un pronóstico mejor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-10-17</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258672" url="/types/soft-tissue-sarcoma/patient/child-soft-tissue-treatment-pdq">Childhood Soft Tissue Sarcoma</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000561391" url="/espanol/tipos/sarcoma-de-tejido-blando/paciente/tratamiento-tejido-blando-infantil-pdq">Tratamiento del sarcoma de tejido blando infantil</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
