<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782667"><TermName>Reese-Ellsworth Classification System</TermName><TermPronunciation>(rees-ELZ-wurth KLA-sih-fih-KAY-shun SIS-tem)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The Reese-Ellsworth classification system for intraocular retinoblastoma is as follows: Group I retinoblastoma (very favorable for maintenance of sight): (1) solitary tumor, smaller than 4 disc diameters (DD), tumor is at or behind the equator; or (2) multiple tumors, none larger than 4 DD, all tumors are at or behind the equator. Group II retinoblastoma (favorable for maintenance of sight): (1) solitary tumor, 4 to 10 DD, tumor is at or behind the equator; or (2) multiple tumors, 4 to 10 DD, all tumors are behind the equator. Group III retinoblastoma (possible maintenance of sight): (1) any lesion anterior to the equator; or (2) solitary tumor, larger than 10 DD, tumor is behind the equator. Group IV retinoblastoma (unfavorable for maintenance of sight): (1) multiple tumors, some larger than 10 DD; or (2) any lesion extending anteriorly to the ora serrata. Group V retinoblastoma (very unfavorable for maintenance of sight): (1) massive tumors involving more than one-half of the retina; or (2) vitreous seeding.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000784419" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Reese-Ellsworth Classification System&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000784418" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Sistema de clasificación de Reese-Ellsworth&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Sistema de clasificación de Reese-Ellsworth</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El sistema de clasificación de Reese-Ellsworth para el retinoblastoma intraocular es como sigue: retinoblastoma de grupo I (muy favorable para la conservación de la vista): 1) tumor solitario, menor de 4 diámetros discales (DD); el tumor está ubicado en el ecuador o detrás de este; o 2) tumores múltiples, ninguno mayor de 4 DD; todos están ubicados en el ecuador o detrás de este. Retinoblastoma de grupo II (favorable para la conservación de la vista): 1) tumor solitario de 4 a 10 DD que se ubica en el ecuador o detrás de este; o 2) tumores múltiples, de 4 a 10 DD; todos los tumores están ubicados detrás del ecuador. Retinoblastoma de grupo III (posible conservación de la vista): 1) cualquier lesión anterior al ecuador; o 2) tumor solitario, mayor de 10 DD, ubicado detrás del ecuador. Retinoblastoma de grupo IV (desfavorable para la conservación de la vista): 1) tumores múltiples, algunos son mayores de 10 DD; o 2) cualquier lesión que se extienda a la porción delantera de la <Emphasis>ora serrata</Emphasis>. Retinoblastoma de grupo V (muy desfavorable para la conservación de la vista): 1) tumores masivos que afectan más de la mitad de la retina; o 2) diseminación vítrea.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-08-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
