<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782643">
  <TermName>undifferentiated pleomorphic sarcoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(un-DIH-feh-REN-shee-AY-ted PLEE-oh-MOR-fik sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of cancer that usually forms in the soft tissue, but it may also form in bone. It can occur anywhere in the body, but it usually occurs in the legs (especially the thighs), arms, or back of the abdomen. It may also occur in a part of the body where a patient received radiation therapy in the past. Undifferentiated pleomorphic sarcomas often grow quickly and spread to other parts of the body, including the lungs. They usually occur in older adults, and they may sometimes occur as a second cancer in patients who had retinoblastoma. Also called malignant fibrous cytoma and malignant fibrous histiocytoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785387" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;undifferentiated pleomorphic sarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785388" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma pleomórfico indiferenciado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sarcoma pleomórfico indiferenciado</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer que por lo general se forma en el tejido blando, pero que también  se forma en el hueso. Se presenta en cualquier parte del cuerpo, pero a menudo lo hace en las piernas (en especial, los muslos), los brazos o en la parte posterior del abdomen. También aparece en partes del cuerpo que recibieron radioterapia en el pasado. Los sarcomas pleomórficos indiferenciados  suelen crecer rápido y diseminarse a  otras partes del cuerpo, como los pulmones.  Este cáncer por lo general se presenta en adultos mayores y, en ocasiones, surge como un segundo cáncer en pacientes que tuvieron retinoblastoma. También se llama citoma fibroso maligno e histiocitoma fibroso maligno.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-10-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2016-10-14</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062949" url="/types/bone/patient/osteosarcoma-treatment-pdq">Osteosarcoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256846" url="/espanol/tipos/hueso/paciente/tratamiento-osteosarcoma-pdq">Tratamiento del osteosarcoma</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
