<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782638">
  <TermName>extraosseous osteosarcoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(EK-struh-OS-see-us OS-tee-oh-sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, fast-growing type of cancer that is made up of bone and cartilage cells, and forms in soft tissue near bones. It usually occurs in the thigh, buttock, shoulder, or trunk (chest and abdomen). It often recurs (comes back) after treatment and spreads to other parts of the body, including the lungs. Extraosseous osteosarcoma usually occurs in middle-aged or older adults, and is rare in children and adolescents. It is a type of soft tissue sarcoma. Also called extraskeletal osteosarcoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785381" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extraosseous osteosarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785382" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;osteosarcoma extraóseo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>osteosarcoma extraóseo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer poco frecuente y de crecimiento rápido que está compuesto de células de hueso y cartílago; se forma en el tejido blando cerca de los huesos. Por lo general, se presenta en el muslo, los glúteos, el hombro o el tronco (tórax y abdomen). Este tipo de cáncer a menudo recidiva (vuelve) después del tratamiento y se disemina a otras partes del cuerpo, como los pulmones. El  osteosarcoma extraóseo habitualmente se presenta en adultos de edad mediana o avanzada; no es muy  frecuente en niños y adolescentes. Es un tipo de sarcoma de tejido blando. También se llama osteosarcoma extraesquelético.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-10-14</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
