<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782642">
  <TermName>inflammatory myofibroblastic tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(in-FLA-muh-TOR-ee MY-oh-FY-broh-BLAS-tik TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare type of cancer that is made up of smooth muscle cells, connective tissue cells, and certain types of immune cells. It can occur anywhere in the body, but it usually occurs in the lung, abdomen, pelvis, or back of the abdomen. Inflammatory myofibroblastic tumors rarely spread to other parts of the body but they are likely to recur (come back) after treatment. The tumor cells may have a certain genetic change called a translocation (part of one chromosome switches places with part of another chromosome). Inflammatory myofibroblastic tumors usually occur in children and young adults. They are a type of soft tissue sarcoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785385" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inflammatory myofibroblastic tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785386" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor miofibroblástico inflamatorio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor miofibroblástico inflamatorio</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer raro compuesto por células de músculo liso, células de tejido conjuntivo y ciertos tipos de células inmunitarias.  Este cáncer surge en cualquier parte del cuerpo, pero por lo general se presenta en el pulmón, el abdomen, la pelvis o en la parte de atrás del   abdomen. Los tumores miofibroblásticos inflamatorios  casi nunca se diseminan a otras partes del cuerpo, pero  es muy probable que recidiven (vuelvan) después del tratamiento. Las células tumorales a veces tienen cierto cambio genético llamado translocación (parte de un cromosoma intercambia su posición con una parte de otro cromosoma). Los tumores miofibroblásticos inflamatorios a menudo  se presentan en niños y adultos jóvenes. Son un tipo de sarcoma de tejido blando.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-10-14</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
