<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000782635"><TermName>extraskeletal myxoid chondrosarcoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EK-struh-SKEH-leh-tul MIK-soyd KON-droh-sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, slow-growing type of cancer that forms in soft tissues outside the bone and usually has certain changes in the <GeneName>NR4A3</GeneName> gene that cause abnormal fusion proteins to be made. Extraskeletal myxoid chondrosarcomas usually occur in the thigh but may also occur in the knee, buttock, or  chest and abdomen. They may grow large and spread to nearby tissue or to other parts of the body, especially the lungs. They may also come back many years after treatment. Extraskeletal myxoid chondrosarcomas usually occur in middle-aged or older adults and are rare in children and adolescents. They are a type of soft tissue sarcoma. Also called EMC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785360" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extraskeletal myxoid chondrosarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785359" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;condrosarcoma mixoide extraesquelético&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>condrosarcoma mixoide extraesquelético</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer raro y de crecimiento lento que se forma en tejidos blandos  fuera del hueso. Suele tener ciertos cambios en el gen <GeneName>NR4A3</GeneName>, lo que hace que se originen unas proteínas de fusión anormales. Los condrosarcomas mixoides extraesqueléticos a menudo se presentan en el muslo, pero también se forman en la rodilla, el glúteo, el tórax y el abdomen. Los tumores a veces crecen mucho y se diseminan a los tejidos cercanos u otras partes del cuerpo, en especial a los pulmones.  Además, es posible que recidiven (vuelvan) muchos años después del tratamiento. Por lo general, los condrosarcomas mixoides extraesqueléticos se presentan en adultos de edad mediana o avanzada y son poco frecuentes en niños y adolescentes. Son un tipo de sarcoma de tejido blando. También se llama CME.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-10-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-06-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
