<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000783040">
  <TermName>undifferentiated sarcoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(un-DIH-feh-REN-shee-AY-ted sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A group of rare cancers that do not look like other types of sarcomas under a microscope and may be hard to diagnose. They usually form in the muscles that are attached to bones and that help the body move. Undifferentiated sarcomas tend to grow quickly and spread to other parts of the body. Some types of  undifferentiated sarcomas may form in a part of the body where a patient had radiation therapy in the past. An undifferentiated sarcoma is a type of soft tissue sarcoma. Also called unclassified sarcoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785399" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;undifferentiated sarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785398" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma indiferenciado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sarcoma indiferenciado</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Grupo de cánceres poco frecuentes que tienen un aspecto diferente al de otros tipos de sarcomas cuando se observan al microscopio  y cuyo diagnóstico puede ser difícil. En general, se forman en los músculos que están unidos a los huesos y que ayudan a mover el cuerpo.  Los sarcomas indiferenciados suelen crecer rápido y diseminarse a otras partes del cuerpo. Algunos tipos de  sarcomas indiferenciados se forman en una parte del cuerpo que recibió radioterapia en el pasado. Un sarcoma indiferenciado es un tipo de sarcoma de tejido blando. También se llama sarcoma sin otra indicación.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-10-14</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
