<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000783164"><TermName>cystitis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sis-TY-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Inflammation of the lining of the bladder. Symptoms include pain and a burning feeling while urinating, blood in the urine, dark or cloudy urine, feeling a need to urinate often or right away, being unable to control the flow of urine, and pain in the pelvis or lower back. Cystitis is most often caused by an infection, but it may also be caused by taking certain medicines (such as anticancer drugs), radiation therapy to the pelvis, being exposed to chemicals (such as perfumes or dyes), or having a catheter in the bladder for a long time. It may also be caused by other conditions, such as diabetes, kidney stones, an enlarged prostate, or a spinal cord injury.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785395" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cystitis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785396" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cistitis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cistitis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Inflamación del revestimiento de la vejiga. Los síntomas incluyen dolor y sensación de ardor al orinar, sangre en la orina, orina oscura o turbia, necesidad de orinar con frecuencia o de forma inmediata, incapacidad de controlar el flujo de la orina, y dolor en la pelvis o la parte inferior de la espalda. Con frecuencia, la cistitis obedece a una infección, pero también pueden causarla ciertos medicamentos (como los medicamentos contra el cáncer), la radioterapia dirigida a la pelvis, la exposición a productos químicos (como perfumes o colorantes) o la colocación de un catéter en la vejiga durante mucho tiempo. También puede ser causada por otras enfermedades, como la diabetes, los cálculos renales, la próstata agrandada o una lesión de la médula espinal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-10-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
