<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000783669"><TermName>RT-PCR</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory method used to make many copies of a specific genetic sequence for analysis. It uses an enzyme called reverse transcriptase to change a specific piece of RNA into a matching piece of DNA. This piece of DNA is then amplified (made in large numbers) by another enzyme called DNA polymerase. The amplified DNA copies help tell whether a specific mRNA molecule is being made by a gene. RT-PCR may be used to look for certain changes in a gene or chromosome or for activation of certain genes, which may help diagnose a disease, such as cancer. It may also be used to study the RNA of certain viruses, such as the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and the hepatitis C virus, to help diagnose and monitor an infection.  Also called reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>RT-PCR</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método de laboratorio que se usa para hacer muchas copias de una secuencia genética específica con el fin de analizarla. Se usa una enzima llamada retrotranscriptasa que convierte un trozo específico de ARN en un trozo de ADN compatible. Luego, otra enzima llamada ADN–polimerasa amplifica (produce en grandes cantidades) ese trozo de ADN. Las copias de ADN amplificadas ayudan a identificar si hay un gen que produce la molécula específica de ARNm. Es posible usar la RT-PCR para detectar ciertos cambios en un gen o cromosoma, o para identificar la activación de ciertos genes, lo que ayuda a diagnosticar enfermedades, como el cáncer. También sirve para estudiar el ARN de ciertos virus, como el virus de la inmunodeficiencia humana  (VIH) y el virus de la hepatitis C, y de esta manera facilita el diagnóstico y control de la infección. También se llama RCP-RT y reacción en cadena de la polimerasa con retrotranscripción.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-02-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-05-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
