<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000783882">
  <TermName>de novo variant</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(deh NOH-voh VAYR-ee-unt)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A genetic alteration that is present for the first time in one family member as a result of a variant (or mutation) in a germ cell (egg or sperm) of one of the parents, or a variant that arises in the fertilized egg itself during early embryogenesis.  Also called de novo mutation, new mutation, and new variant.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term used to describe a change in the DNA sequence of a gene that is seen for the first time in a person and has not  appeared in previous generations.  A de novo variant can explain how a person can have a genetic condition that did not occur in his or her parents. A de novo variant can occur in an egg or sperm cell of a parent, in the fertilized egg soon after the egg and sperm unite, or in another type of cell during embryo development. A person who has a de novo variant may pass the mutation to his or her child. Some de novo variants may lead to cancer or other diseases. Also called de novo mutation, new mutation, and new variant.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785397" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;de novo variant&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804327" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;variante de novo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>variante de novo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Alteración genética que se presenta por primera vez en un familiar como consecuencia de una variante (o mutación) en una célula germinal (óvulo o espermatozoide) de uno de sus progenitores, o de una variante que surge directamente en el cigoto durante la embriogénesis temprana. También se llama mutación de novo, mutación nueva y variante nueva.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que se utiliza para describir un cambio en la secuencia de ADN de un gen que se observa por primera vez en una persona y que no ha aparecido en generaciones anteriores.  Una variante de novo tal vez explique por qué una persona tiene una afección genética que sus padres no presentaron. Una variante de novo se produce en un óvulo o espermatozoide de uno de los padres, en el óvulo fecundado poco después de que el óvulo y el espermatozoide se unen, o en otro tipo de célula durante el desarrollo del embrión. Es posible que una persona con una variante de novo transmita la mutación a su hijo. Algunas variantes de novo causan cáncer u otras enfermedades. También se llama mutación de novo, mutación nueva y variante nueva.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2016-09-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
