<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000783961"><TermName>epigenetic variant</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EH-pih-jeh-NEH-tik VAYR-ee-unt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A heritable change that does not affect the DNA sequence but results in a change in gene expression. Examples include promoter methylation and histone modifications.  Also called epigenetic alteration and epimutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A change in the chemical structure of DNA that does not change the DNA coding sequence. Epigenetic variants occur in the body when chemical groups called methyl groups are added to or removed from DNA or when changes are made to proteins called histones that bind to the DNA in chromosomes. These changes may occur with age and exposure to environmental factors, such as diet, exercise, drugs, and chemicals. They can affect a person’s risk of disease and may be passed from parent to child. Also called epigenetic alteration and epimutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000785425" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epigenetic variant&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804330" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;variación epigenética&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>variación epigenética</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio en la estructura química del ADN que no altera su secuencia de codificación. Una persona presenta variaciones epigenéticas cuando se añaden o se eliminan del ADN grupos químicos llamados grupos metilo, o cuando hay cambios en las proteínas (histonas) que se unen al ADN en los cromosomas. Es posible que estos cambios aparezcan con la edad y la exposición a factores ambientales, como la alimentación, el ejercicio, los medicamentos y las sustancias químicas. Estos cambios modifican el riesgo de enfermedades y a veces pasan de padres a hijos. También se llama alteración epigenética y epimutación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cambio hereditario que influye en la expresión génica, pero no afecta la secuencia de ADN. Por ejemplo, metilación de un promotor o modificaciones en las histonas. También se llama alteración epigenética y epimutación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-09-28</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2017-02-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
