<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000784578"><TermName>PBSCT</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a patient receives healthy blood-forming cells (stem cells) to replace their own stem cells that have been destroyed by disease or by the radiation or high doses of anticancer drugs that are given as part of the procedure. The healthy stem cells may come from the blood of the patient or a donor. A PBSCT may be autologous (using a patient’s own stem cells that were collected and saved before treatment), allogeneic (using stem cells donated by someone who is not an identical twin), or syngeneic (using stem cells donated by an identical twin). Also called peripheral blood stem cell transplant and peripheral stem cell support.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765030" type="image/jpeg" alt="Donor stem cell transplant; (Panel 1): Drawing of stem cells being collected from a donor's bloodstream using an apheresis machine. Blood is removed from a vein in the donor's arm and flows through the machine where the stem cells are removed. The rest of the blood is then returned to the donor through a vein in their other arm. (Panel 2): Drawing of a health care provider giving a patient an infusion of chemotherapy through a catheter in the patient's chest. The chemotherapy is given to kill cancer cells and prepare the patient's body for the donor stem cells. (Panel 3): Drawing of a patient receiving an infusion of the donor stem cells through a catheter in the chest." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Donor stem cell transplant. (Step 1): Four to five days before donor stem cell collection, the donor receives a medicine to increase the number of stem cells circulating through their bloodstream (not shown). The blood-forming stem cells are then collected from the donor through a large vein in their arm. The blood flows through an apheresis machine that removes the stem cells. The rest of the blood is returned to the donor through a vein in their other arm. (Step 2): The patient receives chemotherapy to kill cancer cells and prepare their body for the donor stem cells. The patient may also receive radiation therapy (not shown). (Step 3): The patient receives an infusion of the donor stem cells.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765551" type="image/jpeg" alt="Trasplante de células madre de un donante. Se observan tres paneles. Panel 1: en el dibujo se muestra la extracción de células madre del torrente sanguíneo de una donante mediante una máquina de aféresis. Se extrae sangre de una vena del brazo y se la hace pasar por la máquina que separa las células madre. La sangre que queda se devuelve a la donante por una vena del otro brazo. Panel 2: en el dibujo se observa a una proveedora de atención de la salud que administra una infusión de quimioterapia a un paciente mediante un catéter en el tórax. La quimioterapia se administra para destruir células cancerosas y preparar el cuerpo del paciente para recibir las células madre del donante. Panel 3: en el dibujo se observa a un paciente que recibe una infusión de las células madre del donante a través de un catéter en el tórax." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Trasplante de células madre de un donante. Paso 1: cuatro o cinco días antes de la extracción de las células madre del donante, este recibe un medicamento para aumentar el número de células madre que circulan por el torrente sanguíneo (no se muestra). A continuación, se extraen las células madre formadoras de sangre del donante a través de una vena grande de un brazo. La sangre pasa por una máquina de aféresis que separa las células madre y luego, el resto de la sangre, se devuelve al donante por una vena del otro brazo. Paso 2: el paciente recibe quimioterapia para eliminar las células cancerosas y preparar el cuerpo para recibir las células madre del donante. Es posible que el paciente también reciba radioterapia (no se muestra). Paso 3: el paciente recibe una infusión de las células madre del donante.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>TCMSP</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento por el que un paciente recibe células formadoras de sangre (células madre) sanas para reemplazar sus propias células madre destruidas por enfermedad, radiación o dosis altas de los medicamentos contra el cáncer que se administran como parte del procedimiento. Las células madre sanas  se obtienen de la sangre del paciente o de un donante. Un TCMSP puede ser autógeno (se usan las células madre del propio paciente que se recolectaron y almacenaron antes del tratamiento), alogénico (se usan las células madre de un donante que no es un gemelo idéntico) o singénico (se usan las células madre donadas por un gemelo idéntico). También se llama apoyo de células madre periféricas y trasplante de células madre de sangre periférica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-10-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-08-08</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/stem-cell-transplant">Stem Cell Transplants in Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/trasplante-de-celulas-madre" UseWith="es">Trasplantes de células madre en el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
