<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000784781">
  <TermName>3-D mammography</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… ma-MAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that uses x-rays to take a series of pictures of the inside of the breast from many different angles. A computer is used to make 3-D pictures of the breast from these x-rays. 3-D mammography is used to check for breast cancer and other changes in the breast, such as abnormal lumps, cysts, or calcifications (calcium deposits). It may allow doctors to see breast tissue, including dense breast tissue, more clearly than with 2-D mammography. This may make breast tumors or other changes in the breast easier to find. Also called 3-dimensional mammography and digital breast tomosynthesis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000789253" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;3-D mammography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000789254" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mamografía 3D&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mamografía 3D</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se usan rayos X para crear una serie de imágenes del interior de la mama (seno) desde ángulos diferentes. Se emplean estos rayos X y una computadora para generar imágenes tridimensionales (3D) de la mama. La mamografía 3D se utiliza para detectar cáncer de mama u otros cambios mamarios, como masas anormales, quistes o calcificaciones (depósitos de calcio). Es posible que  este examen le permita a los médicos observar el tejido de la mama, incluso el tejido denso, de manera más clara o definida que la mamografía bidimensional. Esto facilita la detección de tumores u otros cambios en la mama. También se llama mamografía tridimensional y tomosíntesis digital de mama.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-04-28</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/mammograms-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Mammograms</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000257995" url="/types/breast/patient/breast-screening-pdq">Breast Cancer Screening</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-mamografias" UseWith="es">Mamografías</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000744471" url="/espanol/tipos/seno/paciente/deteccion-seno-pdq">Exámenes de detección del cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
