<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000784814">
  <TermName>ovarian reserve</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(oh-VAYR-ee-un reh-SERV)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The total number of healthy, immature eggs in the ovaries. The number of healthy eggs decreases as a woman ages, which can lower fertility (the ability to have children). Damage to the ovaries can also decrease ovarian reserve and fertility. This may be caused by smoking, certain anticancer treatments (such as chemotherapy or radiation therapy), surgery to the ovaries or other organs in the pelvis, and certain diseases or genetic conditions. Ovarian reserve is often checked in women who want to have children and are having problems getting pregnant.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000789274" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ovarian reserve&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000789273" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;reserva ovárica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>reserva ovárica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Número total de óvulos inmaduros sanos en los ovarios. El número de óvulos sanos disminuye a medida que la mujer envejece, lo que reduce la fertilidad (capacidad de tener hijos). El daño en los ovarios también disminuye la reserva ovárica y la fertilidad. Es posible que el daño se produzca por tabaquismo, ciertos tratamientos contra el cáncer (como quimioterapia o radioterapia), cirugía en los ovarios u otros órganos de la pelvis, y determinadas enfermedades o afecciones genéticas. La reserva ovárica a menudo se revisa en las mujeres que quieren tener hijos y tienen dificultades para quedar embarazadas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-04-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
