<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000785627"><TermName>galactography</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GA-lak-TAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses x-rays to create pictures of milk ducts in the breast. A very thin catheter (tube) is inserted into the nipple, and a small amount of dye is injected into the duct. This makes the duct easier to see on the x-ray. Galactography is used in patients who have a bloody or clear discharge from one nipple. A small amount of the fluid may be collected to check for infection or cancer cells. Galactography may be used to help diagnose certain breast conditions, such as papillomas (wart-like growths) in a milk duct, fibrocystic breast changes, and breast cancer. Also called ductography.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789286" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;galactography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789285" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;galactografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>galactografía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se utilizan rayos X con el fin de crear imágenes de los conductos galactóforos de la mama. Se introduce un catéter (tubo) muy delgado por el pezón y se inyecta en el conducto una cantidad pequeña de colorante. Esto permite que el conducto se vea mejor en la radiografía. Una galactografía se usa en los pacientes que tienen una secreción sanguinolenta o transparente que sale del pezón. Es posible que se recoja una pequeña cantidad de líquido para determinar si hay infección o células cancerosas. La galactografía se puede usar para ayudar a diagnosticar ciertas afecciones de la mama, como papilomas (tumores similares a verrugas) en un conducto galactóforo, cambios fibroquísticos en la mama y cáncer de mama. También se llama ductografía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-05-10</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
