<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000785881"><TermName>rucaparib camsylate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(roo-KA-puh-rib KAM-suh-layt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of prostate cancer or ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Rucaparib camsylate blocks an enzyme involved in many cell functions, including the repair of DNA damage. Blocking this enzyme may help keep cancer cells from repairing their damaged DNA, causing them to die. Rucaparib camsylate is a type of PARP inhibitor. Also called AG014699, PARP-1 inhibitor AG014699, and Rubraca.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000786414" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rucaparib camsylate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000786413" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;camsilato de rucaparib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>camsilato de rucaparib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer de próstata o cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompas de Falopio y primario de peritoneo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El camsilato de rucaparib bloquea una enzima que participa en muchas funciones celulares, entre ellas, la reparación del daño al ADN. Bloquear esta enzima quizás ayude a evitar que las células cancerosas reparen el daño a su ADN y esto las destruya. El camsilato de rucaparib es un tipo de inhibidor de PARP. También se llama AG014699, inhibidor de PARP-1 AG014699 y Rubraca.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2016-12-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000785931" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/rucaparibcamsylate">Rucaparib Camsylate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
