<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000787895">
  <TermName>fluorine F 18-fluoromisonidazole</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FLOOR-een ... FLOOR-oh-MY-soh-NIH-duh-zole)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A radioactive substance being studied as an imaging agent in head and neck cancer and other types of cancer. It binds to large molecules in cancer cells that have a low level of oxygen. Radiation given off by fluorine F 18-fluoromisonidazole is detected by a positron emission tomography (PET) scan. Knowing the amount of fluorine F 18-fluoromisonidazole in the cancer cells may help plan the best treatment and help predict whether the cancer will come back after treatment. Also called 18F-fluoromisonidazole, 18F-MISO, and FMISO.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000788389" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fluorine F 18-fluoromisonidazole&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000721194" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;flúor F 18-fluoromisonidazol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>flúor F 18-fluoromisonidazol</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Sustancia radiactiva en estudio para usar en pruebas de imágenes del cáncer de cabeza y cuello, así como otros tipos de cáncer. Se une a moléculas grandes de las células cancerosas que tienen una concentración baja de oxígeno. La radiación que emite el flúor F 18-fluoromisonidazol se detecta con una tomografía por emisión de positrones (TEP). Es posible que conocer la cantidad de flúor F 18-fluoromisonidazol en las células cancerosas ayude a planificar el mejor tratamiento y a pronosticar si el cáncer volverá después del tratamiento. También se llama 18F-fluoromisonidazol, 18F-MISO y FMISO.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-03-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2017-10-24</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
