<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000787988">
  <TermName>squamous cell carcinoma of the skin</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SKWAY-mus sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh … skin)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cancer that begins in cells that form the epidermis (outer layer of the skin). It usually occurs on areas of the skin that have been exposed to natural sunlight or artificial sunlight (such as from tanning beds) over long periods of time. These areas include the face, ears, lower lip, neck, arms, or back of the hands. It may also occur on areas of the skin that have been burned or exposed to chemicals or radiation. Squamous cell carcinoma of the skin may appear as a firm red bump, a scaly red patch, an open sore, or a wart that may crust or bleed easily. Squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has not spread can usually be cured. Also called cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma and squamous cell skin cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000790318" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;squamous cell carcinoma of the skin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000790319" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células escamosas de piel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000787343" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the skin; drawing shows the epidermis (including the squamous cell and basal cell layers), dermis, and subcutaneous tissue. Also shown are the hair shafts, hair follicles, oil glands, lymph vessels, nerves, fatty tissue, veins, arteries, and sweat glands." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">Anatomy of the skin showing the epidermis (including the squamous cell and basal cell layers), dermis, subcutaneous tissue, and other parts of the skin.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000787850" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la piel; en la imagen se observa la epidermis (incluso la capa de células escamosas y la capa de células basales), la dermis y el tejido subcutáneo. También se muestran los tallos del pelo, los folículos pilosos, las glándulas sebáceas, los vasos linfáticos, los nervios, el tejido graso, las venas, las arterias y las glándulas sudoríparas." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Anatomía de la piel. Se observa la epidermis (incluso la capa de células escamosas y la capa de células basales), la dermis, el tejido subcutáneo y otras partes de la piel.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células escamosas de piel</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cáncer que surge en las células que forman la epidermis (capa más externa de la piel). Por lo general, se presenta en áreas de la piel expuestas a la luz solar  o la luz  artificial (como la de las cámaras de bronceado) durante períodos largos. Estas áreas son la cara, las orejas, el labio inferior, el cuello, los brazos o el dorso de las manos. También se presenta en áreas de la piel que se quemaron o estuvieron expuestas a sustancias químicas o radiación. El carcinoma de células escamosas de piel a veces aparece como un  bulto rojo y duro, un área roja escamosa, una llaga o una verruga que forma costra o sangra con mucha facilidad. Por lo habitual, el carcinoma de células escamosas de piel que no se ha diseminado es curable. También se llama cáncer de células escamosas de piel y carcinoma de células escamosas cutáneo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-06-05</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
