<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000788165"><TermName>niraparib tosylate monohydrate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(nih-RA-puh-rib TOH-suh-layt MAH-noh-HY-drayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Niraparib tosylate monohydrate blocks an enzyme involved in many cell functions, including the repair of DNA damage. Blocking this enzyme may help keep cancer cells from repairing their damaged DNA, causing them to die. Niraparib tosylate monohydrate is a type of PARP inhibitor. Also called Zejula.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789279" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;niraparib tosylate monohydrate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789280" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer epitelial de ovario, trompas de Falopio o primario de peritoneo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib bloquea una enzima que participa en muchas funciones de las células, entre ellas, la reparación del daño al ADN. Bloquear esta enzima quizás ayude a evitar que las células cancerosas reparen el daño a su ADN y esto las destruya. El monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib  es un tipo de inhibidor de PARP. También se llama tosilato de niraparib monohidrato y Zejula.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000788257" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/niraparibtosylatemonohydrate">Niraparib Tosylate Monohydrate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
