<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000788167"><TermName>Zejula</TermName><TermPronunciation>(zeh-JOO-luh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Zejula blocks an enzyme involved in many cell functions, including the repair of DNA damage. Blocking this enzyme may help keep cancer cells from repairing their damaged DNA, causing them to die. Zejula is a type of PARP inhibitor. Also called niraparib tosylate monohydrate.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789282" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zejula&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789281" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zejula&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Zejula</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer epitelial de ovario, trompas de Falopio o primario de peritoneo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  Zejula bloquea una enzima que participa en muchas funciones de las células, entre ellas, la reparación del daño al ADN. Bloquear esta enzima quizás ayude a evitar que las células cancerosas reparen el daño a su ADN y esto las destruya. Zejula  es un tipo de inhibidor de PARP. También se llama monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000788257" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/niraparibtosylatemonohydrate">Niraparib Tosylate Monohydrate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
