<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000788775"><TermName>durvalumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(dur-VAL-yoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that binds to the protein PD-L1 to help immune cells kill cancer cells better and is used to treat different types of cancer. Durvalumab is used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of biliary tract cancer (including bile duct cancer and gallbladder cancer), bladder cancer, endometrial cancer, hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), non-small cell lung cancer, and small cell lung cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Durvalumab may block PD-L1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called Imfinzi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789270" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;durvalumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000789269" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;durvalumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>durvalumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se une a la
proteína PD-L1 para ayudar a las células inmunitarias a
destruir más células cancerosas, y que se usa para el
tratamiento de diferentes tipos de cáncer.
El durvalumab se utiliza solo o con otros
medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de
cáncer biliar (incluso cáncer de vías biliares y de vesícula biliar), cáncer de vejiga, cáncer de endometrio, carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas y cáncer de pulmón de células pequeñas. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de
cáncer. Es posible que el durvalumab bloquee PD-L1
y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células
cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de puntos de control
inmunitario. También se llama Imfinzi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-05-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-04-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000788795" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/durvalumab">Durvalumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
