<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000789076"><TermName>systemic mastocytosis with associated hematologic neoplasm</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sis-TEH-mik MAS-toh-sy-TOH-sis … uh-SOH-see-ay-ted HEE-muh-tuh-LAH-jik NEE-oh-PLA-zum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare condition in which too many mast cells (a type of white blood cell) build up in certain tissues and organs in the body, including the bone marrow, lymph nodes, bone, liver, spleen, and small intestine, and may damage them. In systemic mastocytosis with associated hematologic neoplasm, this mast cell buildup occurs together with another blood disorder, usually a myelodysplastic syndrome, myeloproliferative disorder, or acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Systemic mastocytosis with associated hematologic neoplasm usually occurs in adults. Also called SM-AHN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791513" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;systemic mastocytosis with associated hematologic neoplasm&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791512" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mastocitosis sistémica con neoplasia hematológica asociada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mastocitosis sistémica con neoplasia hematológica asociada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que se acumulan demasiados mastocitos (un tipo de glóbulos blancos) en ciertos tejidos y órganos del cuerpo, como la médula ósea, los ganglios linfáticos, los huesos, el hígado, el bazo y el intestino delgado, y los puede dañar. En la mastocitosis sistémica con neoplasia hematológica asociada, esta acumulación de mastocitos se presenta junto con otro trastorno sanguíneo; por lo común, un síndrome mielodisplásico, un trastorno mieloproliferativo o una leucemia mieloide aguda (LMA). La mastocitosis sistémica con neoplasia hematológica asociada por lo habitual se presenta en adultos. También se llama MS-NHA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-09-08</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
