<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000789110">
  <TermName>stage IV medullary thyroid cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... MED-yoo-LAYR-ee THY-royd KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, the tumor is any size and (1) cancer has spread from the thyroid to soft tissue under the skin, the esophagus, the trachea, the larynx, or the recurrent laryngeal nerve (a nerve that goes to the larynx); cancer may have spread to lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck; or (2) cancer may have spread from the thyroid to nearby muscles in the neck; cancer has spread to lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck. In stage IVB, the tumor is any size and cancer has spread to tissue in front of the spine or to the spine or has surrounded the carotid artery or the blood vessels in the area between the lungs. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes. In stage IVC, the tumor is any size and cancer has spread to other parts of the body, such as the lungs or liver. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795201" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV medullary thyroid cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795202" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000780091" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IVA medullary thyroid cancer; drawing shows cancer in the thyroid gland and in the larynx, the esophagus, the left recurrent laryngeal nerve, the trachea, and a lymph node on one side of the neck. Also shown is the right recurrent laryngeal nerve." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IVA medullary thyroid cancer. The tumor is any size and cancer has spread from the thyroid to soft tissue under the skin, the esophagus, the trachea, the larynx, or the recurrent laryngeal nerve (a nerve that goes to the larynx), and cancer may have spread to lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck; or cancer may have spread from the thyroid to nearby muscles in the neck, and cancer has spread to lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000780093" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IVB medullary thyroid cancer; drawing shows cancer has (a) spread from the thyroid gland to tissue in front of the spine and to the spine (inset), (b) surrounded the common carotid artery, and (c) surrounded the blood vessels in the area between the lungs. Also shown are the lymph nodes and trachea." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IVB medullary thyroid cancer. The tumor is any size and cancer has  (a) spread to tissue in front of the spine or to the spine; or (b) surrounded the carotid artery; or (c) surrounded the blood vessels in the area between the lungs. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000780095" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IVC medullary thyroid cancer; drawing shows other parts of the body where thyroid cancer may spread, including the lung and liver. An inset shows cancer cells spreading from the thyroid, through the blood and lymph system, to another part of the body where metastatic cancer has formed." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_5">
    <Caption language="en">Stage IVC medullary thyroid cancer. The tumor is any size and cancer has spread to other parts of the body, such as the lung or liver. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785856" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IVA. En la imagen se muestra cáncer en la glándula tiroidea, la laringe, el esófago, el nervio laríngeo recurrente izquierdo, la tráquea y un ganglio linfático de un lado del cuello. También se muestra el nervio laríngeo recurrente derecho." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IVA. El tumor es de cualquier tamaño, y el cáncer se diseminó desde la glándula tiroidea (tiroides) hasta el tejido blando por debajo de la piel, el esófago, la tráquea, la laringe  o el nervio laríngeo recurrente (nervio que va a la laringe) y es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuello; o es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado desde la tiroides hasta los músculos cercanos del cuello, y el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuello.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785857" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IVB. En la imagen se muestra que el cáncer a) se diseminó desde la glándula tiroidea hasta el tejido delante de la columna vertebral y hasta la columna vertebral, b) rodeó la arteria carótida común y c) rodeó los vasos sanguíneos del área entre los pulmones. También se muestran los ganglios linfáticos y la tráquea." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_7">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IVB. El tumor es de cualquier tamaño, y el cáncer a) se diseminó al tejido delante de la columna vertebral y a la  columna vertebral, b) rodeó la arteria carótida o c) rodeó los vasos sanguíneos del área ubicada entre los pulmones. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000785858" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IVC. En la imagen se muestran otras partes del cuerpo donde es posible que el cáncer de tiroides se disemine, como el pulmón y el hígado. En el recuadro se muestran células cancerosas que se diseminan desde la tiroides, a través del sistema sanguíneo y linfático, hasta otra parte del cuerpo donde se formó el cáncer metastásico." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IVC. El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo, como los pulmones o el hígado. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de tiroides medular en estadio IV</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño  y 1) el cáncer se diseminó desde la tiroides hasta el tejido blando debajo de la piel, el esófago, la tráquea, la laringe o el nervio laríngeo recurrente (nervio que va a la laringe); es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuello; o 2) es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado desde la tiroides hasta los músculos cercanos del cuello; el cáncer se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuello. En el  estadio IVB, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó al tejido delante de la columna vertebral o a la columna vertebral, o rodeó la arteria carótida o los vasos sanguíneos del área entre los pulmones. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos. En el estadio IVC, el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo, como los pulmones o el hígado. Es posible que  el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-05-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258038" url="/types/thyroid/patient/thyroid-treatment-pdq">Thyroid Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000584552" url="/espanol/tipos/tiroides/paciente/tratamiento-tiroides-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de tiroides</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
