<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000789683"><TermName>microsatellite instability-high cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MY-kroh-SA-teh-lite in-stuh-BIH-lih-tee-hy KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes cancer cells that have a high number of mutations (changes) within microsatellites. For example, microsatellite testing that shows mutations in 30% or more microsatellites is called microsatellite instability-high. Microsatellites are short, repeated sequences of DNA. Microsatellite instability-high cancer cells may have a defect in the ability to correct mistakes that occur when DNA is copied in the cell. Microsatellite instability is found most often in colorectal cancer, gastric cancer, and endometrial cancer, but it may also be found in many other types of cancer. Knowing whether cancer is microsatellite instability-high may help plan the best treatment. Also called MSI-H cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791496" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;microsatellite instability-high cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791497" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer con inestabilidad microsatelital alta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer con inestabilidad microsatelital alta</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describe células cancerosas que tienen un número alto de mutaciones (cambios) en los microsatélites. Por ejemplo, se llama inestabilidad microsatelital alta cuando una prueba de microsatélites indica que hay mutaciones en 30 % o más de los microsatélites. Los microsatélites son secuencias de ADN cortas y repetidas. Es posible que las células de un cáncer con inestabilidad microsatelital alta tengan un defecto en la capacidad para corregir los errores que ocurren cuando se copia el ADN de la célula. La inestabilidad microsatelital se encuentra más a menudo en el cáncer colorrectal, el cáncer de estómago y el cáncer de endometrio, pero también se encuentra en otros tipos de cáncer. Saber si un cáncer tiene inestabilidad microsatelital alta quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento más eficaz. También se llama cáncer con IMS-A y cáncer con inestabilidad de microsatélites alta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-09-18</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-10-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
