<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000789795">
  <TermName>supplemental health insurance</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SUH-pleh-MEN-tul helth in-SHOOR-ents)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An additional insurance plan that helps pay for health care costs that are not covered by a person’s regular health insurance plan.  These costs include copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles. There are many different types of supplemental health insurance, including vision, dental, hospital, accident, disability, long-term care, and Medicare supplemental plans. There are also supplemental health insurance plans for specific conditions, such as cancer, stroke, or kidney failure. Some types of supplemental health insurance may also be used to help pay for food, medicine, transportation, and other expenses related to an illness or injury.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792204" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;supplemental health insurance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792205" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;seguro médico complementario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>seguro médico complementario</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Plan de seguro adicional que ayuda a pagar los costos de la atención sanitaria   que no cubre el plan de seguro  médico corriente de la persona.  Estos costos incluyen los copagos, el coseguro y los deducibles.  Hay muchos tipos diferentes de seguro médico complementario, como  los de visión, dental, hospitalario, de accidentes, de incapacidad, de atención a largo plazo y los planes  complementarios de Medicare. También hay planes de seguro médico complementarios para afecciones específicas como el cáncer, el derrame cerebral o la insuficiencia renal. Algunos tipos de seguro médico complementario se pueden usar para  pagar por los alimentos, los medicamentos, el trasporte y otros gastos relacionados con enfermedades o traumatismos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-10-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-02-02</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
