<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000789739"><TermName>biosimilar drug</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BY-oh-SIH-mih-ler …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A biological drug that is very much like another biological drug (called the reference drug) that has already been approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Biosimilar drugs and reference drugs are made from living organisms but they may be made in different ways and of slightly different substances. To be called a biosimilar drug, a biological drug must be shown to be as safe as, work as well as, and work in the same way as its reference drug. It must also be used in the same way, at the same dose, and for the same condition as the reference drug. Biosimilar drugs must be approved by FDA, and may cost less than the reference drugs.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791539" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biosimilar drug&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791538" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicamento biosimilar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicamento biosimilar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento biológico que es muy parecido a otro medicamento biológico (llamado medicamento de referencia) y que ya fue aprobado por la Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos de los Estados Unidos (FDA). Si bien los medicamentos biosimilares y los medicamentos de referencia se elaboran a partir de organismos vivos, es posible que se elaboren de maneras diferentes y con sustancias ligeramente distintas. Para que un medicamento se llame biosimilar, se debe demostrar que un medicamento biológico sea tan seguro, tan eficaz y funcione de la misma manera que su medicamento de referencia. Asimismo, se debe usar de la misma manera, con la misma dosis y para la misma afección que el medicamento de referencia. La FDA debe aprobar los medicamentos biosimilares y quizás cuesten menos que los medicamentos de referencia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-09-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
