<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790160"><TermName>financial distress</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fy-NAN-shul dih-STRES)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, a term used to describe problems a patient has related to the cost of medical care. Not having health insurance or having a lot of costs for medical care not covered by health insurance can cause financial problems and may lead to debt and bankruptcy. Financial distress can also affect a patient’s quality of life and access to medical care. For example, a patient may not take a prescription medicine or may avoid going to the doctor to save money. Cancer patients are more likely to have financial distress than people without cancer. Also called economic burden, economic hardship, financial burden, financial hardship, financial stress, and financial toxicity.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792193" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;financial distress&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792192" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sufrimiento financiero&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sufrimiento financiero</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, término utilizado para describir los problemas del paciente relacionados con los costos de la atención médica. Es posible que no contar con seguro médico, o tener que pagar muchos gastos por la atención sanitaria que no cubre el seguro médico, cause problemas financieros y lleve al endeudamiento y la quiebra. El sufrimiento financiero también afecta la calidad de vida de los pacientes y el acceso a la atención médica. Por ejemplo, es posible que un paciente no tome el medicamento de venta con receta o evite asistir a una consulta médica a fin de ahorrar dinero. Los pacientes de cáncer son más propensos a presentar sufrimiento financiero que las personas sin cáncer. También se llama carga económica, carga financiera, dificultad económica, dificultad financiera, tensión financiera y toxicidad financiera.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-10-12</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000783881" url="/about-cancer/managing-care/track-care-costs/financial-toxicity-pdq">Financial Toxicity (Financial Distress) and Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000790294" url="/espanol/cancer/manejo-del-cancer/costos/toxicidad-financiera-pdq">Toxicidad financiera del tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
