<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790109"><TermName>olfactory neuroblastoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ol-FAK-tuh-ree NOOR-oh-blas-TOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare type of cancer that forms in the tissues of the upper part of the nasal cavity (space inside the nose). This area is near the bone that separates the nasal cavity from the brain. These tissues are involved in the sense of smell. Olfactory neuroblastoma may spread from the nasal cavity to the bone around the eyes, the sinuses, the front part of the brain, or the lymph nodes in the neck. It is the most common type of nasal cavity tumor in children, especially in teens. Also called esthesioneuroblastoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791527" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;olfactory neuroblastoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791526" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neuroblastoma olfatorio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801515" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing shows areas of the body where esthesioneuroblastoma tumors may form, including the olfactory nerve endings, olfactory bulb, nasal cavity, nasal sinuses, and brain." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Esthesioneuroblastomas form in the olfactory nerve endings in the upper part of the nasal cavity. The olfactory nerves (sense of smell) pass through the many tiny holes in the bone at the base of the brain to the olfactory bulb. Esthesioneuroblastomas may spread from the nasal cavity to the nasal sinuses or to nearby tissue. They may also spread to the brain or to other parts of the body (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801574" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observan las áreas del cuerpo donde es posible que se formen tumores del estesioneuroblastoma, como las terminaciones nerviosas olfatorias, el bulbo olfatorio, la cavidad nasal, los senos paranasales y el encéfalo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Los estesioneuroblastomas se forman en las terminaciones nerviosas olfatorias que están en la parte superior de la cavidad nasal. Los nervios olfatorios (sentido del olfato) pasan a través de los múltiples pequeños agujeros en el hueso de la base del cráneo y llegan al bulbo olfatorio. Los estesioneuroblastomas a veces se diseminan de la cavidad nasal a los senos paranasales o el tejido cercano. En ocasiones, también se diseminan al encéfalo o a otras partes del cuerpo (no se ve en la imagen).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>neuroblastoma olfatorio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer raro que se forma en los tejidos de la parte superior de la cavidad nasal (espacio dentro de la nariz) que se relacionan con el sentido del olfato. Esta área está cerca del hueso que separa la cavidad nasal del encéfalo. Es posible que el neuroblastoma olfatorio se disemine de la cavidad nasal al hueso que rodea los ojos, los senos paranasales y la parte delantera del encéfalo, o hasta los ganglios linfáticos del cuello. Es el tipo de tumor de la cavidad nasal más común en los niños; en especial, en adolescentes. También se llama estesioneuroblastoma y neuroblastoma olfativo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-09-11</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-05-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000789047" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/child/esthesioneuroblastoma-treatment-pdq">Childhood Esthesioneuroblastoma</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000791876" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/infantil/tratamiento-estesioneuroblastoma-pdq">Estesioneuroblastoma infantil</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
