<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790244"><TermName>enasidenib mesylate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EH-nuh-SIH-deh-nib MEH-zih-layt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with acute myeloid leukemia that has come back or has not gotten better with other treatment. It is used in patients whose cancer has a mutation (change) in the <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> gene.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Enasidenib mesylate blocks the protein made by the mutated <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> gene.  Blocking this protein may help keep cancer cells from growing.  Enasidenib mesylate is a type of enzyme inhibitor. Also called Idhifa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791531" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enasidenib mesylate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791530" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesilato de enasidenib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mesilato de enasidenib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia mieloide aguda que volvió o no mejoró con otro tratamiento. Se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer tiene una mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName>. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El mesilato de enasidenib bloquea la proteína que se origina del gen <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> mutado. Bloquear esta proteína quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. El mesilato de enasidenib es un tipo de inhibidor enzimático. También se llama Idhifa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-08-07</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000790240" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/enasidenibmesylate">Enasidenib Mesylate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
