<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790212">
  <TermName>bankruptcy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BANK-rup-see)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The situation that occurs when a person or business is not able to pay back debts. Filing for bankruptcy is a legal process that is handled by a U.S. federal court. This process can help people get rid of their debt or reduce their debt through a repayment plan. Certain events, such as job loss, divorce, a long illness, or hospitalization, can affect a person’s ability to pay bills and lead to debt and bankruptcy. Filing for bankruptcy helps people get a fresh start financially, but it also affects their ability to borrow money or have credit in the future.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792223" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bankruptcy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792222" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;quiebra&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>quiebra</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Situación que ocurre cuando una persona o  empresa no puede pagar sus deudas.  La declaración de quiebra es un procedimiento jurídico a cargo de  una corte federal de los Estados Unidos. Este procedimiento puede ayudar a las personas a saldar sus deudas o disminuirlas  mediante un plan de pagos. Determinadas circunstancias, como el desempleo, el divorcio, la enfermedad prolongada o la hospitalización influyen en la capacidad de una persona para pagar sus cuentas y llevan al endeudamiento o la quiebra.  Declararse en quiebra ayuda a la persona a empezar de nuevo desde el punto de vista financiero, pero también afecta su capacidad futura para solicitar préstamos de dinero o  créditos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-10-19</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
