<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790626"><TermName>acute myeloid leukemia with myelodysplasia-related changes</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-KYOOT MY-eh-loyd loo-KEE-mee-uh … MY-eh-loh-dis-PLAY-zhuh-ree-LAY-ted CHAYN-jiz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of acute myeloid leukemia in which at least 20% of a patient’s blood or bone marrow is myeloblasts (immature white blood cells) and the patient has one of the following conditions: 1) has had myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) or a myelodysplastic/myeloproliferative neoplasm (MDS/MPN) before, 2) cells that have changes in certain chromosomes that are similar to those found in MDS, or 3) at least 50% of the cells (of at least two types of blood cells) are abnormal. Acute myeloid leukemia with myelodysplasia-related changes usually occurs in older adults and has a poor prognosis. Also called AML-MRC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792235" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acute myeloid leukemia with myelodysplasia-related changes&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792234" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leucemia mieloide aguda con cambios relacionados con mielodisplasia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>leucemia mieloide aguda con cambios relacionados con mielodisplasia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de leucemia mieloide aguda en la que por lo menos el 20 % de la sangre o la médula ósea del paciente son mieloblastos (glóbulos blancos inmaduros) y el paciente cumple una de las siguientes condiciones: 1) tuvo antes un síndrome mielodisplásico (SMD) o una neoplasia mielodisplásica o mieloproliferativa (NMP); 2) presenta células con cambios en ciertos cromosomas que son similares a los que se encuentran en las células de los SMD, o 3) tiene anormalidades en por lo menos el 50 % de las células (como mínimo de dos tipos de células sanguíneas). La leucemia mieloide aguda con cambios relacionados con mielodisplasia se suele presentar en adultos mayores y tiene un pronóstico precario. También se llama LMA-CRM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-11-15</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
