<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790629">
  <TermName>circadian rhythm</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(sir-KAY-dee-un RIH-thum)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The natural cycle of physical, mental, and behavior changes that the body goes through in a 24-hour cycle. Circadian rhythms are mostly affected by light and darkness and are controlled by a small area in the middle of the brain. They can affect sleep, body temperature, hormones, appetite, and other body functions. Abnormal circadian rhythms may be linked to obesity, diabetes, depression, bipolar disorder, seasonal affective disorder, and sleep disorders such as insomnia. Circadian rhythm is sometimes called the “body’s clock.”</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792239" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;circadian rhythm&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792238" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ritmo circadiano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ritmo circadiano</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Ciclo natural de cambios físicos, mentales y de comportamiento que experimenta el cuerpo en un ciclo de 24 horas. Los ritmos circadianos se ven afectados principalmente por la luz y la oscuridad, y están controlados por un área pequeña en el medio del encéfalo. Pueden afectar el sueño, la temperatura del cuerpo, las hormonas, el apetito y otras funciones del cuerpo. Los ritmos circadianos anormales a veces se relacionan con la obesidad, la diabetes, la depresión, el trastorno bipolar, el trastorno afectivo estacional y los trastornos del sueño; por ejemplo, el insomnio. El ritmo circadiano a veces se llama &quot;reloj biológico&quot;.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-11-15</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
