<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000790952">
  <TermName>secondary ovarian failure</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SEH-kun-dayr-ee oh-VAYR-ee-un FAYL-yer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which the ovaries stop working and menstrual periods stop before age 40. This can cause fertility problems and symptoms of menopause. In secondary ovarian failure, the ovaries are normal but there is a problem getting hormone signals to them from the brain. This is usually caused by diseases of the pituitary gland or hypothalamus. Secondary ovarian failure may also be caused by certain medicines, too much exercise, or certain eating disorders. Some women with secondary ovarian failure sometimes have menstrual periods and may be able to have children. Also called secondary ovarian insufficiency.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000791507" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;secondary ovarian failure&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000791506" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;insuficiencia del ovario secundaria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>insuficiencia del ovario secundaria</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que los ovarios dejan de funcionar y se detiene la menstruación antes de los 40 años. Esto puede causar problemas de reproducción y síntomas de menopausia. En la insuficiencia del ovario secundaria, los ovarios son normales pero tienen un problema para recibir las señales hormonales que vienen del encéfalo. Por lo general, la causa son enfermedades de la hipófisis o el hipotálamo. Otras causas de la insuficiencia del ovario secundaria son determinados medicamentos, exceso de ejercicio o ciertos trastornos de la conducta alimentaria. En ocasiones, algunas mujeres con  insuficiencia del ovario secundaria tienen periodos menstruales y pueden tener hijos. También se llama insuficiencia ovárica secundaria.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-09-13</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
