<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791166"><TermName>hyaluronidase</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HY-al-yoo-RAH-nih-days)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An enzyme that breaks down a substance in the body called hyaluronic acid. Hyaluronic acid is found throughout the body in connective tissue, skin, and fluids in the joints and inside the eye. It causes fluids to have a jelly-like thickness, which can help moisten and protect tissues and joints. In medicine, hyaluronidase is made in the laboratory and given with other drugs by injection under the skin to treat certain conditions. Using hyaluronidase to break down hyaluronic acid helps make the fluids and connective tissue thinner so the drugs can move more easily into the tissues.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792249" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hyaluronidase&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792250" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hialuronidasa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>hialuronidasa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enzima que descompone una sustancia del cuerpo llamada ácido hialurónico. El ácido hialurónico   se encuentra en diferentes partes del cuerpo: en el tejido conjuntivo, la piel, el líquido de las articulaciones  y el líquido de los ojos. Hace que los líquidos adquieran una consistencia gelatinosa, lo que ayuda a hidratar y proteger los tejidos y las articulaciones. En el ámbito de la medicina, la hialuronidasa se elabora en el laboratorio y se administra con otros medicamentos mediante una inyección debajo de la piel para tratar ciertas afecciones. La hialuronidasa descompone el ácido hialurónico, lo cual sirve para disolver los líquidos y aflojar el tejido conjuntivo   de manera que los medicamentos  se absorban con mayor facilidad en los tejidos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-12-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
