<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791334"><TermName>acalabrutinib maleate monohydrate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-KA-luh-BROO-tih-nib MAY-lee-AYT MAH-noh-HY-drayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used alone to treat adults with chronic lymphocytic leukemia or small lymphocytic lymphoma and adults with mantle cell lymphoma that has already been treated with at least one other therapy. Acalabrutinib maleate monohydrate is used with bendamustine and rituximab to treat adults with mantle cell lymphoma that has not been treated and who cannot receive an autologous stem cell transplant. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Acalabrutinib maleate monohydrate blocks a protein called BTK, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called Calquence.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792189" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acalabrutinib maleate monohydrate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000792188" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;monohidrato de maleato de acalabrutinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>monohidrato de maleato de acalabrutinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo para el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia linfocítica crónica o linfoma linfocítico pequeño y adultos con linfoma de células de manto que ya recibieron por lo menos otro tratamiento. El acalabrutinib también se usa con  bendamustina y rituximab para el tratamiento de adultos con linfoma de células de manto que no se han tratado y que no pueden recibir un trasplante de células madre autógeno. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El acalabrutinib bloquea una proteína llamada BTK, lo que quizás evite que las células cancerosas se multipliquen. Es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama Calquence.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2017-11-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-01-31</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000791355" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/acalabrutinib">Acalabrutinib Maleate Monohydrate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
