<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791315"><TermName>Swyer syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SWY-er SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare genetic condition in which people who have an X chromosome and a Y chromosome (the usual pattern for males) look female. They have normal female reproductive organs, including a uterus, fallopian tubes, and vagina. However, the ovaries do not develop and are replaced by clumps of tissue where they would normally form. Swyer syndrome is usually not diagnosed until puberty, when menstrual periods do not begin as they should. Having Swyer syndrome increases the risk of certain types of germ cell tumors.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793306" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Swyer syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793307" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Síndrome de Swyer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Swyer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección genética rara por la que una persona presenta rasgos femeninos a pesar de tener un cromosoma X y un cromosoma Y (patrón del sexo masculino). La persona tiene órganos genitales femeninos, entre ellos, útero, trompas de Falopio y vagina. Sin embargo, los ovarios no se desarrollan y en su lugar hay masas de tejido. A menudo, el síndrome de Swyer se diagnostica durante la pubertad, cuando los periodos menstruales no se inician según lo esperado. El síndrome de Swyer aumenta el riesgo de ciertos tipos de tumores de células germinativas. También se llama disgenesia gonadal 46XY y disgenesia gonadal completa 46XY.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-02-09</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/swyer-syndrome/">Swyer syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/5068/swyer-syndrome">Swyer syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
