<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791361">
  <TermName>patient navigator</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PAY-shunt NA-vih-GAY-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A person who helps guide a patient through the health care system. This includes help going through the screening, diagnosis, treatment, and follow-up of a medical condition, such as cancer. A patient navigator helps patients communicate with their health care providers so they get the information they need to make decisions about their health care. Patient navigators may also help patients set up appointments for doctor visits and medical tests and get financial, legal, and social support. They may also work with insurance companies, employers, case managers, lawyers, and others who may have an effect on a patient’s health care needs. Also called patient advocate.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792220" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;patient navigator&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792221" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;orientador del paciente&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>orientador del paciente</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Persona que orienta a los pacientes a través del sistema de atención de la salud y que proporciona ayuda durante diferentes etapas de la atención de afecciones como el cáncer, por ejemplo: detección, diagnóstico, tratamiento y seguimiento. Las personas que se desempeñan como orientadores de los pacientes facilitan la comunicación entre proveedores de atención de la salud y pacientes con el fin de que estos obtengan la información necesaria para tomar decisiones en relación con su atención médica. También ayudan a programar las consultas médicas y las pruebas clínicas y pueden facilitar la obtención de apoyo económico, legal y social. En ocasiones, colaboran con compañías de seguros, empleadores, coordinadores asistenciales, abogados y otras personas con capacidad de influencia en las necesidades de atención de la salud de los pacientes. También se llama asesor de pacientes y defensor del paciente.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-11-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-02-06</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
