<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791313">
  <TermName>Turner syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(TER-ner SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A genetic condition that occurs in females who have a missing or abnormal X chromosome (sex chromosome). Turner syndrome is marked by a shorter-than-average height, ovaries that do not function normally, and infertility. Other signs and symptoms may include extra folds of skin on the neck, a low hairline at the back of the neck, swelling of the hands and feet, and heart, kidney, bone, and hearing problems. Turner syndrome is present at birth but its signs and symptoms may occur slowly over time. Having Turner syndrome increases the risk of germ cell tumors in the ovaries.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793303" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Turner syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793302" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Turner&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Turner</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección genética que se presenta en mujeres que tienen un cromosoma X (cromosoma sexual) anormal o que les falta un cromosoma X. El síndrome de Turner se caracteriza por una estatura más baja que el promedio,  funcionamiento anormal de los ovarios y esterilidad. Otros signos y síntomas son pliegues en la piel del cuello, línea de cabello baja en la nuca, hinchazón de las manos y los pies, además de alteraciones en el corazón, los riñones, los huesos y la audición. El síndrome de Turner está presente desde el nacimiento, pero a veces los signos  y síntomas se manifiestan lentamente a medida que pasa el tiempo. El síndrome de Turner aumenta el riesgo de tumores de células germinativas en los ovarios. También se llama monosomía X.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-02-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7831/turner-syndrome">Turner syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/turner-syndrome/">Turner syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12896/sindrome-de-turner">Síndrome de Turner (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000379.htm">Síndrome de Turner (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
