<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791353">
  <TermName>cytokine release syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SY-toh-kine reh-LEES SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition that may occur after treatment with some types of immunotherapy, such as monoclonal antibodies and CAR-T cells. Cytokine release syndrome is caused by a large, rapid release of cytokines into the blood from immune cells affected by the immunotherapy. Cytokines are immune substances that have many different actions in the body. Signs and symptoms of cytokine release syndrome include fever, nausea, headache, rash, rapid heartbeat, low blood pressure, and trouble breathing. Most patients have a mild reaction, but sometimes, the reaction may be severe or life threatening.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792218" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cytokine release syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792219" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de liberación de citocinas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de liberación de citocinas</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección que se presenta a veces después de un tratamiento con algunos tipos de inmunoterapia; por ejemplo, con anticuerpos monoclonales y células T con CAR. El síndrome de liberación de citocinas se presenta por una liberación grande y rápida en la sangre de citocinas de células inmunitarias afectadas por la inmunoterapia. Las citocinas son sustancias inmunitarias que tienen muchas acciones diferentes en el cuerpo. Los signos y síntomas del  síndrome de liberación de citocinas incluyen fiebre, náuseas, dolor de cabeza, sarpullidos, latidos cardíacos rápidos, presión arterial baja y dificultad para respirar. La mayoría de los pacientes tienen una reacción leve pero, a veces, la reacción es grave o pone en peligro la vida.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2017-11-14</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
