<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791379"><TermName>tocilizumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(toh-sih-LIH-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults and children aged 2 years and older with severe or life-threatening cytokine release syndrome caused by a type of immunotherapy called chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T-cell therapy. Tocilizumab is also used to treat certain types of arthritis and a condition that causes inflammation of the lining of the arteries. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions. Tocilizumab binds to receptors for a protein called interleukin-6 (IL-6), which is made by white blood cells and other cells in the body. This may help lower the body’s immune response and reduce inflammation. Tocilizumab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Actemra.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793641" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tocilizumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793640" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tocilizumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tocilizumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de los adultos y niños de 2 años o más con el síndrome de liberación de citocinas grave causado por un tipo de inmunoterapia llamada terapia de células T con receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR). El tocilizumab también se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de artritis y una afección que produce la inflamación del revestimiento de las arterias. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones. El tocilizumab se une a los receptores de una proteína llamada interleucina-6 (IL-6), elaborada por los glóbulos blancos y otras células del cuerpo. De esta forma es posible que reduzca la respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo y disminuya la inflamación.  El tocilizumab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Actemra.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-03-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-08-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000792716" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tocilizumab">Tocilizumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
