<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791321"><TermName>hyperalgesia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HY-per-al-JEE-zee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An increased sensitivity to feeling pain and an extreme response to pain. Hyperalgesia may occur when there is damage to the nerves or chemical changes to the nerve pathways involved in sensing pain. This may be caused by tissue injury or inflammation or by taking certain drugs, such as opioids, for chronic pain. People with hyperalgesia tend to feel extreme pain even though an injury or medical condition has not gotten worse. This pain may get worse over time, and it may extend to other areas of the body. It may also become a new or different type of pain than the original pain.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793314" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hyperalgesia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793315" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hiperalgesia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>hiperalgesia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Aumento de la sensibilidad al dolor y reacción extrema al mismo. La hiperalgesia se presenta cuando se dañan los nervios o hay cambios químicos en las vías nerviosas que participan en la percepción del dolor. Es posible que su causa sea  la presencia de una lesión o inflamación en los tejidos, o el consumo de ciertos medicamentos, como los opiodes, para el dolor crónico. Las personas con hiperalgesia tienden a sentir dolor extremo, aunque la lesión o la afección médica no haya empeorado. Con el paso del tiempo, el dolor a veces empeora y se extiende a otras partes del cuerpo. También es posible que se transforme en un tipo de dolor nuevo o diferente del dolor original.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-02-09</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/pain/pain-hp-pdq" UseWith="en">Cancer Pain (Health Professional Version)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/dolor/dolor-pro-pdq">El dolor y el cáncer (Versión para profesionales de salud)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
