<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791448"><TermName>breast cancer resistance protein</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest KAN-ser reh-ZIH-stunts PROH-teen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A protein that is involved in making cancer cells resistant (unable to respond) to anticancer drugs.  Normally, breast cancer resistance protein works with other proteins to help move many different substances, including drugs and other chemicals, in and out of cells. It is found in stem cells and in normal tissues, including the intestine, liver, brain, and placenta. However, it may also be found in higher than normal amounts in some cancer cells, which can cause them to be unable to respond to certain anticancer drugs. Drugs that block breast cancer resistance protein are being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. Breast cancer resistance protein was first identified in breast cancer cells. Also called BCRP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793312" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast cancer resistance protein&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793313" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proteína de resistencia del cáncer de mama&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>proteína de resistencia del cáncer de mama</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proteína que hace que las células cancerosas se vuelvan resistentes (incapaces de responder) a los medicamentos contra el cáncer. Por lo general,  la proteína de resistencia del cáncer de mama actúa con otras proteínas para ayudar a transportar muchas sustancias diferentes; entre ellas, medicamentos y otras sustancias químicas dentro y fuera de la célula. Se encuentra en las células madre y en los tejidos normales, como el intestino, el hígado, el encéfalo y la placenta. Sin embargo, también se encuentra en concentraciones mayores a las normales en algunas células cancerosas, lo que les impide responder a ciertos medicamentos contra el cáncer. Los medicamentos que bloquean la proteína de resistencia del cáncer de mama están en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. La proteína de resistencia del cáncer de mama se identificó por primera vez en células de cáncer de mama. También se llama BCRP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-02-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
