<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791444">
  <TermName>clear liquid diet</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(kleer LIH-kwid DY-et)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A diet that is made up of only liquids and foods that are clear liquids at room temperature. Clear liquids are easy to digest and include water, broth, gelatin, plain tea and coffee, popsicles and juices without pulp, sodas, and sports drinks. Clear liquid diets may be used before certain tests or procedures, such as a colonoscopy, or before or after certain types of surgery. They may also be used to help treat gastrointestinal problems, such as nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea. Clear liquid diets are normally used for only a few days because they do not have enough of the calories and nutrients the body needs.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793309" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clear liquid diet&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793308" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dieta líquida absoluta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>dieta líquida absoluta</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Dieta compuesta solo por líquidos y alimentos líquidos transparentes a temperatura ambiente. Los líquidos transparentes son fáciles de digerir e incluyen, entre otros, agua, caldos, gelatina, té y café simples; paletas de agua y jugos sin pulpa, refrescos y bebidas para deportistas. Las dietas líquidas absolutas a veces se usan antes de ciertas pruebas o procedimientos, como una colonoscopia, o antes o después de ciertos tipos de cirugías. También se emplean para ayudar a tratar problemas gastrointestinales, como náuseas, vómitos o diarrea. Las dietas líquidas absolutas por lo general se utilizan solo durante unos pocos días porque no contienen suficientes calorías y nutrientes para satisfacer las necesidades del cuerpo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-02-13</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
