<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000791735"><TermName>pseudomyogenic hemangioendothelioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SOO-doh-MY-oh-JEH-nik hee-MAN-jee-oh-EN-doh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A very rare blood vessel tumor that usually forms on or under the skin of the arms or legs, but it may also form in deeper tissues, such as muscle and bone. These tumors may spread to nearby tissue, but usually do not spread to other parts of the body. There is often more than one tumor, and the tumor may cause pain in the affected area. Pseudomyogenic hemangioendotheliomas may come back after treatment. They are most common in young adult males. Pseudomyogenic hemangioendotheliomas are a type of vascular tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793332" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pseudomyogenic hemangioendothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793331" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemangioendotelioma pseudomiogénico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>hemangioendotelioma pseudomiogénico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor de los vasos sanguíneos muy poco común que se suele formar encima o debajo de la piel de los brazos y las piernas, pero que también se forma en tejidos más profundos, como los músculos y los huesos. A veces, estos tumores se diseminan a tejidos cercanos, pero en general no se diseminan a otras partes del cuerpo. Con frecuencia, se presenta más de un tumor que quizás cause dolor en el área afectada. Es posible que los hemangioendoteliomas pseudomiogénicos vuelvan después del tratamiento. Son más comunes en los varones adultos jóvenes. Los hemangioendoteliomas pseudomiogénicos son un tipo de tumor vascular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-03-12</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
