<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792084">
  <TermName>intravenous immunoglobulin</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(IN-truh-VEE-nus IH-myoo-noh-GLAH-byoo-lin)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A substance made from antibodies that have been taken from the blood of many healthy donors. It is given to a patient through a needle or tube inserted into a vein. Intravenous immunoglobulins are used to treat certain types of immune disorders in which there are low amounts of antibodies in the blood. They are also used to treat many different autoimmune disorders, infections, or other conditions. They may also be used to help prevent infections in patients who have had a stem cell or organ transplant. Intravenous immunoglobulins are a type of immunotherapy. Also called IVIG.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793617" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intravenous immunoglobulin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793616" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inmunoglobulina intravenosa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>inmunoglobulina intravenosa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Sustancia que se elabora con anticuerpos que se extraen de la sangre de muchos donantes sanos. Se administran al paciente mediante una aguja o un tubo que se introduce en una vena. Las inmunoglobulinas intravenosas se usan para tratar ciertos tipos de trastornos inmunitarios en los que hay pocos anticuerpos en la sangre. Asimismo, se usan para tratar muchos trastornos autoinmunitarios, infecciones u otras afecciones. Es posible también que se utilicen para prevenir infecciones en pacientes que reciben un trasplante de células madre o de un órgano. La inmunoglobulina intravenosa es un tipo de sustancia para la inmunoterapia. También se llama IGIV.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-04-17</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
