<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792118"><TermName>stage IIIC colorectal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... KOH-loh-REK-tul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III colorectal cancer is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIC, cancer has spread (1) through the serosa (outermost layer) of the colon and/or rectum wall to the tissue that lines the organs in the abdomen (visceral peritoneum). Cancer has spread to 4 to 6 nearby lymph nodes; or (2) through the muscle layer of the colon and/or rectum wall to the serosa of the colon and/or rectum wall or has spread through the serosa to the visceral peritoneum. Cancer has spread to seven or more nearby lymph nodes; or (3) through the serosa of the colon and/or rectum wall to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to one or more nearby lymph nodes or cancer cells have formed in tissue near the lymph nodes. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796144" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIC colorectal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796145" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer colorrectal en estadio IIIC&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000688436" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIC colorectal cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the colon/rectum and a three-panel inset. Each panel shows the layers of the colon/rectum wall: the mucosa, submucosa, muscle layers, and serosa. Also shown are a blood vessel and lymph nodes. The first panel shows cancer in all layers, in 4 lymph nodes, and in the visceral peritoneum. The second panel shows cancer in all layers and in 7 lymph nodes. The third panel shows cancer in all layers, in 2 lymph nodes, and spreading to nearby organs." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIC colorectal cancer. Cancer has spread through the serosa of the colon/rectum wall to the visceral peritoneum (tissue that lines the organs in the abdomen). Cancer has spread to four to six nearby lymph nodes; OR cancer has spread through the muscle layer of the colon/rectum wall to the serosa or has spread through the serosa to the visceral peritoneum. Cancer has spread to seven or more nearby lymph nodes; OR cancer has spread through the serosa of the colon/rectal wall to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to one or more nearby lymph nodes or to tissue near the lymph nodes.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000692983" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer colorrectal en estadio IIIC. En la imagen se muestran un corte transversal de la pared del colon o el recto y un recuadro de tres paneles. En cada panel se muestran las capas de la pared del  colon o el recto: la mucosa, la submucosa, las capas de músculo y la serosa. También se muestran vasos sanguíneos y ganglios linfáticos. En el primer panel se observa cáncer en todas las capas, en cuatro ganglios linfáticos y en el peritoneo visceral. En el segundo panel se observa cáncer en todas las capas y en siete ganglios linfáticos. En el tercer panel se observa cáncer en todas las capas, en dos ganglios linfáticos y que se disemina a órganos cercanos." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer colorrectal en estadio IIIC. El cáncer se diseminó a través de la serosa de la pared del colon o el recto al peritoneo visceral (tejido que reviste los órganos del abdomen). El cáncer se diseminó hasta 4 a 6 ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa de músculo de la pared del colon o el recto a la serosa, o se diseminó a través de la serosa al peritoneo visceral. El cáncer se diseminó a 7 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o el cáncer se diseminó a través de la serosa de la pared del colon o el recto a órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó a 1 o más  ganglios linfáticos cercanos o al tejido cercano a los ganglios linfáticos.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer colorrectal en estadio IIIC</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer colorrectal en estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer se diseminó 1) a través de la serosa (capa más externa) de la pared del colon o el recto al tejido que reviste los órganos del abdomen (peritoneo visceral). El cáncer se diseminó hasta 4 a 6 ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o 2) a través de la capa de músculo de la pared del colon o el recto a la serosa de la pared del colon o el recto, o se diseminó a través de la serosa al peritoneo visceral. El cáncer se diseminó hasta 7 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o 3) se diseminó a través de la serosa de la pared del colon o el recto a órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó hasta 1 o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos o se formaron células cancerosas en el tejido cerca de los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-08-16</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062954" url="/types/colorectal/patient/colon-treatment-pdq">Colon Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062959" url="/types/colorectal/patient/rectal-treatment-pdq">Rectal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256772" url="/espanol/tipos/colorrectal/paciente/tratamiento-rectal-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de recto</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256761" url="/espanol/tipos/colorrectal/paciente/tratamiento-colorrectal-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de colon</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
