<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792337"><TermName>apalutamide</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-puh-LOO-tuh-mide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to
          treat prostate cancer that has spread to other parts of the
          body and is castration sensitive (has responded to
          treatments that lower testosterone levels) and prostate
          cancer that has not spread to other parts of the body and
          is castration resistant (has not responded to treatments
          that lower testosterone levels).
          Apalutamide binds to proteins
          called androgen receptors, which are found in some prostate
          cancer cells. These proteins bind to androgens (male
          hormones) and may cause cancer cells to grow.
          Apalutamide blocks these proteins
          and may keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of
          antiandrogen. Also called Erleada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793333" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;apalutamide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793334" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;apalutamida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>apalutamida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para
el tratamiento del cáncer de próstata que se diseminó a otras partes
del cuerpo y que es sensible a la castración (respondió a
los tratamientos que disminuyen la concentración de
testosterona). También se usa para tratar el cáncer de
próstata que no se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y es
resistente a la castración (que no respondió a los tratamientos
que disminuyen la concentración de testosterona).
La apalutamida se une a unas proteínas llamadas
receptores de andrógenos, que se encuentran en algunas
células de cáncer de próstata. Estas proteínas se unen a
los andrógenos (hormonas masculinas) y a veces hacen que las células cancerosas se multipliquen.
La apalutamida bloquea estas proteínas y es
posible que impida la multiplicación de células cancerosas.
Es un tipo de antiandrógeno. También se llama Erleada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-02-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-10-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000792335" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/apalutamide">Apalutamide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
