<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792404">
  <TermName>recurrent respiratory papillomatosis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ree-KER-ent RES-pih-ruh-TOR-ee PA-pih-LOH-muh-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare condition in which wart-like growths called papillomas grow in the respiratory tract (air passages leading from the nose and mouth into the lungs). The papillomas most often grow in the larynx (voice box) and vocal cords. They can grow quickly, and they often grow back after they have been removed by surgery. Signs and symptoms of recurrent respiratory papillomatosis include hoarseness, chronic cough, swallowing problems, and breathing problems, which may sometimes be life-threatening.  Recurrent respiratory papillomatosis is caused by infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). It can occur in both children and adults. Also called RRP.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;recurrent respiratory papillomatosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793656" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;papilomatosis respiratoria recurrente&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>papilomatosis respiratoria recurrente</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que  se forman crecimientos similares a verrugas llamados papilomas en las vías respiratorias (conductos  que comunican la nariz y la boca con los pulmones). Los papilomas suelen crecer en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales. Es posible que crezcan rápido y es común que vuelvan después de que se extirparon mediante cirugía. Los signos y síntomas de papilomatosis respiratoria recurrente son ronquera, tos crónica y problemas para tragar o respirar, que a veces ponen en peligro la vida de la persona. La infección por ciertos tipos del virus del papiloma humano (VPH) causan papilomatosis respiratoria recurrente. Se presenta tanto en niños como adultos. También se llama PRR.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-04-26</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
