<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792754">
  <TermName>barium-meal photofluorography</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BAYR-ee-um … FOH-toh-floor-AH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that uses x-rays to take a series of pictures of the esophagus, stomach, and duodenum (the first part of the small intestine). The x-ray pictures are taken after the patient drinks a liquid that contains barium (a silver-white metallic compound). The barium coats and outlines the inner walls of the esophagus, stomach, and duodenum so they can be seen on the x-ray pictures. Photographs are then taken of the x-ray images and made into a short film to make the organs easier to see. This makes it possible to see the motion of the organs and exposes the patient to less radiation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795189" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;barium-meal photofluorography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795190" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fotofluorografía con bario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>fotofluorografía con bario</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se toma una serie de radiografías del esófago, el estómago y el duodeno (la primera parte del intestino delgado). Las radiografías se toman después de que el paciente bebe un líquido que contiene bario (compuesto metálico de color blanco plateado). El bario reviste y resalta el contorno de las paredes internas del esófago, el estómago y el duodeno para que sea posible observarlas en las radiografías. Luego, se toman fotografías de estas radiografías y se convierten en una película corta para que sea más fácil ver los órganos y cómo se mueven. Esto  expone al paciente a menos radiación. También se llama abreugrafía con bario, fluorografía con bario, fluoroscopia con bario y fotofluorografía del transito esofagogastroduodenal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-06-04</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
