<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792760">
  <TermName>TMD</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A bone marrow disorder that can occur in newborns who have Down syndrome. It is marked by abnormal, immature blood-forming cells in the blood and bone marrow (especially the cells involved in making platelets). The liver may also be larger than normal. TMD is caused by mutations (changes) in a gene called GATA1. TMD usually goes away on its own within the first 3 months of life. Sometimes TMD causes severe or life-threatening problems, such as bleeding problems, infection, heart, kidney, and liver failure, and abnormal build-up of fluid in the tissues that cover the organs in the body. Infants who have TMD have an increased risk of developing acute myeloid leukemia (AML) before the age of 3 years. Also called TAM, transient abnormal myelopoiesis, transient leukemia, and transient myeloproliferative disorder.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermName>TMT</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno de la médula ósea que se presenta en recién nacidos con síndrome de Down. Se caracteriza por células hematopoyéticas anormales e inmaduras en la sangre y la médula ósea (en especial, las células que participan en la producción de plaquetas). Es posible que el hígado sea más grande de lo normal. Las mutaciones (cambios) en un gen que se llama GATA1 producen el TMT, que por lo general desaparece de forma espontánea dentro de los 3 primeros meses de vida. A veces, el TMT causa problemas graves que ponen en peligro la vida, como trastornos hemorrágicos, infecciones, insuficiencia cardíaca, renal y hepática, y acumulación anormal de líquido en los tejidos que cubren los órganos del cuerpo. Los lactantes con TMT tienen un aumento de riesgo de presentar leucemia mieloide aguda (LMA) antes de los 3 años. También se llama leucemia transitoria, MAT, mielopoyesis anormal transitoria y trastorno mieloproliferativo transitorio.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-06-04</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
