<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000792992"><TermName>Lupron Depot</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LOO-pron DEE-poh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used under the brand names Eligard and Lupron Depot to treat prostate cancer and under the brand name Lupron Depot to treat problems with the endometrium (lining of the uterus) and uterine fibroids (noncancerous growths of the uterus) . It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Lupron Depot initially causes the pituitary gland to make more luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), temporarily increasing testosterone levels in men and estrogen levels in women. With continued use, Lupron Depot lowers the amount of LH and FSH the pituitary gland releases, leading to a drop in testosterone levels in men and estrogen levels in women.  Lupron Depot may stop the growth of cancer cells that need testosterone to grow and stop the growth of endometrial tissue and uterine fibroids. It is a type of hormone therapy called a gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonist. Also called Eligard and leuprolide acetate.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793623" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Lupron Depot&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793622" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Lupron Depot&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Lupron Depot</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con los nombres comerciales Eligard y Lupron Depot para el tratamiento del cáncer de próstata, y con el nombre comercial Lupron Depot para el tratamiento de los problemas del endometrio (revestimiento del útero) y los fibromas uterinos (tumores no cancerosos en el útero). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. Al principio, Lupron Depot hace que la hipófisis produzca más hormona luteinizante (LH) y hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH), lo que aumenta de forma temporal la concentración de testosterona en los hombres y de estrógeno en las mujeres. Con el uso continuo, reduce la cantidad de LH y FSH que libera la hipófisis, lo que disminuye la concentración de testosterona en los hombres y de estrógeno en las mujeres. Lupron Depot en ocasiones detiene la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan testosterona para su desarrollo, así como el crecimiento del tejido endometrial y los fibromas uterinos. Pertenece a un grupo de medicamentos de terapia hormonal llamados agonistas de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina (GnRH). También se llama acetato de leuprolida y Eligard.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-01-09</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000588951" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/leuprolideacetate">Leuprolide Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
