<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793005"><TermName>stage IIIB melanoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... MEH-luh-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, IIIC, and IIID. In stage IIIB, it is not known where the cancer began or the primary tumor can no longer be seen, and one of the following is true: (1) cancer is found in one lymph node by physical exam or imaging tests; or (2) there are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; OR the tumor is not more than 1 millimeter thick, without ulceration   (a break in the skin), or not more than 2   millimeters thick, without ulceration, and one of the following is true: (1) cancer is found in one to three lymph nodes by physical exam or imaging tests; or (2) there are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; OR the tumor is more than 1 but not more than 2 millimeters thick, with ulceration, or more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, without ulceration, and one of the following is true: (1) cancer is found in one to three lymph nodes; or (2) there are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796134" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIB melanoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796135" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma en estadio IIIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>melanoma en estadio IIIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB, IIIC y IIID. En el estadio IIIB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) No se sabe dónde se formó el cáncer o ya no se ve el tumor primario. Además, ocurre uno de los siguientes casos:
		se encuentra cáncer en 1 ganglio linfático mediante un examen físico o pruebas con  imágenes; se encuentran tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta. 2) El tumor mide no más de 1 mm de grosor y hay ulceración (rotura de la piel); o el tumor  mide no más de 2 mm de grosor y no hay ulceración.  Además, ocurre uno de los siguientes casos:
		se encuentra cáncer en 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos mediante un examen físico o pruebas con imágenes;
		se encuentran tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta. 3) El tumor mide más de 1 mm pero no más de 2 mm de grosor y hay ulceración; o el tumor mide más de 2 mm pero no más de 4 mm de grosor y no hay ulceración. Además, ocurre uno de los siguientes casos:
		se encuentra cáncer en 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos;

se encuentran tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-09-28</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062713" url="/types/skin/patient/melanoma-treatment-pdq">Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256816" url="/espanol/tipos/piel/paciente/tratamiento-melanoma-pdq">Tratamiento del melanoma</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
