<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793008"><TermName>stage IIIC melanoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... MEH-luh-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, IIIC, and IIID. In stage IIIC, it is not known where the cancer began or the primary tumor can no longer be seen. Cancer is found: (1) in two or three  lymph nodes; or (2) in one lymph node and there are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; or (3) in four or more lymph nodes, or in any number of lymph nodes that are matted together; or (4) in two or more lymph nodes and/or in any number of lymph nodes that are matted together. There are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; OR the tumor is not more than 2 millimeters thick, with or without ulceration (a break in the skin), or not more than 4 millimeters thick, without ulceration. Cancer is found: (1) in one lymph node and there are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; or (2) in four or more lymph nodes, or in any number of lymph nodes that are matted together; or (3) in two or more lymph nodes and/or in any number of lymph nodes that are matted together. There are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; OR the tumor is more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration, or more than 4 millimeters thick, without ulceration. Cancer is found in one or more lymph nodes and/or in any number of lymph nodes that are matted together. There may be microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin; OR the tumor is more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration. Cancer is found in one or more lymph nodes and/or there are microsatellite tumors, satellite tumors, and/or in-transit metastases on or under the skin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796139" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIC melanoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796138" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma en estadio IIIC&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>melanoma en estadio IIIC</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB, IIIC y IIID. En el estadio IIIC, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) No se sabe dónde se formó el cáncer o ya no se ve el tumor primario. Se encuentra cáncer en uno de los siguientes sitios: 2 o 3 ganglios linfáticos; 1 ganglio linfático y hay tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta; 4 o más ganglios linfáticos, o en ganglios linfáticos apelmazados; 2 o más ganglios linfáticos, o en una cantidad cualquiera de ganglios linfáticos apelmazados, y hay tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de la piel. 2) El tumor no mide más de 2 mm de grosor y a veces hay ulceración; o el tumor no mide más de 4 mm de grosor y no hay ulceración. Se encuentra cáncer en uno de los siguientes sitios: 1 ganglio linfático y hay tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta; 4 o más ganglios linfáticos, o en una cantidad cualquiera de ganglios linfáticos apelmazados; 2 o más ganglios linfáticos, o en una cantidad cualquiera de ganglios linfáticos apelmazados, y hay tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta. 3) El tumor mide más de 2 mm de grosor pero no más de 4 mm de grosor y hay ulceración, o el tumor mide más de 4 mm de grosor y no hay ulceración. Se encuentra cáncer en 1 o más ganglios linfáticos, o en una cantidad cualquiera de ganglios linfáticos apelmazados. Es posible que haya tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta. 4) El tumor mide más de 4 mm de grosor y hay ulceración. Se encuentra cáncer en 1 o más ganglios linfáticos, y hay tumores microsatélites, tumores satélites o metástasis en tránsito en la piel o debajo de esta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-09-28</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062713" url="/types/skin/patient/melanoma-treatment-pdq">Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256816" url="/espanol/tipos/piel/paciente/tratamiento-melanoma-pdq">Tratamiento del melanoma</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
