<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793177">
  <TermName>HER2</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A protein involved in normal cell growth. HER2 may be made in larger than normal amounts by some types of cancer cells, including breast, ovarian, bladder, pancreatic, stomach, and esophageal cancers. This may cause cancer cells to grow more quickly and spread to other parts of the body. Checking the amount of HER2 on some types of cancer cells may help plan treatment. Also called c-erbB-2, HER2/neu, human EGF receptor 2, and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800966" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HER2&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>HER2</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proteína que participa en el desarrollo normal de las células. Algunos tipos de células cancerosas, como las del cáncer de mama, ovario, vejiga, páncreas, estómago y esófago, producen cantidades anormales del HER2. Es posible que esto haga que las células cancerosas se multipliquen  más rápido y se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo. Medir la cantidad de esta proteína en algunos tipos de células cancerosas sirve para planificar el tratamiento. También se llama c-erbB-2, HER2/neu, proteína HER2, receptor 2 del EGF humano, receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano y receptor HER2.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-06-26</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-11-02</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/diagnosis/tumor-markers-list" UseWith="en">Tumor Markers in Common Use</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/lista-marcadores-tumorales">Marcadores tumorales más comunes</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
