<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793492">
  <TermName>reversible posterior leukoencephalopathy syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ree-VER-sih-bul pos-TEER-ee-er LOO-koh-en-SEH-fuh-LAH-puh-thee SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare condition marked by headaches, vision problems, mental changes, seizures, and swelling in the brain. The symptoms of reversible posterior leukoencephalopathy syndrome usually come on quickly and can be serious and life threatening. When treated, symptoms often go away within days or weeks. Reversible posterior leukoencephalopathy syndrome may occur in patients with certain conditions, such as high blood pressure, eclampsia, severe infection, kidney disease, and certain autoimmune diseases. It may also occur in patients treated with certain anticancer drugs and immunosuppressive drugs. Also called posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome, PRES, and RPLS.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795175" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;reversible posterior leukoencephalopathy syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795176" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de leucoencefalopatía posterior reversible&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de leucoencefalopatía posterior reversible</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente que se caracteriza por dolores de cabeza, problemas de visión, cambios en el nivel de conciencia, convulsiones e inflamación del encéfalo.  En general, los síntomas aparecen   pronto, y pueden ser graves y mortales. Si estos se tratan, suelen desaparecer en pocos días o semanas. El síndrome de leucoencefalopatía reversible posterior se presenta en pacientes con ciertas afecciones como hipertensión, eclampsia, infecciones graves, enfermedad del riñón y determinadas enfermedades autoinmunitarias. También se presenta en pacientes que se trataron con ciertos medicamentos contra el cáncer y medicamentos inmunodepresores. También se llama PRES, síndrome de encefalopatía posterior reversible y SLPR.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-07-02</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
