<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793707">
  <TermName>stage III adult soft tissue sarcoma of the retroperitoneum</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… uh-DULT ... TIH-shoo sar-KOH-muh ... REH-troh-PAYR-ih-toh-NEE-um)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters but not larger than 10 centimeters and is mid grade or high grade.  Mid-grade and high-grade cancer cells look more abnormal under a microscope and grow and spread more quickly than low-grade cancer cells.  In stage IIIB, the tumor is (1) larger than 10 centimeters and is mid grade or high grade; or (2) any size, any grade, and has spread to nearby lymph nodes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795243" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III adult soft tissue sarcoma of the retroperitoneum&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000795242" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma de tejido blando del retroperitoneo en estadio III en adultos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sarcoma de tejido blando del retroperitoneo en estadio III en adultos</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor mide más de 5 cm, pero  no más de 10 cm y es de grado intermedio o alto. Las células cancerosas de grado intermedio o alto se ven más anormales cuando se observan al microscopio; además, se multiplican y   diseminan más rápido que las células cancerosas de grado bajo. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor: 1) mide más de 10 cm y es de grado intermedio o alto; o 2) es de cualquier tamaño y cualquier grado, y se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-06-25</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258102" url="/types/soft-tissue-sarcoma/patient/adult-soft-tissue-treatment-pdq">Soft Tissue Sarcoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000520407" url="/espanol/tipos/sarcoma-de-tejido-blando/paciente/tratamiento-tejido-blando-adultos-pdq">Tratamiento del sarcoma de tejido blando</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
