<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793857"><TermName>PRCC</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of kidney cancer that forms in the lining of the tiny tubes in the kidney that return filtered substances that the body needs back to the blood and remove extra fluid and waste as urine. Most papillary tumors look like long, thin finger-like growths under a microscope. There are two types of PRCC: type 1 and type 2. Type 1 tends to grow slowly and spread to other parts of the body less often than type 2. Patients with a genetic disorder called hereditary papillary renal cancer have an increased risk of type 1 PRCC. Patients with a genetic disorder called hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer have an increased risk of type 2 PRCC. Also called papillary kidney cancer and papillary renal cell carcinoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000793771" type="image/jpeg" alt="Papillary renal cancer; drawing showing the left kidney, renal pelvis, and ureter. Also shown is a pullout of the renal tubules, which is where urine is made." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Papillary renal cancer forms in cells that line the renal tubules in the kidney. The renal tubules remove waste from the blood and make urine. Urine moves through the renal tubules into the renal pelvis and ureter, which carries urine from the kidney to the bladder.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799113" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de células renales papilar. En la imagen se observan el riñón izquierdo, la pelvis renal y el uréter. En una ampliación, también se muestran los túbulos renales que producen la orina." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">El cáncer de células renales papilar se forma en las células que revisten los túbulos renales. Los túbulos renales eliminan los desechos de la sangre y producen orina. La orina pasa por los túbulos renales a la pelvis renal, y luego por el uréter, que transporta la orina desde el riñón hasta la vejiga.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>CCRP</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer de riñón que se forma en las células que revisten los tubos diminutos que filtran la sangre en los riñones, de donde extraen el exceso de líquido y desechos para evacuarlos por la orina, mientras devuelven a la sangre las sustancias filtradas que el cuerpo necesita. Cuando se observan al microscopio, la mayoría de los tumores papilares se ven como bultos largos y delgados con forma de dedo. Hay dos tipos de CCRP: tipo 1 y tipo 2. El tipo 1 tiende a crecer despacio y se disemina a otras partes del cuerpo con menos frecuencia que el tipo 2. Los pacientes con un trastorno genético que se llama cáncer renal papilar hereditario tienen más riesgo de presentar CCRP de tipo 1. Los pacientes con un trastorno genético que se llama leiomiomatosis hereditaria y cáncer de células renales tienen más riesgo de presentar CCRP de tipo 2. También se llama cáncer de riñón papilar, carcinoma de células renales papilar y PRCC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-07-19</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/9572/papillary-renal-cell-carcinoma">Papillary renal cell carcinoma (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
