<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793870"><TermName>Braftovi</TermName><TermPronunciation>(braf-TOH-vee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with cetuximab to treat certain types of colorectal cancer and with binimetinib to treat certain types of melanoma and non-small cell lung cancer.  It is used in patients whose cancer has a certain mutation (change) in the <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> gene. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Braftovi blocks certain proteins made by the mutated <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> gene, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of kinase inhibitor. Also called encorafenib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000795170" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Braftovi&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000795169" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Braftovi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Braftovi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con cetuximab para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer colorrectal. Además, se utiliza con  binimetinib para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de melanoma y cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas. Se emplea en pacientes cuyo cáncer tiene determinada mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Braftovi bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan del gen <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> mutado, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas. También se llama encorafenib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-07-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-10-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000793919" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/encorafenib">Encorafenib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
