<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000793852">
  <TermName>hereditary papillary renal carcinoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee PA-pih-LAYR-ee REE-nul KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that increases the risk of a type of kidney cancer called type 1 papillary kidney cancer. This cancer forms in cells that line the small tubes in the kidney that filter waste from the blood and make urine. Hereditary papillary renal carcinoma often affects both kidneys, and often there is more than one tumor in each kidney. It is caused by mutations (changes) in a gene called MET. Hereditary papillary renal carcinoma is a type of hereditary cancer syndrome. Also called hereditary papillary renal cancer and HPRC.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796222" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary papillary renal carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796223" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma renal papilar hereditario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000793771" type="image/jpeg" alt="Papillary renal cancer; drawing showing the left kidney, renal pelvis, and ureter. Also shown is a pullout of the renal tubules, which is where urine is made." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Papillary renal cancer forms in cells that line the renal tubules in the kidney. The renal tubules remove waste from the blood and make urine. Urine moves through the renal tubules into the renal pelvis and ureter, which carries urine from the kidney to the bladder.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799113" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de células renales papilar. En la imagen se observan el riñón izquierdo, la pelvis renal y el uréter. En una ampliación, también se muestran los túbulos renales que producen la orina." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El cáncer de células renales papilar se forma en las células que revisten los túbulos renales. Los túbulos renales eliminan los desechos de la sangre y producen orina. La orina pasa por los túbulos renales a la pelvis renal, y luego por el uréter, que transporta la orina desde el riñón hasta la vejiga.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>carcinoma renal papilar hereditario</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Afección hereditaria rara que aumenta el riesgo de un tipo de cáncer de riñón llamado cáncer de riñón papilar de tipo 1.  Este cáncer se forma en las células que revisten los pequeños tubos del riñón que filtran los desechos de la sangre y elaboran la orina. El carcinoma renal papilar hereditario a menudo afecta ambos riñones y, con frecuencia, hay más de un tumor en cada riñón. La causa de esta afección son mutaciones (cambios) en un gen que se llama 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
      . El carcinoma renal papilar hereditario es un tipo de síndrome de cáncer hereditario. También se llama cáncer renal papilar hereditario, carcinoma hereditario papilar de células renales y HPRC.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-07-19</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-08-15</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/9572/papillary-renal-cell-carcinoma">Papillary renal cell carcinoma (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
