<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794087"><TermName>PML gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene that makes a protein that helps control cell growth and cell division. Mutations (changes) in the  PML gene can occur when a piece of the chromosome containing the PML gene breaks off and joins with a gene called <GeneName>RARA</GeneName> on another chromosome. These changes may cause too many immature white blood cells to build up in the blood and bone marrow. This can lead to an aggressive (fast-growing) type of acute myeloid leukemia called acute promyelocytic leukemia. The  PML gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene. Also called promyelocytic leukemia gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796190" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;PML gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen PML&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen PML</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una proteína que ayuda a controlar la división y la multiplicación de las células. A veces se producen mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>PML</GeneName> cuando una parte del cromosoma que contiene este gen se separa y se une a un gen llamado <GeneName>RARA</GeneName> en otro cromosoma. En ocasiones, estos cambios hacen que se acumulen demasiados glóbulos blancos inmaduros en la sangre y la médula ósea. Es posible que esto cause una forma de leucemia mieloide aguda de crecimiento rápido (agresiva) llamada leucemia promielocítica aguda. El gen <GeneName>PML</GeneName> es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores. También se llama gen de la leucemia promielocítica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-08-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-12-02</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
