<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794098"><TermName>amniotic fluid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AM-nee-AH-tik FLOO-id)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The clear or slightly yellow fluid that surrounds and protects an unborn baby as it grows during pregnancy. Amniotic fluid cushions the baby and helps keep the temperature in the womb constant. It also helps the growing baby’s lungs, digestive system, and bones develop properly. Amniotic fluid contains some of the baby’s cells and other substances. Samples of amniotic fluid may be taken to check the health of the baby and to test for genetic changes that may be a sign of a genetic disease or condition. Amniotic fluid also may be used to learn the sex of the baby.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796207" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;amniotic fluid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796206" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;líquido amniótico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>líquido amniótico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Líquido claro o amarillento que rodea y protege al feto a medida que crece durante el embarazo. El líquido amniótico hace de colchón para el bebé y ayuda a mantener constante la temperatura en el útero. También ayuda a que los pulmones, el sistema digestivo y los huesos del bebé en crecimiento se desarrollen de forma adecuada. El líquido amniótico contiene algunas de las células del bebé y otras sustancias. Se pueden tomar muestras de líquido amniótico para verificar la salud del bebé y para detectar cambios genéticos que a veces son un signo de una enfermedad o afección genética. El líquido amniótico además se usa para conocer el sexo del bebé.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-08-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
