<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794090">
  <TermName>RARA gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that makes a protein that controls the activity of certain genes that help white blood cells mature. Mutations (changes) in the RARA gene can occur when a piece of the chromosome containing the RARA gene breaks off and joins with a gene called 
      <GeneName>PML</GeneName>
       on another chromosome. These changes may cause too many immature white blood cells to build up in the blood and bone marrow. This can lead to an aggressive (fast-growing) type of acute myeloid leukemia called acute promyelocytic leukemia. The protein made by the RARA gene  is a type of transcription factor. Also called retinoic acid receptor alpha gene.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796196" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;RARA gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796197" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen RARA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen RARA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que da origen a una proteína que controla la actividad de ciertos genes que ayudan a madurar los glóbulos blancos. A veces se producen mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>RARA</GeneName>
       cuando una parte del cromosoma que contiene este gen se separa y se une a un gen llamado 
      <GeneName>PML</GeneName>
       en otro cromosoma. En ocasiones, estos cambios hacen que se acumulen demasiados glóbulos blancos inmaduros en la sangre y la médula ósea. Es posible que esto cause una forma de leucemia mieloide aguda muy maligna (de crecimiento rápido) llamada leucemia promielocítica aguda. La proteína que se origina del gen 
      <GeneName>RARA</GeneName>
       es un tipo de factor de transcripción. También se llama gen del receptor alfa del ácido retinoico.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-08-17</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-12-07</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
