<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794108"><TermName>genetic counselor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(jeh-NEH-tik KOWN-seh-ler)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A health professional who has special training in medical genetics and counseling. Genetic counselors help patients and families who have, or who may be at risk of, a genetic condition. They help patients find out their chances of having a genetic condition or of having a child or other family member with a genetic condition. They also help patients understand their options for genetic testing, including its risks and benefits. After genetic testing is done, genetic counselors help patients understand their genetic test results, including how the results can affect other family members, and provide counseling and support.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796195" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genetic counselor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796194" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;asesor genético&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>asesor genético</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Profesional de la salud que tiene capacitación especial en genética médica y asesoramiento. Las personas que se dedican a esta profesión ayudan a los pacientes y las familias que tienen una afección genética o que están en riesgo de tenerla. Ayudan a los pacientes a descubrir sus probabilidades de tener una afección genética, o de tener un hijo u otro miembro de la familia con una afección genética. Su orientación también sirve para que los pacientes entiendan sus opciones para someterse a pruebas genéticas, incluso sus riesgos y beneficios. Después de que se realizan las pruebas genéticas, explican a los pacientes los resultados de las pruebas y el modo en que pueden afectar a otros miembros de la familia; asimismo, brindan orientación y apoyo. También se llama consejero genético.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-08-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/risk-assessment-pdq" UseWith="en">Cancer Genetics Risk Assessment and Counseling (Health Professional Version)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/evaluacion-del-riesgo-pdq">Evaluación del riesgo de cáncer y asesoramiento genético (Versión para pofesionales de la salud)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
