<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794101"><TermName>von Hippel-Lindau gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(von HIH-pul-LIN-dow jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene that makes  a protein that helps control cell growth, cell division, and other important cell functions. Mutated (changed) forms of the von Hippel-Lindau gene may increase the growth of cells, including abnormal cells. This mutated gene has been found in nearly all patients with an inherited condition called VHL syndrome. VHL syndrome can cause kidney cancer and tumors of the brain, spinal cord, eye, ear, adrenal glands, pancreas, or other parts of the body. The von Hippel-Lindau gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene. Also called VHL gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796210" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;von Hippel-Lindau gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796211" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen de Von Hippel-Lindau&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen de Von Hippel-Lindau</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una proteína que ayuda a controlar la división y la multiplicación de las células, así como otras funciones celulares importantes. Es posible que las formas mutadas (cambiadas) del gen de Von Hippel-Lindau aumenten la multiplicación de las células, incluso células anormales. Se ha encontrado este gen mutado en casi todos los pacientes con una afección hereditaria llamada síndrome de VHL. El síndrome de VHL a veces causa cáncer de riñón y tumores en el encéfalo, la médula espinal, el ojo, el oído, la glándula suprarrenal, el páncreas u otras partes del cuerpo. El gen de Von Hippel-Lindau es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores. También se llama gen VHL.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-08-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-12-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000797087" url="/types/kidney/patient/kidney-genetics-pdq">Hereditary Kidney Cancer Syndromes</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000808250" url="/espanol/tipos/rinon/paciente/genetica-de-rinon-pdq">Síndromes hereditarios de cáncer de riñón</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
