<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794274">
  <TermName>mogamulizumab</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(moh-GAM-yoo-LIH-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with mycosis fungoides or Sezary syndrome (types of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma) that came back or did not get better after treatment with at least one systemic therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Mogamulizumab binds to a protein called CCR4, which is found on some T cells (a type of white blood cell) and some types of lymphoma cells. Mogamulizumab may block this protein and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Poteligeo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796125" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mogamulizumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796124" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mogamulizumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mogamulizumab</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con micosis fungoide o síndrome de Sézary (tipos de linfoma cutáneo de células T) que volvió o no mejoró después de recibir por lo menos una terapia sistémica. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El mogamulizumab se une a una proteína llamada CCR4, que se encuentra en algunas células T (tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunos tipos de células de linfoma. Es posible que el mogamulizumab bloquee esta proteína y ayude a que el sistema inmunitario destruya las células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Poteligeo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-08-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-08-20</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000794283" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/mogamulizumabkpkc">Mogamulizumab-kpkc</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
