<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794381"><TermName>folliculin gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fuh-LIH-kyoo-lin jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene that makes a protein that may help control cell growth and other important cell functions. Mutated (changed) forms of the folliculin gene may increase the growth of abnormal cells. The mutated folliculin gene  has been found in an inherited condition called Birt-Hogg-Dube syndrome (BHDS). Patients with BHDS have an increased risk of kidney cancer and tumors of the skin and lungs. The folliculin gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene. Also called FLCN gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796106" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;folliculin gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000796107" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen de la foliculina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen de la foliculina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una proteína que quizás ayude a controlar la multiplicación de las células y otras funciones celulares importantes. Las formas mutadas (cambiadas) del gen de la foliculina a veces aumentan la multiplicación de células anormales. Se ha encontrado el gen de la foliculina mutado en pacientes con una afección hereditaria llamada síndrome de Birt-Hogg-Dube (BHDS). Los pacientes con BHDS tienen un mayor riesgo de cáncer de riñón y tumores en la piel y los pulmones. El gen de la foliculina es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores. También se llama gen FLCN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-11-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-12-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000797087" url="/types/kidney/patient/kidney-genetics-pdq">Hereditary Kidney Cancer Syndromes</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000808250" url="/espanol/tipos/rinon/paciente/genetica-de-rinon-pdq">Síndromes hereditarios de cáncer de riñón</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
