<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794367">
  <TermName>Grade Group</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(grayd groop)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A way of describing prostate cancer based on how abnormal the cancer cells in a biopsy sample look under a microscope and how quickly they are likely to grow and spread. It is based on the Gleason score, which is another type of prostate cancer grading system. Grade Group scores range from 1 to 5. The lower the Grade Group score, the more the cancer cells look like normal cells and are likely to grow and spread slowly. The Grade Group system is used to help plan treatment and determine prognosis (outcome).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796229" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Grade Group&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796228" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grupo de grado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>grupo de grado</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma de describir el cáncer de próstata según qué tan anormales se ven al microscopio las células cancerosas de una muestra de biopsia y qué tan probable es que se multipliquen y diseminen rápido. Se basa en el puntaje de Gleason, que es otro tipo de sistema de clasificación del cáncer de próstata. Los puntajes del grupo de grado van de 1 a 5. Cuanto más bajo es el puntaje del grupo de grado, más se parecen las células cancerosas a las células normales y es probable que se multipliquen y diseminen lento. El sistema de grupos de grado se usa para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento y determinar el pronóstico (desenlace). También se llama grupo de grado pronóstico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-11-08</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000045696" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">Gleason score</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000045696" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">puntaje de Gleason</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
