<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794375">
  <TermName>hormonal contraception</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(hor-MOH-nul KON-truh-SEP-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of birth control that uses hormones to prevent pregnancy. Hormonal contraceptives contain estrogen and progesterone, or progesterone only. They prevent pregnancy by blocking the release of eggs from the ovaries, thinning the lining of the uterus, or thickening the mucus in the cervix to help keep sperm from reaching the egg. Hormonal contraceptives may be taken by mouth, injected or inserted under the skin, placed on the skin as a patch, or placed in the vagina or uterus.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796096" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hormonal contraception&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796097" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anticoncepción hormonal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>anticoncepción hormonal</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de planificación familiar para la que se utilizan hormonas que previenen el embarazo. Los anticonceptivos hormonales contienen progesterona sola o una combinación de progesterona y estrógeno. Evitan el embarazo al impedir que los ovarios liberen óvulos, además adelgazan el revestimiento del útero y espesan el moco del cuello uterino de manera que bloquean el paso de los espermatozoides hacia el óvulo. Los anticonceptivos hormonales se administran por la boca, en inyección, o se colocan  debajo de la piel, sobre la piel (parche), en la vagina o en el útero. También se llama contracepción hormonal y contraconcepción hormonal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-11-08</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/hormones/oral-contraceptives-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Oral Contraceptives and Cancer Risk</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/hormonas/hoja-informativa-pildoras-anticonceptivas">Píldoras anticonceptivas y el riesgo de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
