<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794378">
  <TermName>fumarate hydratase gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FYOO-muh-rayt HY-druh-tays jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A gene that makes an enzyme that helps cells in the body use oxygen and make energy.  Mutated (changed) forms of the fumarate hydratase gene may cause cells to lose the ability to use oxygen. This may increase the growth of some cells, including abnormal cells and cancer cells. The mutated fumarate hydratase gene has been found in an inherited condition called hereditary leiomyomatosis and renal cell cancer (HLRCC). Patients with HLRCC have an increased risk of kidney cancer and tumors in the skin and uterus. Also called FH gene.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796157" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fumarate hydratase gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796156" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen de la fumarato–hidratasa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen de la fumarato–hidratasa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una enzima que ayuda a las células del cuerpo a usar oxígeno y producir energía. Es posible que las formas mutadas (cambiadas) del gen de la fumarato–hidratasa hagan que las células pierdan la capacidad de usar el oxígeno. Esto a veces aumenta la multiplicación de algunas células, incluso células anormales y células cancerosas. Se ha encontrado el gen de la fumarato–hidratasa mutado en una afección hereditaria llamada leiomiomatosis hereditaria y cáncer de células renales (HLRCC). Los pacientes con HLRCC tienen un mayor riesgo de cáncer de riñón y tumores en la piel y el útero. También se llama gen FH.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-11-08</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-12-02</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000797087" url="/types/kidney/patient/kidney-genetics-pdq">Hereditary Kidney Cancer Syndromes</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000808250" url="/espanol/tipos/rinon/paciente/genetica-de-rinon-pdq">Síndromes hereditarios de cáncer de riñón</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
