<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794425">
  <TermName>MET gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that makes a protein that is involved in sending signals within cells and in cell growth and survival. Mutated (changed) forms of the 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       gene may cause abnormal cells to grow and spread in the body. Mutations in the 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       gene have been found in an inherited condition called hereditary papillary renal carcinoma (HPRC). Patients with HPRC have an increased risk of a type of kidney cancer called papillary renal carcinoma. 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       gene mutations have also been found in liver cancer and head and neck cancer. The 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       gene is a type of proto-oncogene and a type of receptor tyrosine kinase gene.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796158" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;MET gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796159" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen MET&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen MET</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que da origen a una proteína que participa en el envío de señales dentro de las células, y en la multiplicación y supervivencia celulares. Es posible que las formas mutadas (cambiadas) del gen 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       estimulen la multiplicación y diseminación de células anormales por el cuerpo. Se han encontrado mutaciones en el gen 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       en una afección hereditaria que se llama carcinoma renal papilar hereditario (CRPH). Los pacientes con CRPH tienen un mayor riesgo de un tipo de cáncer de riñón llamado carcinoma renal papilar. También se han encontrado mutaciones en el gen 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       en el cáncer de hígado y el cáncer de cabeza y cuello. El gen 
      <GeneName>MET</GeneName>
       es un tipo de protooncogén y de gen de receptor de  tirosina–cinasas.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-11-08</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-12-02</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
