<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794882">
  <TermName>Nijmegen breakage syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(NY-may-gen BRAY-kij SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare inherited disorder marked by a small head, height that is shorter than normal, unusual facial features, and other growth and developmental problems. People with Nijmegen breakage syndrome have a weakened immune system, which may cause them to have frequent sinus, lung, and other respiratory tract infections. They are also at an increased risk of developing certain types of cancer, especially non-Hodgkin lymphoma, rhabdomyosarcoma (a type of soft tissue tumor), and brain cancer. Nijmegen breakage syndrome is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called 
      <GeneName>NBN</GeneName>
      , which is involved in DNA repair. It is a type of DNA repair deficiency syndrome and a type of autosomal recessive genetic disease.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797245" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Nijmegen breakage syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797246" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de rotura de Nijmegen&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802195" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an autosomal recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their four children: an unaffected father (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene on a chromosome pair; an unaffected mother (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter with two normal genes; an unaffected son (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; and an affected son with two mutated genes." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Autosomal recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child. A genetic condition can occur when the child inherits one copy of a mutated (changed) gene from each parent. The parents of a child with an autosomal recessive condition usually do not have the condition. Unaffected parents are called carriers because they each carry one copy of the mutated gene and can pass it to their children.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802815" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia autosómica recesiva en una familia conformada por padre, madre y cuatro hijos: se muestran un par de cromosomas con un gen mutado y un gen normal en el padre no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en la madre no afectada (portadora); dos genes normales en una hija no afectada; un gen mutado y un gen normal en un hijo no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en una hija no afectada (portadora) y dos genes mutados en un hijo afectado." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">La herencia autosómica recesiva es una de las formas en que un rasgo o una afección genética pasa de padres a hijos. El niño presenta la afección genética cuando hereda dos copias de un gen mutado (cambiado), una del padre y otra de la madre. Por lo general, la madre y el padre no presentan la afección que se hereda de manera autosómica recesiva. Se dice que la madre y el padre no afectados son portadores porque cada uno tiene una copia del gen mutado que puede pasar a sus hijos. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de rotura de Nijmegen</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario raro que se caracteriza por una cabeza pequeña, estatura menor que la normal, rasgos faciales atípicos y otros problemas de crecimiento y desarrollo. Las personas con síndrome de rotura de Nijmegen tienen un sistema inmunitario debilitado, lo que a veces conlleva infecciones respiratorias frecuentes en los senos paranasales, los pulmones y otras partes del aparato respiratorio. También tienen más riesgo de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer; en particular, linfoma no Hodgkin, rabdomiosarcoma (tipo de tumor de tejido blando) y cáncer de encéfalo. El síndrome de rotura de Nijmegen lo causa una mutación (cambio) en un gen llamado 
      <GeneName>NBN</GeneName>
      , que participa en la reparación del ADN. Es un síndrome de deficiencia de la reparación del ADN y un tipo de enfermedad genética autosómica recesiva. También se llama síndrome de rotura de Nimega y síndrome de ruptura de Nijmegen.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-12-31</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/3904/nijmegen-breakage-syndrome">Nijmegen breakage syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/nijmegen-breakage-syndrome/">Nijmegen breakage syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
