<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794884"><TermName>DNA repair deficiency syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… reh-PAYR deh-FIH-shun-see SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of inherited disorder caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes involved in DNA repair. Changes in these genes can cause breaks, rearrangements, and other problems in the DNA. There are many different types of DNA repair deficiency syndromes. Most of these syndromes are marked by growth and developmental problems, premature aging, and disorders of the skin and nervous system. Having a DNA repair deficiency syndrome may increase a person’s risk of certain types of cancer. Also called DNA repair disorder.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797247" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;DNA repair deficiency syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797248" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de deficiencia en la reparación del ADN&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de deficiencia en la reparación del ADN</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de trastorno heredado causado por mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que participan en la reparación del ADN. Los cambios en estos genes producen roturas, reordenamientos y otros problemas en el ADN. Hay muchos tipos diferentes de síndromes de deficiencia en la reparación del ADN. La mayoría de estos trastornos se caracterizan por producir problemas de crecimiento y desarrollo, envejecimiento prematuro, y alteraciones en la piel y el sistema nervioso. Es posible que un síndrome de deficiencia en la reparación del ADN aumente el riesgo de una persona de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer. También se llama trastorno en la reparación del ADN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-12-31</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
