<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000794888"><TermName>cancer predisposing gene mutation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAN-ser PREE-dih-SPOH-zing jeen myoo-TAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe mutations (changes) in certain genes that may increase a person’s risk of some types of cancer. For example, a person who has certain mutations in the BRCA1 or BRCA2 gene has higher than normal risks of developing breast cancer and ovarian cancer. Cancer predisposing gene mutations are usually inherited (passed from parent to child) and may be seen within families. Knowing if a person has a cancer predisposing gene mutation may help prevent, diagnose, and treat cancer. Not all people who have a cancer predisposing gene mutation will develop cancer. Also called cancer susceptibility gene mutation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797254" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cancer predisposing gene mutation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797253" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mutación en gen de predisposición al cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mutación en gen de predisposición al cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término utilizado para describir mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que quizás aumenten el riesgo de una persona de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer. Por ejemplo, una persona con ciertas mutaciones en los genes BRCA1 o BRCA2 tiene mayor riesgo que lo normal de presentar cáncer de mama y cáncer de ovario. Por lo general, las mutaciones en genes de predisposición al cáncer se heredan (pasan de padres a hijos) y es posible que se observen en varios miembros de la misma familia. A veces, saber que una persona tiene una mutación en un gen de predisposición al cáncer ayuda a prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar el cáncer. No todas las personas con estas mutaciones  presentarán cáncer. También se llama mutación en gen de susceptibilidad al cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-12-31</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
