<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000795346">
  <TermName>Talzenna</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(tal-ZEH-nuh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used alone to treat adults with HER2-negative breast cancer that has spread and has certain mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName>
       or 
      <GeneName>BRCA2</GeneName>
       gene and with enzalutamide to treat adults with prostate cancer that has spread, has not responded to treatments that lower testosterone levels, and has a mutation in the 
      <GeneName>HRR</GeneName>
       gene. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Talzenna blocks an enzyme involved in many cell functions, including the repair of DNA damage. Blocking this enzyme may help keep cancer cells from repairing their damaged DNA, causing them to die. Talzenna is a type of PARP inhibitor. Also called talazoparib tosylate.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796149" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Talzenna&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000796148" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Talzenna&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Talzenna</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa en monoterapia (solo) para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de mama negativo para HER2 que se diseminó y tiene ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en los genes 
      <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName>
       o 
      <GeneName>BRCA2</GeneName>
      . También se usa con enzalutamida para tratar a adultos con cáncer de próstata que se diseminó, no respondió a los tratamientos que disminuyen las concentraciones de testosterona y presenta una mutación en el gen 
      <GeneName>HRR</GeneName>
      . Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Talzenna bloquea una enzima que participa en muchas funciones celulares, entre ellas, la reparación del daño al ADN. Bloquear esta enzima quizás ayude a evitar que las células cancerosas reparen el daño a su ADN y esto las destruya. Talzenna es un tipo de inhibidor   de PARP. También se llama tosilato de talazoparib.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-10-18</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-06-22</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000795372" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/talazoparibtosylate">Talazoparib Tosylate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
