<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000795806"><TermName>emapalumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EH-muh-PAL-yoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat a rare immune system disorder called primary hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis (HLH). It is used in patients whose disease came back, got worse, did not get better, or cannot be treated with other therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions. Emapalumab binds to an immune system protein called interferon gamma, which is found at higher than normal levels in patients with HLH. This may help lower the body’s immune response and reduce inflammation. Emapalumab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Gamifant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797277" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;emapalumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797276" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;emapalumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>emapalumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de un trastorno raro del sistema inmunitario llamado linfohistiocitosis hemofagocítica (LHH) primaria. También se usa en pacientes cuya enfermedad volvió, empeoró, no mejoró o que no pueden recibir otro tratamiento. Además está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones. El emapalumab se une a una proteína del sistema inmunitario llamada interferón gamma, que se encuentra en concentraciones más altas que las normales en los pacientes de LHH. Es posible que esto disminuya la respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo y reduzca la inflamación. El emapalumab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Gamifant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-12-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-08-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000796664" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/emapalumab-lzsg">Emapalumab-lzsg</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
