<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000796476">
  <TermName>Elzonris</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(el-ZON-ris)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults and children aged 2 years and older with a rare blood cancer called blastic plasmacytoid dendritic cell neoplasm. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Elzonris is made up of interleukin-3 (IL-3), which binds to an IL-3 receptor protein called CD123. CD123 may be found in higher than normal amounts on some types of cancer cells. Elzonris is also made up of a diphtheria toxin, which may help kill cancer cells. Elzonris is a type of cytotoxin. Also called tagraxofusp.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797307" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Elzonris&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797306" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Elzonris&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Elzonris</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos y niños de 2 años o más con un cáncer de sangre raro llamado neoplasia de células dendríticas plasmocitoides blásticas. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Elzonris contiene interleucina 3 (IL-3) y se une a un receptor proteico de la IL-3 llamado CD123, que se encuentra en cantidades más altas que lo normal en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Elzonris también contiene una toxina diftérica y es posible que ayude a destruir células cancerosas. Elzonris es un tipo de citotoxina. También se llama tagraxofusp.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2018-12-31</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-02-12</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000796460" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tagraxofusp-erzs">Tagraxofusp-erzs</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
