<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000796472"><TermName>ravulizumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RAV-yoo-LIZ-yoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (a rare red blood cell disorder) and adults and children aged 1 month and older with  atypical hemolytic uremic syndrome (a very rare disorder in which tiny blood clots form in small blood vessels). It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions. Ravulizumab binds to an immune system protein called C5. This may help keep red blood cells from breaking down and blood clots from forming. Ravulizumab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Ultomiris.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797301" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ravulizumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797300" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ravulizumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ravulizumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de los adultos con hemoglobinuria paroxística nocturna (trastorno raro de los glóbulos rojos) y además se utiliza en adultos y niños de 1 año   o más con síndrome hemolítico urémico atípico (trastorno muy raro por el que se forman coágulos de sangre diminutos en los vasos sanguíneos pequeños). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones. El ravulizumab se une a una proteína del sistema inmunitario llamada C5, y es posible que esto impida la destrucción de los glóbulos rojos y la formación de coágulos. El ravulizumab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Ultomiris.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2018-12-31</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-08-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000796461" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ravulizumab-cwvz">Ravulizumab-cwvz</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
