<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000796822"><TermName>CD30 protein</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PROH-teen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A protein found on some T cells and B cells (two types of white blood cells). It is a receptor for a protein called tumor necrosis factor, which is involved in cell growth and cell survival. The CD30 protein may be found in higher than normal amounts on some types of cancer cells, including lymphoma cells. Knowing how much CD30 protein is on a patient’s cancer cells may help diagnose cancer and plan treatment. The CD30 protein is a type of tumor necrosis factor receptor and a type of tumor marker.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797981" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CD30 protein&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797982" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proteína CD30&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>proteína CD30</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proteína que se encuentra en algunas células T y células B (dos tipos de glóbulos blancos). Es un receptor de una proteína llamada factor de necrosis tumoral, que participa en  la multiplicación y  la supervivencia celular. La proteína CD30 se encuentra en cantidades más altas de lo normal en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, como en las células de un linfoma. Saber qué cantidad de proteína CD30 hay en las células cancerosas de un paciente quizás ayude a diagnosticar un cáncer y planificar el tratamiento. La proteína CD30 es un tipo de marcador tumoral y de receptor del factor de necrosis tumoral.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-04-09</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/diagnosis/tumor-markers-list" UseWith="en">Tumor Markers in Common Use</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/lista-marcadores-tumorales">Marcadores tumorales más comunes</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
