<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000796875"><TermName>epidermal growth factor receptor gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-pih-DER-mul grothe FAK-ter reh-SEP-ter jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene that makes a protein that is involved in cell growth and cell survival. Mutated (changed) forms of the epidermal growth factor receptor gene and protein have been found in some types of cancer, including non-small cell lung cancer. These changes may cause cancer cells to grow and spread in the body. Checking for changes in the epidermal growth factor receptor gene in tumor tissue may help plan cancer treatment. Also called EGFR gene, ERBB1 gene, and HER1 gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798018" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermal growth factor receptor gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798025" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen del receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen del receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una proteína que participa en la multiplicación y supervivencia celular. Se han encontrado formas mutadas (cambiadas) del   gen del receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico y de su proteína en algunos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas. Es posible que estos cambios hagan que las células cancerosas se multipliquen y se diseminen por el cuerpo. Saber si el tejido tumoral  tiene cambios en el gen del receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico quizás ayude a planificar el tratamiento del cáncer. También se llama gen EGFR, gen ERBB1 y gen HER1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-12-02</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
