<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000796814">
  <TermName>TRK protein family</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… PROH-teen FA-mih-lee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A family of proteins that are found on nerve cells. They are involved in cell signaling pathways that control cell growth, cell maturation, and cell survival. The genes that make the TRK proteins may have mutations (changes) that cause abnormal TRK proteins to be made. These abnormal proteins may be too active or found in higher than normal amounts on some types of cancer cells, which may cause cancer cells to grow. Drugs that block TRK proteins are being used in the treatment of some types of cancer. TRK proteins are receptor tyrosine kinases. Also called tropomyosin receptor kinase protein family.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797972" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;TRK protein family&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000797971" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;familia de proteínas TRK&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>familia de proteínas TRK</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Familia de proteínas de las células nerviosas. Participan en las vías de señalización celular que controlan la multiplicación, maduración y supervivencia de las células. A veces, los genes que producen las proteínas TRK tienen mutaciones (cambios) que hacen que se produzcan proteínas TRK  anormales que son muy activas o se encuentran en concentraciones más altas que lo normal en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, lo que estimula su multiplicación. Se usan medicamentos que bloquean las proteínas TRK para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Las proteínas TRK son tipos de receptores tirosina–cinasa. También se llama familia de proteínas cinasas receptoras relacionadas con la tropomiosina.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-04-09</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
