<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797094"><TermName>adoptive cell transfer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-DOP-tiv sel TRANZ-fer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of immunotherapy in which T cells (a type of immune cell) are given to a patient to help the body fight diseases, such as cancer. In cancer therapy, T cells are usually taken from the patient's own blood or tumor tissue, grown in large numbers in the laboratory, and then given back to the patient to help the immune system fight the cancer. Sometimes, the T cells are changed in the laboratory to make them better able to target the patient's cancer cells and kill them. Types of adoptive cell transfer include chimeric antigen receptor T-cell (CAR T-cell) therapy and tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte (TIL) therapy. Adoptive cell transfer that uses T cells from a donor is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer and some infections. Also called adoptive cell therapy, cellular adoptive immunotherapy, and T-cell transfer therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797993" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adoptive cell transfer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000797992" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;transferencia celular adoptiva&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><EmbeddedVideo id="_3" ref="CDR0000795517" hosting="youtube" unique_id="kfi-2fPp4dE" language="en" audience="Patients" template="Video75NoTitle"><VideoTitle>T-Cell Transfer Therapy</VideoTitle><Caption language="en">Immunotherapy uses the body’s immune system to fight cancer. This animation explains one type of immunotherapy called T-cell transfer therapy that is used to treat cancer.</Caption></EmbeddedVideo><EmbeddedVideo id="_4" ref="CDR0000795597" hosting="youtube" unique_id="Dr92cKtrghM" language="es" audience="Patients" template="Video75NoTitle"><VideoTitle>T-Cell Transfer Therapy-Spanish</VideoTitle><Caption language="es">La inmunoterapia usa el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo para combatir el cáncer. En este video se describe un tipo de inmunoterapia para tratar el cáncer que se llama terapia de transferencia de células T.</Caption></EmbeddedVideo><SpanishTermName>transferencia celular adoptiva</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de inmunoterapia en la que se administran células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria) al paciente para ayudarle a combatir enfermedades como el cáncer. Durante el tratamiento de un cáncer, se extraen células T de la sangre o el tejido tumoral del paciente, se produce una gran cantidad de copias de estas células en el laboratorio y se devuelven al paciente para ayudar al sistema inmunitario a combatir el cáncer. En ocasiones, las células T se modifican en el laboratorio para mejorar su capacidad de dirigirse a las células cancerosas del paciente y destruirlas. Los tipos de transferencia celular adoptiva incluyen la terapia de células T con receptor de antígeno quimérico (terapia de células T con CAR) y la terapia con linfocitos infiltrantes tumorales (LIT). La transferencia celular adoptiva con células T de un donante está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer y algunas infecciones. También se llama inmunoterapia celular adoptiva, terapia celular adoptiva y terapia de transferencia de células T.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-03-04</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-03-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/immunotherapy/t-cell-transfer-therapy">T-cell Transfer Therapy</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/inmunoterapia/terapia-transferencia-de-celulas-t">Terapia de transferencia de células T</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
