<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797058"><TermName>bucket trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BUH-ket TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of clinical trial that tests how well a new drug or other substance works in patients who have different types of cancer that all have the same mutation or biomarker. In bucket trials, patients all receive the same treatment that targets the specific mutation or biomarker found in their cancer. Bucket trials may allow new drugs to be tested and approved more quickly than traditional clinical trials. Bucket trials may also be useful for studying rare cancers and cancers with rare genetic changes. Also called basket trial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798831" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bucket trial&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798830" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ensayo en canasta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ensayo en canasta</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de ensayo clínico en el que se prueba la eficacia de nuevos medicamentos u otras sustancias en pacientes que tienen distintos tipos de cáncer pero presentan la misma mutación  (cambio) en los genes o el mismo biomarcador. Para los ensayos en canasta, se administra el mismo tratamiento dirigido en forma específica a la mutación o el biomarcador que se detectó en el cáncer. Mediante este tipo de ensayo, es posible hacer pruebas y obtener la aprobación de medicamentos nuevos más rápido que a través de los ensayos clínicos tradicionales. Los ensayos en canasta tal vez sirvan también para estudiar cánceres poco comunes y cánceres con cambios genéticos poco frecuentes. También se llama ensayo en cesta y estudio en canasta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-27</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
