<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797072">
  <TermName>risk model</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… MAH-dul)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, a tool used to estimate a person’s risk of developing a certain condition or disease, such as cancer. Risk models may also be used to estimate a person’s risk of carrying a certain gene change or of having a child with a certain condition. Risk models use computer programs and statistics to estimate risk based on information about a person that may include their age, sex, personal and family medical history, ethnic background, lifestyle, and other factors. There are many types of risk models, and each model looks at different factors that increase risk in different groups of people.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798844" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;risk model&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798845" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;modelo de riesgo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>modelo de riesgo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el ámbito de la medicina, herramienta que se usa para calcular el riesgo de una persona de presentar una afección o enfermedad, como el cáncer. Los modelos de riesgo también sirven para estimar el riesgo de ser portador de un cambio en un gen o de tener un hijo o hija con cierta afección. Mediante el uso de programas de computación y estadística, se calcula el riesgo a partir de información como la edad, el sexo, los antecedentes médicos personales y familiares, el origen étnico, el estilo de vida y otros factores. Hay muchos tipos de modelos de riesgo, en cada modelo se analizan diversos factores que aumentan el riesgo de distintos grupos de personas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
