<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797033"><TermName>panic disorder</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PA-nik dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of anxiety
          disorder in which a person has repeated panic attacks when
          there is no actual danger. Panic attacks are sudden periods
          of intense anxiety or fear that may cause irrational
          thoughts or actions. During a panic attack, a person may
          experience chest pain, trouble breathing, a fast heartbeat,
          sweating, shaking, dizziness, and feelings of impending
          doom or being out of control. Panic attacks may last for
          several minutes or longer. People with a panic disorder
          often worry that the panic attacks will happen again and
          try to avoid places or situations in which they have
          occurred.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798880" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;panic disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798881" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno de pánico&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>trastorno de pánico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de trastorno de ansiedad por el que la persona tiene crisis de pánico o angustia que se repiten, cuando no hay un peligro verdadero. Las crisis de pánico son períodos de ansiedad o miedo intensos y de inicio brusco que a veces producen pensamientos 
          o acciones irracionales. Durante una crisis de pánico, la persona puede presentar dolor en el tórax,  dificultad para respirar, latidos cardíacos rápidos, sudoración, temblor, mareo y sensación de peligro inminente o de pérdida de control. Por lo general, estas crisis duran varios minutos o más. Con frecuencia, a las personas con este trastorno les preocupa que las crisis de pánico se repitan  y tratan de evitar los lugares o las situaciones en los que estas ocurrieron. También se llama trastorno de angustia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000269124" url="/about-cancer/coping/feelings/anxiety-distress-pdq">Adjustment to Cancer: Anxiety and Distress</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000269587" url="/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/sentimientos/ansiedad-sufrimiento-pdq">Adaptación al cáncer: ansiedad y sufrimiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
