<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797085">
  <TermName>Schedule I drug</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SKEH-jool …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug or other substance that has a high chance of being abused or causing addiction and has no FDA-approved medical use in the United States. Schedule I drugs are tightly regulated by the federal government. Examples of Schedule I drugs are heroin, LSD, and ecstasy. Although marijuana (Cannabis) is classified as a Schedule I drug by the federal government, some states have passed laws that allow the medical and recreational use of marijuana. Also called Schedule I controlled substance.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798850" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Schedule I drug&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798851" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;droga de clasificación I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>droga de clasificación I</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Droga u otra sustancia que presenta una probabilidad alta de abuso o adicción, y que no posee aprobación de la FDA para uso médico en los Estados Unidos. El Gobierno federal regula de forma estricta las drogas de clasificación I. Algunos ejemplos son la heroína, la lisergida (LSD) y el éxtasis. Aunque el Gobierno federal incluye a la marihuana (
      <Emphasis>Cannabis</Emphasis>
      ) como droga de clasificación I, algunos estados han aprobado leyes que permiten su uso recreativo y medicinal. También se llama droga de abuso de clasificación I, estupefaciente de clasificación I y sustancia controlada de clasificación I.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
