<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797043"><TermName>porphyria cutanea tarda</TermName><TermPronunciation>(por-FEER-ee-uh kyoo-TAY-nee-uh TAR-duh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare disorder that affects the skin and causes painful blisters on parts of the body that are exposed to the sun, usually the hands, arms, and face. The affected skin may be fragile, and it may blister or peel after a minor injury. Other signs and symptoms of porphyria cutanea tarda include changes in skin color, increased hair growth (especially on the face), and redness, swelling, itching, scarring, and thickening of the affected skin. Liver problems may occur, and patients with porphyria cutanea tarda may have an increased risk of liver cancer. In porphyria cutanea tarda, the body does not make enough of an enzyme called uroporphyrinogen decarboxylase. Porphyria cutanea tarda may be inherited, or it may be caused by too much iron in the body, certain infections (such as hepatitis C or HIV infection), smoking, drinking too much alcohol, taking the hormone estrogen, and certain genetic disorders. Porphyria cutanea tarda is usually diagnosed after the age of 30 years. Also called PCT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798892" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;porphyria cutanea tarda&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798893" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;porfiria cutánea tardía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>porfiria cutánea tardía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno raro que afecta la piel y produce ampollas dolorosas en las partes del cuerpo expuestas al sol, como las manos, los brazos y la cara. La piel afectada es delicada y se ampolla o se desprende después de una herida insignificante. Otros signos y síntomas son cambios en el color de la piel, aumento en la cantidad de pelo (en especial en la cara), además de enrojecimiento, hinchazón, picazón, cicatrización  y engrosamiento de la piel afectada. Es posible que los pacientes con porfiria cutánea tardía tengan problemas hepáticos que aumentan el riesgo de cáncer de hígado. Las personas con esta afección no producen suficiente cantidad de una enzima llamada uroporfirinógeno–descarboxilasa. La porfiria cutánea tardía a veces se hereda y otras veces se produce debido a un exceso de hierro en la sangre, ciertas infecciones (hepatitis C o VIH), el tabaquismo, el consumo excesivo de bebidas alcohólicas, el uso de la hormona estrógeno y algunos trastornos genéticos. La porfiria cutánea tardía suele diagnosticarse después de los 30 años de edad. También se llama PCT, porfiria cutánea tarda y porfiria hepatocutánea tardía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7433/porphyria-cutanea-tarda">Porphyria cutanea tarda (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/porphyria/">Porphyria (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001208.htm">Porfiria (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
