<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797068"><TermName>GBS</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare condition in which the body’s immune system attacks the nerves located outside the brain and spinal cord. Symptoms of GBS include muscle weakness, muscle pain, numbness, and tingling that often begin in the legs or back and may spread to the arms, upper body, and face. Other symptoms may include problems with vision, speech, swallowing, digestion, and bladder control. GBS can get worse quickly and cause paralysis and other serious or life-threatening problems, such as breathing problems and an abnormal blood pressure or heart rate. Most people with GBS get better over time. GBS is a type of autoimmune disease. Also called Guillain-Barré syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>SGB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección rara por la que el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo ataca los nervios fuera del encéfalo y la médula espinal. Los síntomas son debilidad muscular, dolor muscular, entumecimiento y hormigueo que suelen comenzar en las piernas o la espalda y pasan a los brazos, la parte superior del tronco y la cara. Otros síntomas son problemas para ver, hablar, tragar, digerir y controlar la vejiga. Es posible que el SGB empeore rápido y produzca parálisis y otras afecciones potencialmente mortales, como dificultad respiratoria y anormalidades de la presión arterial o el ritmo cardíaco. La mayoría de las personas con esta afección mejoran después de un tiempo. El SGB es un tipo de enfermedad autoinmunitaria. También se llama síndrome de Guillain-Barré.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6554/guillain-barr-syndrome">Guillain-Barre syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/guillain-barre-syndrome/">Guillain-Barré syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12899/sindrome-de-guillain-barre">Síndrome de Guillain-Barré (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/guillainbarresyndrome.html">Síndrome de Guillain-Barré (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
