<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797037"><TermName>hereditary hemochromatosis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee HEE-moh-kroh-muh-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited condition in which too much iron builds up in the body. The extra iron is stored in the body’s tissues and organs, especially the liver, heart, pancreas, skin, and joints. This can cause liver disease, heart problems, diabetes, and organ failure. Symptoms include changes in skin color, pain in the joints and abdomen, fatigue, and loss of sex drive. Patients with hereditary hemochromatosis also have an increased risk of liver cancer. There are five types of hereditary hemochromatosis. Each type is caused by changes in different genes. Symptoms for each type typically begin at different ages. Type 1 hemochromatosis is one of the most common genetic disorders in the United States.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798884" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary hemochromatosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798885" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hemocromatosis hereditaria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>hemocromatosis hereditaria</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección hereditaria por la que se acumula demasiado hierro en el cuerpo. El exceso de hierro se almacena en los tejidos y órganos del cuerpo, sobre todo en el hígado, el corazón, el páncreas, la piel y las articulaciones. Esto puede causar enfermedad hepática, problemas cardíacos, diabetes e insuficiencia de órganos. Los síntomas incluyen cambios en el color de la piel, dolor en las articulaciones y el abdomen, fatiga y pérdida del deseo sexual. Los pacientes con hemocromatosis hereditaria también tienen un aumento del riesgo de cáncer de hígado. Hay cinco tipos de hemocromatosis hereditaria causados por cambios en diferentes genes. Los síntomas de cada tipo suelen aparecer a edades diferentes. La hemocromatosis de tipo 1 es uno de los trastornos genéticos más frecuentes en los Estados Unidos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/hereditary-hemochromatosis/">Hereditary hemochromatosis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10746/hemochromatosis">Hemochromatosis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/13195/hemocromatosis">Hemocromatosis (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/hemochromatosis.html">Hemocromatosis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
