<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797031">
  <TermName>anxiety disorder</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ang-ZY-eh-tee dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which a person has excessive worry and feelings of fear, dread, and uneasiness. Other symptoms may include sweating, restlessness, irritability, fatigue, poor concentration, trouble sleeping, trouble breathing, a fast heartbeat, and dizziness. The symptoms can get worse over time and affect a person’s day-to-day life. Anxiety disorders may be caused by a medical problem, a traumatic or stressful event, certain medicines, or other factors. There are many types of anxiety disorders, including generalized anxiety disorder, social anxiety disorder, panic disorder, post-traumatic stress disorder, and phobia-related disorders.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798878" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anxiety disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798879" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno de ansiedad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>trastorno de ansiedad</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que una persona tiene preocupación y sentimientos de miedo, terror o intranquilidad excesivos. Otros síntomas son sudoración, inquietud, irritabilidad, fatiga, falta de concentración, problemas para dormir, dificultad para respirar, latidos cardíacos rápidos y mareo. A veces los síntomas empeoran con el tiempo y afectan la vida diaria de la persona. Es posible que un problema médico, un  hecho traumático o estresante, ciertos medicamentos u otros factores provoquen un trastorno de ansiedad. Hay muchos tipos de trastornos de ansiedad, como el trastorno de ansiedad generalizada, el trastorno de ansiedad social, el trastorno de pánico (trastorno de angustia), el trastorno por estrés postraumático y las fobias.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000269124" url="/about-cancer/coping/feelings/anxiety-distress-pdq">Adjustment to Cancer: Anxiety and Distress</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000269587" url="/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/sentimientos/ansiedad-sufrimiento-pdq">Adaptación al cáncer: ansiedad y sufrimiento</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
