<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797028"><TermName>acquired thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-KWY-erd throm-BAH-tik THROM-boh-sy-toh-PEE-nik PUR-pyoo-ruh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare condition in which blood clots form in small blood vessels throughout the body. These clots can block the flow of blood and oxygen to the body’s organs, which leads to a lower-than-normal number of platelets in the blood. Signs and symptoms of acquired thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura include purple bruises or tiny red or purple spots on the skin, bleeding problems, anemia, fever, chest pain, nervous system problems, and kidney problems. acquired thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura occurs when the body starts producing antibodies that block an enzyme called ADAMTS13, which is involved in blood clotting. It may be brought on by certain diseases or conditions (such as pregnancy, cancer, lupus, HIV, or other infections), certain medicines (such as chemotherapy or hormone therapy), or certain procedures (such as surgery or a stem cell transplant). acquired thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura usually occurs in adults. Also called aTTP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798876" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acquired thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798877" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;púrpura trombocitopénica trombótica adquirida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>púrpura trombocitopénica trombótica adquirida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que se forman coágulos en los vasos sanguíneos pequeños del cuerpo entero. Es posible que estos coágulos bloqueen el flujo de sangre y oxígeno a los órganos del cuerpo y que esto disminuya la cantidad de plaquetas que hay en la sangre. Los signos y síntomas de la púrpura trombocitopénica trombótica adquirida son los  moretones púrpuras, las pequeñas manchas rojas o púrpuras en la piel, el sangrado, la anemia, la fiebre, el dolor de tórax, los problemas del sistema nervioso y los problemas de riñón. La púrpura trombocitopénica trombótica adquirida ocurre cuando el cuerpo comienza a producir anticuerpos contra una enzima llamada ADAMTS13, que participa en la coagulación sanguínea. A veces aparece debido a determinadas situaciones o enfermedades (como el embarazo, el cáncer, el lupus, la infección por el VIH o infecciones de otro tipo), ciertos medicamentos (como los que se administran durante la quimioterapia o la terapia con hormonas), o algunos procedimientos (como una cirugía o un trasplante de células madre). Por lo general, esta enfermedad se presenta en adultos. También se llama PTTa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
