<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797047"><TermName>AAT deficiency</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… deh-FIH-shun-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited condition in which the body either does not make enough of a protein called alpha-1 antitrypsin (AAT) or makes an abnormal form of AAT. AAT is made in the liver and helps protect the body’s organs, especially the liver and lungs, from damage. AAT deficiency can lead to serious lung conditions (including emphysema and bronchiectasis) and liver conditions (including cirrhosis, hepatitis, and liver cancer). It may also cause inflammation of the blood vessels and a rare skin condition that causes painful lumps on or under the skin. Lung problems caused by AAT deficiency almost always occur in adults, but liver and skin problems may occur in both adults and children. AAT deficiency is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called SERPINA1. Also called alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798897" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;AAT deficiency&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798896" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deficiencia de AAT&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>deficiencia de AAT</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección hereditaria por la que el cuerpo no produce suficiente proteína alfa-1 antitripsina (AAT) o produce una forma anormal de dicha  proteína. La AAT se produce en el hígado, y su función es evitar daños en los órganos del cuerpo, en especial, el hígado y los pulmones. Es posible que la deficiencia de AAT conduzca a trastornos pulmonares graves (como el enfisema y las bronquiectasias) y trastornos hepáticos (como la cirrosis, la hepatitis y el cáncer de hígado). En ocasiones, también causa inflamación de los vasos sanguíneos y una afección rara en la que aparecen bultos dolorosos en la piel o debajo de esta. Las afecciones pulmonares suelen presentarse en adultos,  mientras que las afecciones del hígado y la piel  se presentan en adultos y niños. La  causa de la deficiencia de AAT es una mutación (cambio) en el gen <GeneName>SERPINA1</GeneName>. También se llama deficiencia de alfa-1-antitripsina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/5784/alpha-1-antitrypsin-deficiency">Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/alpha-1-antitrypsin-deficiency/">Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/12870/deficiencia-de-alfa-1-antitripsina">Deficiencia de alfa-1 antitripsina (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000120.htm">Deficiencia de alfa-1 antitripsina (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
