<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797041"><TermName>hepatolenticular degeneration</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-PA-toh-len-TIH-kyoo-ler dee-JEH-neh-RAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which too much copper builds up in the body. The extra copper is stored in the body’s tissues and organs, especially in the liver, brain, and eyes. This can cause liver disease, central nervous system (brain and spinal cord) problems, and mental problems. Signs and symptoms of hepatolenticular degeneration include yellowing of the skin and the whites of the eyes, a gold or brown ring around the colored part of the eyes, swelling in the abdomen and legs, fatigue, loss of appetite, problems with speech and swallowing, uncontrolled movements or muscle stiffness, anxiety, depression, and mood swings. Hepatolenticular degeneration is caused by mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>ATP7B</GeneName> gene. It is a genetic disorder that is inherited in an autosomal recessive manner and is usually diagnosed in teens and young adults. It is a type of copper storage disease. Also called Wilson disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798890" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hepatolenticular degeneration&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798891" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;degeneración hepatolenticular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802195" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an autosomal recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their four children: an unaffected father (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene on a chromosome pair; an unaffected mother (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter with two normal genes; an unaffected son (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; and an affected son with two mutated genes." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Autosomal recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child. A genetic condition can occur when the child inherits one copy of a mutated (changed) gene from each parent. The parents of a child with an autosomal recessive condition usually do not have the condition. Unaffected parents are called carriers because they each carry one copy of the mutated gene and can pass it to their children.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802815" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia autosómica recesiva en una familia conformada por padre, madre y cuatro hijos: se muestran un par de cromosomas con un gen mutado y un gen normal en el padre no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en la madre no afectada (portadora); dos genes normales en una hija no afectada; un gen mutado y un gen normal en un hijo no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en una hija no afectada (portadora) y dos genes mutados en un hijo afectado." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">La herencia autosómica recesiva es una de las formas en que un rasgo o una afección genética pasa de padres a hijos. El niño presenta la afección genética cuando hereda dos copias de un gen mutado (cambiado), una del padre y otra de la madre. Por lo general, la madre y el padre no presentan la afección que se hereda de manera autosómica recesiva. Se dice que la madre y el padre no afectados son portadores porque cada uno tiene una copia del gen mutado que puede pasar a sus hijos. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>degeneración hepatolenticular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se acumula demasiado cobre en el cuerpo. El exceso de cobre se almacena en los tejidos y órganos, en especial, el hígado, el encéfalo y los ojos. Es posible que esto cause enfermedad del hígado, problemas del sistema nervioso central (encéfalo y médula espinal) y trastornos mentales. Los signos y síntomas de la degeneración hepatolenticular son color amarillento en la piel y la parte blanca del ojo, un anillo marrón o dorado que rodea la parte de color del ojo, distensión del abdomen, hinchazón de las piernas, fatiga, pérdida de apetito, problemas para hablar y tragar, movimientos descontrolados o rigidez muscular, ansiedad, depresión e inestabilidad emocional. La causa de la degeneración hepatolenticular son mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>ATP7B</GeneName>. Es un trastorno genético de herencia autosómica recesiva que suele diagnosticarse en adolescentes y adultos jóvenes. Es un tipo de enfermedad por almacenamiento de cobre. También se llama enfermedad de Wilson.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-05-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7893/wilson-disease">Wilson disease (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/wilson-disease/">Wilson disease (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/wilsondisease.html">Enfermedad de Wilson (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000339339" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">autosomal recessive inheritance</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000339339" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">herencia autosómica recesiva</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
