<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797377">
  <TermName>differentiation syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(DIH-feh-REN-shee-AY-shun SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A serious side effect that may occur in patients with acute promyelocytic leukemia or other types of acute myeloid leukemia who have been treated with certain types of anticancer drugs. Differentiation syndrome usually occurs within 1 to 2 weeks after starting treatment, but it can occur later. It is caused by a large, rapid release of cytokines (immune substances) from leukemia cells that are affected by the anticancer drugs. Signs and symptoms of differentiation syndrome include fever; cough; trouble breathing; weight gain; swelling of the arms, legs, and neck; build-up of excess fluid around the heart and lungs; low blood pressure; and kidney failure. Differentiation syndrome can be life-threatening if not treated early.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799564" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;differentiation syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799565" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de diferenciación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de diferenciación</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Efecto secundario grave que a veces presentan los pacientes de leucemia promielocítica aguda u otros tipos de leucemias mieloides agudas cuando se tratan con ciertos tipos de medicamentos contra el cáncer. A menudo el síndrome de diferenciación ocurre durante las primeras dos semanas después de iniciar el tratamiento, pero se puede presentar más tarde. Los medicamentos contra el cáncer afectan las células leucémicas y se liberan muy rápido cantidades grandes de citocinas (sustancias inmunitarias) que causan el  síndrome de diferenciación. Los signos y síntomas son fiebre; tos; problemas para respirar; aumento de peso; hinchazón de los brazos, las piernas o el cuello; acumulación de líquido alrededor del corazón y los pulmones; presión sanguínea baja e insuficiencia de los riñones. Si no se trata rápido el síndrome de diferenciación es potencialmente mortal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-07-24</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
