<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797379">
  <TermName>sarcopenia</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SAR-koh-PEE-nee-uh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition characterized by loss of muscle mass, strength, and function in older adults. Signs and symptoms include weakness, fatigue, loss of energy, balance problems, and trouble walking and standing. Muscle loss or weakness can lead to falls, broken bones, and other serious injuries and can affect a person's ability to care for oneself. Older age, getting little or no exercise, and poor nutrition may increase the risk of sarcopenia. Sarcopenia may also occur in people with cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799567" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcopenia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799566" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcopenia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sarcopenia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección que se caracteriza por la pérdida de masa muscular, fuerza y funcionamiento de los músculos en los adultos mayores. Los signos y síntomas incluyen debilidad, cansancio o fatiga, falta de energía, problemas de equilibrio y dificultades para caminar y mantenerse de pie. La pérdida de masa muscular o la debilidad en ocasiones provocan caídas, rotura de huesos y otras lesiones graves que afectan  la capacidad de la persona para cuidar de sí misma. La edad avanzada, hacer muy poco o nada de ejercicio y una nutrición inadecuada  aumentan el riesgo de sarcopenia. Las personas con cáncer también pueden presentan sarcopenia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-07-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/appetite-loss/nutrition-hp-pdq" UseWith="en">Nutrition in Cancer Care (Health Professional Version)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/perdida-apetito/nutricion-pro-pdq">La nutrición en el tratamiento del cáncer (Versión para profesionales de salud)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
