<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797587"><TermName>radiation recall</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RAY-dee-AY-shun REE-kawl)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inflammatory reaction that can occur when certain anticancer drugs are given after radiation therapy. It usually affects the part of the body that received radiation, especially the skin. It can also affect the lungs, mouth, larynx, esophagus, other parts of the digestive tract, muscles, and the brain. On the skin, radiation recall may look like a severe sunburn and may blister, peel, and become red, swollen, and painful. If other areas of the body are affected, signs and symptoms will vary depending on the site of the radiation. Radiation recall can occur weeks, months, or years after radiation therapy has ended.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799522" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiation recall&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799523" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;reacción de recuerdo de la radiación&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/><SpanishTermName>reacción de recuerdo de la radiación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Reacción inflamatoria que se puede presentar cuando ciertos medicamentos contra el cáncer se administran después de la radioterapia. A menudo afecta la parte del cuerpo que recibió la radiación, en especial, la piel. En ocasiones también afecta los pulmones, la boca, la laringe, el esófago, otras partes del tubo digestivo, los músculos y el encéfalo. En la piel, la reacción de recuerdo de la radiación se parece a una quemadura solar grave y a veces se producen ampollas, desprendimiento de la piel, enrojecimiento, hinchazón y dolor. Cuando hay compromiso de otras partes del cuerpo, los signos y síntomas varían de acuerdo con el sitio que recibió la radiación. La reacción de recuerdo de la radiación a veces se presenta semanas, meses o años después de terminar la radioterapia. También se llama fenómeno de evocación de la radiación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
