<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797584">
  <TermName>cytokine storm</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SY-toh-kine …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A severe immune reaction in which the body releases too many cytokines into the blood too quickly. Cytokines play an important role in normal immune responses, but having a large amount of them released in the body all at once can be harmful. A cytokine storm can occur as a result of an infection, autoimmune condition, or other disease. It may also occur after treatment with some types of immunotherapy. Signs and symptoms include high fever, inflammation (redness and swelling), and severe fatigue and nausea. Sometimes, a cytokine storm may be severe or life threatening and lead to multiple organ failure. Also called hypercytokinemia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799516" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cytokine storm&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799517" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tormenta de citocinas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tormenta de citocinas</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Reacción inmunitaria grave por la que el cuerpo libera muy rápido demasiadas citocinas en la sangre. Las citocinas cumplen una función importante en las respuestas inmunitarias normales, pero son dañinas cuando el cuerpo produce de una vez cantidades grandes de citocinas. La tormenta de citocinas puede ser consecuencia de una infección, una afección autoinmunitaria u otra afección. A veces también ocurre después del tratamiento con algunos tipos de inmunoterapia. Los signos y síntomas incluyen fiebre alta, inflamación (enrojecimiento e hinchazón), cansancio intenso y náuseas. Algunas veces, la   tormenta de citocinas es grave o pone en  peligro la vida y quizás cause falla de múltiples órganos. También se llama hipercitocinemia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
