<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797633"><TermName>uveitis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(YOO-vee-I-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare condition in which all or part of the uvea (middle layer of the wall of the eye) becomes inflamed. The uvea includes the choroid, the ciliary body, and the iris. Uveitis may also affect the lens, retina, optic nerve, and vitreous humor (the gel-like fluid inside the eye). It may be caused by an injury, infection, a tumor in the eye, or an autoimmune or inflammatory condition. One or both eyes may be affected. The signs and symptoms may occur suddenly and get worse quickly. They include redness and pain in the eye, sensitivity to light, blurred vision, dark floating spots in the vision, and vision loss. If not treated, uveitis can lead to tissue scarring and blindness.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799511" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;uveitis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799510" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;uveítis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000543553" type="image/jpeg" alt="Eye anatomy; two-panel drawing showing the outside and inside of the eye. The top panel shows the outside of the eye, including the eyelid, pupil, sclera, and iris. The bottom panel shows the inside of the eye, including the cornea, lens, ciliary body, retina, choroid, optic nerve, and vitreous humor." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the eye showing the outside and inside of the eye, including the eyelid, pupil, sclera, iris, cornea, lens, ciliary body, retina, choroid, optic nerve, and vitreous humor. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000562257" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del ojo. En la imagen de dos paneles se observa la parte exterior e interior del ojo. En el panel de arriba se muestra el exterior del ojo que incluye el párpado, la pupila, la esclerótica y el iris; en el panel de abajo se muestra el interior del ojo que incluye la córnea, el cristalino, el cuerpo ciliar, la retina, la coroides, el nervio óptico y el humor vítreo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del ojo. En la imagen se observa la parte exterior e interior del ojo que incluye el párpado, la pupila, la esclerótica, el iris, la córnea, el cristalino, el cuerpo ciliar, la retina, la coroides, el humor vítreo y el nervio óptico.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>uveítis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que se inflama una parte de la úvea o toda la úvea (capa intermedia de la pared del ojo) de uno o ambos ojos. La coroides, el cuerpo ciliar y el iris forman la úvea. La uveítis también puede afectar el cristalino, la retina, el nervio óptico y el  humor vítreo (líquido parecido a un gel dentro del ojo). Las causas de esta afección son una lesión, una infección, un tumor en el ojo o una afección autoinmunitaria o inflamatoria. Los signos y síntomas a veces son repentinos y empeoran rápido. Estos incluyen enrojecimiento, dolor en el ojo, hipersensibilidad a la luz, visión borrosa, visión de puntos negros y disminución de la visión. Si no se trata, la uveítis puede producir cicatrización en los tejidos y ceguera.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
