<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797671">
  <TermName>pericardium</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PAYR-ih-KAR-dee-um)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The thin, fluid-filled sac that surrounds the heart, including the top of the heart that is connected to major blood vessels, such as the aorta and vena cava. The pericardium is made up of an outer layer of connective tissue that holds the heart in place within the chest, protects it from inflammation, and acts as a barrier against infection. It also keeps the heart from stretching out and filling up with too much blood. The pericardium is also made up of two thin, inner layers of tissue that have a small amount of fluid in between them. The fluid helps keep the tissues from rubbing against each other as the heart moves within the pericardium.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799610" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pericardium&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799611" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pericardio&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>pericardio</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Saco delgado, lleno de líquido que rodea el corazón, incluso la parte superior que se conecta con los vasos sanguíneos principales, como la aorta y la vena cava. El pericardio está formado por una capa exterior de tejido conjuntivo que mantiene el corazón en su lugar dentro del tórax, lo protege de inflamación y actúa de barrera contra las infecciones. Además, evita que el corazón se estire y se llene de demasiada sangre. El pericardio también está formado por dos capas internas delgadas de tejido que tienen una  cantidad pequeña de líquido entre ellas. El líquido impide que los tejidos rocen entre sí cuando el corazón se mueve dentro del pericardio. También se llama saco pericárdico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-08-22</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
