<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797669">
  <TermName>brain</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(brayn)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The organ inside the head that controls all body functions of a human being. Made up of billions of nerve cells, the brain is protected by the cranium (the bones that form the head). It is made up of three major parts: the cerebrum, the cerebellum, and the brain stem. The cerebrum is the largest part of the brain and controls thinking, learning, problem solving, emotions, memory, speech, reading, writing, and voluntary movement. The cerebellum controls fine motor movement, balance, and posture. The brain stem controls breathing, heart rate, and the nerves and muscles used to see, hear, walk, talk, and eat. The brain stem connects the brain to the spinal cord. The brain and the spinal cord make up the central nervous system.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799608" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;brain&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799609" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;encéfalo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000680399" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of brain anatomy showing the brain stem, pons, medulla, spinal cord, cerebellum, cerebrum, meninges, ventricles (fluid-filled spaces), and skull." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">Anatomy of the brain, showing the cerebrum, cerebellum, brain stem, and other parts of the brain.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000687013" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo de la anatomía del encéfalo que muestra el tronco encefálico, la protuberancia, la médula espinal, el cerebelo, el cerebro, las meninges, los ventrículos (espacios llenos de líquido) y el cráneo." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>encéfalo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Órgano que se encuentra dentro de la cabeza y que controla todas las funciones de un ser humano. El encéfalo está formado por miles de millones de células nerviosas y está protegido por el cráneo (huesos que forman la cabeza). Está compuesto por tres partes principales: el cerebro, el cerebelo y el tronco encefálico. El cerebro es la parte más grande del encéfalo y controla el pensamiento, el aprendizaje, la resolución de problemas, las emociones, la memoria, el habla, la lectura, la escritura y los movimientos voluntarios. El cerebelo controla la motricidad fina, el equilibrio y la postura. El tronco encefálico controla la respiración y la frecuencia cardíaca, así como los nervios y músculos que se usan para ver, oír, caminar, hablar y comer. El tronco encefálico conecta el encéfalo con la médula espinal. El encéfalo y la médula espinal forman el sistema nervioso central.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-08-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2019-08-22</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
