<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797625"><TermName>encephalitis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(en-SEH-fuh-LY-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare condition in which the tissues in the brain become inflamed. Encephalitis is usually caused by a viral infection, but it may also be caused by bacterial or parasitic infections, cancer, or certain drugs or toxins. Signs and symptoms include fever, headache, joint or muscle aches, poor appetite, fatigue, weakness, confusion, changes in behavior, seizures, and problems with vision, speech, or movement. Infants and young children may have nausea, vomiting, body stiffness, feeding problems, and irritability. Most patients have mild symptoms, but sometimes symptoms may be severe or life threatening.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799554" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;encephalitis&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799555" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;encefalitis&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>encefalitis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que se inflaman los tejidos del encéfalo. La causa de la encefalitis a menudo es una infección vírica, pero también  tiene otras causas como bacterias o parásitos, cáncer, ciertos medicamentos o toxinas. Los signos y síntomas incluyen fiebre, dolores de cabeza, dolores en las articulaciones o los músculos, pérdida del apetito, cansancio, debilidad, confusión, cambios de comportamiento, convulsiones y problemas para ver, hablar o moverse. Los bebés y niños pequeños a veces tienen náuseas, vómitos, rigidez del cuerpo, problemas de alimentación e irritabilidad. La mayoría de los pacientes tienen síntomas leves, pero en ocasiones son graves o potencialmente mortales. También se llama cerebritis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
