<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797661"><TermName>pressure ulcer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PREH-sher UL-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Damage to an area of the skin caused by constant pressure on the area for a long time. This pressure can lessen blood flow to the affected area, which may lead to tissue damage and tissue death. Pressure ulcers often form on the skin covering bony areas of the body, such as the back, tailbone, hips, buttocks, elbows, heels, and ankles. Patients who are not able to get out of bed or change their position, or who always use a wheelchair have an increased risk of  pressure ulcers. Signs and symptoms include changes in skin color and swelling, warmth, tenderness, and pain in the affected area. If untreated, the skin may crack, blister, or break open and form a sore or ulcer, which may have pus-like drainage. Pressure ulcers often heal slowly and if not treated can damage tissues deep under the skin, including fat, muscle, and bone. Also called bedsore, decubitus ulcer, and pressure sore.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799594" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pressure ulcer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799595" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;úlcera por presión&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>úlcera por presión</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Lesión de un área de la piel causada por  presión constante durante mucho tiempo. Esta presión disminuye el flujo de sangre al área afectada, lo que produce daño y destrucción del tejido. Las  úlceras por presión a menudo se forman en la piel que cubre áreas  donde los huesos están cerca de la piel, como la espalda, la región del cóccix, las caderas, las nalgas, los codos, los talones y los tobillos. Los pacientes que no se pueden levantar de la cama, que no pueden cambiar de posición o que permanecen en una silla de ruedas tienen un riesgo alto de  úlceras por presión. Los signos y síntomas incluyen cambios en el color de la piel, hinchazón, calor, sensibilidad y dolor en el área afectada. Cuando no se tratan, la piel se agrieta, se ampolla o  se rompe y se forma una llaga o úlcera  que a veces produce un líquido parecido a pus. Las úlceras por presión a menudo sanan muy lento y si no se tratan es posible que dañen los tejidos profundos debajo de la piel, como la grasa, el músculo y  el hueso. También se llama escara de decúbito, escara por presión, úlcera de decúbito y úlcera de presión.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-07-26</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
