<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797635"><TermName>acute paronychia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-KYOOT PAYR-uh-NIH-kee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An infection
          of the soft tissue around a fingernail or toenail that
          begins suddenly and can get worse quickly. It is usually
          caused when bacteria enter through a break in the skin from
          a hangnail or ingrown toenail, by damage to the cuticle
          (skin at the base of the nail), or by an injury to the area
          where the nail and skin meet. Acute paronychia may also
          sometimes be caused by treatment with certain drugs used to
          treat cancer or immune system disorders. Signs and symptoms
          include pain, tenderness, warmth, redness, and swelling
          around the nail. Pus may form in the skin around or under
          the nail. When treated, acute paronychia usually heals
          within 10 days.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799596" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acute paronychia&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799597" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;paroniquia aguda&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>paroniquia aguda</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Infección del tejido blando que rodea una uña de la mano o el pie, que comienza de repente  y empeora rápido. La causa a menudo es una bacteria que entra a través de una abertura de la piel en un uñero (padrastro) o una uña encarnada, por daño en la cutícula (piel de la base de la uña) o 
          por una lesión de la zona donde la uña se une con la piel. A veces, la causa de la paroniquia aguda es el tratamiento con ciertos medicamentos para el cáncer o trastornos inmunitarios. Los signos y síntomas son dolor, sensibilidad, calor, enrojecimiento e hinchazón alrededor de la uña. Es posible que se acumule pus en la piel que rodea la uña o por debajo de la uña. Cuando la paroniquia aguda se trata, por lo general se cura en 10 días. También se llama panadizo y perionixis aguda.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
