<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797627">
  <TermName>myocarditis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MY-oh-kar-DY-tis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare condition in which the heart muscle becomes thick and inflamed and may also become weak. Myocarditis is usually caused by a viral infection, but it may also be caused by bacterial, parasitic, or fungal infections; autoimmune disorders; or being exposed to radiation or certain chemicals or drugs. Signs and symptoms include chest pain, fast or abnormal heartbeat, trouble breathing, fatigue, and swelling of the legs. Other signs and symptoms include fever, headache, body aches, sore throat, and diarrhea. Some patients have mild symptoms or no symptoms at all. Sometimes the symptoms may be severe or life threatening and may lead to heart failure, stroke, or heart attack.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799557" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;myocarditis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799556" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;miocarditis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>miocarditis</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que el músculo del corazón se vuelve grueso, se inflama y a veces también se debilita. La causa de la miocarditis a menudo es una infección vírica, pero también tiene otras causas como bacterias, parásitos y hongos, enfermedades autoinmunitarias, exposición a radiación, ciertas sustancias químicas o medicamentos. Los signos y síntomas son dolor en el tórax, latidos cardiacos rápidos o irregulares, problemas para respirar, cansancio e hinchazón en las piernas. Otros signos y síntomas son fiebre, dolores de cabeza, dolores en el cuerpo, irritación de la garganta y diarrea. Algunos pacientes tienen síntomas leves o no tienen síntomas. En ocasiones los síntomas son graves o potencialmente mortales, y llevan a insuficiencia cardiaca, accidente cerebrovascular o infarto del corazón.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
