<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797794"><TermName>histrelin acetate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(his-TREH-lin A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used under the brand name Vantas as palliative therapy for advanced prostate cancer. Histrelin acetate initially causes the pituitary gland to make more luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), temporarily increasing testosterone levels in men. With continued use, histrelin acetate lowers the amount of LH and FSH the pituitary gland releases, leading to a drop in testosterone levels. Histrelin acetate is also used under the brand name Supprelin LA to treat early puberty in males and females. It is a type of hormone therapy called a luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist and a type of androgen deprivation therapy that is reversible.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799602" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;histrelin acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799603" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetato de histrelina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>acetato de histrelina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con  el nombre comercial  Vantas como terapia paliativa para el cáncer de próstata avanzado. Al principio, el acetato de histrelina hace que la hipófisis produzca más hormona luteinizante (LH) y hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH), lo que aumenta de forma temporal la concentración de testosterona en los hombres. Con el uso continuo, reduce la cantidad de LH y FSH que libera la hipófisis, lo que disminuye la concentración de testosterona. El acetato de histrelina se usa también con el nombre comercial Supprelin LA para tratar la pubertad precoz en niños y niñas. Pertenece a un grupo de medicamentos de terapia hormonal llamados agonistas de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante (LHRH) y es un medicamento usado para la terapia de privación de andrógenos reversible.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-08-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-01-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
