<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797792">
  <TermName>hereditary syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A disorder caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes or chromosomes that are passed down from parent to child. Hereditary syndromes may be inherited from one or both parents, and several close family members (such as a mother, daughter, and sister) may have the same disorder. There are many different types of hereditary syndromes, including those in which family members have a higher-than-normal risk of developing certain types of cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799545" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799544" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome hereditario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome hereditario</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno causado por la presencia de mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes o cromosomas que pasan de padres a hijos. Los síndromes hereditarios se heredan de uno o ambos padres y es posible que varios familiares cercanos (como la madre, la hija y la hermana) tengan el mismo trastorno. Hay muchos tipos de síndromes hereditarios, incluso algunos síndromes que hacen que los miembros de una familia  tengan un riesgo mayor que el normal de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-08-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Genetic Testing for Inherited Cancer Susceptibility Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/risk-assessment-pdq" UseWith="en">Cancer Genetics Risk Assessment and Counseling (Health Professional Version)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas" UseWith="es">Pruebas genéticas para detectar el riesgo de cáncer hereditario</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/evaluacion-del-riesgo-pdq" UseWith="es">Evaluación del riesgo de cáncer y asesoramiento genético (Versión para profesionales de salud)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
