<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000797801"><TermName>androgen receptor blocker</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AN-droh-jen reh-SEP-ter BLAH-ker)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that keeps androgens (male sex hormones) from binding to proteins called androgen receptors, which are found in normal prostate cells, some prostate cancer cells, and in cells of some other tissues. Preventing this binding blocks the effects of these hormones in the body. Treatment with androgen receptor blockers may keep prostate cancer cells from growing. Examples of androgen receptor blockers used to treat prostate cancer are apalutamide, bicalutamide, darolutamide, enzalutamide, flutamide, and nilutamide. Also called androgen receptor antagonist and antiandrogen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799635" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;androgen receptor blocker&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799634" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor del receptor de andrógeno&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor del receptor de andrógeno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que impide que los andrógenos (hormonas masculinas) se unan a proteínas llamadas receptores de andrógenos, que se encuentran en las células normales de la próstata, en algunas células del cáncer de próstata y en las células de otros tejidos. Cuando se impide esta unión, se bloquean los efectos de esas hormonas en el cuerpo. Es posible que el tratamiento con inhibidores del receptor de andrógeno evite la multiplicación de células cancerosas en la próstata. La apalutamida, la bicalutamida, la darolutamida, la enzalutamida, la flutamida y la nilutamida son ejemplos de  inhibidores del receptor de andrógeno que se usan para tratar el cáncer de próstata. También se llama antagonista del receptor de andrógeno, antiandrógeno e inhibidor del receptor androgénico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-08-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-04-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
