<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798365">
  <TermName>alpelisib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AL-peh-LIH-sib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used with fulvestrant to treat postmenopausal women, and men, with hormone-receptor positive, HER2-negative breast cancer that is advanced or has spread and has a mutation (change) in the 
      <GeneName>PIK3CA</GeneName>
       gene. It is used in patients whose cancer got worse during or after treatment with hormone therapy.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Alpelisib blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It is a type of kinase inhibitor. Also called Piqray.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798859" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alpelisib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000798858" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alpelisib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>alpelisib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa con fulvestrant para el tratamiento de hombres y mujeres posmenopáusicas con cáncer de mama positivo para receptores hormonales y negativo para HER2, en estadio avanzado o que se diseminó y que tiene una mutación en el gen 
      <GeneName>PIK3CA</GeneName>
      . Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer empeoró durante el tratamiento hormonal o después de este. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El alpelisib bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas y las destruya. Es un tipo de inhibidor de  cinasas. También se llama Piqray.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-06-03</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-09-28</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000798387" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/alpelisib">Alpelisib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
