<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798457"><TermName>polatuzumab vedotin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(POH-lah-TOO-zoo-mab veh-DOH-tin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs  to treat adults with certain types of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Polatuzumab vedotin contains a monoclonal antibody that binds to a protein called CD79B, which is found on B cells (a type of white blood cell) and some lymphoma cells. It also contains an anticancer drug, which may help kill cancer cells. Polatuzumab vedotin is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called Polivy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798898" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;polatuzumab vedotin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000798899" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;polatuzumab vedotina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>polatuzumab vedotina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos que presentan ciertos tipos de linfoma difuso de células B  grandes. También  está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El polatuzumab vedotina contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal que se une a una proteína llamada CD79B, que se encuentra en las células B (un tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunas células de linfoma. También contiene un fármaco contra el cáncer que quizás ayude a destruir células cancerosas. El polatuzumab vedotina es un tipo de conjugado anticuerpo-fármaco. También se llama Polivy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-06-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-04-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000798438" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/polatuzumabvedotin-piiq">Polatuzumab Vedotin-piiq</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
