<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798598"><TermName>endoscopic mucosal resection</TermName><TermPronunciation>(en-doh-SKAH-pik myoo-KOH-sul ree-SEK-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses an endoscope to remove abnormal growths or tissue from the lining of the digestive tract without open surgery. An endoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing. The endoscope may be passed through the mouth into the esophagus, stomach, or upper part of the small intestine, or it may be passed through the anus into the colon. Special tools are then inserted through the endoscope to remove the abnormal tissue, which will be checked under a microscope for signs of disease. Sometimes suction is used to remove the abnormal tissue, or a solution is injected around the abnormal tissue to separate it from other tissue before it is removed. Endoscopic mucosal resection may be used to help diagnose and treat early-stage cancers of the esophagus, stomach, small intestine, colon, or rectum. It may also be used to treat Barrett esophagus or other precancerous conditions of the digestive tract.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800983" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;endoscopic mucosal resection&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800984" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;resección endoscópica de mucosa&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>resección endoscópica de mucosa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa un endoscopio a fin de extraer bultos o tejidos anormales del revestimiento del tubo digestivo sin necesidad de cirugía abierta. Un endoscopio es un instrumento delgado en forma de tubo, con una luz y una lente para observar. El endoscopio se introduce a través de la boca hasta el esófago, el estómago o la primera parte del intestino delgado, o en otros casos se introduce a través del ano hasta el colon. Luego se introducen a través del endoscopio herramientas especiales a fin de  extirpar el tejido anormal que se observa al microscopio para verificar si hay signos de enfermedad. A veces, se usa succión para extraer el tejido anormal, o se inyecta una solución alrededor del tejido anormal para ayudar a separarlo de otro tejido antes de sacarlo. La resección endoscópica de mucosa se utiliza para el diagnóstico y tratamiento de los cánceres en estadio temprano de esófago, estómago, intestino delgado, colon y recto. También se usa para el tratamiento del esófago de Barrett y otras afecciones precancerosas del tubo digestivo.  También se llama mucosectomía endoscópica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-10-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
