<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798611"><TermName>eructation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eer-ruk-TAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The release of air or gas from the stomach or esophagus through the mouth.  Eructation is usually caused by a buildup of air in the esophagus or upper part of the stomach when too much air is swallowed. This can occur when eating or drinking too fast, talking while eating, drinking carbonated drinks, chewing gum, smoking, or having an anxiety attack. Eructation may also be a side effect of certain medicines or a symptom of some gastrointestinal conditions and digestive problems, such as gastroesophageal reflux disease, gastritis, and stomach ulcers or infections. Also called belching and burping.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800995" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eructation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800996" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eructación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>eructación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Expulsión de aire o gas desde el estómago o esófago a través de la boca. La causa de la eructación a menudo es la acumulación de aire en el esófago o en la parte superior del estómago cuando se traga mucho aire. Es posible que esto ocurra cuando la persona come o bebe muy rápido, habla mientras come, consume bebidas carbonatadas, mastica goma de mascar, fuma o tiene un ataque de ansiedad. La eructación también puede ser un efecto secundario de determinados medicamentos, y a veces es un síntoma de una afección gastrointestinal o de problemas digestivos como la enfermedad por reflujo gastroesofágico, la gastritis, las úlceras en el estómago o las infecciones. También se llama eructo y regüeldo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-10-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
