<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798616">
  <TermName>afib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AY-fib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An irregular heartbeat that occurs when the electrical signals in the atria (the two upper chambers of the heart) fire rapidly at the same time. This causes the heart to beat faster than normal. Although afib can occur without any signs or symptoms, it may sometimes cause fatigue, chest pain, heart palpitations, trouble breathing, low blood pressure, dizziness or fainting, weakness, and other signs and symptoms. Afib may be caused by certain conditions, such as high blood pressure, heart attack, coronary artery disease, abnormal heart valves, congenital heart disease, lung disease, viral infections, or an overactive thyroid gland. Previous heart surgery, stress, or exposure to caffeine, tobacco, alcohol, or certain medicines may also lead to afib. It may go away on its own or it may last for many years. If not treated, afib can lead to serious problems, such as blood clots, stroke, and heart failure. It is more common in older adults. Also called atrial fibrillation.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801003" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;afib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <SpanishTermName>FA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Latido cardiaco irregular que se presenta cuando las señales eléctricas de ambas aurículas (dos cavidades superiores en el corazón) son rápidas y simultáneas. Esto acelera los latidos del corazón de manera anormal. Aunque es posible que la FA se presente sin signos ni síntomas, a veces causa fatiga, dolor torácico, palpitaciones, dificultad para respirar, presión arterial baja, mareos, desmayos, debilidad y otros signos y síntomas. Las causas de la FA son determinadas afecciones, como la hipertensión, el  infarto del miocardio, la enfermedad coronaria, las válvulas cardiacas anormales, las cardiopatías congénitas, la enfermedad pulmonar, las infecciones víricas y la tiroides hiperactiva. Es posible que una cirugía en el corazón, el estrés o la exposición a cafeína, tabaco, alcohol o determinados medicamentos también conduzcan a la FA. En ocasiones desaparece por si sola o puede durar muchos años. Si no se trata, la FA produce problemas graves como coágulos de sangre, accidentes cerebrovasculares e insuficiencia cardiaca. Es más común en los adultos mayores. También se llama fibrilación auricular.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-10-07</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
