<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798760">
  <TermName>prostate cancer antigen 3 mRNA test</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PROS-tayt KAN-ser AN-tih-jen …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A laboratory test that measures the amount of genetic material called PCA3 mRNA and PSA mRNA in the first urine sample after a digital rectal examination. PCA3 mRNA and PSA mRNA are made by normal prostate cells and prostate cancer cells but are made in higher amounts by prostate cancer cells. The PCA3 score is based on the ratio of PCA3 mRNA to PSA mRNA in the urine. A high PCA3 score may be a sign of prostate cancer. The prostate cancer antigen 3 mRNA test may be done in men with a high PSA level whose biopsy of the prostate did not show cancer. The prostate cancer antigen 3 mRNA test is used to help decide if another prostate biopsy may be needed. Also called PCA3 mRNA test.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801012" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prostate cancer antigen 3 mRNA test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801013" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba del ARNm del antígeno 3 del cáncer de próstata&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>prueba del ARNm del antígeno 3 del cáncer de próstata</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio para medir la cantidad del material genético llamado ARNm de PCA3 y ARNm de PSA en la primera muestra de orina después de un examen digital del recto. Las células normales de la próstata  y las células del cáncer de próstata producen ARNm de PCA3 y  ARNm de PSA, pero las células del cáncer de próstata producen más cantidad de este material. El puntaje de PCA3 se basa en el cociente entre el ARNm de PCA3 y el ARNm   de PSA de  la orina. Un puntaje de PCA3 alto quizá sea un signo de cáncer de próstata. A veces la prueba del ARNm del antígeno 3 del cáncer de próstata se hace cuando un hombre tiene una concentración alta de PSA y no se encuentra cáncer en la biopsia de próstata. La prueba del ARNm del antígeno 3 del cáncer de próstata se usa para ayudar a decidir si se necesita otra biopsia de próstata. También se llama prueba del ARNm de PCA3.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-10</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
