<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798779">
  <TermName>MUTYH-associated polyposis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… uh-SOH-see-ay-ted PAH-lee-POH-sis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare, inherited disorder in which multiple polyps (abnormal growths) form on the inner walls of the colon and rectum. People with MUTYH-associated polyposis usually develop fewer than 100 colon polyps, and polyps may also occur in the stomach and small intestine. People with MUTYH-associated polyposis have a high risk of developing colorectal cancer. They may also be at increased risk of developing cancers of the stomach, small intestine, ovary, endometrium, bladder, liver, thyroid, and skin. MUTYH-associated polyposis is caused by mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>MUTYH</GeneName>
       gene that are inherited in an autosomal recessive manner. It is a type of hereditary cancer syndrome.  Also called MAP.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801026" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;MUTYH-associated polyposis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801027" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;poliposis asociada a MUTYH&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802195" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing an autosomal recessive inheritance pattern between a father, mother, and their four children: an unaffected father (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene on a chromosome pair; an unaffected mother (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter with two normal genes; an unaffected son (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; an unaffected daughter (carrier) with a mutated gene and a normal gene; and an affected son with two mutated genes." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Autosomal recessive inheritance is a way a genetic trait or condition can be passed down from parent to child. A genetic condition can occur when the child inherits one copy of a mutated (changed) gene from each parent. The parents of a child with an autosomal recessive condition usually do not have the condition. Unaffected parents are called carriers because they each carry one copy of the mutated gene and can pass it to their children.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802815" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la imagen se observa la distribución del tipo de herencia autosómica recesiva en una familia conformada por padre, madre y cuatro hijos: se muestran un par de cromosomas con un gen mutado y un gen normal en el padre no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en la madre no afectada (portadora); dos genes normales en una hija no afectada; un gen mutado y un gen normal en un hijo no afectado (portador); un gen mutado y un gen normal en una hija no afectada (portadora) y dos genes mutados en un hijo afectado." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">La herencia autosómica recesiva es una de las formas en que un rasgo o una afección genética pasa de padres a hijos. El niño presenta la afección genética cuando hereda dos copias de un gen mutado (cambiado), una del padre y otra de la madre. Por lo general, la madre y el padre no presentan la afección que se hereda de manera autosómica recesiva. Se dice que la madre y el padre no afectados son portadores porque cada uno tiene una copia del gen mutado que puede pasar a sus hijos. </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>poliposis asociada a MUTYH</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman muchos pólipos (bultos anormales) en la pared interna del colon y el recto. Por lo general, las personas con poliposis asociada a MUTYH tienen menos de 100 pólipos en el colon, y es posible que también tengan pólipos en el estómago y el intestino delgado. Esta afección aumenta el riesgo de presentar cáncer colorrectal, así como cánceres de estómago, intestino delgado, ovario, endometrio, vejiga, hígado, tiroides y piel.  La causa de la poliposis asociada a MUTYH son mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>MUTYH</GeneName>
       que se heredan de manera autosómica dominante. Es un tipo de síndrome de cáncer hereditario. También se llama PAM.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10805/myh-associated-polyposis">MYH-associated polyposis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/familial-adenomatous-polyposis/">Familial adenomatous polyposis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
