<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798773"><TermName>5-HIAA</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance formed by the breakdown of a hormone called serotonin in the liver. Nerves use serotonin to send messages to one another. After 5-HIAA is broken down from serotonin in the liver, the kidneys filter it from the blood and pass it into the urine. Serotonin and 5-HIAA may be found in higher-than-normal amounts in patients with certain tumors, such as carcinoid tumor. Measuring the amount of 5-HIAA in the urine may help diagnose and monitor carcinoid tumors and other conditions. 5-HIAA is a type of tumor marker. Also called 5-hydroxyindoleacetic acid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>5-HIAA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que se produce a partir de la descomposición de la hormona serotonina en el hígado. Los nervios usan la serotonina para transmitir mensajes entre sí.  El 5-HIAA que se forma tras la descomposición de la serotonina en el hígado, pasa a la sangre y llega a los riñones donde se filtra para que el cuerpo lo elimine en la orina. A veces, se encuentran concentraciones altas de serotonina y  5-HIAA en los pacientes que tienen determinados tumores, como los tumores carcinoides. Medir la cantidad del  5-HIAA en la orina ayuda a diagnosticar y vigilar los tumores carcinoides y otras afecciones.  El 5-HIAA es un tipo de marcador tumoral. También se llama A5-HIA y ácido 5-hidroxiindolacético.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-01-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/diagnosis/tumor-markers-list">Tumor Marker Tests in Common Use</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/lista-marcadores-tumorales" UseWith="es">Marcadores tumorales más comunes</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
