<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798765"><TermName>cardiac catheterization</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAR-dee-ak KA-theh-ter-rih-ZAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure used to diagnose and treat some heart conditions. During cardiac catheterization, a flexible tube called a catheter is inserted into a blood vessel in the arm, groin, upper thigh, or neck. The catheter is then guided through the aorta into the heart using a special x-ray machine. A cardiac catheterization may be done to measure blood pressure and oxygen levels in different parts of the heart, to check how well the heart muscle is working, to take a sample of tissue from the heart, or to look for defects in the valves or chambers of the heart. A dye may be injected through the catheter in order to look at blood flow in the heart and to check for blockages in the arteries leading to the heart. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801016" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cardiac catheterization&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801017" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cateterismo cardíaco&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>cateterismo cardíaco</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se usa para diagnosticar y tratar algunas afecciones del corazón. Durante el cateterismo cardíaco, se inserta un tubo flexible llamado catéter en un vaso sanguíneo en el brazo, la ingle, la parte superior del muslo o el cuello. Luego se utiliza una máquina especial de rayos X para pasar el catéter por la aorta hasta el corazón. Es posible que se haga un cateterismo cardíaco para medir la presión arterial y la concentración de oxígeno en diferentes partes del corazón, para ver qué tan bien está trabajando el músculo cardíaco, para tomar una muestra de tejido del corazón o para buscar defectos en las válvulas o las cavidades del corazón. A veces, se inyecta un tinte a través del catéter para observar el flujo sanguíneo en el corazón y comprobar si hay obstrucciones en las arterias que llegan al corazón.  También se llama cateterización cardíaca.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-10</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
