<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798769"><TermName>dermatomyositis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DER-muh-toh-MY-oh-SY-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A disease that causes inflammation of the skin and muscles. Signs and symptoms include a red or bluish-purple patchy rash on the face, eyelids, knuckles, elbows, knees, toes, chest, or back. The rash may cause swelling, itching, and pain. Dermatomyositis can also cause muscle weakness in the upper body, hips, and thighs; trouble swallowing; breathing problems; and calcium deposits, which look like hard bumps under the skin or in the muscle. People with dermatomyositis may have an increased risk of certain heart, lung, or connective tissue diseases and certain types of cancer, including cancers of the cervix, lungs, pancreas, breast, ovaries, and gastrointestinal tract. Dermatomyositis can occur in both children and adults.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801020" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dermatomyositis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801021" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dermatomiositis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>dermatomiositis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad que causa inflamación de la piel y los músculos. Los signos y síntomas incluyen un exantema (sarpullido) con manchas rojas o púrpuras azuladas en la cara, los párpados, los nudillos, los codos, las rodillas, los dedos de los pies, el pecho o la espalda. El exantema a veces causa hinchazón, picazón y dolor. En ocasiones, la dermatomiositis también causa debilidad muscular en la parte superior del cuerpo, las caderas y los muslos; dificultad para tragar; problemas respiratorios; y depósitos de calcio que parecen bultos duros debajo de la piel o en los músculos. Es posible que las personas con dermatomiositis tengan un mayor riesgo de ciertas enfermedades cardíacas, pulmonares o del tejido conjuntivo y determinados tipos de cáncer, incluso cáncer de cuello uterino, pulmón, páncreas, mama, ovario o tubo gastrointestinal. La dermatomiositis se presenta en niños y en adultos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-10</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/000839.htm">Dermatomyositis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6263/dermatomyositis">Dermatomyositis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000839.htm">Dermatomiositis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
