<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798767"><TermName>nephrotic syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(neh-FRAH-tik SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A combination of symptoms caused by damage to the tiny blood vessels in the kidney that filter waste and extra fluid from the blood and send them to the bladder as urine. Signs and symptoms of nephrotic syndrome include higher-than-normal amounts of protein in the urine and fat and cholesterol in the blood. Swelling, especially in the legs, feet, or ankles, may occur. Nephrotic syndrome may be caused by certain diseases that affect only the kidneys or by infection, immune system disorders (such as lupus), certain genetic disorders, and other diseases or conditions, such as cancer, diabetes, and amyloidosis. It may also be caused by taking certain medicines. Nephrotic syndrome can occur in both children and adults.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801018" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nephrotic syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801019" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome nefrótico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome nefrótico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Combinación de síntomas causados por daños en los vasos sanguíneos pequeños del riñón que filtran los desechos y el exceso de líquido de la sangre para producir la orina, que después pasa a la vejiga. Los signos y síntomas del síndrome nefrótico incluyen cantidades más altas de lo normal de proteínas en la orina, y de grasas y colesterol en la sangre. Es posible que se produzca hinchazón, en especial en las piernas, los pies  o los tobillos. El síndrome nefrótico puede ser causado por ciertas enfermedades que afectan solo los riñones, o por infecciones, trastornos del sistema inmunitario (como el lupus), ciertos trastornos genéticos y otras enfermedades o afecciones como el cáncer, la diabetes y la amiloidosis. También es posible que  ciertos medicamentos causen este síndrome. El síndrome nefrótico se presenta en niños y en adultos. También se llama nefrosis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-10</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/000490.htm">Nephrotic syndrome</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000490.htm">Síndrome nefrótico (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
