<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798783">
  <TermName>JPS</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A rare, inherited disorder in which multiple abnormal growths called juvenile polyps  form in the gastrointestinal tract, usually before the age of 20 years. To be diagnosed with JPS, a person must have one or more of the following: (1) more than five juvenile polyps in the colon or rectum; (2) juvenile polyps in other parts of the gastrointestinal tract, including the stomach or small intestine; (3) any number of juvenile polyps and a family history of JPS. Other signs and symptoms include diarrhea, gastrointestinal bleeding, abdominal pain, anemia, extra fingers and toes, and abnormalities of the heart, brain, roof of the mouth, intestines, urinary tract, and genitals. People with JPS also have an increased risk of colorectal cancer, stomach cancer, small intestine cancer, and pancreatic cancer. JPS is caused by mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>SMAD4</GeneName>
       or 
      <GeneName>BMPR1A </GeneName>
       genes that are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. It is a type of hereditary cancer syndrome. Also called juvenile polyposis syndrome.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermName>PJ</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman muchos pólipos juveniles (bultos anormales) en el tubo gastrointestinal que suelen aparecer antes de los 20 años.  Para diagnosticar el PJ, deben presentarse una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) más de 5 pólipos juveniles en el colon o el recto; 2) pólipos juveniles en otras partes del tubo gastrointestinal, como el estómago o el intestino delgado; 3) cualquier número  de pólipos juveniles en una persona con antecedentes familiares de PJ. Otros signos y síntomas son diarrea, hemorragia gastrointestinal, dolor abdominal, anemia, dedos adicionales en las manos o los pies, anomalías del corazón, el encéfalo, el paladar, los intestinos, las vías urinarias y los órganos genitales. Las personas con  esta afección también tienen un riesgo alto de presentar cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de estómago, cáncer de intestino delgado y cáncer de páncreas. La causa del PJ son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes 
      <GeneName>SMAD4</GeneName>
       o 
      <GeneName>BMPR1A</GeneName>
       que se heredan de manera autosómica dominante. Es un tipo de síndrome de cáncer hereditario. También se llama síndrome de poliposis juvenil.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/3065/juvenile-polyposis-syndrome">Juvenile polyposis syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/juvenile-polyposis-syndrome/">Juvenile polyposis syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
