<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798782"><TermName>juvenile polyposis syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(JOO-veh-nile PAH-lee-POH-sis SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which multiple abnormal growths called juvenile polyps  form in the gastrointestinal tract, usually before the age of 20 years. To be diagnosed with juvenile polyposis syndrome, a person must have one or more of the following: (1) more than five juvenile polyps in the colon or rectum; (2) juvenile polyps in other parts of the gastrointestinal tract, including the stomach or small intestine; (3) any number of juvenile polyps and a family history of juvenile polyposis syndrome. Other signs and symptoms include diarrhea, gastrointestinal bleeding, abdominal pain, anemia, extra fingers and toes, and abnormalities of the heart, brain, roof of the mouth, intestines, urinary tract, and genitals. People with juvenile polyposis syndrome also have an increased risk of colorectal cancer, stomach cancer, small intestine cancer, and pancreatic cancer. Juvenile polyposis syndrome is caused by mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>SMAD4</GeneName> or <GeneName>BMPR1A </GeneName> genes that are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. It is a type of hereditary cancer syndrome. Also called JPS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801028" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;juvenile polyposis syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801029" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de poliposis juvenil&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de poliposis juvenil</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman muchos pólipos juveniles (bultos anormales) en el tubo gastrointestinal que suelen aparecer antes de los 20 años.  Para diagnosticar el síndrome de poliposis juvenil, deben presentarse una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) más de 5 pólipos juveniles en el colon o el recto; 2) pólipos juveniles en otras partes del tubo gastrointestinal, como el estómago o el intestino delgado; 3) cualquier número  de pólipos juveniles en una persona con antecedentes familiares de síndrome de poliposis juvenil. Otros signos y síntomas son diarrea, hemorragia gastrointestinal, dolor abdominal, anemia, dedos adicionales en las manos o los pies, anomalías del corazón, el encéfalo, el paladar, los intestinos, las vías urinarias y los órganos genitales. Las personas con  esta afección también tienen un riesgo alto de presentar cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de estómago, cáncer de intestino delgado y cáncer de páncreas. La causa del síndrome de poliposis juvenil son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes <GeneName>SMAD4</GeneName> o <GeneName>BMPR1A</GeneName> que se heredan de manera autosómica dominante. Es un tipo de síndrome de cáncer hereditario. También se llama PJ y poliposis gastrointestinal juvenil.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/3065/juvenile-polyposis-syndrome">Juvenile polyposis syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/juvenile-polyposis-syndrome/">Juvenile polyposis syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
