<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798771">
  <TermName>pure red cell aplasia</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… sel uh-PLAY-zhuh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare disorder in which the bone marrow does not make enough red blood cells. Signs and symptoms include fatigue, pale skin, breathing problems, dizziness, and headaches. Pure red cell aplasia mainly affects adults and may be caused by infection, kidney failure, an autoimmune disease (such as lupus or rheumatoid arthritis), pregnancy, a thymoma (tumor of the thymus gland), and certain types of cancer, including leukemia. It may also be caused by taking certain medicines. Pure red cell aplasia may also be inherited and seen in the first year of life, but this is very rare. Also called PRCA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801022" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pure red cell aplasia&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801023" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aplasia pura de células rojas&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>aplasia pura de células rojas</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno raro por el que la médula ósea no produce suficientes glóbulos rojos. Los signos y síntomas son cansancio, piel pálida, problemas para respirar, mareos y dolores de cabeza. La aplasia pura de células rojas afecta sobre todo a adultos. Las causas de este trastorno son infecciones, insuficiencia renal, enfermedades autoinmunitarias (como lupus y artritis reumatoide), embarazo, timoma (tumor de timo), y determinados tipos de cáncer, como la leucemia. Además,  es posible que ciertos medicamentos produzcan esta alteración. La aplasia pura de células rojas a veces es hereditaria y se presenta durante el primer año de vida, aunque esto es muy infrecuente. También se llama APCR, aplasia pura de glóbulos rojos, aplasia pura de la serie roja y eritroblastopenia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7504/pure-red-cell-aplasia">Pure red cell aplasia (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
