<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798786">
  <TermName>enchondromatosis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(en-kon-DROH-muh-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare disorder that causes benign (not cancer) growths of cartilage in the bones that may become cancer. These growths, called  enchondromas, usually occur in the bones of the hands and feet, but they may also occur in the skull, ribs, and spine. They may cause bones to break, to be deformed, or to be shorter than usual. People with enchondromatosis have an increased risk of developing certain types of cancer, including chondrosarcoma (cancer that forms in bone cartilage) and cancers of the ovary or liver. Enchondromatosis is most common in children and young adults. Also called Ollier disease.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801032" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enchondromatosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801033" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;encondromatosis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>encondromatosis</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno raro por el que se forman tumores benignos (no cancerosos) de cartílago en los huesos, que en ocasiones se transforman en cáncer. Estos tumores se llaman encondromas y suelen observarse en los huesos de las manos y los pies, pero también se encuentran en el cráneo, las costillas y la columna vertebral. Es posible que causen fracturas, deformación o  acortamiento de los huesos. Las personas con encondromatosis tienen un riesgo elevado de presentar ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el condrosarcoma (cáncer de cartílago óseo) y cáncer de ovario o de hígado. La encondromatosis es más común en niños y adultos jóvenes. También se llama síndrome de Ollier.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-02-21</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/7251/ollier-disease">Ollier disease (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/ollier-disease/">Ollier disease (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
