<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798776"><TermName>attenuated familial adenomatous polyposis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-TEN-yoo-way-ted fuh-MIH-lee-ul A-deh-NOH-muh-tus PAH-lee-POH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which multiple polyps (abnormal growths) form on the inner walls of the colon and rectum. People with attenuated familial adenomatous polyposis usually develop fewer than 100 polyps. Benign (not cancer) tumors may also occur in the stomach, small intestine, bone, skin, and soft tissue. People with attenuated familial adenomatous polyposis have a very high risk of developing colorectal cancer and may also be at risk of developing cancers of the stomach, small intestine, liver, and breast. Attenuated familial adenomatous polyposis is caused by mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>APC</GeneName> gene that are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. It is a type of hereditary cancer syndrome.  Also called AFAP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801024" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;attenuated familial adenomatous polyposis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801025" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;poliposis adenomatosa familiar atenuada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>poliposis adenomatosa familiar atenuada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman muchos  pólipos (bultos anormales) en las paredes internas del colon y el recto. Las personas con  poliposis adenomatosa familiar atenuada suelen tener menos de 100 pólipos. A veces, también presentan tumores benignos (no cancerosos) en el estómago, el intestino delgado, los huesos, la piel y los tejidos blandos. Las personas con este trastorno tienen un riesgo muy alto de presentar cáncer colorrectal y quizá también tengan riesgo de cáncer de estómago, intestino delgado, hígado y mama. La causa de la poliposis adenomatosa familiar atenuada son mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>APC</GeneName> que se heredan de manera autosómica dominante. Es un tipo de síndrome de cáncer hereditario. También se llama PAFA y poliposis familiar adenomatosa atenuada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/8532/attenuated-familial-adenomatous-polyposis">Attenuated familial adenomatous polyposis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/familial-adenomatous-polyposis/">Familial adenomatous polyposis (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
