<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798920">
  <TermName>nonalcoholic steatohepatitis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(non-AL-kuh-HAW-lik STEE-uh-toh-HEH-puh-TY-tis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of liver disease in which fat builds up in the liver of people who drink little or no alcohol. This causes inflammation of the liver and damage to the cells in the liver, which may lead to cirrhosis (scarring of the liver) and liver failure. People with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis are at increased risk of developing liver cancer. It is more common in middle-aged adults, especially in those who are overweight or obese or who have diabetes or high levels of cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat) in the blood. Also called NASH.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801042" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nonalcoholic steatohepatitis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801043" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;esteatohepatitis no alcohólica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>esteatohepatitis no alcohólica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de enfermedad hepática por la que se acumula grasa en el hígado de personas que no consumen bebidas alcohólicas o las consumen en poca cantidad. Esto produce inflamación del hígado y daño de las células hepáticas, lo que a veces deriva en cirrosis (cicatrización del hígado) e insuficiencia hepática. Las personas con esteatohepatitis no alcohólica tienen un riesgo elevado de presentar cáncer de hígado. Es más común en adultos de mediana edad, en especial, en personas con sobrepeso, obesidad, diabetes o concentraciones altas de colesterol y triglicéridos (tipos de grasa) en la sangre. También se llama EHNA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6430/nonalcoholic-steatohepatitis">Nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease/">Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/fattyliverdisease.html">Hígado graso (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
