<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798911">
  <TermName>glomerulonephritis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(gloh-MAYR-yoo-loh-neh-FRY-tis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which the tissues in the kidney become inflamed and have problems filtering waste from the blood. Glomerulonephritis may be caused by infection, inflammatory conditions (such as lupus), certain genetic conditions, and other diseases or conditions. It may also be caused by taking certain medicines or being exposed to certain chemicals. Signs and symptoms include blood and protein in the urine; high blood pressure; swelling of the face, hands, feet, and legs; fatigue; and anemia. If not treated or controlled, glomerulonephritis may lead to kidney damage and kidney failure. Also called nephritis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799637" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;glomerulonephritis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799636" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;glomerulonefritis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>glomerulonefritis</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que se inflaman los  tejidos del riñón y se dificulta la filtración de los desechos de la sangre. Las causas de la glomerulonefritis son infecciones, afecciones inflamatorias (como el lupus), ciertas afecciones genéticas y otras enfermedades o afecciones. Otras causas son  tomar determinados medicamentos o exponerse a ciertas sustancias químicas. Los signos y síntomas son  sangre y proteínas en la orina; presión arterial alta; hinchazón de la cara, las manos, los pies y las piernas; cansancio y anemia. Si no se trata, la glomerulonefritis quizás lleve a daño del riñón e insuficiencia renal. También se llama nefritis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-07-25</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
