<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798944">
  <TermName>fluorescein angiography</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(floor-EH-seen an-jee-AH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a special dye and camera to look at the blood vessels in the back of the eye. A yellow dye called fluorescein is injected into a vein and travels throughout the body, including the blood vessels in the eye. The dye causes the blood vessels to light up when a picture is taken with a special camera. Fluorescein angiography may be used to check for damaged, blocked, or leaking blood vessels in the eye, swelling in the retina, and other eye problems, including macular degeneration and a type of eye cancer called intraocular melanoma. It may also be used to see how well certain eye treatments are working.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801056" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fluorescein angiography&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801057" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;angiografía con fluoresceína&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/>
  <SpanishTermName>angiografía con fluoresceína</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa un tinte especial y una cámara para observar los vasos sanguíneos de la parte posterior del ojo. Se inyecta en una vena un tinte amarillo llamado fluoresceína, que viaja por el cuerpo hasta los vasos sanguíneos del ojo. El tinte hace que los vasos sanguíneos se vean más brillantes cuando se toma una fotografía usando una cámara especial. La angiografía con  fluoresceína a veces se usa para examinar lesiones, obstrucciones o derrames en los vasos sanguíneos del ojo, hinchazón de la retina y otros problemas oculares como la degeneración macular y un tipo de cáncer de ojo que se llama melanoma ocular. Este procedimiento también sirve para determinar la eficacia de los tratamientos en el ojo. También se llama angiofluoresceinografía y angiografía fluoresceínica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
