<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798951">
  <TermName>darolutamide</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(DAR-oh-LOO-tuh-mide)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with docetaxel to treat adults with certain types of prostate cancer. Darolutamide is used in patients whose cancer has spread to other parts of the body and responds to treatment that lowers testosterone levels or whose cancer has not spread to other parts of the body and no longer responds to treatment that lowers testosterone levels. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Darolutamide binds to proteins called androgen receptors, which are found in some prostate cancer cells. These proteins bind to androgens (male hormones) and may cause cancer cells to grow. Darolutamide blocks these proteins and may keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of antiandrogen. Also called Nubeqa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799619" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;darolutamide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000799618" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;darolutamida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>darolutamida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con docetaxel para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer de próstata.  La darolutamida se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y respondió al tratamiento que disminuye las concentraciones de testosterona, o en pacientes cuyo cáncer no se ha diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo, pero que dejó de responder al tratamiento que disminuye las concentraciones de testosterona. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. La darolutamida se une a unas proteínas llamadas receptores de andrógeno, que se encuentran en algunas células del cáncer de próstata. Estas proteínas se unen a los andrógenos (hormonas masculinas) y en ocasiones hacen que las células cancerosas se multipliquen. La darolutamida bloquea estas proteínas y es posible que prevenga la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de antiandrógeno. También se llama Nubeqa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-08-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-08-08</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000798976" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/darolutamide">Darolutamide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
