<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798928"><TermName>DKC</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that can affect many parts of the body, especially the nails, skin, and mouth. It is marked by abnormally shaped fingernails and toenails that may grow poorly; changes in skin color, especially on the neck and chest; and white patches inside the mouth. Other problems may include hair loss or early graying of the hair, eye and dental problems, osteoporosis, joint problems, liver disease, and a narrowing of the urethra (tube that carries urine from the bladder to the outside of the body) in men. People with DKC may develop serious conditions, such as bone marrow failure, myelodysplastic syndrome, pulmonary fibrosis, and certain types of cancer, especially leukemia and cancers of the head and neck, mouth, anus, and genitals. DKC may be caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes that affect the length of telomeres (the ends of chromosomes). Also called dyskeratosis congenita.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>DC</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro que afecta muchas partes del cuerpo, en especial, las uñas, la piel y la boca. Se caracteriza por uñas de forma anormal que crecen muy poco; cambios en el color de la piel, en especial, en el cuello y el tórax; así como manchas blancas dentro de la boca. Otros problemas son caída del pelo, canas prematuras, problemas en los ojos y los dientes, osteoporosis, alteraciones articulares, enfermedad del hígado y estrechamiento de la uretra  (tubo por el que sale la orina de la vejiga) en los hombres. Las personas con DC a veces presentan afecciones graves, como insuficiencia de la  médula ósea, síndrome mielodisplásico, fibrosis pulmonar y determinados tipos de cáncer, en especial, leucemias y cánceres de cabeza y cuello, boca, ano y órganos genitales. Es posible que la causa de la  DC sean mutaciones (cambios) en determinados genes que afectan el tamaño de los telómeros (extremos de los cromosomas). También se llama disqueratosis congénita.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10905/dyskeratosis-congenita">Dyskeratosis congenita (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/dyskeratosis-congenita/">Dyskeratosis congenita (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
