<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000798935"><TermName>Right to Try Act</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A U.S. law that allows patients access to certain drugs that have not been approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). The patient must be unable to receive the drug in a clinical trial and must have a life-threatening illness for which other treatments are not available. Drugs used under the Right to Try Act must have been tested in a phase 1 clinical trial (the first step of testing a new treatment in people) and must be undergoing study to be approved by the FDA. Companies who develop and make drugs determine whether to make their products available to patients who qualify for access under the Right to Try Act.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801048" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Right to Try Act&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801049" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Ley de Derecho a Probar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Ley de Derecho a Probar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Ley de los Estados Unidos que permite a los pacientes el acceso a determinados medicamentos que la  Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos (FDA) no ha aprobado. En la Ley de Derecho a Probar (Right to Try Act) se exige que los pacientes no hayan podido recibir el medicamento en un ensayo clínico, y que padezcan una enfermedad potencialmente mortal para la que no se dispongan de otras opciones de tratamiento. Los medicamentos que se usan de acuerdo con lo dispuesto en esta ley, se deben haber sometido a pruebas en un ensayo clínico de fase 1 (primer paso para probar un tratamiento nuevo en seres humanos) y deben ser parte de estudios sometidos a la aprobación de la FDA. Las empresas que formulan y elaboran medicamentos determinan si ofrecen estos medicamentos a los pacientes que cumplen con los requisitos de acceso exigidos en esta ley.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/access-experimental">Access to Experimental Cancer Drugs</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/medicamentos/acceso-fase-investigacion">Acceso a medicamentos experimentales para cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
