<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799118"><TermName>Supprelin LA</TermName><TermPronunciation>(suh-PREH-lin ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat early puberty in males and females. Supprelin LA initially causes the pituitary gland to make more luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), temporarily increasing testosterone levels in males and estrogen levels in females. With continued use, Supprelin LA lowers the amount of LH and FSH the pituitary gland releases, leading to a drop in testosterone levels in males and estrogen levels in females. Supprelin LA contains the active ingredient histrelin acetate. It is a type of hormone therapy called a luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist and a type of androgen deprivation therapy that is reversible.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799539" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Supprelin LA&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000799538" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Supprelin LA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Supprelin LA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar la pubertad precoz en niños y niñas. Cuando se comienza a usar, Supprelin LA hace que la hipófisis produzca más hormona luteinizante (LH) y hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH), lo que aumenta de forma temporal la concentración de testosterona en los niños y de estrógeno en las niñas. Con el uso continuo, reduce la cantidad de LH y FSH que libera la hipófisis, lo que disminuye la concentración de testosterona en los niños y de estrógeno en las niñas. Supprelin LA contiene el ingrediente activo acetato de histrelina. Pertenece a un grupo de medicamentos de terapia hormonal llamados agonistas de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante (LHRH) y es un medicamento usado para la terapia de privación de andrógenos reversible.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-08-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-01-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
