<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799190">
  <TermName>shared decision making</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… deh-SIH-zhun MAY-king)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, a process in which both the patient and health care professional work together to decide the best plan of care for the patient. When making a shared decision, the patient’s values, goals, and concerns are considered. Shared decision making helps patients learn more about their health condition, the different testing and treatment options that may be available, and the possible risks and benefits of each option. It is often used when important medical decisions need to be made, such as about having a genetic test or cancer screening test, having major surgery, or taking a medicine over a long time.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801078" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;shared decision making&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proceso de decisión compartida&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>proceso de decisión compartida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En medicina es el proceso en el que el paciente y el profesional de la salud trabajan juntos para decidir el mejor plan de atención para el paciente. Cuando se toman decisiones de manera compartida, se consideran los valores, las metas y las preocupaciones del paciente. Este proceso ayuda a los pacientes a aprender más sobre su afección, las diferentes pruebas y opciones de tratamiento disponibles, así como los riesgos y beneficios de cada opción. A menudo se usa este proceso cuando se deben tomar decisiones médicas importantes, como hacerse una prueba genética, exámenes de detección de un cáncer o una  cirugía mayor, o tomar un medicamento durante un periodo largo. También se llama toma de decisión compartida.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-02-06</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
