<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799139">
  <TermName>sinusitis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SINE-yoo-SY-tis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which the tissue lining the sinuses (small hollow spaces in the bones around the nose) becomes swollen or inflamed. The sinuses are lined with cells that make mucous. Sinusitis can occur when too much mucous builds up in the sinuses or their openings become blocked. It is usually caused by a viral, bacterial, or fungal infection. Signs and symptoms include headache, facial pain or pressure, stuffy or runny nose, sore throat, fever, cough, fatigue, bad breath, and reduced sense of smell and taste. Having certain conditions, such as allergies, nasal polyps (growths) or other nasal problems, a weak immune system, or certain medical conditions (such as cystic fibrosis), may increase the risk of developing sinusitis. Smoking or being exposed to secondhand smoke may also increase the risk of sinusitis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801062" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sinusitis&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801063" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sinusitis&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sinusitis</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que se produce hinchazón o inflamación del tejido que reviste los senos paranasales (espacios huecos pequeños en los huesos que rodean la nariz). Los senos paranasales están cubiertos por células que elaboran moco. La sinusitis se presenta cuando se acumula demasiado moco o se obstruyen los orificios de los senos. Las infecciones por virus, bacterias u hongos son causas comunes de esta afección. Los signos y síntomas de la sinusitis son dolor de cabeza, dolor o presión en la cara, nariz congestionada o con secreción, dolor de garganta, fiebre, tos, cansancio, mal aliento y disminución del sentido del olfato y el gusto. El riesgo de sinusitis aumenta cuando hay otras afecciones como alergias, pólipos nasales (bultos) u otros problemas en la nariz, un sistema inmunitario debilitado o determinadas enfermedades (como la fibrosis quística). El riesgo también aumenta en las personas que fuman o están expuestas de manera pasiva al humo del tabaco. También se llama rinosinusitis y sinusitis paranasal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-23</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
