<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799146"><TermName>confirmatory clinical trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kun-FIR-muh-TOR-ee KLIH-nih-kul TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A study that confirms how well a new treatment works after it was shown in early-phase clinical trials that it might be beneficial for patients. New drugs that are given an accelerated approval by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to treat a serious or life-threatening disease, such as cancer, are required to be tested in a confirmatory clinical trial. This is done to verify that they really work when they are tested on many more people in a randomized study. The FDA may remove a drug from the market if a confirmatory clinical trial shows that the drug is not beneficial for patients.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801070" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;confirmatory clinical trial&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801071" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ensayo clínico confirmatorio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ensayo clínico confirmatorio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estudio para confirmar la eficacia de un tratamiento nuevo luego de que se demostró un beneficio para los pacientes en los ensayos clínicos de fase temprana. Los medicamentos nuevos que reciben la aprobación acelerada de la Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos de los Estados Unidos (FDA) para el tratamiento de una enfermedad grave o potencialmente mortal, como el cáncer, deben someterse a un ensayo clínico confirmatorio. Este estudio se hace para verificar que el medicamento realmente funciona cuando se prueba en muchas más personas en un estudio aleatorizado. Es posible que la FDA retire un medicamento del mercado si en el ensayo clínico confirmatorio no se logra demostrar un beneficio para los pacientes. También se llama estudio clínico confirmatorio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
