<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799141"><TermName>facial nerve</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FAY-shul nerv)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nerve that runs from the brainstem, through openings in the skull, to the face and tongue. The facial nerve sends information between the brain and the muscles used in facial expression (such as smiling and frowning), some muscles in the jaw, and the muscles of a small bone in the middle ear. It also sends information to the front part of the tongue for the sense of taste and to the outer parts of the ear. The facial nerve also stimulates the glands that make tears and saliva. It is a type of cranial nerve. There are two facial nerves, one on each side of the face. Also called seventh cranial nerve.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801064" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;facial nerve&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801065" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nervio facial&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>nervio facial</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nervio que parte del tronco encefálico, pasa por orificios del cráneo y llega a la cara y la lengua. El nervio facial lleva información entre el encéfalo y los músculos de las expresiones faciales (como sonreír y fruncir el ceño), algunos músculos del maxilar y los músculos de los huesecillos del oído medio. Además, transmite la información del sentido del gusto a la parte delantera de la lengua,  y  transmite información a la parte externa de la oreja. El  nervio facial también estimula las glándulas que elaboran lágrimas y saliva. Es un tipo de nervio craneal. Hay dos nervios faciales, uno a cada lado de la cara. También se llama séptimo par craneal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
