<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799144"><TermName>accelerated approval</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ak-SEH-leh-ray-ted uh-PROO-vul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An official process that allows a new drug to be approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) before it has gone through all of the required levels of testing in humans. It is only used for drugs that treat serious or life-threatening diseases for which other treatments may not be available or may no longer be effective. A drug may be approved through the accelerated approval process if it has shown certain signs in clinical trials that it might be beneficial for patients, such as a shrinking tumor. Further testing of the drug is required after it has received accelerated approval and is on the market to confirm that it really works. Accelerated approval is one way that patients can receive promising new drugs when other treatment options may not exist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801068" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;accelerated approval&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801069" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aprobación acelerada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>aprobación acelerada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso oficial que permite que la Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos de los Estados Unidos (FDA) apruebe un medicamento antes de que pase por todos los niveles de pruebas en seres humanos  exigidos normalmente. Solo se usa para medicamentos que sirven para el tratamiento de enfermedades graves o potencialmente mortales para las que no se disponen de otros tratamientos o para las que los tratamientos ya no son eficaces. Es posible aprobar un medicamento mediante este proceso acelerado si en los ensayos clínicos se observaron indicios  de beneficio para los pacientes, por ejemplo,  disminución del tamaño de un tumor. Después de que el medicamento recibe la aprobación acelerada y comienza a venderse, se exigen otras pruebas para confirmar que en realidad funciona. La probación acelerada es una de las formas en que los pacientes acceden a nuevos medicamentos prometedores cuando ya agotaron otras opciones de tratamiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
