<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799324"><TermName>phase 1/phase 2 clinical trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fayz …/fayz ... KLIH-nih-kul TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A study that tests the safety, side effects, and best dose of a new treatment. Phase 1/phase 2 clinical trials also test how well a certain type of cancer or other disease responds to a new treatment. In the phase 2 part of the clinical trial, patients usually receive the highest dose of treatment that did not cause harmful side effects in the phase 1 part of the clinical trial. Combining phases 1 and 2 may allow research questions to be answered more quickly or with fewer patients. Also called phase I/II clinical trial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801090" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;phase 1/phase 2 clinical trial&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801091" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ensayo clínico de fase 1/2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ensayo clínico de fase 1/2</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estudio en el que se pone a prueba  la seguridad, los efectos secundarios y la mejor dosis de un tratamiento nuevo. En los ensayos clínicos de fase 1/2 también se prueba la respuesta al tratamiento nuevo de cierto tipo de cáncer u otra enfermedad. Por lo general, en la fase 2 del ensayo clínico los pacientes reciben la dosis más alta del tratamiento que no causó efectos secundarios perjudiciales en la fase 1 del ensayo clínico. La combinación de las fases 1 y 2 permite que se   respondan preguntas de investigación de una manera más rápida o con menos pacientes. También se llama ensayo clínico de fase I/II y estudio clínico de fase 1/2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-09-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-09-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
