<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799320"><TermName>phase 1 clinical trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fayz … KLIH-nih-kul TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The first step in testing a new treatment in humans. A phase 1 clinical trial tests the safety, side effects, best dose, and timing of a new treatment. It may also test the best way to give a new treatment (for example, by mouth, infusion into a vein, or injection) and how the treatment affects the body. The dose is usually increased a little at a time in order to find the highest dose that does not cause harmful side effects. Phase 1 clinical trials usually include only a small number of patients who have not been helped by other treatments. Sometimes they include healthy volunteers. Also called phase I clinical trial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801082" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;phase 1 clinical trial&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801083" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ensayo clínico de fase 1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ensayo clínico de fase 1</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Primer paso para poner a prueba un tratamiento nuevo en seres humanos. En los ensayos clínicos de fase 1 se prueban la seguridad, los efectos secundarios, la mejor dosis y el momento adecuado de administrar el  tratamiento nuevo. También se puede evaluar la mejor manera de administrar un tratamiento nuevo (es decir, por vía oral, por infusión intravenosa o por inyección) y la manera en que el tratamiento afecta el cuerpo. Por lo general, la dosis se aumenta de a poco hasta encontrar la dosis máxima que no causa efectos secundarios perjudiciales. En los ensayos clínicos de fase 1 solo se suelen incluir a unos pocos pacientes que no mejoraron con otros tratamientos. En ocasiones, participan voluntarios sanos. También se llama ensayo clínico de fase I y estudio clínico de fase 1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-09-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-09-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
