<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799476"><TermName>epidermolysis bullosa simplex, Dowling-Meara</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EH-pih-der-MAH-lih-sis buh-LOH-suh SIM-plex, DOW-ling-MEER-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which many clusters of blisters form all over the body, especially on the face, hands, feet, arms, legs, and trunk. Blisters may also form in the inner lining of the mouth and other parts of the gastrointestinal tract and the upper respiratory tract. Other signs and symptoms include scarring, changes in skin color, nail problems, and thickening of the skin on the palms of the hands and bottoms of the feet. The signs and symptoms usually appear at birth and tend to get better over time. However, infants with a severe form of the disease die within the first year of life. People with epidermolysis bullosa simplex, Dowling-Meara have a high risk of developing basal cell skin cancer by age 55 years. Epidermolysis bullosa simplex, Dowling-Meara is caused by mutations (changes) in the KRT5 or KRT14 genes. Also called EBS-DM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermolysis bullosa simplex, Dowling-Meara&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802530" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermolisis ampollosa simple de tipo Dowling-Meara&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>epidermolisis ampollosa simple de tipo Dowling-Meara</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman muchos grupos de ampollas por todo el cuerpo, en especial, en la cara, las manos, los pies, los brazos, las piernas y el tronco. También aparecen ampollas en la mucosa (recubrimiento interno) de la boca, y en otras partes del tubo gastrointestinal y las vías respiratorias. Otros signos y síntomas son cicatrización, cambios en el color de la piel, alteraciones en las uñas y engrosamiento de la piel de las palmas de las manos y las plantas de los pies. Los signos y síntomas a menudo aparecen desde el nacimiento y tienden a mejorar con el tiempo. Sin embargo, los  lactantes con formas graves de la enfermedad  mueren durante el primer año de vida. Las personas con epidermolisis ampollosa simple de tipo Dowling-Meara tienen un riesgo alto de presentar cáncer de células basales de piel hacia los 55 años de edad. La causa de la epidermolisis ampollosa simple de tipo Dowling-Meara son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes <GeneName>KRT5</GeneName> o <GeneName>KRT14</GeneName>. También se llama EBS-DM y epidermolisis bullosa simple, tipo Dowling-Meara.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/2141/epidermolysis-bullosa-simplex-dowling-meara-type">Epidermolysis bullosa simplex, Dowling-Meara type (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/epidermolysis-bullosa-simplex/">Epidermolysis bullosa simplex (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/001457.htm">Epidermólisis ampollosa (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
