<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799472"><TermName>junctional epidermolysis bullosa</TermName><TermPronunciation>(JUNK-shuh-nul EH-pih-der-MAH-lih-sis buh-LOH-suh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which blisters form on the skin and the moist inner lining of some organs and body cavities. The blisters usually appear at birth and may occur on certain parts of the body (such as the hands, feet, elbows, and knees) or all over the body (including the mouth and other parts of the digestive tract, the eyes, the genitourinary tract, and the respiratory tract). This can lead to scarring and red, bumpy skin that bleeds easily in the affected areas. Other signs and symptoms include deformities in the fingers, toes, nails, and joints; thinning of the teeth; hair loss; trouble eating and digesting food; slow growth; and poor nutrition. Some infants with junctional epidermolysis bullosa have a severe form of the disease and may die within the first year of life. Other patients have a mild form and may have a normal life span. Some people with this disorder have an increased risk of developing squamous cell skin cancer at an early age. Junctional epidermolysis bullosa is caused by mutations (changes) in the COL17A1, ITGA6, ITGB4, LAMA3, LAMB3, or LAMC2 gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802525" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;junctional epidermolysis bullosa&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802526" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermólisis ampollosa de la unión&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>epidermólisis ampollosa de la unión</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman ampollas en la piel y las mucosas (recubrimiento húmedo interno) de algunos órganos y cavidades del cuerpo. Las ampollas suelen aparecer desde el nacimiento en determinadas partes del cuerpo (manos, pies, codos y rodillas) o en todo el cuerpo (incluso la boca, otras partes del tubo digestivo, los ojos, el aparato genitourinario y las vías respiratorias). Estas lesiones a veces producen cicatrices y una piel irregular que sangra con facilidad.  Otros signos y síntomas son deformidades en los dedos, las uñas y las articulaciones; debilitamiento de los dientes; caída del pelo; dificultades para la alimentación y la digestión; retraso del crecimiento y desnutrición. Algunos lactantes tienen una enfermedad grave y es posible que mueran   durante el primer año de vida. Otros pacientes tienen una forma leve y su esperanza de vida es normal. Algunas personas con este trastorno tienen un riesgo elevado de presentar cáncer de células escamosas de piel a una edad temprana. La causa de la epidermólisis ampollosa de la unión son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes <GeneName>COL17A1</GeneName>, <GeneName>ITGA6</GeneName>, <GeneName>ITGB4</GeneName>, <GeneName>LAMA3</GeneName>, <GeneName>LAMB3</GeneName> o <GeneName>LAMC2</GeneName>. También se llama epidermólisis bullosa de la unión.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/2152/junctional-epidermolysis-bullosa">Junctional epidermolysis bullosa (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/junctional-epidermolysis-bullosa/">Junctional epidermolysis bullosa (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
