<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799488">
  <TermName>Rombo syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ROM-boh SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A very rare, inherited disorder that causes a bluish-red skin color on the lips, hands, and feet. It also causes skin lesions that leave pitted scars, usually on the cheeks. Other signs and symptoms include little or no hair growth in the affected areas and thin or missing eyelashes and eyebrows; small, yellowish bumps that cause the skin to become rough; thinning of the skin; and other skin problems. The signs and symptoms usually appear between 7 and 10 years of age. People with Rombo syndrome have a very high risk of developing basal cell skin cancer, usually around the age of 35 years. The gene involved in Rombo syndrome is not known.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802537" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Rombo syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802538" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Rombo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Rombo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario muy raro por el que la piel de los labios, las manos y los pies es de color rojo azulado. Además, produce lesiones en la piel que dejan cicatrices en hoyuelos, por lo general, en las mejillas. Otros signos y síntomas son poco crecimiento del pelo en las zonas afectadas; pestañas y cejas escasas o ausentes; pequeños bultos amarillentos que causan irregularidad en la piel; adelgazamiento de la piel y otros problemas cutáneos. Los signos y síntomas con frecuencia aparecen entre los 7 y 10 años de edad. Las personas con síndrome de Rombo tienen un riesgo muy alto de cáncer de células basales de piel, a menudo alrededor de los 35 años. No se conoce el gen que causa este síndrome.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/4738/rombo-syndrome">Rombo syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
