<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799483">
  <TermName>Bazex-Dupré-Christol syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BA-zex-doo-PRAY-kris-TOL SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A very rare, inherited disorder that affects the hair follicles on the scalp and other areas of the body where hair normally grows. There is little or no hair growth in the affected areas, and the hair may be lighter in color, course in texture, and appear flat and twisted when looked at under a microscope. Other signs and symptoms include little or no sweating; small white bumps or cysts on the face, tops of the hands and feet, the back of the elbow, and the front of the knee; and other skin problems. The signs and symptoms usually appear at birth or during infancy. People with  Bazex-Dupré-Christol syndrome have an increased risk of developing basal cell skin cancer at an early age, especially on the face. Bazex-Dupré-Christol syndrome may be caused by a mutation (change) in the UBE2A gene on the X chromosome. Also called BDCS.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802535" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Bazex-Dupré-Christol syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802536" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Bazex-Dupré-Christol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Bazex-Dupré-Christol</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario muy raro que afecta los folículos pilosos (del pelo) del cuero cabelludo y otras áreas donde hay vello corporal. En las áreas afectadas, no crece el pelo o este es muy escaso, de color claro, áspero y se ve aplanado y retorcido al microscopio. Otros signos y síntomas son sudor escaso o ausente; pequeños tumores blancos o quistes en la cara, el dorso de las manos  y los pies, la parte de atrás de los codos y delante de las rodillas; así como otros problemas de la piel. Los signos y síntomas a menudo aparecen desde el nacimiento o al principio de la lactancia. Las personas con síndrome de Bazex-Dupré-Christol tienen un aumento del riesgo de cáncer de células escamosas de piel a una edad temprana, en especial, en la cara. La causa de este trastorno es una mutación (cambio) en el gen 
      <GeneName>UBE2A </GeneName>
       del cromosoma X. También se llama SBDC.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/838/bazex-dupre-christol-syndrome">Bazex-Dupre-Christol syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
