<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799474">
  <TermName>epidermodysplasia verruciformis</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(EH-pih-der-moh-dis-PLAY-zhuh veh-ROO-sih-for-mis)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that makes people susceptible to chronic infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). It causes wart-like lesions or reddish-brown scaly patches to form most often on the skin of the face, neck, hands, arms, legs, feet, and trunk. Epidermodysplasia verruciformis usually appears at an early age and can get worse over time. People with this disorder have a high risk of developing nonmelanoma skin cancer at an early age, especially squamous cell skin cancer. Epidermodysplasia verruciformis is caused by mutations (changes) in the EVER1/TMC6 or EVER2/TMC8 genes.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802527" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermodysplasia verruciformis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802528" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epidermodisplasia verruciforme&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>epidermodisplasia verruciforme</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario poco común que produce susceptibilidad a infecciones crónicas por determinados tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). Se producen lesiones parecidas a verrugas o placas escamosas marrón rojizas que se forman más a menudo en la piel de la cara, el cuello, las manos, los brazos, las piernas, los pies y el tronco. La epidermodisplasia verruciforme por lo general aparece a  una edad temprana y empeora con el tiempo. Las personas con este trastorno tienen un riesgo alto de presentar cáncer de piel no melanoma a una edad temprana, en especial, cáncer de células escamosas de piel. La causa de este trastorno son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes 
      <GeneName>EVER1/TMC6</GeneName>
       o 
      <GeneName>EVER2/TMC8</GeneName>
      .
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6357/epidermodysplasia-verruciformis">Epidermodysplasia verruciformis (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
