<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799470">
  <TermName>DEB</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which blisters form on the skin and the moist inner lining of some organs and body cavities. The blisters usually appear at birth and may occur on certain parts of the body (such as the hands, feet, elbows, and knees) or all over the body (including the mouth, esophagus, and other parts of the gastrointestinal tract, the eyes, and the genitourinary tract). This can lead to scarring in the affected areas and thinning of the skin. Other signs and symptoms include small white bumps on the skin; deformities in the fingers, toes, nails, teeth, and joints; trouble chewing and swallowing; vision loss and other eye problems; anemia; slow growth; and poor nutrition. Some people with DEB have a very high risk of developing squamous cell skin cancer at an early age. There are several types of DEB. It is caused by a mutation (change) in the COL7A1 gene. Also called dystrophic epidermolysis bullosa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermName>EAD</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se forman ampollas en la piel y en las mucosas (recubrimiento húmedo interno) de algunos órganos y cavidades del cuerpo. Las ampollas a menudo surgen desde el nacimiento y aparecen en determinadas partes del cuerpo (manos, pies, codos y rodillas) o en todo el cuerpo (boca, ojos, aparato genitourinario, esófago y otras partes del tubo gastrointestinal). Estas lesiones  a veces producen cicatrices y adelgazamiento de la piel. Otros signos y síntomas incluyen pequeños bultos blancos en la piel; deformidades en los dedos, las uñas, los dientes y las articulaciones; problemas para masticar y tragar; pérdida de visión y otras alteraciones de los ojos; anemia; retraso del crecimiento y desnutrición. Algunas personas con EAD tienen un riesgo muy alto de presentar cáncer de células escamosas de la piel a una edad temprana. Hay varios tipos de EAD. La causa de este trastorno es una mutación (cambio) en el gen 
      <GeneName>COL7A1</GeneName>
      . También se llama epidermólisis ampollosa distrófica.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/2150/dystrophic-epidermolysis-bullosa">Dystrophic epidermolysis bullosa (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/dystrophic-epidermolysis-bullosa/">Dystrophic epidermolysis bullosa (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
