<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799691"><TermName>hematoxylin and eosin staining</TermName><TermPronunciation>(hee-muh-TOK-suh-lin … EE-oh-sin STAY-ning)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A common laboratory method that uses two dyes called hematoxylin and eosin that make it easier to see different parts of the cell  under a microscope. Hematoxylin  shows the ribosomes, chromatin (genetic material) within the nucleus, and other structures as a deep blue-purple color. Eosin shows the cytoplasm, collagen, connective tissue, and other structures that surround and support the cell as an orange-pink-red color. Hematoxylin and eosin staining helps identify different types of cells and tissues and provides important information about the pattern, shape, and structure of cells in a tissue sample. It is used to help diagnose diseases, such as cancer. Also called H and E staining.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801100" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hematoxylin and eosin staining&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801101" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tinción con hematoxilina y eosina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tinción con hematoxilina y eosina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método de laboratorio de uso frecuente en el que se utilizan dos tintes llamados hematoxilina y eosina para observar mejor las diferentes partes de la célula al microscopio. La hematoxilina tiñe de violeta azulado intenso los ribosomas, la cromatina (material genético) dentro del núcleo y otras estructuras. La eosina tiñe de rosa anaranjado o rosado el citoplasma, el colágeno, el tejido conjuntivo y otras estructuras que rodean y sostienen la célula. La tinción con hematoxilina y eosina ayuda a identificar diferentes tipos de células y tejidos, y a obtener información importante sobre las características, la forma y la estructura celular de una muestra de tejido. Se usa para el diagnóstico de enfermedades como el cáncer. También se llama coloración de hematoxilina y eosina y tinción H y E.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-10-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-08-24</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
