<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799692">
  <TermName>H and E staining</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… STAY-ning)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A common laboratory method that uses two dyes called hematoxylin and eosin that make it easier to see different parts of the cell  under a microscope. Hematoxylin  shows the ribosomes, chromatin (genetic material) within the nucleus, and other structures as a deep blue-purple color. Eosin shows the cytoplasm, collagen, connective tissue, and other structures that surround and support the cell as an orange-pink-red color. H and E staining helps identify different types of cells and tissues and provides important information about the pattern, shape, and structure of cells in a tissue sample. It is used to help diagnose diseases, such as cancer. Also called hematoxylin and eosin staining.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801102" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;H and E staining&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801103" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tinción H y E&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tinción H y E</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Método de laboratorio de uso frecuente en el que se utilizan dos tintes llamados hematoxilina y eosina para observar mejor las diferentes partes de la célula al microscopio. La hematoxilina tiñe de violeta azulado intenso los ribosomas, la cromatina (material genético) dentro del núcleo y otras estructuras. La eosina tiñe de rosa anaranjado o rosado el citoplasma, el colágeno, el tejido conjuntivo y otras estructuras que rodean y sostienen la célula. La tinción H y E ayuda a identificar diferentes tipos de células y tejidos, y a obtener información importante sobre las características, la forma y la estructura celular de una muestra de tejido. Se usa para el diagnóstico de enfermedades como el cáncer. También se llama tinción con hematoxilina y eosina.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-10-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-08-24</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
