<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799791">
  <TermName>Muir-Torre syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(myoor-TOR-ay SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that causes tumors to form in the oil glands in skin and in at least one internal organ. The skin tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer) and usually occur on the face, scalp, and eyelids. The internal tumors are malignant and usually form in the gastrointestinal tract (especially the colon and rectum) or genitourinary tract (endometrium and bladder). Muir-Torre syndrome is caused by mutations (changes) in the MLH1, MSH2, or MSH6 gene. Muir-Torre syndrome is a type of Lynch syndrome. Also called MTS.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802545" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Muir-Torre syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802546" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Muir-Torre&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de Muir-Torre</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Trastorno hereditario raro por el que se producen tumores en las glándulas sebáceas (que producen sebo) de la piel y en por lo menos un órgano del interior del cuerpo. Los tumores de piel pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos) y a menudo surgen en la cara, el cuero cabelludo y los párpados. Los tumores internos son malignos  y a menudo surgen en el tubo gastrointestinal (en especial, el colon y el recto) o en el aparato  genitourinario (endometrio y vejiga). La causa del síndrome de Muir-Torre son mutaciones (cambios) en los genes 
      <GeneName>MLH1</GeneName>
      , 
      <GeneName>MSH2</GeneName>
       o 
      <GeneName>MSH6</GeneName>
      . El síndrome de Muir-Torre es un tipo de síndrome de Lynch. También se llama SMT.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-02-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/6821/muir-torre-syndrome">Muir-Torre syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
