<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799823"><TermName>stage III HPV-positive oropharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PAH-zih-tiv OR-oh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of the following is true: (1) cancer has spread to the larynx (voice box), front part of the roof of the mouth, lower jaw, muscles that move the tongue, or to other parts of the head or neck. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes in the neck; or (2) the tumor is any size and cancer may have spread to the larynx, front part of the roof of the mouth, lower jaw, muscles that move the tongue, or to other parts of the head or neck. Cancer has spread to one or more lymph nodes that are larger than 6 centimeters, anywhere in the neck.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801110" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III HPV-positive oropharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801111" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de orofaringe positivo para el VPH en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de orofaringe positivo para el VPH en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el estadio III, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó a la laringe, la parte delantera del paladar, el maxilar inferior (mandíbula), los músculos que mueven la lengua o a otras partes de la cabeza o el cuello. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos del cuello. 2) El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a la laringe, la parte delantera del paladar, el maxilar inferior, los músculos que mueven la lengua o a otras partes de la cabeza o el cuello. Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos que miden más de 6 cm en cualquier parte del cuello.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-11-08</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258025" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/oropharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Oropharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256822" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-orofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de orofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
