<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799821">
  <TermName>stage II HPV-positive oropharyngeal cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… PAH-zih-tiv OR-oh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>One of the following is true: (1) one or more lymph nodes with cancer that is HPV p16-positive are found but the place where the cancer began is not known. The lymph nodes with cancer are 6 centimeters or smaller, on one or both sides of the neck; or (2) the tumor is 4 centimeters or smaller. Cancer has spread to lymph nodes that are 6 centimeters or smaller, on the opposite side of the neck as the primary tumor or on both sides of the neck; or (3) the tumor is larger than 4 centimeters or cancer has spread to the top of the epiglottis (the flap that covers the trachea during swallowing). Cancer may have spread to one or more lymph nodes that are 6 centimeters or smaller, anywhere in the neck.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801108" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II HPV-positive oropharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801109" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de orofaringe positivo para el VPH en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de orofaringe positivo para el VPH en estadio II</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el estadio II, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se encuentra en 1 o más ganglios linfáticos que son positivos para el VPH (se detecta una proteína llamada p16), pero se desconoce el sitio donde comenzó el cáncer. Los ganglios linfáticos cancerosos miden 6 cm o menos y están en uno o ambos lados del cuello. 2) El tumor mide 4 cm o menos. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a ganglios linfáticos en el cuello del lado contrario al tumor primario o de ambos lados del cuello; los ganglios linfáticos miden 6 cm o menos. 3) El tumor mide más de 4 cm o el cáncer se diseminó a la parte superior de la epiglotis (lámina de tejido que tapa la tráquea al tragar). Es posible que el cáncer también se haya diseminado a 1 o más ganglios linfáticos de cualquier parte del cuello; los ganglios linfáticos miden 6 cm o menos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-11-08</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258025" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/oropharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Oropharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256822" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-orofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de orofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
