<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799835"><TermName>stage IV HPV-negative oropharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... NEH-guh-tiv OR-oh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, cancer (1) has spread to the larynx (voice box), front part of the roof of the mouth, lower jaw, or muscles that move the tongue. Cancer may have spread to one lymph node that is 3 centimeters or smaller, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor; or (2) is any size and may have spread to the top of the epiglottis, larynx, front part of the roof of the mouth, lower jaw, or muscles that move the tongue. Cancer has spread to one of the following: (a) one lymph node that is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, on the same side of the neck as the primary tumor; or (b) more than one lymph node that is 6 centimeters or smaller, anywhere in the neck. In stage IVB, cancer (1) has spread to the muscle that moves the lower jaw, the bone attached to the muscle that moves the lower jaw, the base of the skull, or to the area behind the nose or around the carotid artery. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes in the neck; or (2) may be any size and may have spread to other parts of the head or neck. Cancer has spread to a lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters or has spread through the outside covering of a lymph node into nearby connective tissue. In stage IVC, cancer has spread to other parts of the body, such as the lung, liver, or bone.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801122" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV HPV-negative oropharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801123" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de orofaringe negativo para el VPH en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de orofaringe negativo para el VPH en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó a la laringe, la parte delantera del paladar, el maxilar inferior (mandíbula) o los músculos que mueven la lengua. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos. 2) El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que se haya diseminado a la parte superior de la epiglotis, la laringe, la parte delantera del paladar, el maxilar inferior o los músculos que mueven la lengua. Además, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) el cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor primario; el ganglio linfático mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 6 cm; b) El cáncer se diseminó a más de 1 ganglio linfático en cualquier parte del cuello; los ganglios linfáticos miden 6 cm o menos. En el estadio IVB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) El cáncer se diseminó al músculo que mueve el maxilar inferior, el hueso conectado al músculo que mueve el maxilar inferior, la base del cráneo o al área detrás de la nariz o alrededor de la arteria carótida. Es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos del cuello. 2) El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y es posible que el cáncer se haya diseminado a otras partes de la cabeza o el cuello. El cáncer se diseminó a 1 ganglio linfático que mide más de 6 cm, o se diseminó a través de la capa externa de 1 ganglio linfático al tejido conjuntivo cercano. En el estadio IVC, el cáncer se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo, como el pulmón, el hígado o el hueso.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2019-11-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2019-11-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258025" url="/types/head-and-neck/patient/adult/oropharyngeal-treatment-pdq">Oropharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256822" url="/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello/paciente/adulto/tratamiento-orofaringe-pdq">Tratamiento del cáncer de orofaringe</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
