<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799967">
  <TermName>zanubrutinib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ZAN-yoo-BROO-tih-nib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with another drug to treat adults with chronic lymphocytic leukemia, small lymphocytic lymphoma, or certain types of non-Hodgkin lymphoma, including follicular lymphoma, mantle cell lymphoma, marginal zone lymphoma, and Waldenström’s macroglobulinemia. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Zanubrutinib blocks a protein called BTK, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called Brukinsa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801124" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;zanubrutinib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801125" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;zanubrutinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>zanubrutinib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otro medicamento para el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia linfocítica crónica, linfoma linfocítico pequeño o ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin, como el linfoma folicular, el linfoma de células de manto, el linfoma de zona marginal  y la macroglobulinemia de Waldenström. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El zanubrutinib bloquea la proteína BTK, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama Brukinsa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2019-12-19</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-03-08</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000800195" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/zanubrutinib">Zanubrutinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
