<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000799920">
  <TermName>dense breast</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(dents brest)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term used to describe breast tissue that has more fibrous and glandular tissue than fatty tissue. Dense breast tissue can only be seen on a mammogram. Having dense breast tissue may make it harder to see breast cancer or other changes in the breast on a mammogram. Women with dense breast tissue have a higher risk of breast cancer than those with mostly fatty or less dense breast tissue. Having dense breast tissue is common, especially in younger women and in women taking hormone therapy for menopause.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802549" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dense breast&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802550" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mama densa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mama densa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que describe el tejido de la mama con más contenido de fibras y glándulas que grasa. El tejido de mama denso solo se ve en una mamografía. Es posible que tener este tipo de tejido dificulte la detección de cáncer de mama o de otros cambios de la mama en las imágenes de la mamografía. Las mujeres con tejido denso en la mama tienen un riesgo más alto de cáncer de mama en comparación con las mujeres que tienen un tejido menos denso o con más grasa. Este tipo de tejido es muy común, en especial, en las mujeres jóvenes y en quienes reciben terapia hormonal para la menopausia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-02-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-02-27</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/breast-changes/dense-breasts">Dense Breasts: Answers to Commonly Asked Questions</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/significado-cambios-en-los-senos/senos-densos">Senos densos: Respuestas a las preguntas más frecuentes</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
