<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800014">
  <TermName>CM-AVM syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare genetic condition that causes abnormalities of blood vessels, including swelling of the capillaries (small blood vessels) near the surface of the skin. The swollen capillaries usually appear as small, round, pink or red spots on the skin of the face, arms, and legs. They may appear at birth or develop during childhood. More serious blood vessel abnormalities that affect the skin, muscle, bone, spine, brain, and heart may also occur. These can lead to serious problems, including abnormal bleeding, migraines, seizures, and congestive heart failure. CM-AVM syndrome is a type of disease called a RASopathy that is caused by mutations (changes) in the RASA1 gene. This gene makes a protein involved in a cell signaling pathway that controls many important cell functions. Also called capillary malformation-arteriovenous malformation syndrome.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802557" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CM-AVM syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802558" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de MC-MAV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome de MC-MAV</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Afección genética rara que causa anomalías en los vasos sanguíneos, como inflamación de los capilares (vasos sanguíneos pequeños) cerca de la superficie de la piel. Los capilares inflamados por lo general se ven como pequeños puntos redondos, rojos o rosados, en la piel de la cara, los brazos o las piernas. Aparecen desde el nacimiento o durante la niñez. En ocasiones,  también hay anomalías más graves en los vasos sanguíneos que afectan la piel, los músculos, los huesos, la columna vertebral, el encéfalo y el corazón. Es posible que esto  cause problemas graves como sangrados anormales, migrañas, convulsiones e insuficiencia cardíaca congestiva.  El síndrome de MC-MAV es un tipo de rasopatía causada por mutaciones (cambios) en el gen  
      <GeneName>RASA1</GeneName>
       que elabora una proteína de una vía de señalización que controla muchas funciones importantes de la célula. También se llama síndrome de malformación capilar-malformación arteriovenosa.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
