<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800021">
  <TermName>RASopathy syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ras-AH-puh-thee SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A group of rare conditions caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes that make proteins involved in the Ras/MAPK cell signaling pathway. This pathway plays an important role in controlling many cell functions, including cell growth, cell maturation, and cell death. There are many different RASopathy syndromes. Most of these syndromes are marked by unusual facial features, heart defects, skin abnormalities, and problems with the eyes, muscles, and bones. There may also be gastrointestinal and nervous system problems and growth, learning, and developmental delays. Having a RASopathy syndrome may increase a person’s risk of certain types of cancer. RASopathy syndromes include cardiofaciocutaneous syndrome, Costello syndrome, Legius syndrome, neurofibromatosis type 1, Noonan syndrome, and capillary malformation-arteriovenous malformation syndrome.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802563" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;RASopathy syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802564" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rasopatía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>rasopatía</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cada una de las afecciones raras causadas por mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que elaboran proteínas de la vía de señalización Ras/MAPK. Esta vía cumple una función de control importante de muchas funciones de la célula, como la multiplicación, la maduración y la muerte celular. Hay muchos tipos de rasopatías, que en su mayoría se caracterizan por rasgos faciales atípicos, defectos cardíacos, anomalías en la piel y problemas en los ojos, los músculos y los huesos. A veces también hay problemas gastrointestinales y del sistema nervioso, así como retrasos en el  crecimiento, el aprendizaje y el desarrollo. Tener una rasopatía  quizá aumente el riesgo de ciertos tipos de cáncer. El síndrome  cardiofaciocutáneo, el síndrome de Costello, el síndrome de Legius, la neurofibromatosis de tipo 1, el síndrome de Noonan y el síndrome de malformación capilar-malformación arteriovenosa son tipos de rasopatías.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
