<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800032"><TermName>pericarditis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAYR-ih-kar-DY-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which the pericardium (the sac around the heart) becomes inflamed. Pericarditis is usually caused by an infection, but it may also be caused by an autoimmune disorder or by cancer or cancer treatment (such as chemotherapy and radiation therapy). It may also be caused by heart attack, heart surgery, injury to the chest, kidney failure, and certain medicines. The most common symptom of pericarditis is chest pain. Other signs and symptoms may include fever, cough, fast or abnormal heartbeat, trouble breathing, anxiety, fatigue, and swelling of the ankles, feet, and legs. Pericarditis is most common in men aged 20 to 50 years.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802577" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pericarditis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802578" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pericarditis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pericarditis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección que describe la inflamación del pericardio (saco que rodea el corazón). La causa de la pericarditis por lo general es una infección, pero a veces también se produce por un  trastorno autoinmunitario, un cáncer o un tratamiento del cáncer (como la quimioterapia o la radioterapia). Otras causas de pericarditis son  un infarto de miocardio, una cirugía cardíaca, una herida en el tórax,  la insuficiencia renal o el  uso de ciertos medicamentos. El signo más frecuente de la pericarditis es el dolor de tórax. Otros signos y síntomas incluyen fiebre, tos, latidos cardíacos rápidos o anormales, problemas para respirar, ansiedad, fatiga e hinchazón de  los tobillos, los pies y las piernas. La pericarditis es más frecuente en hombres de 20 a 50 años.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
