<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800017"><TermName>pancytopenia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(pan-SY-toh-PEE-nee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which there is a lower-than-normal number of red and white blood cells and platelets in the blood. Pancytopenia occurs when there is a problem with the blood-forming stem cells in the bone marrow. Signs and symptoms include fatigue, weakness, dizziness, trouble breathing, fast heartbeat, fever, pale skin, purple or red spots on the skin, rash, easy bruising, and abnormal bleeding. Pancytopenia may be caused by certain autoimmune, bone marrow, or genetic disorders. It may also be caused by infection, poor nutrition, pregnancy, cancer treatment (such as chemotherapy or radiation therapy), or exposure to certain toxins, chemicals, or medicines.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802559" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancytopenia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802560" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancitopenia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pancitopenia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la cual el número de glóbulos rojos, glóbulos blancos y plaquetas en la sangre es más bajo de lo normal. La pancitopenia se produce cuando hay un problema con las células madre formadoras de sangre en la médula ósea. Los signos y síntomas incluyen cansancio, debilidad, mareos, dificultad para respirar, latidos cardíacos acelerados, fiebre, palidez, manchas moradas o rojas en la piel, erupción, tendencia a formar moretones, y sangrado anormal. Algunos trastornos autoinmunitarios, de la médula ósea o genéticos  causan pancitopenia. Otras causas son infecciones, desnutrición, embarazo, tratamientos del cáncer (como quimioterapia o radioterapia), o  exposición a ciertas toxinas, sustancias químicas o medicamentos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
