<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800019"><TermName>agranulocytosis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ay-GRAN-yoo-loh-sy-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A serious condition that occurs when there is an extremely low number of granulocytes (a type of white blood cell) in the blood. Granulocytes are an important part of the immune system and help the body fight infection. Having very low levels of granulocytes in the blood can lead to serious or life-threatening infections. Signs and symptoms of agranulocytosis include fever, chills, weakness, sore throat, sores in the mouth or throat, bleeding gums, bone pain, low blood pressure, fast heartbeat, and trouble breathing. Agranulocytosis may be inherited or caused by certain autoimmune or bone marrow disorders, infection, poor nutrition, cancer treatment (such as chemotherapy or bone marrow transplant), or exposure to certain toxins, chemicals, or medicines.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802561" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;agranulocytosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802562" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;agranulocitosis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>agranulocitosis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección grave que se produce cuando hay un número muy bajo de granulocitos (tipo de glóbulo blanco) en la sangre. Los granulocitos son una parte importante del sistema inmunológico y ayudan a combatir las infecciones. Una cantidad muy baja de granulocitos en la sangre da lugar a infecciones potencialmente mortales. Los signos y síntomas de la agranulocitosis incluyen fiebre, escalofríos, debilidad, dolor de garganta, llagas en la boca o la garganta, sangrado de las encías, dolor de hueso, presión arterial baja, latidos cardíacos rápidos y dificultad para respirar. A veces la agranulocitosis es hereditaria, otras causas son ciertos trastornos autoinmunitarios o de la médula ósea,   infecciones, desnutrición, tratamientos contra el cáncer (como la quimioterapia o un transplante de médula ósea), o  la exposición a ciertas toxinas, sustancias químicas o medicamentos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
