<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800023"><TermName>cardiofaciocutaneous syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAR-dee-oh-FAY-shee-oh-kyoo-TAY-nee-us SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare genetic
          condition that affects many parts of the body, especially
          the heart, face, and skin. People with
          cardiofaciocutaneous syndrome usually have growth,
          developmental, and learning delays. Other signs and
          symptoms include heart defects, an abnormally large head,
          unusual facial features, and problems with the skin, eyes,
          and the gastrointestinal and nervous systems. People with
          cardiofaciocutaneous syndrome may also have thin, dry,
          curly hair and sparse or no eyelashes or eyebrows.
          Cardiofaciocutaneous syndrome is a type of disease
          called a RASopathy that is caused by mutations (changes) in
          the BRAF, MAP2K1, MAP2K2, or KRAS gene. These genes make
          proteins involved in a cell signaling pathway that controls
          many important cell functions. Also called CFC syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802565" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cardiofaciocutaneous syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802566" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome cardiofaciocutáneo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome cardiofaciocutáneo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección genética rara que afecta muchas partes del cuerpo, en especial el corazón, la cara y la piel. Las personas con
          síndrome cardiofaciocutáneo por lo general tienen retrasos en el crecimiento, el desarrollo y el aprendizaje. Otros signos y síntomas incluyen defectos cardíacos, una cabeza más grande de lo normal, rasgos faciales atípicos y problemas en la piel, los ojos, el tubo gastrointestinal y el sistema nervioso. Además, las personas afectadas a veces tienen el cabello fino, seco y rizado, y no tienen pestañas ni cejas,  o son escasas.
          El síndrome cardiofaciocutáneo es un tipo de rasopatía causada por mutaciones (cambios) en los genes <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>, <GeneName>MAP2K1</GeneName>, <GeneName>MAP2K2</GeneName> o <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName> que elaboran proteínas de una vía de señalización celular que controla muchas funciones importantes de la célula. También se llama síndrome CFC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
