<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800034"><TermName>pulmonary embolism</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PUL-muh-NAYR-ee EM-boh-lih-zum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A sudden blockage of an artery (blood vessel) in the lung. A pulmonary embolism usually occurs when a blood clot in a deep vein in the leg or pelvis breaks loose and travels through the blood to the lungs. It may not cause any signs or symptoms, or it may cause shortness of breath, chest pain, a bloody cough, or a fast or abnormal heartbeat. A pulmonary embolism can be life-threatening, especially if the blood clot is large or there are many clots. It may be caused by surgery and by certain medical conditions, such as cancer, heart disease, or lung disease. It can also be caused by taking medicines that contain hormones, pregnancy and childbirth, not moving for long periods of time, older age, smoking, obesity, and having a family history of blood clots or pulmonary embolism.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802579" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pulmonary embolism&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802580" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;embolia pulmonar&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>embolia pulmonar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Obstrucción súbita de una arteria (vaso sanguíneo) en el pulmón. Una embolia pulmonar por lo general ocurre cuando se desprende un coágulo sanguíneo de una vena profunda de la extremidad inferior o la pelvis y este coágulo llega a los pulmones porque viaja a través de la corriente sanguínea. A veces no causa signos ni síntomas, pero otras veces causa dificultades para respirar, dolor de tórax, tos con sangre, o latidos cardíacos rápidos o anormales. La embolia pulmonar es potencialmente mortal, en especial si el coágulo sanguíneo es grande o cuando hay varios coágulos. Una cirugía, ciertas afecciones como  un cáncer,  una cardiopatía o una enfermedad pulmonar son causas de la embolia pulmonar. Otras causas son el uso de ciertos medicamentos que contienen hormonas, el embarazo y el parto, estar quieto durante períodos largos, la edad avanzada, el consumo de cigarrillos, la obesidad y los antecedentes familiares de coágulos sanguíneos o embolia pulmonar. También se llama embolismo pulmonar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
