<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800176"><TermName>parathyroid hyperplasia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAYR-uh-THY-royd HY-per-PLAY-zhuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which the parathyroid glands (four pea-sized glands found in the neck) are larger than normal. This condition may cause the glands to make too much parathyroid hormone, which can lead to a loss of calcium from the bones, too much calcium in the blood, broken bones, and other health problems. Parathyroid hyperplasia may be caused by chronic kidney disease, low vitamin D levels, and other medical conditions. It may also occur in people who have certain inherited disorders, including multiple endocrine neoplasia (MEN) syndrome and familial isolated hyperparathyroidism.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802592" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;parathyroid hyperplasia&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802593" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hiperplasia paratiroidea&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>hiperplasia paratiroidea</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección que se produce cuando las glándulas paratiroideas (cuatro glándulas del tamaño de una arveja que se encuentran en el cuello) son más grandes  que lo normal. Esta afección a veces produce aumento de la producción de hormona paratiroidea que lleva a una concentración alta de calcio en la sangre, pérdida de calcio en los huesos y fracturas, además de otros problemas de salud. Las causas de la hiperplasia paratiroidea son enfermedad renal crónica, concentraciones bajas de vitamina D y otras afecciones. También es posible que se presente en personas con determinados trastornos hereditarios, como  el síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple (NEM) y el hiperparatiroidismo familiar aislado. También se llama hiperplasia de paratiroides.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
