<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800173"><TermName>evidence-based medicine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EH-vih-dents-bayst MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A systematic approach to medicine in which doctors and other health care professionals use the best available scientific evidence from clinical research to help make decisions about the care of individual patients. A physician’s clinical experience and the patient’s values and preferences are also important in the process of using the evidence to make decisions. The use of evidence-based medicine may help plan the best treatment and improve quality of care and patient outcomes. Also called EBM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802590" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;evidence-based medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802591" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina basada en la evidencia&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/><SpanishTermName>medicina basada en la evidencia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Abordaje sistemático de la medicina según el cual profesionales médicos y de otras áreas de la salud utilizan la mejor evidencia científica  disponible a partir de la investigación clínica para tomar decisiones en relación con la atención de cada paciente. Cuando se utiliza la evidencia científica con el fin de tomar decisiones también se tienen en cuenta otros factores importantes, como la experiencia profesional en la práctica médica y los valores  y preferencias de cada paciente. La medicina basada en la evidencia sirve para planificar el tratamiento más apropiado y mejorar la calidad de vida y los desenlaces de los pacientes. También se llama MBE, medicina basada en pruebas, medicina científico-estadística, medicina factual, medicina fundamentada, medicina metacrítica y medicina probatoria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
