<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800171">
  <TermName>genomic instability</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(jeh-NOH-mik in-stuh-BIH-lih-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The increased tendency for DNA mutations (changes) and other genetic changes to occur during cell division. Genomic instability is caused by defects in certain processes that control the way cells divide. It occurs in many types of cancer. These defects may include mutations in certain genes involved in repairing damaged DNA or mistakes that don’t get corrected when DNA is copied in a cell. They may also include defects such as broken, missing, rearranged, or extra chromosomes. Studying genomic instability may help researchers understand how certain diseases, such as cancer, form. This may lead to new ways to diagnose, treat, and prevent disease.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802588" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;genomic instability&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802589" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inestabilidad genómica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>inestabilidad genómica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Aumento en la tendencia de presentar mutaciones (cambios) en el ADN u otros cambios genéticos que aparecen durante la división celular. Esta inestabilidad ocurre en muchos tipos de cáncer. La causa de la inestabilidad genómica son  defectos en determinados procesos que controlan la forma en que la célula se divide. Ejemplos de estos defectos son las mutaciones en determinados genes que participan en la reparación del daño al ADN, o los errores que no  se corrigen cuando el ADN se copia en la célula. Otros defectos son cromosomas rotos, faltantes, reordenados o adicionales. El estudio de la inestabilidad genómica ayuda a los investigadores a entender cómo se forman ciertas enfermedades como el cáncer, y es posible que esto lleve al descubrimiento de nuevas formas de diagnosticar, tratar y prevenir enfermedades.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-04-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
