<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800165">
  <TermName>Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KLIH-nih-kul LA-bruh-tor-ee im-PROOV-ment uh-MEND-ments)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Changes to a 1988 U.S. law that sets the standards for all laboratory testing that is done on human tissue, blood, and other body fluid samples used to screen, diagnose, prevent, or treat a disease or condition. The Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments program makes sure laboratories follow these standards and have quality control programs in place so that patient test results are accurate and reliable. The federal government agencies that manage the Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments program are the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Certain types of laboratory testing, such as testing done in clinical trials, research studies, crime labs, and work-related drug testing, are not covered by the Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments program. Also called CLIA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802583" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802584" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Enmiendas para el Mejoramiento de Laboratorios Clínicos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Enmiendas para el Mejoramiento de Laboratorios Clínicos</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Reforma a la ley  de 1988  de los Estados Unidos que fija las normas exigidas para hacer  pruebas de laboratorio en tejidos humanos, sangre y otras muestras de líquidos corporales que se usan para la detección, el diagnóstico, la prevención o el tratamiento de una enfermedad o afección. El programa de las  Enmiendas para el Mejoramiento de Laboratorios Clínicos (CLIA) asegura que los laboratorios cumplan estas normas y que cuenten con programas de control de calidad en curso para garantizar que los resultados de las pruebas sean exactos y confiables. Las agencias del Gobierno federal que dirigen este programa son  la Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos (FDA), los Centros de Servicios de Medicare y Medicaid (CMS) y los Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades (CDC). El programa no abarca algunas pruebas de laboratorio, como las pruebas de los ensayos clínicos, los estudios de investigación, los laboratorios de criminalística y los controles laborales de consumo de drogas. También se llama CLIA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-04-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
