<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800248">
  <TermName>Enhertu</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(en-HER-too)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used to treat adults with certain types of HER2-positive or HER2-low breast cancer, HER2-positive stomach cancer, gastroesophageal junction cancer, or other solid tumor, or non-small cell lung cancer that has a certain mutation in the 
      <GeneName>HER2</GeneName>
       gene. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Enhertu contains a monoclonal antibody called trastuzumab that binds to a protein called HER2, which is found on some cancer cells. It also contains an anticancer drug called deruxtecan, which may help kill cancer cells. Enhertu is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called fam-trastuzumab deruxtecan and trastuzumab deruxtecan.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801134" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Enhertu&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801135" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Enhertu&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Enhertu</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer de mama positivo para HER2 o con HER2 bajo,  cáncer de estómago, cáncer de unión gastroesofágica u otro tumor sólido positivos para HER2, o cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que tiene determinada mutación en el gen 
      <GeneName>HER2</GeneName>
      . También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Enhertu contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal llamado trastuzumab que se une a una proteína llamada HER2, presente en algunas células cancerosas. Además contiene un medicamento contra el cáncer llamado deruxtecán, que quizás ayude a destruir células cancerosas. Enhertu es un tipo de conjugado anticuerpo-fármaco. También se llama fam-trastuzumab deruxtecán y trastuzumab deruxtecán.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-02</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-10</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000800219" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/famtrastuzumabderuxtecan-nxki">Fam-Trastuzumab Deruxtecan-nxki</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
