<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800255">
  <TermName>plantar pit</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PLAN-ter ...)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A small depression in the skin on the sole of the foot. Depressions may also be seen on the palm of the hand (palmar pits). They are usually pink or flesh-colored and range from 2 to 3 mm in diameter and 1 to 3 mm in depth. Plantar pits are often more visible after a brief soaking of the hands or feet. This condition is associated with basal cell nevus syndrome, which is a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of basal cell carcinoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A tiny dent in the skin on the bottom (sole) of the foot. Plantar pits are usually pink or skin-colored and can often be seen more easily after soaking the feet in water. They are often found in people with a rare, inherited condition called basal cell nevus syndrome (BCNS). People with BCNS have a very high risk of developing basal cell skin cancer and are also at risk of developing other types of cancer, including medulloblastoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801138" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;plantar pit&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000801139" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hoyuelo plantar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800271" type="image/jpeg" alt="Photograph showing three small, flesh-colored depressions on the palm of the hand." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">Palmar pits are small depressions in the skin on the palm of the hand that may be seen in individuals with basal cell nevus syndrome, a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of basal cell carcinoma. Depressions may also be seen on the sole of the foot (plantar pits, not shown). </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800271" type="image/jpeg" alt="Photograph showing three small, flesh-colored depressions on the palm of the hand." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6">
    <Caption language="en">Palmar pits are small depressions in the skin on the palm of the hand that may be seen in individuals with basal cell nevus syndrome, a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of basal cell carcinoma. Depressions may also be seen on the sole of the foot (plantar pits, not shown). </Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800271" type="image/jpeg" alt="Fotografía en la que se observan tres depresiones pequeñas del color de la piel en la palma de la mano." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Los hoyuelos palmares son depresiones pequeñas en la piel de la palma de la mano que a veces se encuentran en personas con el síndrome del nevo de células basales, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de carcinoma de células basales. Estas depresiones en ocasiones se forman en la planta del pie (hoyuelos plantares).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000800271" type="image/jpeg" alt="Fotografía en la que se observan tres depresiones pequeñas del color de la piel en la palma de la mano." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8">
    <Caption language="es">Los hoyuelos palmares son depresiones pequeñas en la piel de la palma de la mano que a veces se encuentran en personas con el síndrome del nevo de células basales, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de carcinoma de células basales. Estas depresiones en ocasiones  se forman en la planta del pie (hoyuelos plantares).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>hoyuelo plantar</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Depresión pequeña en la piel de la planta del pie. Estas depresiones a veces se encuentran en la palma de la mano (hoyuelos palmares). Con frecuencia son rosados o del color de la piel. Su diámetro oscila entre 2 y 3 mm y su profundidad entre 1 y 3 mm. Los hoyuelos a menudo se resaltan después de humedecer las manos o los pies. Esta afección se relaciona con el síndrome del nevo de células basales, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de carcinoma de células basales.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Hendidura pequeña en la piel de la planta del pie. Los hoyuelos plantares con frecuencia son rosados o del color de la piel y suele ser más fácil verlos después de mojar los pies. A menudo se encuentran en personas con una afección hereditaria rara llamada síndrome del nevo de células basales (SNCB). Las personas con SNCB tienen un riesgo muy alto de cáncer de piel de células basales y también tienen riesgo de otros tipos de cáncer, como el meduloblastoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-01-03</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000256555" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">basal cell nevus syndrome</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000256555" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">síndrome de nevo de células basales</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
