<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800257"><TermName>oral papilloma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(OR-ul PA-pih-LOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign growth of epithelial cells in the mouth or on the lips. This condition is associated with Cowden syndrome, which is a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of several types of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer), wart-like growth that occurs on the lips or in the mouth, including the tongue, gums, tonsils, and back of the throat. Oral papillomas often appear as pink or white bumps that may be different sizes. They are usually painless and do not cause symptoms. Oral papillomas may be caused by chronic infection with certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV). They may also be found in people with a rare, inherited condition called Cowden syndrome. Oral papillomas most often occur in adults.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801140" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oral papilloma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801141" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;papiloma oral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800279" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel photograph showing the tongues of two individuals with Cowden syndrome. The left panel shows a tongue covered with many small white bumps. The right panel shows a tongue with larger, irregularly shaped growths on its surface." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Oral papillomas are benign growths of epithelial cells that may be seen in individuals with Cowden syndrome, a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of several types of cancer. The papillomas may vary in size.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800279" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel photograph showing the tongues of two individuals with Cowden syndrome. The left panel shows a tongue covered with many small white bumps. The right panel shows a tongue with larger, irregularly shaped growths on its surface." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_6"><Caption language="en">Oral papillomas are benign (not cancer), wart-like growths that occur on the lips or in the mouth, including the tongue, and may be different sizes. They may be seen in people with Cowden syndrome, a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of several types of cancer.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800279" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dos fotografías que muestran la lengua de dos personas con síndrome de Cowden. A la izquierda se observa una lengua cubierta por muchos tumores pequeños de color blanco. A la derecha se observa una lengua con tumores superficiales más grandes con forma irregular." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Los papilomas orales son tumores benignos  de células epiteliales que a veces se encuentran en personas con el síndrome de Cowden, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de varios tipos de cáncer. El tamaño de los papilomas es variable. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800279" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dos fotografías que muestran la lengua de dos personas con síndrome de Cowden. A la izquierda se observa una lengua cubierta por muchos tumores pequeños de color blanco. A la derecha se observa una lengua con tumores superficiales más grandes con forma irregular." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_8"><Caption language="es">Los papilomas orales son tumores benignos (no cancerosos), parecidos a las verrugas, que se forman en los labios o en la boca, incluso en la lengua. Son de diferentes tamaños  y en ocasiones se observan en personas con síndrome de Cowden, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación  de varios tipos de cáncer.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>papiloma oral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor benigno de células epiteliales de la boca o los labios. Esta afección se relaciona con el síndrome de Cowden, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de varios tipos de cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso) parecido a una verruga, que se presenta en la boca o los labios, incluso en la lengua, la encía, las amígdalas y la parte posterior de la garganta. Los papilomas orales suelen verse como bultos rosados o blancos de diferentes tamaños. Por lo general, no producen dolor ni síntomas. Es posible que la causa de esta afección sea una infección crónica por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH). También se encuentran en personas con una afección hereditaria rara llamada síndrome de Cowden. Los papilomas orales son más frecuentes en adultos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
