<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800259"><TermName>sebaceous epithelioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(seh-BAY-shus EH-pih-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign yellow or flesh-colored lesion originating from an oil gland in the skin. Sebaceous epitheliomas are typically found on the face or neck. They may be associated with Muir-Torre syndrome, which is a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of several types of cancer.  Also called sebaceoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, benign (not cancer) tumor that forms in an oil gland in the skin. Most sebaceous epitheliomas appear as yellow, orange, or skin-colored bumps that occur on the head or neck. They tend to grow slowly and are painless. Sebaceous epitheliomas may be found in people with a rare, inherited condition called Muir-Torre syndrome (MTS). People with MTS have an increased risk of developing several types of cancer. Sebaceous epitheliomas most often occur in older adults. Also called sebaceoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801142" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sebaceous epithelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000801143" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;epitelioma sebáceo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800272" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel photograph showing the forehead of an individual with three small, flesh-colored bumps on the surface of the skin (left panel) and a close-up of a single bump on the skin with hair surrounding it (right panel)." language="en" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Sebaceous epitheliomas (or sebaceomas) are benign lesions originating from oil glands in the skin. They may be seen in individuals with Muir-Torre syndrome, a hereditary syndrome associated with the development of several types of cancer. They are commonly found on the face or neck.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000800272" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dos fotografías que muestran la frente de una persona. A la izquierda se observan tres bultos pequeños del color de la piel y a la derecha se observan en una ampliación un solo bulto en la piel y el pelo que lo rodea." language="es" audience="Health_professionals" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Los epiteliomas sebáceos o sebaceomas son lesiones benignas que se originan en las glándulas sebáceas de la piel. A veces se observan en personas con el síndrome de Muir-Torre, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de varios tipos de cáncer. Estas lesiones por lo general se encuentran en la cara o el cuello.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>epitelioma sebáceo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Lesión benigna amarilla o del color de la piel que se origina en una glándula sebácea de la piel. Los epiteliomas sebáceos por lo general se encuentran en la cara o el cuello. A veces se relacionan con el síndrome de Muir-Torre, un síndrome hereditario asociado con la formación de varios tipos de cáncer. También se llama sebaceoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor raro, benigno (no canceroso) que se forma en una glándula sebácea de la piel. La mayoría de los  epiteliomas sebáceos son   bultos amarillos, naranjas o del color de la piel que se encuentran en la cabeza o el cuello. Tienden a crecer de forma lenta y no son dolorosos. Es posible que los epiteliomas sebáceos surjan en personas con una afección hereditaria rara llamada síndrome de Muir-Torre (SMT). Las personas con SMT tienen un aumento en el riesgo de varios tipos de cáncer. Los epiteliomas sebáceos se presentan con más frecuencia en adultos mayores. También se llama sebaceoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-01-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
