<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800881">
  <TermName>Turalio</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(tur-A-lee-oh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with tenosynovial giant cell tumor (a rare, usually benign tumor that affects the joints). It is used in patients who have a severe form of the disease that is not likely to get better with surgery. It is also being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer and other conditions. Turalio blocks certain proteins, which may help keep tumor cells from growing and spreading. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called pexidartinib hydrochloride.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802638" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Turalio&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802639" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Turalio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Turalio</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con tumor tenosinovial de células gigantes (tumor raro, por lo general benigno que afecta las articulaciones). Se utiliza en adultos con una forma grave de la enfermedad que es probable que no mejore con cirugía. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer y otras afecciones. Turalio bloquea determinadas proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación y la diseminación de células tumorales. Es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama clorhidrato de pexidartinib.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-03-19</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-10-22</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000800888" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/pexidartinib">Pexidartinib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
