<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800818">
  <TermName>bariatric surgery</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(BAYR-ee-A-trik SER-juh-ree)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Surgery done to help people who are obese lose weight. There are different types of  bariatric surgery, and each type changes the way the digestive system works. Some types make the stomach smaller, which decreases the amount of food that it can hold so the person feels full sooner and eats less. Other types make changes to the stomach and the small intestine, which decreases the nutrients and calories that are absorbed from food.  Bariatric surgery can improve many obesity-related health problems, such as diabetes, high blood pressure, unhealthy cholesterol levels, sleep apnea, and knee, hip, or other body pain. Having bariatric surgery may also decrease the risk of some cancers, including endometrial cancer. Also called weight loss surgery.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802626" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bariatric surgery&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802627" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cirugía bariátrica&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cirugía bariátrica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cirugía que ayuda a las personas obesas a adelgazar. Hay diferentes tipos de cirugía bariátrica, y todas cambian el funcionamiento del sistema digestivo. Algunos tipos achican el estómago y reducen su capacidad para contener alimentos, de manera que la persona se siente satisfecha más rápido y come menos.  Otros tipos modifican el estómago y el intestino delgado, de manera que se disminuye la absorción de nutrientes y calorías de los alimentos. Es posible que la cirugía bariátrica mejore muchos problemas de salud relacionados con la obesidad, como la diabetes, la hipertensión, las concentraciones altas de colesterol, la apnea del sueño, y los dolores de rodilla, cadera u otras partes del cuerpo. La cirugía bariátrica quizás disminuya el riesgo de algunos cánceres, como el cáncer de endometrio. También se llama cirugía para adelgazar y operación de cirugía bariátrica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/obesity/obesity-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Obesity and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/obesidad/hoja-informativa-obesidad" UseWith="es">Obesidad y cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
