<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800814"><TermName>germinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(JER-mih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of tumor that begins in germ cells (cells that form sperm or eggs). Germinomas can occur in the ovaries or testicles or other parts of the body, but they occur most often in the central nervous system (brain and spinal cord). This happens when a germ cell travels to the brain during fetal development and later becomes a germ cell tumor. Some germinomas make a hormone called beta-human chorionic gonadotropin (beta-HCG). Germinomas are usually malignant (cancer) but tend to grow and spread slowly and can usually be cured. They are the most common type of central nervous system germ cell tumor. They usually occur in teenagers and young adults.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802622" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;germinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802623" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;germinoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>germinoma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tumor que empieza en las células germinativas (células que se convierten en los espermatozoides o los óvulos).  Los germinomas surgen en los ovarios, los testículos u otras partes del cuerpo, más a menudo en el sistema nervioso central (encéfalo y médula espinal). Esto sucede cuando una célula germinativa se desplaza hasta el encéfalo durante el desarrollo fetal y más tarde se transforma en una célula tumoral. Algunos germinomas elaboran una hormona llamada gonadotropina coriónica humana β (GCH-β). Por lo general, los germinomas son malignos (cáncer) pero suelen crecer y diseminarse de forma lenta, y a menudo se curan. Son el tipo más común de tumor de células germinativas del sistema nervioso central, y casi siempre se presentan en adolescentes y adultos jóvenes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-05-06</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
