<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800816">
  <TermName>nongerminoma</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(non-JER-mih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of tumor that begins in germ cells (cells that form sperm or eggs). Nongerminomas can occur in the ovaries or testicles or other parts of the body, but they occur most often in the central nervous system (brain and spinal cord). This happens when a germ cell travels to the brain during fetal development and later becomes a germ cell tumor. There are several types of nongerminoma tumors, including embryonal carcinoma, yolk sac tumor, choriocarcinoma, teratoma, and mixed germ cell tumor. Most nongerminomas make hormones, such as alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) and beta-human chorionic gonadotropin (beta-hCG). Nongerminomas are usually malignant (cancer) and tend to grow and spread quickly. They usually occur in children.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802624" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nongerminoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802625" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor no germinomatoso&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor no germinomatoso</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de tumor que empieza en las células germinativas (células que se convierten en los espermatozoides o los óvulos). Los tumores no germinomatosos surgen en los ovarios, los testículos u otras partes del cuerpo, más a menudo en el sistema nervioso central (encéfalo y médula espinal). Esto sucede cuando una célula germinativa se desplaza hasta el encéfalo durante el desarrollo fetal y más tarde se transforma en una célula tumoral. Hay varios tipos de tumores no germinomatosos, como el carcinoma embrionario, el tumor de saco vitelino, el coriocarcinoma, el teratoma y el tumor mixto de células germinativas. La mayoría de los tumores no germinomatosos elaboran hormonas, como la α-fetoproteína (AFP) y la gonadotropina coriónica humana β (GCH-β). Por lo general, los tumores no germinomatosos son malignos (cáncer) y suelen crecer y diseminarse rápido. A menudo se presentan en niños.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-06</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
