<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800912">
  <TermName>autonomic nervous system disorder</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(AW-toh-NAH-mik NER-vus SIS-tem dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition that affects the part of the nervous system called the autonomic nervous system (ANS). The ANS controls many important automatic body processes, such as blood pressure, heart rate, breathing, body temperature, digestion, sweating, urination, and sexual response. An autonomic nervous system disorder can affect all or part of the ANS and can cause serious problems, such as heart and blood pressure problems, trouble breathing or swallowing, or impotence in males. There are many different types of autonomic nervous system disorders. They may be inherited or caused by injury or by conditions such as diabetes, Parkinson disease, autoimmune disease, and alcoholism. Sometimes, the cause is not known. Also called dysautonomia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802648" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;autonomic nervous system disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802649" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno del sistema nervioso autónomo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>trastorno del sistema nervioso autónomo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección de la parte del sistema nervioso llamada sistema nervioso autónomo (SNA). El SNA controla muchos procesos automáticos vitales para el organismo, como la presión arterial, la frecuencia cardíaca, la respiración, la temperatura corporal, la digestión, la transpiración, la micción (acción de orinar) y la respuesta sexual. Un trastorno del sistema nervioso autónomo puede afectar todo el SNA o una parte de este, y a veces causa problemas graves, como alteraciones del corazón y la presión arterial, dificultades para respirar o tragar, e impotencia en los hombres. Hay muchos tipos de trastornos del sistema nervioso autónomo. Es posible que sean hereditarios o causados  por  una lesión, o por afecciones como la diabetes, la enfermedad de Parkinson, una enfermedad autoinmunitaria o  el alcoholismo. En ocasiones, la causa es desconocida. También se llama disautonomía.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
