<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800921">
  <TermName>vocational rehabilitation counselor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(voh-KAY-shuh-nul REE-huh-BIH-lih-TAY-shun KOWN-seh-ler)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A person who has special training to help people with a disability find a job or career. A vocational rehabilitation counselor evaluates a person’s education, training, skills, interests, and financial needs to help him or her make employment decisions. A vocational rehabilitation counselor also monitors job performance and provides counseling, education, and resources for job-related issues and access to special accommodations in the workplace. Also called vocational therapist.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vocational rehabilitation counselor&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802659" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;consejero de rehabilitación profesional&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>consejero de rehabilitación profesional</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Persona que tiene una formación especial para ayudar a la gente con  incapacidad a encontrar un empleo o una profesión. El consejero de rehabilitación profesional tiene en cuenta la educación y  capacitación, las habilidades, los intereses y las necesidades económicas para asesorar a las personas en la toma de decisiones ocupacionales. Además, el consejero de rehabilitación profesional supervisa el desempeño laboral y brinda asesoramiento, educación y recursos sobre aspectos del trabajo, así como acceso a condiciones de adaptación especiales según el tipo de incapacidad. También se llama asesor de rehabilitación vocacional, consejero de rehabilitación vocacional y terapeuta de orientación profesional.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
