<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800902"><TermName>interval breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-ter-vul brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Breast cancer that is diagnosed during the time between a regular screening mammogram that appears normal and the next screening mammogram. A “true” interval breast cancer was not present when the last screening mammogram was done. A “missed” interval breast cancer was present but missed when the last screening mammogram was read. Interval breast cancers tend to be larger, grow and spread more quickly, and have a worse prognosis than those found on screening mammograms. Researchers are studying interval breast cancer to learn how to identify women who may need more frequent mammograms or other screening tests for breast cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802640" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;interval breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802641" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama de intervalo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama de intervalo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer de mama que se diagnostica durante el periodo de tiempo entre una mamografía de detección de rutina que parece normal y la siguiente mamografía.  Un cáncer de mama de intervalo "oculto" es el que estaba presente pero no se identificó cuando se interpretó la última mamografía de detección. Un cáncer de mama de intervalo "verdadero" es el que no estaba presente cuando se hizo la última mamografía de detección. Estos cánceres verdaderos suelen ser más grandes, crecen y se diseminan más rápido, y tienen peor pronóstico que los que se detectan en las mamografías. Los investigadores estudian este tipo de cáncer de mama para saber cuáles mujeres necesitan más mamografías u otros exámenes de detección del cáncer de mama.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2020-06-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
