<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800909">
  <TermName>anticipatory nausea and vomiting</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(an-TIH-suh-puh-TOR-ee NAW-zee-uh … VAH-mih-ting)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Nausea and vomiting that may occur before a chemotherapy treatment session begins in a patient who has had chemotherapy before. Anticipatory nausea and vomiting is caused by triggers, such as the sights, smells, or sounds of the treatment room. For example, a patient who smells an alcohol swab when starting chemotherapy may later become nauseous or vomit at the smell of an alcohol swab. The more chemotherapy sessions a patient has, the more likely it is that anticipatory nausea and vomiting will occur. Also called ANV.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802646" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anticipatory nausea and vomiting&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802647" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;náuseas y vómitos anticipatorios&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>náuseas y vómitos anticipatorios</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Náuseas y vómitos que se presentan antes de que comience una sesión de tratamiento con quimioterapia en una persona que recibió  quimioterapia antes.  Hay factores desencadenantes, como las imágenes, los olores, o los sonidos de la sala de tratamiento, que provocan las náuseas y vómitos anticipatorios. Por ejemplo, una persona que huele un hisopo con alcohol cuando comienza la quimioterapia, quizás luego sienta náuseas o vomite cuando vuelva a percibir el mismo olor del hisopo con alcohol. A medida que el paciente se somete a más sesiones de quimioterapia, es más probable que presente náuseas y vómitos anticipatorios. También se llama NVA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2020-06-04</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/nausea-vomiting" UseWith="en">Nausea and Vomiting and Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/nauseas-vomitos" UseWith="es">Náuseas y vómitos relacionados con el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
