<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800907">
  <TermName>chemo brain</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KEE-moh brayn)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term commonly used to describe thinking and memory problems that a patient with cancer may have before, during, or after cancer treatment. Signs and symptoms of chemo brain include disorganized behavior or thinking, confusion, memory loss, and trouble concentrating, paying attention, learning, and making decisions. Chemo brain may be caused by the cancer itself (such as brain tumors) or by cancer treatment, such as chemotherapy and other anticancer drugs, radiation therapy, hormone therapy, and surgery. It may also be caused by conditions related to cancer treatment, such as anemia, fatigue, infection, pain, hormone changes, sleep problems, nutrition problems, stress, anxiety, and depression. Chemo brain may last for a short time or for many years.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802644" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chemo brain&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802645" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deterioro cognitivo por quimioterapia&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/>
  <SpanishTermName>deterioro cognitivo por quimioterapia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Problemas del pensamiento y la memoria que se presentan antes, durante o después del tratamiento del cáncer.  Los signos y síntomas  incluyen desorden del comportamiento o el pensamiento, confusión, pérdida de la memoria, y alteraciones de la concentración, la atención, el aprendizaje y la toma de decisiones. A veces, la causa de este deterioro cognitivo es el cáncer en sí mismo (como en los tumores de encéfalo) otras veces la causa es el tratamiento  (quimioterapia, otros medicamentos contra el cáncer, radioterapia, terapia con hormonas y cirugía). También se relaciona con otros efectos del tratamiento, como anemia, cansancio, infección, dolor, cambios hormonales, trastornos del sueño, problemas de alimentación, estrés, ansiedad y depresión. Es posible que este deterioro dure un tiempo corto o muchos años. También se llama cerebro de quimioterapia y efectos neuropsicológicos de la quimioterapia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
