<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800916"><TermName>UTI</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which bacteria invade and grow in the urinary tract (the kidneys, ureters, bladder, and urethra). Most UTIs occur in the bladder or urethra. Signs and symptoms may include pain or burning during urination, cloudy or bad-smelling urine, blood in the urine, feeling a need to urinate often or right away, pain in the back or lower abdomen, fever, chills, and fatigue. Certain conditions, such as diabetes, hormone changes, kidney stones, an enlarged prostate, or a spinal cord injury, may increase the risk of a UTI. Other risk factors include radiation therapy or surgery to the pelvis, taking certain types of medicines (such as anticancer drugs), or using a catheter to empty the bladder. UTIs are common, especially in women. Also called urinary tract infection.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765031" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the male urinary system (left panel) and female urinary system (right panel); two-panel drawing showing the right and left kidneys, the ureters, the bladder filled with urine, and the urethra. The inside of the left kidney shows the renal pelvis. An inset shows the renal tubules and urine. Also shown are the prostate and penis (left panel) and the uterus (right panel)." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the male urinary system (left panel) and female urinary  system (right panel) showing the kidneys, ureters, bladder, and urethra. The inside of the left kidney shows the renal pelvis. An inset shows the renal tubules and urine. Also shown are the prostate and penis (left panel) and the uterus (right panel). Urine is made in the renal tubules and collects in the renal pelvis of each kidney. The urine flows from the kidneys through the ureters to the bladder. The urine is stored in the bladder until it leaves the body through the urethra.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765552" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del aparato urinario masculino (panel de la izquierda) y del aparato urinario femenino (panel de la derecha). En la imagen se muestran dos paneles en los que se observan los riñones derecho e izquierdo, los uréteres, la vejiga llena de orina y la uretra. En el interior del riñón izquierdo se observa la pelvis renal. En los recuadros se muestran los túbulos renales y la orina. También se muestra la próstata y el pene (panel de la izquierda), y el útero (panel de la derecha)." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del aparato urinario masculino (panel de la izquierda) y del aparato urinario femenino (panel de la derecha). En la imagen se muestran los riñones, los uréteres, la vejiga y la uretra. En el interior del riñón izquierdo se observa la pelvis renal. En los recuadros se muestran los túbulos renales y la orina. También se muestra la próstata y el pene (panel de la izquierda), y el útero (panel de la derecha). La orina se elabora en los túbulos renales y se acumula en la pelvis renal de cada riñón. La orina fluye desde los riñones, pasa por los uréteres y se almacena en la vejiga hasta que sale del cuerpo por la uretra. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>IU</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección que se presenta cuando las bacterias entran y se multiplican en el aparato urinario (riñones, uréteres, vejiga y uretra). La mayoría de las IU ocurren en la vejiga o la uretra. Los signos y síntomas incluyen dolor o ardor al orinar, orina turbia o  con mal olor, sangre en la orina, orinar con mucha frecuencia o sensación de urgencia para orinar, dolor de espalda o en la parte baja del abdomen, fiebre, escalofríos y cansancio. Ciertas afecciones, como la diabetes, los cambios hormonales, los cálculos renales, una próstata agrandada, o daños en la médula espinal, aumentan el riesgo de una IU. Otros factores de riesgo son la  radioterapia o las cirugías en la pelvis, algunos medicamentos (como los medicamentos contra el cáncer) o el uso de catéteres para vaciar la vejiga. Las IU son comunes, en especial en las mujeres. También se llama infección urinaria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
