<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000800918">
  <TermName>urinary retention</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(YOOR-ih-NAYR-ee reh-TEN-shun)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which urine cannot empty from the bladder. Urinary retention can be acute and develop very quickly, or it can be chronic and occur over a long time. Signs and symptoms include not being able to urinate, feeling a need to urinate right away, urinating often but in small amounts, leaking urine, and lower abdominal pain or swelling. Urinary retention is usually caused by a blockage or narrowing in the bladder or urethra (tube through which urine leaves the body). This may result from an enlarged prostate, a bulging or sagging bladder, kidney or bladder stones, tumor, infection, or inflammation. Urinary retention may also be caused by nerve problems, weak bladder muscles, surgery, and certain medicines.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802654" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;urinary retention&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802655" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;retención urinaria&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>retención urinaria</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección por la que una persona es incapaz de orinar. La retención urinaria en ocasiones es aguda y se produce de forma rápida, otras veces es crónica y dura mucho tiempo. Los signos y síntomas incluyen la imposibilidad de expulsar la orina para vaciar la vejiga, la sensación de tener urgencia para orinar, orinar seguido pero muy poco, orinarse de manera involuntaria, y dolor o inflamación en la parte inferior del abdomen. La retención urinaria por lo general se produce por una obstrucción o estrechamiento de la vejiga o la uretra (tubo por el que la orina sale del cuerpo). La obstrucción se produce por una próstata agrandada, una vejiga que sobresale o está caída, cálculos renales o de vejiga, un tumor, una infección o una inflamación. También es posible que la retención urinaria se deba a problemas en los nervios, debilitamiento de los músculos de la vejiga, cirugía y ciertos medicamentos. También se llama retención de orina.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-29</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
