<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801199"><TermName>anal wart</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AY-nul wort)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A raised growth in or around the anus caused by human papillomavirus (HPV). HPV can spread by skin-to-skin contact, usually during oral, anal, or genital sex with an infected partner. Anal warts often appear as small, light brown or skin-colored bumps that may be clumped together. They are usually painless and do not cause any symptoms, so a person may not know they have them. However, sometimes they can grow large and cause itching and bleeding. Anal warts may come back after treatment. People who have had anal warts have an increased risk of developing anal cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802664" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anal wart&quot;" language="en" id="_8"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802665" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;verruga anal&quot;" language="es" id="_9"/><SpanishTermName>verruga anal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Masa elevada en el ano o en la piel que lo rodea y que surge a partir de una infección por virus del papiloma humano (VPH). Estos virus se diseminan por contacto piel a piel, a menudo durante las relaciones sexuales orales, anales o genitales con una pareja infectada. Las verrugas anales suelen aparecer como pequeños bultos de color marrón claro o del mismo color de la piel que pueden estar agrupados. Por lo general, no producen dolor ni síntomas, por lo que es posible que las personas no sepan que las tienen; no obstante, en ocasiones crecen, pican y sangran. Estas lesiones a veces reaparecen después del tratamiento. Las personas con verrugas anales tienen un riesgo elevado de cáncer de ano. También se llama papiloma anal, papiloma perianal y verruga perianal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-06-11</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-06-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
