<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801209">
  <TermName>tenosynovial giant cell tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(TEH-noh-sih-NOH-vee-ul JY-unt sel TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of rare tumor that forms in the synovium (tissue that lines the joints), the tendon sheath (tissue that covers the tendons), or the bursa (a fluid-filled sac between bones, tendons, and muscles). These tumors cause the affected synovium, tendon sheath, or bursa to thicken and overgrow.  Tenosynovial giant cell tumors can occur in any joint. Although tenosynovial giant cell tumors are not cancer, they can grow and cause damage to surrounding tissues or structures. Symptoms may include reduced movement or pain in the affected joint and a locking or catching sensation when moving the joint. Tenosynovial giant cell tumors usually occur in young and middle-aged adults. Also called TGCT.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802672" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tenosynovial giant cell tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802673" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor de células gigantes tenosinoviales&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor de células gigantes tenosinoviales</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de tumor raro que se forma en la membrana sinovial (tejido que recubre las articulaciones), la vaina tendinosa (tejido que cubre los tendones) o la  bolsa sinovial (saco lleno de líquido que separa huesos, tendones y músculos). Estos tumores producen engrosamiento y crecimiento de la membrana sinovial, la vaina tendinosa o la bolsa sinovial afectada. Los tumores de células gigantes tenosinoviales aparecen en cualquier articulación y aunque no son cancerosos, a veces crecen y dañan los tejidos o estructuras cercanas. Los síntomas de estos tumores son disminución del movimiento o dolor en la articulación afectada, y sensación de freno o bloqueo al mover la articulación. Estos tumores suelen presentarse en adultos jóvenes y de edad mediana. También se llama TCGT.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-06-11</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
