<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801270"><TermName>luspatercept</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lus-PA-ter-cept)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat anemia in adults with certain types of myelodysplastic syndromes or myelodysplastic/myeloproliferative neoplasms who need regular red blood cell transfusions and whose anemia did not respond to or cannot be treated with an erythropoiesis-stimulating agent. Luspatercept is also used to treat anemia in adults with beta thalassemia (an inherited blood disorder) who need regular red blood cell transfusions. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions. Luspatercept helps the bone marrow make more red blood cells. It is a type of antianemic and a type of recombinant fusion protein. Also called Reblozyl.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802692" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;luspatercept&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802693" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;luspatercept&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>luspatercept</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de la anemia en adultos con determinados tipos de síndromes mielodisplásicos o neoplasias mielodisplásicas o mieloproliferativas que necesitan transfusiones de glóbulos rojos frecuentes, y  cuya anemia no respondió a un medicamento estimulante de la eritropoyesis o que no es posible tratar con este tipo de medicamentos. El luspatercept también se usa para el tratamiento de la anemia en adultos con la talasemia β (trastorno sanguíneo hereditario) que necesitan trasfusiones de glóbulos rojos frecuentes. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones. El luspatercept estimula la producción de  glóbulos rojos en la médula ósea. Es un tipo de antianémico y de proteína de fusión recombinante. También se llama Reblozyl.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-05-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000801351" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/luspatercept-aamt">Luspatercept-aamt</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
