<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801220">
  <TermName>VIP-secreting tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… seh-KREE-ting TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A very rare tumor that usually forms in the islet cells of the pancreas and makes the hormone vasoactive intestinal peptide (VIP). VIP helps control the secretion of water, salts, enzymes, and gastric acid during digestion and relaxes certain muscles in the digestive tract. Signs and symptoms of  VIP-secreting tumor include chronic watery diarrhea, dehydration, abdominal pain, nausea, flushing or redness in the face, weight loss, and very low levels of potassium in the blood. Most VIP-secreting tumors are cancer and have often spread to other parts of the body when they are found. VIP-secreting tumor is a type of pancreatic neuroendocrine tumor. Also called VIP-producing neuroendocrine tumor and VIPoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802682" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;VIP-secreting tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802683" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor secretor de péptido intestinal vasoactivo&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor secretor de péptido intestinal vasoactivo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor muy raro que por lo general se forma en las células de los islotes del páncreas y produce la hormona péptido intestinal vasoactivo (VIP). Esta hormona controla la secreción de agua, sales, enzimas y ácido gástrico durante la digestión y hace que se relajen algunos  músculos del tubo digestivo. Los signos y síntomas del  tumor secretor de péptido intestinal vasoactivo incluyen diarrea líquida crónica, deshidratación, dolor abdominal, náuseas, rubor o enrojecimiento  de la cara, pérdida de peso, y concentraciones muy bajas de potasio en la sangre. La mayoría de los tumores secretores de VIP son cancerosos y a menudo se han diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo en el momento de su detección. El tumor secretor de péptido intestinal vasoactivo es un tipo de tumor neuroendocrino pancreático. También se llama tumor neuroendocrino secretor de péptido intestinal vasoactivo, tumor secretor de VIP y vipoma.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-06-11</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
