<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801224"><TermName>adrenocorticotropic-secreting tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-DREE-noh-KOR-tih-koh-TROH-pik-seh-KREE-ting TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare tumor that makes the hormone adrenocorticotropin (ACTH), which causes the adrenal glands to make too much cortisol. Adrenocorticotropic-secreting tumors can lead to Cushing syndrome. Signs and symptoms of adrenocorticotropic-secreting tumors and Cushing syndrome include a round face, thin arms and legs, severe fatigue and muscle weakness, high blood pressure, high blood sugar, purple or pink stretch marks on the skin, and weight gain, especially in the abdomen. Adrenocorticotropic-secreting tumors usually form in the pituitary gland or in the islet cells of the pancreas, but they may also form in other organs, including the lung, thyroid, and thymus. Adrenocorticotropic-secreting tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer).  Also called ACTHoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802686" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adrenocorticotropic-secreting tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802687" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor secretor de hormona adrenocorticotrópica&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>tumor secretor de hormona adrenocorticotrópica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor raro que elabora hormona adrenocorticotropina (ACTH), que a su vez hace que las glándulas suprarrenales produzcan demasiado cortisol. Los tumores secretores de adrenocorticotropina a veces ocasionan el síndrome de Cushing. Los signos y síntomas de los tumores secretores de adrenocorticotropina  y el síndrome de Cushing incluyen cara redonda, brazos y piernas delgadas, cansancio intenso, debilidad muscular, presión arterial alta, glucosa sanguínea alta, estrías púrpuras o rosadas en la piel y aumento de peso, en especial en el abdomen. Los tumores secretores de adrenocorticotropina suelen aparecer en la glándula pituitaria o en las células de los islotes del páncreas, pero también se forman en otros órganos, como el pulmón, la tiroides y el timo. Los tumores secretores de adrenocorticotropina pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos).  También se llama acthoma y tumor secretor de corticotropina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-06-11</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
