<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801479">
  <TermName>severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(seh-VEER uh-KYOOT RES-pih-ruh-TOR-ee SIN-drome kuh-ROH-nuh-VY-rus …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The virus that causes a respiratory disease called coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19). Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2  is a member of a large family of viruses called coronaviruses. These viruses can infect people and some animals. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 was first known to infect people in 2019. The virus is thought to spread from person to person through droplets released when an infected person coughs, sneezes, or talks. It may also be spread by touching a surface with the virus on it and then touching one’s mouth, nose, or eyes, but this is less common. Research is being done to treat COVID-19 and to prevent infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2.  Also called SARS-CoV-2.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802710" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;coronavirus del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave de tipo 2&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/>
  <SpanishTermName>coronavirus del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave de tipo 2</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Virus que causa una enfermedad respiratoria llamada enfermedad por  coronavirus de 2019 (COVID-19). El coronavirus del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave de tipo 2  es un virus de la gran familia de los coronavirus. Los coronavirus infectan  a seres humanos y algunos animales. La infección por el coronavirus del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave de tipo 2 en las personas se identificó por primera vez en 2019. Se piensa que este virus se transmite de una persona a otra en las gotitas que se dispersan cuando la persona infectada tose, estornuda o habla. Es posible que también se transmita por tocar una superficie con el virus y luego llevarse las manos a la boca, la nariz o los ojos, aunque esto es menos frecuente. Hay estudios de investigación en curso sobre el tratamiento de la COVID-19 y la prevención de la infección por el coronavirus del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave de tipo 2.  También se llama coronavirus 2 del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave, coronavirus 2 del síndrome respiratorio agudo severo, coronavirus de Wuhan, coronavirus pandémico de 2020, nuevo coronavirus de 2019, SARS-CoV-2, segundo coronavirus del síndrome respiratorio agudo grave y virus de la covid-19.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-04-28</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-01-27</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/contact/emergency-preparedness/coronavirus">COVID-19: What People with Cancer Should Know</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/index.html">COVID-19 (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/contactenos/emergencia/coronavirus">Coronavirus: información para las personas con cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://espanol.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/index.html">COVID-19 (Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
