<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801482"><TermName>coronavirus disease 19</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kuh-ROH-nuh-VY-rus dih-ZEEZ …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A highly contagious respiratory disease caused by the SARS-CoV-2 virus. SARS-CoV-2 is thought to spread from person to person through droplets released when an infected person coughs, sneezes, or talks. It may also be spread by touching a surface with the virus on it and then touching one’s mouth, nose, or eyes, but this is less common. The most common signs and symptoms of coronavirus disease 19 are fever, cough, and trouble breathing. Fatigue, muscle pain, chills, headache, sore throat, runny nose, nausea or vomiting, diarrhea, and a loss of taste or smell may also occur. The signs and symptoms may be mild or severe and usually appear 2 to 14 days after exposure to the SARS-CoV-2 virus. Some people may not have any symptoms but are still able to spread the virus. Most people with coronavirus disease 19 recover without needing special treatment. But other people are at higher risk of serious illness. Those at higher risk include older adults and people with serious medical problems, such as heart, lung, or kidney  disease, diabetes, cancer, or a weak immune system. Serious illness may include life-threatening pneumonia and organ failure. Research is being done to treat coronavirus disease 19 and to prevent infection with SARS-CoV-2. 

 Also called COVID-19.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802713" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;coronavirus disease 19&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000802714" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad por coronavirus de 2019&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad por coronavirus de 2019</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad respiratoria muy contagiosa causada por el virus SARS-CoV-2. Se piensa que este virus se transmite de una persona a otra en las gotitas que se dispersan cuando la persona infectada tose, estornuda o habla. Es posible que también se transmita al tocar una superficie con el virus y luego llevarse las manos a la boca, la nariz o los ojos, pero esto es menos frecuente. Los signos y síntomas más frecuentes de la enfermedad por coronavirus de 2019 son fiebre, tos y dificultad para respirar.  A veces, también se presentan fatiga, dolores musculares, escalofríos, dolor de cabeza, dolor de garganta, goteo nasal, náusea o vómito, diarrea y pérdida del sentido del gusto o el olfato. Los signos y síntomas pueden ser leves o graves y suelen aparecer entre 2 y 14 días después de la exposición al SARS-CoV-2. Algunas personas no tienen síntomas pero pueden transmitir el virus. La mayoría de las personas con la enfermedad por coronavirus de 2019 se recuperan sin un tratamiento especial; sin embargo, algunas corren un riesgo más alto de sufrir una enfermedad grave. Quienes tienen el riesgo más alto son los adultos de edad avanzada y las personas con problemas de salud graves, como las afecciones del corazón, los pulmones o los riñones, la diabetes, el cáncer y la debilidad del sistema inmunitario. La enfermedad grave incluye la neumonía  y la insuficiencia orgánica que son potencialmente mortales. Están en marcha investigaciones sobre el tratamiento de la enfermedad por coronavirus de 2019 y la prevención de la infección por el SARS-CoV-2. También se llama coronavirosis de 2019, enfermedad por SARS-CoV-2 y neumonía por 2019-nCoV.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-04-28</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-01-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/contact/emergency-preparedness/coronavirus">COVID-19: What People with Cancer Should Know</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/index.html">COVID-19 (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/contactenos/emergencia/coronavirus">Coronavirus: información para las personas con cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://espanol.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/index.html">COVID-19 (Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
