<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801557">
  <TermName>daratumumab and hyaluronidase</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(DAYR-uh-TOOM-yoo-mab … HY-al-yoo-RAH-nih-days)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A combination of two drugs used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of multiple myeloma or light chain amyloidosis. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Daratumumab binds to a protein called CD38, which is found on some types of immune cells and cancer cells, including myeloma cells. Daratumumab may block CD38 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. Hyaluronidase allows daratumumab to be given by injection under the skin. Daratumumab and hyaluronidase can be given in less time than daratumumab alone, which is given as an infusion.  Also called Darzalex Faspro.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802719" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;daratumumab and hyaluronidase&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804355" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;daratumumab con hialuronidasa&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>daratumumab con hialuronidasa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que está compuesto por dos fármacos y que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de mieloma múltiple o amiloidosis de cadenas ligeras. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El daratumumab se une a una proteína llamada CD38, que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células inmunitarias y células cancerosas, como las células del mieloma. Es posible que el daratumumab bloquee CD38 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. La hialuronidasa permite que el daratumumab se administre por inyección debajo de la piel. La combinación de daratumumab con hialuronidasa se administra más rápido que el daratumumab solo, que se administra por infusión. También se llama daratumumab y hialuronidasa y Darzalex Faspro.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-06</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-01-19</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000801597" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/daratumumabandhyaluronidase-fihj">Daratumumab and Hyaluronidase-fihj</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
