<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801614">
  <TermName>selpercatinib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SEL-per-KA-tih-nib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used to treat certain types of non-small cell lung cancer in adults and certain types of thyroid cancer or other solid tumor in adults and children aged 2 years and older. It is used in patients whose cancer has  an abnormal 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       gene. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Selpercatinib blocks certain proteins, including those made by the 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       fusion gene or the mutated 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       gene. Blocking these proteins may help keep cancer cells from growing. Selpercatinib is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called Retevmo.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802729" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;selpercatinib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802730" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;selpercatinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>selpercatinib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en adultos, y ciertos tipos de cáncer de tiroides u otros tumores sólidos en adultos y en niños de 2 años o más. Se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer presenta un gen 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       anormal. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El selpercatinib bloquea ciertas proteínas, incluso las que se originan del gen de fusión 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       o del gen 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       mutado. Bloquear estas proteínas quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. El selpercatinib es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas.  También se llama Retevmo.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-05-12</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-05-30</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000801635" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/selpercatinib">Selpercatinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
