<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801706"><TermName>polychlorinated biphenyl</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAH-lee-KLOR-ih-NAY-ted BY-feh-nil)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a large group of man-made chemical compounds that were used to make many products, including electrical equipment, insulation, fluorescent lights, paints, plastics, rubber, dyes, inks, adhesives, and pesticides. Being exposed to polychlorinated biphenyls can cause skin conditions, such as acne and rashes, and eye irritation. Long-term exposure to high levels of polychlorinated biphenyls can affect other body systems, and may also cause learning and developmental delays, low birth weight, and cancer. Polychlorinated biphenyls were banned in the United States in the 1970s, but they may still be found in contaminated soil, air, water, and food. Also called PCB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804372" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;polychlorinated biphenyl&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804373" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;policlorobifenilo&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>policlorobifenilo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cada una de las sustancias que forman un grupo numeroso de compuestos químicos artificiales utilizados para fabricar muchos productos, como aparatos eléctricos, aislamientos, luces fluorescentes, pinturas, plásticos, gomas, tinturas, tintas, adhesivos y pesticidas. Es posible que exponerse a los policlorobifenilos  cause afecciones en la piel, como acné o sarpullido, e irritación en los ojos. La exposición a concentraciones altas  de  estos compuestos durante mucho tiempo afecta otros sistemas del cuerpo y causa retrasos en el aprendizaje y el desarrollo, peso bajo al nacer y cáncer. Los policlorobifenilos se prohibieron en los Estados Unidos en la década de 1970, pero aún se encuentran como contaminantes en el suelo, el aire, el agua y los alimentos. También se llama bifenilo policlorado y PCB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-07-02</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
