<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801709"><TermName>conditionally reprogrammed cell</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kun-DIH-shuh-nuh-lee ree-PROH-gramd sel)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of cell grown in the laboratory from samples of normal cells or cancer cells from patient tissue. These cells can be kept alive for as long as needed and grown to large numbers. The cells are treated with substances that cause them to resemble stem cells (cells from which other types of cells develop) and grow rapidly. Under certain conditions, conditionally reprogrammed cells can be made to look and act like the original tissue or specific type of tumor from which they came. They are used to study how cancers and other diseases form, and to test new drugs and other types of treatment before they are given to people. Also called CRC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804374" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;conditionally reprogrammed cell&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804375" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;célula reprogramada condicionalmente&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>célula reprogramada condicionalmente</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de célula producida en el laboratorio a partir de muestras de células normales o cancerosas del tejido del paciente. Es posible  mantener estas células vivas durante el tiempo que sea necesario y hacer que se multipliquen en grandes cantidades. Las células se tratan con sustancias para que se parezcan a las células madre (células que dan origen a otros tipos de células) y  se multipliquen de forma rápida. Bajo ciertas condiciones, es posible hacer que la célula reprogramada condicionalmente se vea y se comporte como el tejido original o el tipo específico de tumor del que provienen. Este tipo de células se usan para estudiar cómo se forman los cánceres y otras enfermedades, además sirven para probar nuevos medicamentos y otros tipos de tratamiento antes de administrarlos a las personas. También se llama CRC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-07-02</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
