<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801883"><TermName>pertuzumab, trastuzumab, and hyaluronidase</TermName><TermPronunciation>(per-TOO-zoo-mab tras-TOO-zoo-mab … HY-al-yoo-RAH-nih-days)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A combination of three drugs used with other drugs to treat adults with HER2-positive breast cancer. It is used before surgery in patients with locally advanced, inflammatory, or early-stage breast cancer and after surgery in patients with early-stage breast cancer who have a high risk that their cancer will recur (come back). It is also used to treat patients with breast cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and has not already been treated with anti-HER2 therapy or chemotherapy. Pertuzumab and trastuzumab bind to a protein called HER2, which is found on some breast cancer cells. Pertuzumab and trastuzumab  may block HER2 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. Hyaluronidase allows pertuzumab and trastuzumab to be given by injection under the skin. Pertuzumab, trastuzumab, and hyaluronidase can be given in less time than pertuzumab or trastuzumab alone, which are given as infusions. Also called Phesgo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804382" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pertuzumab, trastuzumab, and hyaluronidase&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804383" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pertuzumab y trastuzumab con hialuronidasa&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>pertuzumab y trastuzumab con hialuronidasa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Combinación de tres medicamentos que se utiliza con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de mama positivo para HER2. Se usa antes de la cirugía en pacientes con cáncer de mama localmente avanzado, inflamatorio o en estadio temprano. También se usa después de la cirugía en pacientes con cáncer de mama en estadio temprano y riesgo alto de recidiva (reaparición del cáncer). Además, se utiliza para el tratamiento del cáncer de mama que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo en pacientes que no recibieron terapia anti-HER2 ni quimioterapia. El pertuzumab y el trastuzumab se unen a la proteína HER2 que está presente en algunas células de cáncer de mama, de manera que al bloquear HER2 ayudan al sistema inmunitario a destruir estas células. La hialuronidasa permite que esta combinación se administre en una sola inyección debajo de la piel, lo que acorta el tiempo de cada sesión de tratamiento porque la inyección se aplica más  rápido que las infusiones del pertuzumab o el trastuzumab. También se llama pertuzumab, trastuzumab y hialuronidasa y Phesgo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-07-07</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000801930" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/pertuzumabtrastuzumabandhyaluronidase-zzxf">Pertuzumab, Trastuzumab, and Hyaluronidase-zzxf</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
