<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000801854">
  <TermName>robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ROH-bot-uh-SIS-ted LA-puh-ruh-SKAH-pik RA-dih-kul PROS-tuh-TEK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Surgery that uses a computer-assisted mechanical device (robot) to remove the entire prostate and some of the tissue around it, including the seminal vesicles (a gland that helps make semen). Nearby lymph nodes may also be removed. During robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy, several small incisions (cuts) are made in the wall of the lower abdomen. The surgeon inserts an instrument with a camera through one of the openings and surgical instruments through the other openings using the robotic arms. The camera gives the surgeon a clear, 3-dimensional view of the prostate and surrounding structures. The surgeon then uses the robotic arms to remove the prostate.  An attempt is made to protect the nerves that control penile erection and the bladder from damage. Also called robotic laparoscopic radical prostatectomy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802749" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000802750" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prostatectomía radical laparoscópica asistida por robot&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>prostatectomía radical laparoscópica asistida por robot</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cirugía para la que se usa un robot (máquina computarizada) con el fin de extirpar toda la próstata y algo del tejido que la rodea, como las vesículas seminales (glándulas que ayudan a producir el semen). A veces, también se extirpan los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. Durante una prostatectomía radical laparoscópica asistida por robot se hacen varias incisiones (cortes) pequeñas  en la pared del abdomen inferior, luego el cirujano introduce una cámara por uno de los orificios y varios brazos robóticos con instrumentos quirúrgicos por los otros orificios. La cámara ofrece una vista tridimensional de la próstata y las estructuras que la rodean. El cirujano usa los brazos robóticos para extirpar la próstata mientras intenta proteger los nervios que controlan la erección del pene y evitar una lesión en la vejiga. También se llama prostatectomía radical laparoscópica robótica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-06-22</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
