<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802099"><TermName>integrin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-teh-grin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of protein found on the surface of cells that helps them attach to, and communicate with, nearby cells. Integrins also help cells attach to large molecules in the extracellular matrix, the substance that surrounds and gives structure to cells. Integrins help cells receive signals from other cells and from the surrounding environment, and they help control the activity of certain genes. They play an important role in cell growth, cell movement, and other cell functions. Integrins are involved in wound healing, blood vessel growth, and in the growth and spread of cancer cells. Drugs that target integrins are being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804412" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;integrin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804413" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;integrina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>integrina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de proteína que se encuentra en la superficie de las células y las ayuda a unirse y comunicarse con las células cercanas. Las integrinas también ayudan a las células a unirse a moléculas grandes en la matriz extracelular, la sustancia que rodea y da estructura a las células. Las integrinas ayudan a las células a recibir señales de otras células y del ambiente que las rodea, así como a controlar la actividad de ciertos genes. Desempeñan una función importante en la multiplicación, el movimiento y otras funciones celulares. Las integrinas participan en la cicatrización de heridas, el crecimiento de los vasos sanguíneos, y la multiplicación y diseminación de células cancerosas. Están en estudio medicamentos que se dirigen a las integrinas para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-10-20</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
