<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802092">
  <TermName>cotinine</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KOH-tuh-neen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A chemical substance formed by the breakdown of nicotine in the body. Nicotine is an addictive, harmful chemical found in tobacco and tobacco products, including cigarettes and chewing tobacco. Exposure to nicotine can be measured by checking the amount of cotinine in the blood, urine, or saliva in smokers and in nonsmokers exposed to secondhand smoke. Cotinine stays in the body longer than nicotine and is used to help monitor tobacco use and the use of nicotine replacement therapy in people trying to stop smoking.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804404" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cotinine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804405" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cotinina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cotinina</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Sustancia química que se forma por la descomposición de la nicotina en el cuerpo. La nicotina es una sustancia química adictiva y dañina que se encuentra en el tabaco y los productos con tabaco, como los cigarrillos y el tabaco de mascar. La exposición a la nicotina se puede medir verificando la cantidad de cotinina en la sangre, la orina o la saliva de fumadores y no fumadores expuestos al humo de tabaco en el ambiente. La cotinina permanece en el cuerpo durante más tiempo que la nicotina, y se utiliza para ayudar a controlar el consumo de tabaco y el uso de la terapia de reemplazo de nicotina en personas que intentan dejar de fumar.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-10-19</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
