<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802193"><TermName>tafasitamab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TA-fuh-SIH-tuh-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with lenalidomide to treat adults with certain types of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma that relapsed (came back) or did not get better after treatment with other anticancer therapy. It is used in patients who cannot be treated with an autologous stem cell transplant.   It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Tafasitamab binds to a protein called CD19, which is found on most B cells (a type of white blood cell) and some lymphoma cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Tafasitamab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Monjuvi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804430" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tafasitamab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804431" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tafasitamab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tafasitamab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con lenalidomida para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de linfoma difuso de células B en recaída (cáncer que volvió) o que no mejoró después de recibir otra terapia contra el cáncer. Se utiliza en pacientes que no pueden recibir un trasplante autógeno de células madre. Además, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El tafasitamab se une a una proteína llamada CD19, que está en la mayoría de las células B (tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunas células de linfoma, y de esta manera ayuda al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. El tafasitamab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Monjuvi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-08-04</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000802196" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tafasitamab-cxix">Tafasitamab-cxix</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
