<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802108"><TermName>exosome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EK-soh-some)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tiny sac-like structure that is formed inside a cell and  contains some of the cell’s proteins, DNA, and RNA. Exosomes get released into the blood by many types of cells, including cancer cells, and travel through the blood to other parts of the body. They are able to transfer the proteins, DNA, and RNA they contain into other cells. Exosomes may play a role in the spread of cancer and may also keep immune cells from killing cancer cells. They are being studied in the laboratory to help develop new ways of diagnosing and treating cancer, including preventing the spread of cancer cells in the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804420" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exosome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804421" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exosoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>exosoma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estructura diminuta en forma de bolsa que se forma dentro de una célula y contiene algunas de las proteínas celulares, así como porciones del ADN y ARN de la célula. Muchos tipos de células, como las células cancerosas, liberan exosomas en la sangre que viajan a otras partes del cuerpo. Los exosomas pasan las proteínas, el ADN y el ARN que contienen a otras células. Es posible que desempeñen una función en la diseminación del cáncer y también que eviten que las células inmunitarias destruyan las células cancerosas. Los exosomas están en estudio en el laboratorio para ayudar a desarrollar nuevas formas de diagnosticar y tratar el cáncer, incluso para prevenir la diseminación de las células cancerosas en el cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-10-20</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/research/areas/biology/david-lyden-exosomes-metastasis">Shining a Spotlight on Tumor Exosomes</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
