<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802101">
  <TermName>extracellular matrix</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(EK-struh-SEL-yoo-ler MAY-trix)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A large network of proteins and other molecules that surround, support, and give structure to cells and tissues in the body. The extracellular matrix helps cells attach to, and communicate with, nearby cells, and plays an important role in cell growth, cell movement, and other cell functions. The extracellular matrix is also involved in repairing damaged tissue. Abnormal changes in the extracellular matrix may lead to the development of certain diseases, such as cancer. The extracellular matrix of cancer cells can affect how they grow and spread. Also called ECM.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804414" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extracellular matrix&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804415" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;matriz extracelular&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>matriz extracelular</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Red grande de proteínas y otras moléculas que rodean, sostienen y dan estructura a las células y tejidos del cuerpo. La matriz extracelular ayuda a que las células se unan y se comuniquen con las células cercanas, y desempeña una función importante en la multiplicación celular, el movimiento celular y otras funciones celulares. También participa en la reparación del tejido dañado. Los cambios anormales en la matriz extracelular a veces causan ciertas enfermedades, como el cáncer. La matriz extracelular de las células cancerosas afecta la forma en que estas se multiplican y se diseminan. También se llama matriz intercelular, matriz intersticial y MEC.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-10-20</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
