<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802144">
  <TermName>Tecartus</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(teh-KAR-tus)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with mantle cell lymphoma or B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia that came back or did not get better after other treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Tecartus is made using a patient’s T cells (a type of immune system cell). A gene for a special receptor called chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is added to the T cells in the laboratory. These changed T cells called CAR T cells are grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. Tecartus binds to a protein called CD19, which is found on some lymphoma cells and leukemia cells. This helps the body’s immune system kill cancer cells. Tecartus is a type of CAR T-cell therapy. Also called brexucabtagene autoleucel.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804424" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Tecartus&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804425" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Tecartus&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000774647" type="image/jpeg" alt="CAR T-cell therapy; drawing of blood being removed from a vein in a patient’s arm to get T cells. Also shown is a special receptor called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) being made in the laboratory; the gene for CAR is inserted into the T cells and then millions of CAR T cells are grown. Drawing also shows the CAR T cells being given to the patient by infusion and binding to antigens on the cancer cells and killing them." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">CAR T-cell therapy. A type of treatment in which a patient’s T cells (a type of immune cell) are changed in the laboratory so they will bind to cancer cells and kill them. Blood from a vein in the patient’s arm flows through a tube to an apheresis machine (not shown), which removes the white blood cells, including the T cells, and sends the rest of the blood back to the patient. Then, the gene for a special receptor called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is inserted into the T cells in the laboratory. Millions of the CAR T cells are grown in the laboratory and then given to the patient by infusion. The CAR T cells are able to bind to an antigen on the cancer cells and kill them.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000791284" type="image/jpeg" alt="Terapia de células T con CAR. En el dibujo se muestra que se extrae sangre de una vena del brazo de un paciente para obtener células T. También se muestra que se elabora en el laboratorio un receptor especial, que se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR); se añade a las células T el gen que produce el CAR y luego se reproducen millones de células T con CAR. Además, se muestra que el paciente recibe las células T con CAR mediante infusión, y que luego estas células se unen a los antígenos de las células cancerosas y las destruyen." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Terapia de células T con CAR. Tipo de tratamiento  en el que se modifican las células T (un tipo de célula inmunitaria) de un paciente en el laboratorio a fin de que se unan a las células cancerosas y las destruyan. La sangre de una vena del brazo del paciente pasa por un tubo hasta una máquina de  aféresis (no se muestra) que extrae los glóbulos blancos, incluso las células T, y devuelve el resto de la sangre al paciente. Luego,   en el laboratorio, el gen que produce un receptor especial, que se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR), se añade a las células T, y se reproducen millones de células T con CAR que el paciente recibe mediante infusión. Las células T   con CAR se unen a un antígeno de las células cancerosas y las destruyen.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>Tecartus</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con linfoma de células de manto que recidivó (volvió) o no mejoró después de recibir otro tratamiento contra el cáncer. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Tecartus se produce usando células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria) de un paciente. En el laboratorio, se añade a las células T un gen de un receptor especial llamado receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR), luego estas células T con CAR se producen en grandes cantidades y se administran al paciente mediante infusión.  Tecartus se une a una proteína llamada CD19 que se encuentra en la mayoría de las células del linfoma de células B, lo que ayuda al sistema inmunitario del cuerpo a destruir células cancerosas. Tecartus es un tipo de terapia de células T con CAR. También se llama brexucabtagén autoleucel.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-07-29</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-10-06</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000802145" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/brexucabtageneautoleucel">Brexucabtagene Autoleucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
