<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802104"><TermName>environmental exposure</TermName><TermPronunciation>(en-VY-run-MEN-tul ek-SPOH-zher)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Having contact with chemical, biological, or physical substances found in air, water, food, or soil that may have a harmful effect on a person’s health. Examples of environmental exposures include UV radiation from the sun and cigarette smoke, radon, or other forms of air pollution. A person may also be exposed to harmful substances by swallowing food or water that is contaminated with bacteria or pesticides or by absorbing harmful chemicals through the skin. The amount of harm caused by an environmental exposure depends on the amount of the exposure, the way a person is exposed, and how long a person is exposed. Some types of environmental exposures may increase the risk of certain diseases, such as lung disease, heart disease, and cancer, and may also lead to birth defects.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804416" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;environmental exposure&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804417" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exposición ambiental&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>exposición ambiental</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Contacto con sustancias químicas, biológicas o físicas que se encuentran en el aire, el agua, los alimentos o el suelo, y que tienen un efecto dañino en la salud de una persona. La radiación ultravioleta (UV) del sol, el humo del cigarrillo, el radón y otras formas de contaminación del aire son ejemplos de exposiciones ambientales. Una persona se expone a sustancias dañinas cuando consume alimentos o agua contaminados con bacterias o pesticidas, o cuando absorbe sustancias químicas dañinas a través de la piel. La gravedad del daño causado por una exposición ambiental depende de la cantidad, la forma y el tiempo de la exposición. Algunos tipos de exposición ambiental aumentan el riesgo de ciertas enfermedades, como las enfermedades pulmonares, las enfermedades cardíacas y el cáncer, además es posible que también causen anomalías congénitas (de nacimiento). También se llama exposición medioambiental.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-10-20</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
