<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802267"><TermName>Zirabev</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ZEER-uh-bev)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient bevacizumab and is used to treat many different types of cancer. Zirabev is used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of cervical cancer, colorectal cancer, non-small cell lung cancer, renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer), and glioblastoma (a type of brain cancer). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Zirabev binds to a protein called VEGF, which may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of antiangiogenesis agent and a type of monoclonal antibody.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804438" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zirabev&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804439" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zirabev&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Zirabev</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo bevacizumab y se usa para el tratamiento de muchos tipos diferentes de cáncer. Zirabev se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer de cuello uterino, cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas, carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón) y glioblastoma (tipo de cáncer de encéfalo). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Zirabev se une a una proteína llamada factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular (VEGF), y es posible que esto impida la formación de los vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de anticuerpo monoclonal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-08-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-04-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000487564" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/bevacizumab">Bevacizumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
