<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802268">
  <TermName>Ruxience</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(RUK-see-ents)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug that contains the active ingredient rituximab and is used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma or chronic lymphocytic leukemia that are CD20 positive. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Ruxience binds to a protein called CD20, which is found on B cells (a type of white blood cell) and some types of cancer cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Ruxience is a type of monoclonal antibody.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804440" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Ruxience&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804441" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Ruxience&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Ruxience</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que contiene el principio activo rituximab y se utiliza solo o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B o leucemia linfocítica crónica que expresan CD20. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. Ruxience se une a una proteína llamada CD20, que se encuentra en las células B (tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Ruxience es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-08-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000495778" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/rituximab">Rituximab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
