<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802345"><TermName>natural killer T cell</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NA-chuh-rul KIH-ler … sel)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of immune cell that plays an important role in the body’s first immune response to invading microorganisms. Natural killer T cells are a type of T cell that also have certain features of natural killer (NK) cells. They can kill invading microorganisms, such as bacteria and viruses, by releasing cytokines. They can also kill certain cells, such as cancer cells, either directly or by causing other immune cells to kill them. If natural killer T cells become inactive, this may contribute to the development and progression of certain diseases, such as cancer. Also called NKT cell.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804448" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;natural killer T cell&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804449" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfocito T citolítico natural&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfocito T citolítico natural</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de célula inmunitaria que cumple una función importante en la primera respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo a los microorganismos invasores. Los linfocitos T citolíticos naturales son un tipo de célula T que además presentan ciertas características de los linfocitos citolíticos naturales (linfocitos NK). Son capaces de destruir microorganismos invasores, como bacterias y virus, mediante la liberación de citocinas. También pueden destruir ciertas células, como las células cancerosas, de forma directa o haciendo que otras células inmunitarias las destruyan. Es posible que la inactivación de los linfocitos T citolíticos naturales favorezca la formación y la progresión de ciertas enfermedades, como el cáncer. También se llama linfocito NKT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-11-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
