<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802350">
  <TermName>patient-reported outcome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PAY-shunt-reh-POR-ted OWT-kum)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Information about a patient’s health that comes directly from the patient. Examples of patient-reported outcomes include a patient’s description of their symptoms, their satisfaction with care, and how a disease or treatment affects their physical, mental, emotional, spiritual, and social well-being. In clinical trials, patient-reported outcomes may provide information about the side effects of the new treatment being studied. The use of patient-reported outcomes may help plan the best treatment and improve quality of care. Also called PRO.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804454" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;patient-reported outcome&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804455" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;resultado percibido por el paciente&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>resultado percibido por el paciente</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Información sobre la salud que proporciona el paciente en forma directa. Algunos ejemplos de  resultados percibidos por el paciente son la descripción que hace  un paciente de sus síntomas, de  su satisfacción con la atención, y de cómo una enfermedad o un tratamiento afectan su bienestar físico, mental, emocional, espiritual y social. En los ensayos clínicos, es posible que los resultados percibidos por el paciente aporten información sobre los efectos secundarios del nuevo tratamiento en estudio. El uso de los resultados percibidos por el paciente a veces ayuda a planificar el  tratamiento más apropiado y mejorar la calidad de la atención.  También se llama resultado comunicado por el paciente, resultado reportado por el paciente y RPP.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-11-18</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
