<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802348"><TermName>T-cell exhaustion</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… sel eg-ZOS-chun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes a condition in which T cells (a type of immune cell) lose their ability to kill certain cells, such as cancer cells or cells infected with a virus. This can happen when cancer, chronic infection, or other conditions cause the body’s immune system to stay active for a long time. Exhausted T cells have high amounts of immune checkpoint proteins on their surface, which may keep the activity of the T cells suppressed. In cancer treatment, drugs that target these proteins may be given to allow the T cells to better kill cancer cells. Learning more about T-cell exhaustion may help in the development of new types of immunotherapy to treat cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804452" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;T-cell exhaustion&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000804453" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;agotamiento de los linfocitos T&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>agotamiento de los linfocitos T</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que los linfocitos T (tipo de célula inmunitaria) pierden la capacidad de destruir ciertas células, como las células cancerosas o las células infectadas por un virus. En ocasiones, se presenta cuando un cáncer, una infección crónica u otro tipo de afección produce la activación del sistema inmunitario durante mucho tiempo. Los linfocitos T agotados tienen muchas proteínas de puntos de control inmunitario en su superficie, lo que quizás mantenga inhibida la actividad de los linfocitos T. En el tratamiento del cáncer, a veces se administran medicamentos  que actúan sobre esas proteínas para permitir que los linfocitos T destruyan más células cancerosas. Entender mejor el agotamiento de los linfocitos T quizás ayude al desarrollo de nuevos tipos de inmunoterapia para el tratamiento del cáncer. También se llama agotamiento de las células T.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-11-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
