<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802358"><TermName>LC-MS</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory technique that combines two different processes to separate, identify, and measure the amount of different substances in a liquid sample. In the liquid chromatography (LC) part of the process, a liquid sample is passed through a column filled with a material that separates the different substances in the sample. In the mass spectrometry (MS) part of the process, the separated substances then pass through a special machine that reports the molecular weight, structure, identity, and number of different substances in the sample. LC-MS has many uses, including screening for drugs, identifying toxins in the environment, and detecting certain metabolic disorders in infants. Also called liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>LC-MS</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Técnica de laboratorio que combina dos procesos diferentes para separar, identificar y medir la cantidad de varias sustancias en una muestra líquida. En la parte del proceso llamada cromatografía de líquidos (LC), se pasa una muestra líquida a través  de una columna llena de un material que separa las diferentes sustancias de la muestra. Luego, en la parte del proceso llamada espectrometría de masas (MS), cada una de las sustancias pasan por una máquina especial que informa el peso molecular, la estructura, la identidad y el número de  las sustancias de la muestra. La LC-MS tiene muchos usos, como examen de detección del consumo de drogas, la identificación de toxinas en el medio ambiente y la detección de ciertos trastornos metabólicos en los niños. También se llama cromatografía de líquidos con espectrometría de masas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2020-11-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
