<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802874">
  <TermName>CDKN2A gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that makes two major proteins involved in controlling cell growth, cell division, and a type of cell death called apoptosis. Mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>CDKN2A</GeneName>
       gene may cause cells to grow and divide too quickly or in an uncontrolled way or may keep cells from undergoing apoptosis. This may cause abnormal cells, including cancer cells, to grow. 
      <GeneName>CDKN2A</GeneName>
       gene mutations have been found in melanoma and in many other types of cancer. The 
      <GeneName>CDKN2A</GeneName>
       gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805205" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CDKN2A gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805206" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen CDKN2A&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen CDKN2A</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que da origen a dos proteínas importantes que participan en el control de la diferenciación celular, la división celular y un tipo de muerte celular llamada apoptosis. Es posible que las mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>CDKN2A</GeneName>
       hagan que las células se formen y se dividan demasiado rápido o de una manera descontrolada, o quizás impidan la apoptosis celular. En ocasiones, esto causa la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso células cancerosas. Se han encontrado mutaciones del gen 
      <GeneName>CDKN2A</GeneName>
       en el melanoma y en muchos otros tipos de cáncer. El gen 
      <GeneName>CDKN2A</GeneName>
       es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-02-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-02-19</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/cdkn2a/">CDKN2A gene (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
