<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802859"><TermName>SUFU gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A gene that is part of a cell signaling pathway involved in the formation of tissues and organs, cell growth, and cell division during embryonic development. Mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>SUFU</GeneName> gene may cause cells to grow and divide too quickly or in an uncontrolled way. This may cause abnormal cells, including cancer cells, to grow. <GeneName>SUFU</GeneName> gene mutations have been found in an inherited condition called basal cell nevus syndrome and in a type of brain cancer called medulloblastoma. The <GeneName>SUFU</GeneName> gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;SUFU gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805192" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen SUFU&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen SUFU</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Gen que forma parte de una vía de señalización celular que participa en la formación de tejidos y órganos, la diferenciación celular y la división celular durante el desarrollo embrionario. Es posible que las mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>SUFU</GeneName> hagan que las células se formen y se dividan demasiado rápido o de manera descontrolada. En ocasiones, esto causa la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso células cancerosas. Se han encontrado mutaciones del gen <GeneName>SUFU</GeneName> en una afección hereditaria llamada síndrome del nevo de células basales y en un tipo de cáncer de encéfalo llamado  meduloblastoma. El gen <GeneName>SUFU</GeneName> es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-02-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-02-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
