<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802861">
  <TermName>CYLD gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that makes a protein involved in controlling cell growth, cell division, and a type of cell death called apoptosis. Mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>CYLD</GeneName>
       gene may cause cells to grow and divide too quickly or in an uncontrolled way. This may cause abnormal cells, including cancer cells, to grow. 
      <GeneName>CYLD</GeneName>
       gene mutations have been found in an inherited condition called Brooke-Spiegler syndrome and in some types of cancer, including multiple myeloma and cancers of the kidney, liver, uterus, and colon. The 
      <GeneName>CYLD</GeneName>
       gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805193" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;CYLD gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805194" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen CYLD&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen CYLD</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que da origen a una proteína que participa en el control de la diferenciación celular, la división celular y un  tipo de muerte celular llamada apoptosis. Es posible que las mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>CYLD</GeneName>
       hagan que las células se formen y se dividan demasiado rápido o de una manera  descontrolada. En ocasiones, esto causa la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso células cancerosas. Se han encontrado mutaciones del gen 
      <GeneName>CYLD</GeneName>
       en una afección hereditaria llamada síndrome de Brooke-Spiegler y en algunos tipos de cáncer, como el mieloma múltiple y los cánceres de riñón, hígado, útero y colon. El gen 
      <GeneName>CYLD</GeneName>
       es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-02-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-02-19</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/cyld/">CYLD gene (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
