<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000802855">
  <TermName>PTCH1 gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that is part of a cell signaling pathway involved in the formation of tissues and organs, cell growth, and cell division during embryonic development. Mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>
       gene may cause cells to grow and divide too quickly or in an uncontrolled way. This may cause abnormal cells, including cancer cells, to grow. 
      <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>
       gene mutations have been found in an inherited condition called basal cell nevus syndrome and in many types of cancer, including basal cell skin cancer, medulloblastoma (a type of brain cancer), breast cancer, and colon cancer. The 
      <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>
       gene is a type of tumor suppressor gene.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805187" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;PTCH1 gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805188" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen PTCH1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen PTCH1</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que forma parte de una vía de señalización celular que participa en la formación de tejidos y órganos, la diferenciación celular y la división celular durante el desarrollo embrionario. Es posible que las mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>
       hagan que las células se formen y se dividan demasiado rápido o de manera descontrolada.  En ocasiones, esto causa la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso células cancerosas. Se han encontrado mutaciones del gen 
      <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>
       en una afección hereditaria llamada síndrome del nevo de células basales y en muchos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de piel de células basales, el meduloblastoma (tipo de cáncer de encéfalo), el cáncer de mama y el cáncer de colon. El gen 
      <GeneName>PTCH1</GeneName>
       es un tipo de gen supresor de tumores.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-02-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-02-19</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/ptch1/">PTCH1 gene (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
