<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803173">
  <TermName>USB1 gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that makes an enzyme involved in protecting a certain type of RNA from damage, which helps the RNA perform its role in making proteins. Mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>USB1</GeneName>
       gene have been found in Rothmund-Thomson syndrome, which increases the risk of skin cancer. Mutations in this gene have also been found in dyskeratosis congenita (DKC),  which causes abnormal changes in the skin and nails and white patches inside the mouth. People with DKC have an increased risk of bone marrow failure (a condition in which the bone marrow does not make enough blood cells), myelodysplastic syndrome, pulmonary fibrosis (scarring of the lungs), and certain types of cancer.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805239" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;USB1 gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805240" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen USB1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen USB1</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que da origen a una proteína que participa en la protección de cierto tipo de ARN y evita que se dañe, lo que ayuda a que el ARN cumpla su función en la elaboración de proteínas. Se han encontrado mutaciones (cambios) del gen 
      <GeneName>USB1</GeneName>
       en el síndrome de  Rothmund-Thomson, que aumenta el riesgo de presentar cáncer de piel. También se han encontrado mutaciones de este gen en la disqueratosis congénita (DC), que causa cambios anormales en la piel y en las uñas, así como manchas blancas en el interior de la boca. Las personas con DC tienen un aumento del riesgo de insuficiencia de médula ósea (afección por la que la médula ósea no produce suficientes células sanguíneas), síndrome mielodisplásico, fibrosis pulmonar (cicatrización de los pulmones ) y ciertos tipos de cáncer. 
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-03-10</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/usb1/">USB1 gene (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
