<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803214"><TermName>intracellular matrix</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-truh-SEL-yoo-ler MAY-trix)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The large network consisting of protein fibers and other molecules that gives shape and structure to cells in the body. The intracellular matrix helps organize structures within the cell called organelles and other substances found in the fluid inside the cell. It plays an important role in many cell functions, including cell movement, signaling, and division. Abnormal changes in the intracellular matrix may lead to the development of many different diseases, including cancer. The intracellular matrix can also affect how cancer cells grow and spread in the body. Also called cytoskeleton.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805265" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intracellular matrix&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805266" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;matriz intracelular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>matriz intracelular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Red grande de fibras proteicas y otras moléculas  que determinan la forma y estructura de las células del cuerpo. La matriz intracelular ayuda a organizar las estructuras llamadas orgánulos  y otras sustancias en el líquido  dentro de las células. Es un componente importante de muchas funciones celulares, como el movimiento, la señalización y la división. Los cambios anormales en esta red quizás conduzcan a la aparición de muchas enfermedades distintas, como el cáncer. La matriz intracelular también puede afectar la multiplicación de las células cancerosas y su diseminación por el cuerpo. También se llama citoesqueleto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-02-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
