<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803200">
  <TermName>low-dose computed tomography</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(loh-dose kum-PYOO-ted toh-MAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a computer linked to an x-ray machine that gives off a very low dose of radiation to make a series of detailed pictures of areas inside the body. The pictures are taken from different angles and are used to create 3-D views of tissues and organs. Low-dose computed tomography is recommended as a screening test for adults who have a high risk of developing lung cancer based on their age and smoking history.  Also called LDCT and low-dose CT scan.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805261" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;low-dose computed tomography&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805262" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tomografía computarizada de dosis baja&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tomografía computarizada de dosis baja</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa una computadora conectada a una máquina de rayos X que emite una dosis muy baja de radiación con el fin de crear una serie de imágenes detalladas del interior del cuerpo. Las imágenes se obtienen desde ángulos diferentes y se combinan para crear imágenes  tridimensionales de los órganos y los tejidos. La tomografía computarizada de dosis baja se recomienda como examen de detección para adultos que tienen un riesgo alto de cáncer de pulmón debido a la edad y los antecedentes de tabaquismo. También se llama LDCT, TC de dosis baja y tomografía computarizada de baja dosis.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-02-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/ct-scans-fact-sheet">Computed Tomography (CT) Scans and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/hoja-informativa-tomografia-computarizada">Exploraciones con tomografía computarizada (TC) para el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
