<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803518">
  <TermName>clonal hematopoiesis of indeterminate potential</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KLOH-nul hee-MA-toh-poy-EE-sis ... IN-deh-TER-mih-nut poh-TEN-shul)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The presence of somatic mutations in hematopoietic stem cells in an individual without a detectable hematologic cancer. The definition of clonal hematopoiesis of indeterminate potential requires that mutations are present with a variant allele frequency of 2% or higher and they are located in genes described to be affected in hematologic cancers. This condition is more common in older individuals and in those who have received treatment for other cancers. It is associated with both an increased risk of developing cardiovascular disease and hematologic cancers.  Also called CHIP.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804482" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clonal hematopoiesis of indeterminate potential&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000804483" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hematopoyesis clonal de potencial indeterminado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hematopoyesis clonal de potencial indeterminado</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Presencia de mutaciones somáticas en las células madre hematopoyéticas de una persona sin un cáncer hematológico detectable. Para definir la hematopoyesis clonal de potencial indeterminado se requiere que las mutaciones estén presentes con una frecuencia del alelo variante de 2 % o más, y que estén ubicadas en genes  que se describen como afectados en los cánceres hematológicos. Esta afección es más frecuente en personas mayores y en aquellos que recibieron tratamiento para otros cánceres. Se relaciona con un aumento del riesgo de enfermedades cardiovasculares y cánceres hematológicos. También se llama CHIP.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-11-24</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
