<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803553">
  <TermName>cognitive impairment</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KOG-nih-tiv im-PAYR-ment)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Problems with a person’s ability to think, learn, remember, use judgement, and make decisions. Signs of cognitive impairment include memory loss and trouble concentrating, completing tasks, understanding, remembering, following instructions, and solving problems. Other common signs may include changes in mood or behavior, loss of motivation, and being unaware of surroundings. Cognitive impairment may be mild or severe. There are many causes of cognitive impairment, including cancer and some cancer treatments.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805325" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cognitive impairment&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805326" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deterioro cognitivo&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>deterioro cognitivo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Alteraciones en el pensamiento, el aprendizaje, la memoria, el juicio y la toma de decisiones. Los signos del deterioro cognitivo incluyen pérdida de la memoria y dificultad para concentrarse, completar actividades, comprender, recordar, seguir instrucciones y solucionar problemas. Otros signos frecuentes son trastornos en el estado de ánimo o cambios de comportamiento, pérdida de la motivación y desorientación. El deterioro cognitivo puede ser leve o grave. Sus causas son muchas, entre ellas, el cáncer y algunos tratamientos del cáncer. También se llama deterioro cognoscitivo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-02-10</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000791425" url="/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/memory/cognitive-impairment-pdq">Cognitive Impairment in Adults with Cancer</RelatedSummaryRef>
    <RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000793794" url="/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/memoria/deterioro-cognitivo-pdq">Deterioro cognitivo en adultos con cáncer</RelatedSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
