<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803547">
  <TermName>naxitamab</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(nak-SIH-tuh-mab)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used with granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) to treat children aged 1 year and older and adults with certain types of high-risk neuroblastoma in the bone or bone marrow that came back or did not get better with other treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Naxitamab binds to a substance called GD2, which is found on some types of cancer cells. Naxitamab may block GD2 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Danyelza.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805319" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;naxitamab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805320" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;naxitamab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>naxitamab</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con el factor estimulante de colonias de granulocitos y macrófagos (GM-CSF) para el tratamiento de adultos y niños de 1 año o más con ciertos tipos de neuroblastoma de riesgo alto en el hueso o la médula ósea, y cuyo cáncer volvió o no mejoró después de recibir otro tratamiento. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El naxitamab se une a una sustancia llamada GD2, que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que el naxitamab bloquee GD2 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Danyelza.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2020-12-22</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
