<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803671">
  <TermName>trisomy 21</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(TRY-soh-mee …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A genetic condition caused by having an extra chromosome 21 in some or all of the body’s cells. Trisomy 21 is marked by growth, developmental, and learning delays that vary from mild to severe. People with trisomy 21 often have certain distinct physical features,  such as a shorter-than-normal height, a flat face with a short nose, eyes that are slanted and almond-shaped, small ears, a short neck, a tongue that tends to stick out of the mouth, small hands and feet, and a deep line that goes across the palm of the hand. People with trisomy 21 may also have muscle weakness, loose joints, heart defects, and other health problems. Having trisomy 21 increases the risk of developing Alzheimer disease at an early age, usually around the age of 50, and leukemia, especially in young children. Trisomy 21 is usually not inherited (passed from parent to child). Also called Down syndrome.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805345" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trisomy 21&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805346" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trisomía 21&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>trisomía 21</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección genética causada por tener un cromosoma 21 de más en todas las células del cuerpo o en algunas células. La trisomía 21 se caracteriza por retrasos del crecimiento, el desarrollo y el aprendizaje, que van de leves a graves. Las personas con trisomía 21 suelen tener rasgos físicos característicos, como una estatura más baja que lo normal, cara aplanada con nariz corta, ojos  rasgados con forma de almendra, orejas pequeñas, cuello corto y lengua que tienen a mantener fuera de la boca, además de manos y pies pequeños, y un surco profundo que atraviesa la palma de la mano. Las personas afectadas a veces también presentan músculos débiles, articulaciones elásticas, defectos del corazón y otros problemas de salud. Tener trisomía 21 aumenta el riesgo de enfermedad de Alzheimer a una edad temprana, a menudo cerca de los 50 años, y también aumenta el riesgo de leucemia, en especial, en personas jóvenes. La trisomía 21 por lo general no se hereda (no pasa de padres a hijos). También se llama síndrome de Down.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-03-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2021-03-23</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/diseases/10247/down-syndrome">Down syndrome (Genetic and Rare Diseases Information Center)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/down-syndrome/">Down syndrome (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://rarediseases.info.nih.gov/espanol/11883/sindrome-de-down">Síndrome de Down (Centro de Información sobre Enfermedades Genéticas y Raras)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/downsyndrome.html" UseWith="es">Síndrome de Down (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
