<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803736"><TermName>tumor heterogeneity</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TOO-mer HEH-teh-roh-jeh-NEE-ih-tee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term that describes the differences between tumors of the same type in different patients, the differences between cancer cells within a single tumor, or the differences between a primary (original) tumor and a secondary tumor. These differences may involve the tumor’s genes and proteins. For example, some cancer cells in a tumor may have genetic mutations (changes) that aren’t present in other cancer cells in that tumor.  Tumor heterogeneity can play an important role in how cancer is diagnosed and treated and how it responds to treatment.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805359" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor heterogeneity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805360" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;heterogeneidad tumoral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>heterogeneidad tumoral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que describe las diferencias entre tumores del mismo tipo que se presentan en diferentes pacientes, también se usa para describir diferencias en las células cancerosas del mismo tumor, o para describir diferencias entre un tumor primario (original) y un tumor secundario. En ocasiones, estas diferencias se encuentran en los genes y las proteínas del tumor. Por ejemplo, algunas células cancerosas tienen mutaciones (cambios) genéticas que no se presentan en otras células cancerosas del mismo tumor. La heterogeneidad tumoral a veces cumple una función importante durante el diagnóstico y el tratamiento del cáncer, y quizás afecte la respuesta al tratamiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-03-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
