<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803844"><TermName>chickenpox</TermName><TermPronunciation>(CHIH-ken-pox)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A highly contagious disease marked by an itchy, blister-like rash caused by the varicella-zoster virus (a type of herpesvirus). The virus is easily spread from person to person through contact with mucus, saliva, or fluid from the blisters of an infected person or through droplets released when an infected person coughs or sneezes. The rash usually appears first on the face, chest, and back and then spreads to the rest of the body. Other symptoms may include fever, headache, fatigue, and loss of appetite. Chickenpox can sometimes cause serious health problems, especially in infants, teenagers, adults, pregnant women, and those who have a weakened immune system. Widespread use of the chickenpox vaccine since the early 1990s has prevented most cases of chickenpox in the United States. Also called varicella.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805369" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chickenpox&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805370" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;varicela&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>varicela</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad muy contagiosa causada por el virus de la varicela zóster (tipo de virus del herpes) que se caracteriza por sarpullido con vesículas y picazón. El virus se transmite con facilidad de una persona a otra por el contacto con el moco, la saliva o el líquido de las vesículas de una persona infectada o mediante las gotitas que se dispersan cuando una persona infectada tose o estornuda. Por lo general, el sarpullido aparece primero en la cara, el tórax y la espalda y después se extiende al resto del cuerpo. Otros síntomas incluyen fiebre, dolor de cabeza, fatiga y pérdida de apetito. En ocasiones,  la varicela causa problemas de salud graves, en especial, en lactantes, adolescentes, adultos, embarazadas y quienes tienen un sistema inmunitario debilitado. En los Estados Unidos, la vacunación generalizada contra la varicela desde comienzos de la década de 1990  ha prevenido la mayoría de los casos de esta enfermedad. También se llama lechina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-04-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
