<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803848">
  <TermName>herpes zoster</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(HER-peez ZOS-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A common condition that occurs when the virus that causes chickenpox is reactivated in the body. After having chickenpox, the virus stays inactive in the body, usually in the nerves along the spinal cord or at the base of the skull. The virus can become active again many years later and cause  herpes zoster. Herpes zoster is marked by a painful rash that usually appears as small clusters of blisters. The blisters often form a band across the skin on one side of the body, especially on the chest, back, waist, or face. The pain in the affected area can last for many weeks or months after the rash disappears. Other symptoms may include fever, chills, headache, fatigue, and upset stomach. Herpes zoster is most common in older adults and in those who have a weakened immune system. It cannot be passed from person to person, but those who have never had chickenpox or the chickenpox vaccine can develop chickenpox if they come in contact with a person who has herpes zoster. Vaccines are available to prevent herpes zoster. Also called shingles.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805375" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;herpes zoster&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805376" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;herpes zóster&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>herpes zóster</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección común que se presenta cuando el virus que causa la varicela se reactiva en el cuerpo. Después de tener varicela, el virus permanece inactivo en el cuerpo, por lo general en los nervios de la médula espinal o en la base del cráneo. El virus a veces se reactiva después de muchos años y causa el herpes zóster, que se caracteriza por un sarpullido doloroso que a menudo aparece como grupos pequeños de vesículas o ampollas. Las vesículas suelen formar una franja en la piel de un lado del cuerpo, en particular en el tórax, la espalda, la cintura o la cara. Es posible que el área afectada duela por muchas semanas o meses después que el sarpullido desaparece. Otros síntomas incluyen fiebre, escalofríos, dolor de cabeza, fatiga y malestar estomacal. El herpes zóster es más frecuente en adultos mayores y en personas con el sistema inmunitario debilitado. No se transmite de una persona a otra, pero es posible que quienes nunca tuvieron varicela ni recibieron la vacuna contra este virus, se contagien con la varicela si entran en contacto con una persona que tenga el herpes zóster. Hay vacunas disponibles para prevenir el herpes zóster. También se llama culebrilla y herpes zona.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-04-07</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
