<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803842"><TermName>STD</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A disease caused by infection with certain bacteria, viruses, or other microorganisms that can be passed from one person to another through blood, semen, vaginal fluids, or other body fluids, during oral, anal, or genital sex with an infected partner. These diseases can also be spread through sharing needles, blood transfusions, breastfeeding, or from an infected mother to an infant during pregnancy and childbirth. Symptoms of  STDs may include sores, blisters, or bumps on the genitals or in the mouth or rectal area, pain or burning during urination or sex, unusual drainage or bleeding from the penis or vagina, itching and redness in the genital or anal area, pain in the lower abdomen, fever, and sore, swollen lymph nodes, especially in the groin. There are many types of STDs, including human papillomavirus (HPV), HIV, genital herpes, chlamydia, gonorrhea, and syphilis. If not treated, some STDs can lead to long-term health problems. Also called sexually transmitted disease, sexually transmitted infection, and STI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>ETS</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad causada por la infección por ciertas bacterias, virus u otros microorganismos y que se transmite de una persona a otra a través  de la sangre, el semen, las secreciones vaginales u otros líquidos corporales durante el sexo oral, anal o genital con un compañero infectado. También, en ocasiones, estas enfermedades se transmiten al compartir agujas, durante las transfusiones de sangre, en la lactancia materna o durante el embarazo y el parto, cuando una madre infectada pasa la infección al bebé. Los síntomas de una ETS  son llagas, ampollas o abultamientos en los genitales o en el área de la boca o el recto, dolor o ardor al orinar o al tener relaciones sexuales, secreción inusual o sangrado del pene o la vagina, picazón y enrojecimiento en el área de los genitales o el ano, dolor en la parte baja del abdomen, fiebre, así como ganglios linfáticos hinchados y adoloridos, en particular en la ingle. Hay varios tipos de ETS, como la sífilis y la gonorrea, o las causadas por el virus del papiloma humano (VPH), el virus de la inmunodeficiencia humana (VIH), el herpes genital y la clamidia. Es posible que algunas ETS causen problemas de salud a largo plazo si no se tratan. También se llama enfermedad de transmisión sexual, infección de transmisión sexual e ITS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-04-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
