<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000803964"><TermName>Breyanzi</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brey-AN-zee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A treatment used for adults with chronic lymphocytic leukemia, small lymphocytic lymphoma, follicular lymphoma, mantle cell lymphoma, or certain types of large B-cell lymphoma that relapsed (came back) or did not get better after treatment with at least one or two lines of systemic therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Breyanzi is made using a patient’s T cells (a type of immune system cell). A gene for a special receptor called chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is added to the T cells in the laboratory. These changed T cells called CAR T cells are grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. Breyanzi binds to a protein called CD19, which is found on most B-cell lymphoma cells. This helps the body’s immune system kill cancer cells. Breyanzi is a type of cellular immunotherapy called CAR T-cell therapy. Also called lisocabtagene maraleucel.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805385" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Breyanzi&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805386" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Breyanzi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774647" type="image/jpeg" alt="CAR T-cell therapy; drawing of blood being removed from a vein in a patient’s arm to get T cells. Also shown is a special receptor called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) being made in the laboratory; the gene for CAR is inserted into the T cells and then millions of CAR T cells are grown. Drawing also shows the CAR T cells being given to the patient by infusion and binding to antigens on the cancer cells and killing them." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">CAR T-cell therapy. A type of treatment in which a patient’s T cells (a type of immune cell) are changed in the laboratory so they will bind to cancer cells and kill them. Blood from a vein in the patient’s arm flows through a tube to an apheresis machine (not shown), which removes the white blood cells, including the T cells, and sends the rest of the blood back to the patient. Then, the gene for a special receptor called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is inserted into the T cells in the laboratory. Millions of the CAR T cells are grown in the laboratory and then given to the patient by infusion. The CAR T cells are able to bind to an antigen on the cancer cells and kill them.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000791284" type="image/jpeg" alt="Terapia de células T con CAR. En el dibujo se muestra que se extrae sangre de una vena del brazo de un paciente para obtener células T. También se muestra que se elabora en el laboratorio un receptor especial, que se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR); se añade a las células T el gen que produce el CAR y luego se reproducen millones de células T con CAR. Además, se muestra que el paciente recibe las células T con CAR mediante infusión, y que luego estas células se unen a los antígenos de las células cancerosas y las destruyen." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Terapia de células T con CAR. Tipo de tratamiento  en el que se modifican las células T (un tipo de célula inmunitaria) de un paciente en el laboratorio a fin de que se unan a las células cancerosas y las destruyan. La sangre de una vena del brazo del paciente pasa por un tubo hasta una máquina de  aféresis (no se muestra) que extrae los glóbulos blancos, incluso las células T, y devuelve el resto de la sangre al paciente. Luego,   en el laboratorio, el gen que produce un receptor especial, que se llama receptor quimérico para el antígeno (CAR), se añade a las células T, y se reproducen millones de células T con CAR que el paciente recibe mediante infusión. Las células T   con CAR se unen a un antígeno de las células cancerosas y las destruyen.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>Breyanzi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia linfocítica crónica, linfoma linfocítico pequeño, linfoma folicular, linfoma de células de manto o ciertos tipos de linfoma de células B grandes que recidivó (volvió), o que o no mejoró después de recibir al menos una o dos líneas de tratamiento sistémico. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Breyanzi se produce a partir de las células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria) de un paciente. En el laboratorio, se añade a las células T un gen de un receptor especial llamado receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR). Estas células T modificadas, llamadas células T con CAR, se producen en grandes cantidades en el laboratorio y se administran al paciente mediante infusión. Breyanzi se une a una proteína  llamada CD19 que se encuentra en la mayoría de las células del linfoma de células B, lo que ayuda al sistema inmunitario del cuerpo a destruir  células cancerosas. Breyanzi es un tipo de inmunoterapia celular llamada terapia de células T con CAR. También se llama lisocabtagén maraleucel.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-02-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-06-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000803971" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/lisocabtagenemaraleucel">Lisocabtagene Maraleucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
