<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804081">
  <TermName>serology test</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(seh-RAH-loh-jee …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A laboratory test that checks for the presence of antibodies or other substances in a blood sample. Antibodies are proteins made by the body’s immune system in response to a foreign substance or microorganism, such as a virus. Serology tests look for certain antibodies to see whether a person has been exposed to or infected with a virus or other infectious agent. Sometimes antibodies are made against the body’s own tissues. In that case, serology tests are used to look for those antibodies and help diagnose certain immune system disorders, such as autoimmune disorders and immunodeficiency disorders. Serology tests are also used to determine a person’s blood or tissue type.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805958" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;serology test&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805959" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba serológica&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>prueba serológica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio para detectar  anticuerpos u otras sustancias en una muestra de sangre. Los anticuerpos son proteínas que elabora el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo como respuesta a una sustancia o microorganismo extraño, como un virus. Con  una prueba serológica se busca detectar ciertos anticuerpos para determinar si una persona se expuso o se infectó por un microorganismo infeccioso. A veces, se producen anticuerpos contra los tejidos del propio cuerpo y en ese caso, la prueba serológica se usa para determinar la presencia de estos anticuerpos y ayudar a diagnosticar ciertos trastornos del sistema inmunitario, como los trastornos autoinmunitarios y de inmunodeficiencia. Las pruebas serológicas también sirven para determinar el tipo de sangre o de tejido de una persona. También se llama análisis serológico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-06-08</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
