<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804083"><TermName>seropositive</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SEER-oh-PAH-zih-tiv)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes a laboratory test result that shows the presence of a specific marker, usually an antibody, in the blood. Antibodies are proteins made by the body’s immune system in response to a foreign substance or microorganism, such as a virus. A seropositive test result usually means that a person has been exposed to or infected with a virus or other infectious agent and has made antibodies against it. Sometimes antibodies are made against the body’s own tissues. In that case, a seropositive test result means that a person has antibodies or other markers for a certain disease, such as an autoimmune disease. More testing may be needed to make a diagnosis or to make sure a seropositive test result is correct.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805960" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;seropositive&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805961" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;seropositivo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>seropositivo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Resultado de una prueba de laboratorio que indica la presencia de un marcador específico, por lo común un anticuerpo, en la sangre. Los anticuerpos son proteínas que elabora el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo como respuesta a una sustancia o microorganismo extraño, como un virus. Un resultado seropositivo por lo general significa que una persona se expuso o se infectó por un virus u otro microorganismo infeccioso de manera que produjo anticuerpos contra ese microorganismo. A veces, se producen anticuerpos contra los  tejidos del propio cuerpo y en este caso, un resultado seropositivo significa que una persona tiene anticuerpos u otros marcadores para determinada enfermedad, como una enfermedad autoinmunitaria. Es posible que se necesiten más pruebas para  hacer un diagnóstico o para asegurarse de que el resultado seropositivo de una prueba es correcto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-06-08</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
