<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804085">
  <TermName>seronegative</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SEER-oh-NEH-guh-tiv)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Describes a laboratory test result that shows that a substance the test is supposed to find, such as an antibody, is not present at all or is present  in very small amounts. Antibodies are proteins made by the body’s immune system in response to a foreign substance or microorganism, such as a virus. A seronegative test result usually means that a person has not been exposed to or infected with a virus or other infectious agent and has not made antibodies against that agent. Sometimes antibodies are made against the body’s own tissues. In that case, a seronegative test result means that a person does not have the antibodies or other markers for a certain disease, such as an autoimmune disease. More testing may be needed to make sure a seronegative test result is correct.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805962" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;seronegative&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805963" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;seronegativo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>seronegativo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Resultado de una prueba de laboratorio que indica que no se detectó una sustancia, como un anticuerpo, que se busca detectar con esta prueba, o que se detectó en cantidades muy pequeñas. Los anticuerpos son proteínas que elabora el sistema inmunitario  del cuerpo como respuesta a una sustancia o microorganismo extraño, como un virus. Un resultado seronegativo por lo general significa que una persona no se expuso ni se infectó  por un virus u otro  microorganismo infeccioso  de manera que no  produjo anticuerpos contra ese microorganismo. A veces, se producen anticuerpos contra los  tejidos del propio cuerpo y en ese caso, un resultado seronegativo significa que una persona no tiene los anticuerpos u otros marcadores para determinada enfermedad, como una enfermedad autoinmunitaria. Es posible que se necesiten más pruebas para asegurarse de que el resultado seronegativo de una prueba es correcto.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-06-08</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
