<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804062">
  <TermName>reduced penetrance</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ree-DOOST PEH-neh-trunts)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Penetrance refers to the likelihood that a clinical condition will occur when a particular genotype is present. A condition is said to show incomplete penetrance when some individuals who carry the pathogenic variant express the associated trait while others do not. Also called incomplete penetrance.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term that describes when some people with a disease-causing mutation (change) in a gene develop the disease while others don’t. For example, certain gene mutations cause cancer, but because of reduced penetrance, not everyone who has the mutation will develop cancer. Currently, there is no way to know which people who have a cancer-causing gene mutation will develop cancer. Also called incomplete penetrance.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805946" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;reduced penetrance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000805947" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;penetrancia reducida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>penetrancia reducida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>La penetrancia se refiere a la probabilidad de que una afección clínica se manifieste cuando está presente un genotipo específico. Se dice que una afección tiene penetrancia incompleta cuando algunos portadores de la variante patógena expresan  el rasgo asociado mientras que otros no lo expresan. También se llama penetrancia incompleta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término que se usa cuando solo algunas de las personas que tienen una mutación (cambio en un gen) causal de enfermedad presentan la enfermedad, mientras que otras no se enferman. Por ejemplo, ciertas mutaciones causan cáncer, pero debido  a su penetrancia reducida, no todas las personas que tienen la mutación se enfermarán de cáncer. En la actualidad, no hay manera de saber si una persona que tiene una mutación causal de enfermedad presentará cáncer. También se llama penetrancia incompleta.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-06-08</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
