<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804510"><TermName>tivozanib hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ty-VOH-zuh-nib HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with advanced renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer). It is used in patients whose cancer has relapsed (come back) or has not gotten better after treatment with at least two other types of systemic therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Tivozanib hydrochloride blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Tivozanib hydrochloride is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called Fotivda.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805397" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tivozanib hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805398" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de tivozanib&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de tivozanib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón) en estadio avanzado. Se emplea en pacientes cuyo cáncer recidivó (volvió) o no mejoró después de recibir por lo menos otros dos tipos de terapia sistémica. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de tivozanib bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás  evite la multiplicación de células cancerosas. Además, es posible que evite la formación de los vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. El clorhidrato de tivozanib es un tipo de antiangiogénico y de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama Fotivda y tivozanib hidrocloruro.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-03-22</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000804514" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tivozanibhydrochloride">Tivozanib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
