<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804587">
  <TermName>onychodystrophy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ON-ih-koh-DIS-truh-fee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Distortion or malformation of the fingernails and toenails. Also called nail dystrophy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Abnormal changes in the shape, color, texture, and growth of the fingernails or toenails. Onychodystrophy is often caused by infection or injury to the nail. It may also be caused by certain conditions, including psoriasis, eczema, warts, cysts, and some tumors. Changes in nails can also be a sign of chronic heart, lung, liver, or kidney disease. Treatment with certain drugs, including chemotherapy drugs, can also cause changes to the nails. Also called nail dystrophy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000806829" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;onychodystrophy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000806830" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;onicodistrofia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>onicodistrofia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Distorsión o deformidad de las uñas de las manos y los pies. También se llama distrofia ungueal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Health professional</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Cambios anormales en la forma, el color, la textura y el crecimiento de las uñas de las manos y los pies. La causa de la onicodistrofia a menudo es una infección o traumatismo en la uña. También, es posible que ciertas afecciones, como psoriasis, eczema, verrugas, quistes y algunos tumores causen estos cambios. Además, a veces son un signo de enfermedades crónicas en el corazón, los pulmones, el hígado o los riñones. Asimismo, el tratamiento con ciertos medicamentos, como los que se usan en la quimioterapia, puede causar cambios en las uñas. También se llama distrofia ungueal.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-09-10</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
