<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804622"><TermName>Abecma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-BEK-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A treatment used for adults with multiple myeloma that came back or did not get better after treatment with at least two lines of anticancer therapy that included an immunomodulating agent, a proteasome inhibitor, and an anti-CD38 monoclonal antibody. Abecma is made using a patient’s T cells (a type of immune system cell). A gene for a special receptor called chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is added to the T cells in the laboratory. These changed T cells called CAR T cells are grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. Abecma binds to a protein called BCMA, which is found on myeloma cells and some types of immune cells. This helps the body’s immune system kill cancer cells. Abecma is a type of cellular immunotherapy called CAR T-cell therapy. Also called idecabtagene vicleucel.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805404" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Abecma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805965" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Abecma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Abecma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con mieloma múltiple que recidivó (volvió), o que no mejoró después de recibir por lo menos dos líneas de terapias contra el cáncer que incluyeron un inmunomodulador, un inhibidor del proteasoma y un anticuerpo monoclonal anti-CD38. Abecma se produce a partir de las células T (tipo de célula del sistema inmunitario) del paciente. En el laboratorio, se añade a las células T el gen de un receptor especial llamado receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR). Estas células T modificadas, llamadas células T con CAR, se producen en grandes cantidades en el laboratorio y se administran al paciente mediante infusión. Abecma se une a una proteína llamada BCMA, que se encuentra en las células de mieloma y en algunos tipos de células inmunitarias, lo que ayuda al sistema inmunitario del cuerpo a destruir células cancerosas. Abecma es un tipo de inmunoterapia celular llamada terapia de células T con CAR. También se llama idecabtagén vicleucel.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-04-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000804623" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/Idecabtagenevicleucel">Idecabtagene Vicleucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
