<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804893"><TermName>Zynlonta</TermName><TermPronunciation>(zin-LON-tuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma that relapsed (came back) or did not get better after treatment with at least two other types of systemic therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Zynlonta contains a monoclonal antibody that binds to a protein called CD19, which is found on some lymphoma cells. It also contains an anticancer drug, which may help kill cancer cells. Zynlonta is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called loncastuximab tesirine.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805974" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zynlonta&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805975" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zynlonta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Zynlonta</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B que recidivó (volvió) o no mejoró después de recibir por lo menos otros dos tipos de tratamiento sistémico. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Zynlonta contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal  que se une a una proteína llamada CD19 que se encuentra en algunas células del linfoma. También contiene un fármaco contra el cáncer y es posible que ayude a destruir células cancerosas. Zynlonta es un tipo de conjugado anticuerpo-fármaco. También se llama loncastuximab tesirina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-05-05</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000804889" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/loncastuximabtesirine-lpyl">Loncastuximab Tesirine-lpyl</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
