<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804973"><TermName>complex sclerosing lesion</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-plex skleh-ROH-sing LEE-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) area of hardened tissue in the breast that looks like a scar when viewed under a microscope. Complex sclerosing lesions often occur in both breasts, and more than one lesion is usually present in each breast. They usually cannot be felt and do not cause symptoms but may look like breast cancer on a mammogram, especially if the lesions are large. A biopsy is usually needed to tell the difference between these lesions and breast cancer. Complex sclerosing lesions may slightly increase the risk of breast cancer. Also called radial scar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806843" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complex sclerosing lesion&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806844" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lesión esclerosante compleja&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>lesión esclerosante compleja</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Área de la mama con tejido benigno (no canceroso) endurecido que se parece a una cicatriz cuando se observa al microscopio. Las lesiones esclerosantes complejas suelen aparecer  en ambas mamas, y casi siempre hay más de una lesión en cada una de ellas. A menudo, no se sienten al tacto ni producen síntomas, pero en la mamografía se ven  parecidas al cáncer de mama, en especial, cuando las lesiones son grandes. Por lo general, se necesita una biopsia para diferenciar estas lesiones del cáncer de mama. La presencia de lesiones esclerosantes complejas quizás aumente un poco el riesgo de cáncer de mama. También se llama cicatriz radial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-08-09</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-11-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
