<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804934"><TermName>prostate-specific membrane antigen PET scan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PROS-tayt-speh-SIH-fik MEM-brayn AN-tih-jen … skan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An imaging procedure that is used to help find prostate cancer cells in the body. For this procedure, a cell-targeting molecule linked to a radioactive substance is injected into the body and travels through the blood. It attaches to a protein called prostate-specific membrane antigen (PSMA) that is found on the surface of prostate cancer cells. A PET scanner detects high concentrations of the radioactive molecule and shows where the prostate cancer cells are in the body. A prostate-specific membrane antigen PET scan may be used to help diagnose prostate cancer that may have come back or spread to other parts of the body. It may also be used to help plan treatment. Also called PSMA PET scan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805976" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prostate-specific membrane antigen PET scan&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000805977" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;TEP con antígeno prostático específico de membrana&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>TEP con antígeno prostático específico de membrana</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento con imágenes que se usa para encontrar células de cáncer de próstata en el cuerpo. Para este procedimiento  se utiliza una molécula dirigida a las células unida a  una sustancia radiactiva, que se inyecta en el cuerpo y viaja por la sangre. Esta molécula se adhiere a una proteína llamada antígeno prostático específico de membrana (PSMA) en la superficie de las células del cáncer de próstata. Luego se usa una tomografía por emisión de positrones (TEP) para detectar concentraciones altas de la molécula radiactiva de manera que se resalta la ubicación de las células del cáncer de próstata en el cuerpo. Es posible usar una TEP con antígeno prostático específico de membrana para facilitar el diagnóstico del cáncer de próstata que recidivó o se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo, así como para planificar el tratamiento. También se llama TEP con PSMA y tomografía por emisión de positrones con antígeno prostático específico de membrana.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-05-27</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
