<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000804989">
  <TermName>breast pain</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(brest payn)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Pain or discomfort in one or both breasts. The pain can be mild or severe and affect one area of the breast or the whole breast, including under the arm. It may also come from nearby muscles or joints outside the breast. Breast pain in women is most often caused by hormone changes before and during the menstrual cycle. It may also be unrelated to the menstrual cycle, with causes that include pregnancy, breastfeeding, smoking, too much caffeine or fat in the diet, certain medicines, breast surgery, injury to the breast or chest wall, or certain breast conditions. It is rarely caused by breast cancer. Breast pain can occur in both women and men. Also called mastalgia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000806861" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast pain&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000806862" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dolor de mama&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>dolor de mama</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Dolor o molestia en una o ambas mamas. El dolor puede ser leve o intenso. A veces afecta solo una parte de la mama, y otras veces afecta toda la mama y llega a la axila. También es posible que se origine en los músculos o en las articulaciones cercanas. La causa más frecuente del dolor de mama en las mujeres son  los cambios hormonales propios del ciclo menstrual. En otros casos no se relaciona con el ciclo menstrual, y se debe a  causas como embarazo, lactancia materna, consumo de tabaco, consumo excesivo de cafeína o grasa en la dieta, uso  de ciertos medicamentos, cirugía mamaria, traumatismos en las mamas o la pared torácica y determinadas afecciones. El cáncer de mama es una causa infrecuente de este síntoma.   El dolor de mama se presenta en hombres y mujeres. También se llama dolor de seno, dolor mamario y mastalgia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-08-09</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
