<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805000"><TermName>breast fibrosis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest fy-BROH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) condition in which thickened or fibrous (scar-like) tissue is found in the breast. The areas of fibrosis usually feel firm, rubbery, or hard under the skin. Breast fibrosis may occur along with other changes in the breast, including cysts, breast swelling or discomfort, and nipple discharge. These changes may come and go throughout the menstrual cycle and usually stop after menopause. Breast fibrosis can occur at any age but is most common in younger women. Having breast fibrosis does not increase the risk of breast cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806869" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast fibrosis&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806870" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fibrosis mamaria&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>fibrosis mamaria</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección benigna (no cancerosa) en la que se encuentra tejido fibroso (similar a una cicatriz) o engrosado en la mama. Las áreas con  fibrosis suelen sentirse firmes, gomosas o duras debajo de la piel. La fibrosis a veces se presenta al mismo tiempo que otros cambios en la mama, como quistes, hinchazón o molestias, o secreción por el pezón. Los cambios pueden ser pasajeros o cambiantes durante el ciclo menstrual y a menudo desaparecen después de la menopausia. La fibrosis de la mama ocurre a cualquier edad, pero es más frecuente en mujeres jóvenes. Esta afección no aumenta el riesgo de cáncer de mama. También se llama fibrosis de la mama y fibrosis en los senos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-08-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
