<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805179"><TermName>grade I ductal carcinoma in situ</TermName><TermPronunciation>(grayd … DUK-tul KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which cells that look mostly like normal cells under a microscope are found in the lining of a breast duct. The abnormal cells have not spread outside the duct to other tissues in the breast.  Grade I ductal carcinoma in situ tends to grow more slowly than grade II or grade III ductal carcinoma in situ. It is also less likely to come back or become invasive breast cancer and spread to other tissues.  Also called grade I DCIS, low-grade DCIS, and low-grade ductal carcinoma in situ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808438" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grade I ductal carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808439" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma ductal in situ de grado I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma ductal in situ de grado I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que se encuentran células anormales en el revestimiento de un conducto de la mama. Estas células son muy parecidas a las células normales cuando se observan al microscopio. Las células anormales no se han diseminado a otros tejidos de la mama fuera del conducto.  El carcinoma ductal in situ de grado I suele crecer más despacio que el carcinoma ductal in situ de grado II o de grado III. Además, es menos probable que vuelva o se convierta en un cáncer de mama invasivo y se disemine a otros tejidos. También se llama carcinoma ductal in situ de grado bajo, CDIS de grado bajo y CDIS de grado I.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-10-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-05-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
