<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805159">
  <TermName>lifestyle risk factor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... FAK-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Personal behaviors or choices that can increase a person’s chance of developing a disease. Lifestyle risk factors can often be avoided, controlled, or changed to reduce the risk of certain diseases, such as cancer, diabetes, obesity, and heart disease. Some examples of lifestyle risk factors include cigarette smoking or other tobacco use, having an unhealthy diet, not getting enough exercise, and drinking too much alcohol.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808418" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lifestyle risk factor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808419" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;factor de riesgo relacionado con el estilo de vida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>factor de riesgo relacionado con el estilo de vida</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Comportamientos o elecciones de una persona que aumentan la probabilidad de que presente una enfermedad. Es posible evitar, controlar o cambiar los factores de riesgo relacionados con el estilo de vida para minimizar el riesgo de ciertas enfermedades, como el cáncer, la diabetes, la obesidad o las cardiopatías. Algunos ejemplos de factores de riesgo relacionados con el estilo de vida son el consumo de cigarrillo y el uso del tabaco, la alimentación poco saludable, el ejercicio físico insuficiente o el consumo excesivo de bebidas alcohólicas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-10-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk" UseWith="en">Risk Factors for Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo" UseWith="es">Factores de riesgo de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
