<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805174"><TermName>grade II ductal carcinoma in situ</TermName><TermPronunciation>(grayd … DUK-tul KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which cells that look somewhat abnormal under a microscope are found in the lining of a breast duct. The abnormal cells have not spread outside the duct to other tissues in the breast. Grade II ductal carcinoma in situ tends to grow more quickly than grade I ductal carcinoma in situ but not as quickly as grade III ductal carcinoma in situ. It is also more likely than grade I ductal carcinoma in situ to come back or become invasive breast cancer and spread to other tissues but not as likely as grade III ductal carcinoma in situ. Also called grade II DCIS, intermediate-grade DCIS, and intermediate-grade ductal carcinoma in situ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808432" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grade II ductal carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808433" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma ductal in situ de grado II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma ductal in situ de grado II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que se encuentran células anormales en el revestimiento de un conducto de la mama. Estas células se ven un poco anormales cuando se observan al microscopio. Las células anormales no se han diseminado a  otros tejidos de la mama fuera del conducto. El carcinoma ductal in situ de grado II suele crecer más rápido que el carcinoma ductal in situ de grado I, pero no tan rápido como el de grado III. Además, es más probable que vuelva, o se convierta en un cáncer de mama invasivo y se disemine a otros tejidos, cuando se lo compara con el carcinoma ductal in situ de grado I. Pero menos probable, cuando se lo compara con el de grado III. También se llama carcinoma ductal in situ de grado intermedio, CDIS de grado II y CDIS de grado intermedio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-10-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-05-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
