<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805419"><TermName>molecular profiling</TermName><TermPronunciation>(muh-LEH-kyoo-ler PROH-fy-ling)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory method that uses a sample of tissue, blood, or other body fluid to check for certain genes, proteins, or other molecules that may be a sign of a disease or condition, such as cancer.  Molecular profiling can also be used to  check for certain changes in a gene or chromosome that may increase a person’s risk of developing cancer or other diseases. Molecular profiling may be done with other procedures, such as biopsies, to help diagnose some types of cancer. It may also be used to help plan treatment, find out how well treatment is working, make a prognosis, or predict whether cancer will come back or spread to other parts of the body. Also called biomarker testing and molecular testing.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808450" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;molecular profiling&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808451" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;perfil molecular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>perfil molecular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método de laboratorio en el que se usa una muestra de tejido, sangre o líquido corporal para verificar si hay ciertos genes, proteínas u otras moléculas que son signo de una enfermedad o afección, como el cáncer. El perfil molecular también se usa para detectar si hay ciertos cambios en un gen o cromosoma que quizás aumenten el riesgo de una persona de presentar cáncer u otras enfermedades. El perfil molecular a veces se hace con otros procedimientos, como biopsias, para ayudar a diagnosticar algunos tipos de cáncer. Además, en ocasiones se utiliza para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento, determinar cuán eficaz es el mismo, establecer un pronóstico o predecir si el cáncer volverá o se diseminará a otras partes del cuerpo. También se llama prueba de biomarcadores y prueba molecular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-10-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-10-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/biomarker-testing-cancer-treatment">Biomarker Testing for Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/pruebas-de-biomarcadores-tratamiento-cancer">Pruebas de biomarcadores para el tratamiento de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
