<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805625">
  <TermName>social determinants of health</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SOH-shul deh-TER-mih-nunts … helth)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The social, economic, and physical conditions in the places where people are born and where they live, learn, work, play, and get older that can affect their health, well-being, and quality of life. Social determinants of health include  factors such as education level, income, employment, housing, transportation, and access to healthy food, clean air and water, and health care services. Social determinants of health have  an important effect on health outcomes, especially in certain groups of people. For example, people who cannot afford healthy food or who do not live in a safe area for exercise are more likely to have a poor diet, be physically inactive, and have obesity. This can increase their risk of developing certain diseases, such as cancer. Also called SDOH.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808460" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;social determinants of health&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808461" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;determinantes sociales de la salud&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>determinantes sociales de la salud</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Condiciones sociales, económicas y físicas del lugar donde una persona nace, vive, estudia, trabaja, se divierte y envejece, que pueden afectar la salud, el bienestar y la calidad de vida. Los determinantes sociales de la salud son, por ejemplo, el grado de escolaridad, el ingreso, el empleo, la vivienda, el transporte y el acceso a alimentos saludables, aire y agua limpios y servicios de atención de la salud. Estos determinantes tienen efectos importantes en los resultados de salud, en especial, en ciertos grupos de personas. Por ejemplo, es más probable que las personas que no pueden comprar alimentos saludables y que no viven en áreas seguras para hacer ejercicio ingieran una dieta poco saludable, sean sedentarios y presenten obesidad, lo que quizás aumente el riesgo de ciertas enfermedades, como el  cáncer. También se llama determinantes sociales en salud y DSS.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-11-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/understanding/disparities" UseWith="en">Cancer Disparities</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/naturaleza/desigualdades" UseWith="es">Desigualdades por cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
