<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805616"><TermName>palliative care specialist</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PA-lee-uh-tiv kayr SPEH-shuh-list)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A health care professional who has special training in providing care to people who have a serious or life-threatening disease, such as cancer. Palliative care specialists prevent or treat as early as possible the symptoms of a disease, side effects caused by treatment of a disease, and psychological, social, and spiritual problems related to a disease or its treatment. They also provide family and caregiver support and coordinate communication between other members of the health care team. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808452" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;palliative care specialist&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808453" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;especialista en cuidados paliativos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>especialista en cuidados paliativos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Profesional de atención de la salud que ha recibido formación especializada en la atención de personas con enfermedades graves o potencialmente mortales, como el cáncer. Las personas que se dedican a los cuidados paliativos se encargan de la prevención o el tratamiento, tan pronto como sea posible, de los síntomas de la enfermedad, los efectos secundarios del tratamiento y los problemas psicológicos, sociales y espirituales vinculados con la enfermedad o su tratamiento. También proporcionan apoyo a la familia y cuidadores del paciente; además, coordinan la comunicación con otros miembros del equipo de atención médica. También se llama especialista en atención paliativa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-11-23</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/advanced-cancer/care-choices/palliative-care-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Palliative Care in Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq/information-summaries/supportive-care" UseWith="en">PDQ® Cancer Information Summaries: Supportive and Palliative Care</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/cancer-avanzado/opciones-de-cuidado/hoja-informativa-cuidados-paliativos" UseWith="es">Cuidados paliativos durante el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq/sumarios-de-informacion/cuidados-medicos-apoyo" UseWith="es">Sumarios del PDQ® de información sobre el cáncer: Cuidados médicos de apoyo y cuidados paliativos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
