<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805622">
  <TermName>health equity</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(helth EH-kwih-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A situation in which all people are given the chance to live as healthy a life as possible regardless of their  race, ethnicity, sex, sexual orientation, disability, education, job, religion, language, where they live, or other factors. A lack of health equity can result in differences in health outcomes, such as rates and severity of disease, disability, death, and quality of life. There are efforts to promote health equity by looking at root causes and removing barriers to equal access to health care services.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808458" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;health equity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808459" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;equidad en salud&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>equidad en salud</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Situación en la que todas las personas tienen la oportunidad de llevar una vida lo más saludable posible sin importar su raza, etnia, sexo, orientación sexual, discapacidad, formación, empleo, religión, lenguaje y domicilio, entre otros factores. Es posible que la inequidad en salud derive en diferencias en los resultados de salud, como en las tasas de una enfermedad y su gravedad, discapacidad, muerte y calidad de vida. Hay esfuerzos en curso para promover la equidad en salud mediante el estudio de las causas primarias y la eliminación de las barreras para un acceso equitativo a los servicios de salud.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-11-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2025-01-31</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
