<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805620"><TermName>diversity</TermName><TermPronunciation>(dih-VER-sih-tee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Having people with different physical, social, and personal traits or characteristics in a group or organization. These characteristics may include race, ethnicity, age, gender, sexual identity, religion, physical and mental ability, language, income, and education. Diversity may also include different life experiences, cultural backgrounds, beliefs, and interests in a group. In cancer research, there are efforts being made to increase the diversity of people enrolled in clinical trials so that the trial results represent a wider group of people who would most likely benefit from the treatment or intervention being studied.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808456" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;diversity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808457" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;diversidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>diversidad</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Presencia de personas con diferentes características físicas, sociales y personales en un grupo u organización. Estas características son, entre otras, raza, etnia, edad, sexo, identidad sexual, religión, capacidad física y mental, idioma, ingresos y formación. La diversidad a veces también indica diferencias en las experiencias de vida, los antecedentes culturales, las creencias y los intereses dentro del grupo. En la investigación del cáncer, se están haciendo esfuerzos por aumentar la diversidad de las personas que se inscriben en los ensayos clínicos para que los resultados representen a un grupo más amplio de personas que es probable que se beneficien del tratamiento o la intervención en estudio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-11-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
