<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805627"><TermName>health disparity</TermName><TermPronunciation>(helth dih-SPAYR-ih-tee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of preventable health difference that is closely linked with social, political, economic, and environmental disadvantage. Health disparities may occur because of race, ethnicity, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability, education, income, where people live, or other characteristics. For example, certain race and ethnic groups may have higher rates of disease, disability, and death than those in other groups because they are more likely to have problems having access to good health care, healthy food, or the latest medical treatments. Research is being done to learn more about health disparities in certain groups of people and ways to reduce them. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808462" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;health disparity&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808463" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;desigualdad en salud&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>desigualdad en salud</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de diferencia en el estado de salud que es prevenible y presenta una relación estrecha con desventajas sociales, políticas, económicas y ambientales. Las desigualdades en salud a veces se originan en características como la raza, la etnia, el sexo, la identidad de género, la orientación sexual, la edad, la religión, la discapacidad, la formación, el ingreso, el domicilio, entre otras. Por ejemplo, determinados grupos de raza o etnia en ocasiones tienen tasas más altas de enfermedad, discapacidad y muerte en comparación con otros grupos porque es más probable que se les dificulte el acceso a una atención de salud adecuada, alimentación saludable o tratamientos médicos de vanguardia. Están en curso  investigaciones para aprender más sobre las desigualdades en salud de determinados grupos de personas y los métodos para disminuirlas. También se llama disparidad en salud.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-11-23</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/understanding/disparities" UseWith="en">Cancer Disparities</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/research/areas/disparities" UseWith="en">Cancer Health Disparities Research</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/naturaleza/desigualdades" UseWith="es">Desigualdades por cáncer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/investigacion/areas/desigualdades" UseWith="es">Investigación de las desigualdades en salud por cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
