<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000805761"><TermName>breast columnar cell lesion</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest kuh-LUM-nar sel LEE-zhun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A common breast biopsy finding in which the cuboidal (square-ish) cells that normally line the lobules (milk glands) of the breast are replaced with one or more layers of column-shaped cells called columnar cells. These columnar cells may look like normal cells or abnormal cells under a microscope. The lobules may also look larger than normal. Breast columnar cell lesions often occur with deposits of calcium in the breast tissue. Breast columnar cell lesions are not cancer but may increase the risk of certain other breast conditions or invasive breast cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808470" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast columnar cell lesion&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808471" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lesión de células columnares de la mama&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>lesión de células columnares de la mama</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Resultado común de una biopsia de mama en el que las células cúbicas (cuadradas) que, por lo general, revisten los lobulillos (glándulas mamarias) son reemplazadas con una o más capas de células alargadas llamadas células columnares. Al microscopio, estas células columnares tienen  el aspecto de células normales o anormales. También es posible que los lobulillos se vean más grandes de lo normal. Las lesiones de células columnares de mama a menudo se presentan junto a depósitos de calcio en el tejido mamario. Las lesiones de células columnares de mama no son cancerosas, pero es posible que aumenten el riesgo de  ciertas afecciones de la mama o un cáncer de mama invasivo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-10-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
