<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806015">
  <TermName>structural racism</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(STRUK-cher-ul RAY-sih-zum)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A system of organizational and institutional policies created over time that support a continued unfair advantage for some people and unfair or harmful treatment of others based on their race or ethnic group. Structural racism comes from deep patterns of social, economic, and cultural differences that have developed over time between different groups of people. It affects the physical, social, and economic conditions of where people live, learn, work, and play. Structural racism is a serious problem and can lead to poor health outcomes, such as higher rates of disease and death in certain racial and ethnic groups.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808480" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;structural racism&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808481" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;racismo estructural&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>racismo estructural</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Sistema de políticas organizacionales e institucionales que se generan con el tiempo y que respaldan situaciones injustas y continuas donde se benefician algunas personas o se perjudica a otras según su raza o etnia. El racismo estructural proviene de patrones arraigados en las diferencias sociales, económicas y culturales que se crearon con el tiempo entre diferentes grupos de personas. Este afecta las condiciones físicas, sociales y económicas del lugar donde una persona vive, estudia, trabaja y juega, incluso el acceso a los servicios de salud. Es un problema serio y a veces deriva en resultados de salud precarios, como tasas más altas de enfermedad y muerte en ciertos grupos raciales o étnicos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-12-30</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
