<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806047"><TermName>clear cell renal cell cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kleer sel REE-nul sel KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of kidney cancer in which the cells look clear or very pale when viewed under a microscope. Clear cell renal cell cancer begins in cells that line tiny tubes in the kidney. These tubes return filtered nutrients, fluids, and other substances that the body needs back to the blood. Clear cell renal cell cancer is the most common type of kidney cancer in adults. People with an inherited condition called von Hippel-Lindau syndrome are at an increased risk of developing clear cell renal cell cancer. Also called ccRCC, clear cell renal cell carcinoma, and conventional renal cell carcinoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808488" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clear cell renal cell cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808489" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer renal de células claras&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer renal de células claras</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer de riñón en el que las células tienen un aspecto claro o transparente cuando se observan al microscopio. El cáncer renal de células claras comienza en las células que revisten los conductos diminutos del riñón. Estos conductos devuelven a la sangre los nutrientes, líquidos y otras sustancias filtradas que el cuerpo necesita.  El cáncer renal de células claras es el tipo de cáncer renal más común en los adultos. Las personas con una afección hereditaria llamada síndrome de von Hippel-Lindau tienen un mayor riesgo de presentar un cáncer renal de células claras. También se llama cáncer de células renales de células claras, cáncer de riñón de células claras, carcinoma de células renales convencional, carcinoma renal de células claras y ccRCC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-12-30</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/kidney" UseWith="en">Kidney (Renal Cell) Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/pediatric-adult-rare-tumor/rare-tumors/rare-kidney-tumors/clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma" UseWith="en">Clear Cell Renal Cell Carcinoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/rinon" UseWith="es">Cáncer de riñón (células renales)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
