<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806003"><TermName>complementary therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-pleh-MEN-tuh-ree THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Treatment that is used along with standard treatment, but is not considered standard.  Standard treatments are based on the results of scientific research and are currently accepted and widely used. Less research has been done for most types of complementary therapy. Complementary therapy  includes acupuncture, dietary supplements, massage therapy, hypnosis, and meditation. For example, acupuncture may be used with certain drugs to help lessen cancer pain or nausea and vomiting. Also called complementary medicine.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806878" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complementary therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000806879" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia complementaria&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>terapia complementaria</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cualquier tratamiento que se usa junto con el tratamiento estándar, pero que no se considera como tal. Los tratamientos estándar se fundamentan en la investigación científica y se aceptan y utilizan de manera amplia en la actualidad. Para la mayoría de los tipos de terapia complementaria se han llevado a cabo menos investigaciones. Este tipo de tratamientos abarca la acupuntura, los suplementos alimentarios, la terapia de masaje, la hipnosis y la meditación. Por ejemplo, es posible usar acupuntura con ciertos medicamentos para ayudar a reducir el dolor del cáncer, las náuseas o los vómitos. También se llama medicina complementaria y tratamiento complementario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-08-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2021-08-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/cam">Complementary and Alternative Medicine </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/mca">Medicina complementaria y alternativa</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
