<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806203"><TermName>cancer predisposition gene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAN-ser PREE-dih-spuh-ZIH-shun jeen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe a gene that may increase a person’s risk of developing some types of cancer if it has certain mutations (changes).  For example, a person who has mutations in the <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> or <GeneName>BRCA2</GeneName> gene has more risk than normal of developing breast cancer and/or ovarian cancer. Cancer predisposition genes are usually passed from parent to child and may be seen within families. Knowing if a person has a cancer predisposition gene may help prevent, diagnose, and treat cancer. Not all people who have a cancer predisposition gene will develop cancer. Also called cancer susceptibility gene.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808494" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cancer predisposition gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808495" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen de predisposición al cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gen de predisposición al cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término utilizado para describir un gen que, si tiene ciertas mutaciones (cambios), quizás aumente el riesgo de algunos tipos de cáncer.  Por ejemplo, una persona con mutaciones en los genes  <GeneName>BRCA1</GeneName> o <GeneName>BRCA2</GeneName> tiene más riesgo de lo normal de presentar cáncer de mama y de ovario. Los genes de predisposición al cáncer, por lo general, se pasan de padres a hijos y a veces se observan en varios miembros de una familia. Saber si una persona tiene un gen de predisposición al cáncer quizás ayude a prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar el cáncer. No todas las personas que tienen un gen de predisposición al cáncer presentarán cáncer. También se llama gen de susceptibilidad al cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-01-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
