<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806208">
  <TermName>recall bias</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(REE-kawl BY-us)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of bias that occurs when participants in a research study or clinical trial do not accurately remember a past event or experience or leave out details when reporting about them. Recall bias is more likely to occur when the event happened a long time ago  or when the study participant has a poor memory. Other factors that could affect recall bias are the participant’s age, disease status, education, socioeconomic status, pre-existing beliefs, and how important the event being recalled is to the participant. Recall bias can lead to wrong conclusions about what the study showed. It can occur in studies that ask participants to provide information from memory, such as in case-control studies or retrospective cohort studies.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808500" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;recall bias&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808501" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sesgo de recuerdo&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sesgo de recuerdo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de sesgo que ocurre cuando los participantes de un estudio de investigación o ensayo clínico no recuerdan con exactitud un evento o experiencia pasada, o se olvidan de algunos detalles cuando los notifican. Es más probable que el sesgo de recuerdo se produzca cuando pasó mucho tiempo desde el evento o  el participante tiene mala memoria. Otros factores que en ocasiones afectan el sesgo de recuerdo son la edad del paciente, el estado de la enfermedad, la educación, el nivel socioeconómico, las creencias preexistentes y la importancia para el paciente del evento que se quiere recordar. El sesgo de recuerdo a veces lleva a conclusiones erróneas sobre lo que se demostró en la investigación. Puede ocurrir en estudios en los que se le pide al paciente información de memoria, como en los estudios de casos y controles o en los estudios retrospectivos de cohortes. También se llama sesgo de memoria y sesgo de olvido.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-01-03</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
