<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806340">
  <TermName>NREM sleep</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(... sleep)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The phase of sleep that is considered the quiet or restful phase. During the three stages of NREM sleep, a person falls asleep and then moves from a light sleep into a deep sleep. This is when a person’s brain activity, breathing, and heart rate slow down, body temperature drops, muscles relax, and eye movements stop. NREM sleep plays an important role in helping the body repair tissues, build bone and muscle, and strengthen its immune system. During normal sleep, a person goes through four to five sleep cycles that last about 90 minutes each and include both NREM sleep and REM sleep. Also called non-rapid eye movement sleep and non-REM sleep.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809764" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;NREM sleep&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809765" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sueño no REM&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sueño no REM</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Fase del sueño considerada como la etapa tranquila o de descanso. Durante las 3 etapas del sueño sin movimientos oculares rápidos (no REM), la persona se queda dormida y pasa de un sueño ligero a uno profundo. Es entonces cuando la actividad cerebral, la respiración y la frecuencia cardíaca de la persona se tornan más lentas, la temperatura corporal baja, los músculos se relajan y los movimientos oculares se detienen. Este tipo de sueño desempeña una función importante para ayudar al cuerpo a reparar tejidos, reconstruir huesos y músculos y fortalecer su sistema inmunológico. Durante el sueño normal, una persona pasa por 4 o 5 ciclos de sueño, que duran unos 90 minutos cada uno e incluyen el sueño de movimientos oculares rápidos y el sueño sin movimientos oculares rápidos. También se llama etapa no REM del sueño, fase no REM del sueño, sueño NREM, sueño sin MOR y sueño sin movimientos oculares rápidos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-03-16</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
