<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806338">
  <TermName>non-REM sleep</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… sleep)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>The phase of sleep that is considered the quiet or restful phase. During the three stages of non-REM sleep, a person falls asleep and then moves from a light sleep into a deep sleep. This is when a person’s brain activity, breathing, and heart rate slow down, body temperature drops, muscles relax, and eye movements stop. Non-REM sleep plays an important role in helping the body repair tissues, build bone and muscle, and strengthen its immune system. During normal sleep, a person goes through four to five sleep cycles that last about 90 minutes each and include both non-REM sleep and REM sleep. Also called non-rapid eye movement sleep and NREM sleep.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809760" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;non-REM sleep&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809761" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sueño sin MOR&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sueño sin MOR</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Fase del sueño considerada como la etapa tranquila o de descanso. Durante las 3 etapas del sueño sin movimientos oculares rápidos (sueño sin MOR), la persona se queda dormida y pasa de un sueño ligero a uno profundo. Es entonces cuando la actividad cerebral, la respiración y la frecuencia cardíaca de la persona se tornan más lentas, la temperatura corporal baja, los músculos se relajan y los movimientos oculares se detienen. Este tipo de sueño desempeña una función importante para ayudar al cuerpo a reparar tejidos, reconstruir huesos y músculos y fortalecer su sistema inmunológico. Durante el sueño normal, una persona pasa por 4 o 5 ciclos de sueño, que duran unos 90 minutos cada uno e incluyen el sueño de movimientos oculares rápidos y el sueño sin movimientos oculares rápidos. También se llama fase no MOR del sueño, sueño NMOR, sueño no MOR, sueño no REM y sueño sin movimientos oculares rápidos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-03-16</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
