<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806347"><TermName>asciminib hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(as-KIH-mih-nib HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with chronic phase chronic myelogenous leukemia that is Philadelphia chromosome positive. It is used in patients whose cancer has the T315I mutation, whose cancer is newly diagnosed, or whose cancer was treated with at least two other tyrosine kinase inhibitors. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Asciminib hydrochloride blocks the BCR::ABL1 fusion protein, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. Asciminib hydrochloride is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called Scemblix.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808506" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;asciminib hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000808507" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de asciminib&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de asciminib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia mielógena en fase crónica positiva para el cromosoma Filadelfia. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer tiene la mutación T315I, que recibieron un diagnóstico reciente de cáncer o que se trataron con, por lo menos, otros dos tipos de inhibidores de tirosina–cinasas. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de asciminib bloquea la proteína de fusión BCR::ABL1, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas y las destruya. El clorhidrato de asciminib es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama hidrocloruro de asciminib y Scemblix.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2021-11-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-12-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000806378" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/asciminib-hydrochloride">Asciminib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
