<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806962">
  <TermName>sirolimus protein-bound particles</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(sih-ROH-lih-mus PROH-teen-bownd PAR-tih-kulz)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A form of the drug sirolimus that is used to treat adults with malignant  perivascular epithelioid cell tumor that has spread or cannot be removed by surgery. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Sirolimus protein-bound particles may have fewer side effects and work better than other forms of sirolimus. It binds to a protein called mTOR, which may help keep tumor cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Sirolimus protein-bound particles is a type of kinase inhibitor, a type of angiogenesis inhibitor, and a type of immunosuppressant. Also called Fyarro.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808516" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sirolimus protein-bound particles&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808517" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;partículas unidas a proteínas de sirólimus&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>partículas de sirólimus unidas a proteínas</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma del medicamento sirólimus que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con un tumor maligno de células epitelioides perivasculares que se diseminó o que no es posible extirpar mediante cirugía. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Es posible que con las partículas de sirólimus unidas a proteínas se produzcan menos efectos secundarios y, tal vez, su eficacia sea mayor que la de otras formas de sirólimus. Se une a una proteína llamada mTOR, lo que quizás ayude a impedir la multiplicación de células tumorales. Es posible que también prevenga la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Las partículas de sirólimus unidas a proteínas son un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas, un inhibidor de la angiogénesis y un inmunodepresor. También se llama Fyarro y partículas de sirólimus fijadas a proteínas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-01-13</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000808197" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/sirolimus-protein-bound-particles">Sirolimus Protein-Bound Particles</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
