<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806992"><TermName>radiology report</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RAY-dee-AH-loh-jee reh-PORT)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A detailed report that describes the results of an imaging test. A radiology report includes information about the type of imaging test that was done and how it was done. It also includes a brief medical history of the person having the test, including any symptoms or known diseases and why the test was needed. The report also describes the findings seen in the areas of the body that were scanned and compares them with findings from a previous imaging test, if available. A summary of all the findings, which may be used to make a diagnosis of a disease, and any recommendations for further testing are also included in the report.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809780" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiology report&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809781" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;informe radiológico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>informe radiológico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Informe detallado que describe los resultados de una prueba con imágenes. Un informe radiológico incluye información sobre el tipo de prueba que se realizó y cómo se hizo. También incluye breves antecedentes médicos de la persona que se somete a la prueba, como cualquier síntoma o enfermedad conocida y el motivo por el que se necesitaba dicha prueba. El informe también describe los hallazgos observados en las áreas del cuerpo que se exploraron y los compara con los hallazgos de una imagen anterior, si está disponible. También incluye un resumen de todos los hallazgos, que puede utilizarse para hacer un diagnóstico de una enfermedad, y cualquier recomendación para realizar más pruebas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-03-16</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
