<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806986"><TermName>breast cyst</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest sist)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A fluid-filled sac that forms in the breast that is sometimes filled with a mix of fluid and solid material. Breast cysts may occur in one or both breasts, and there may be more than one. Most cysts feel like a round or oval lump with a smooth, well-defined border that moves easily under the skin of the breast. But some cysts are too small to be felt. Symptoms may include pain or tenderness in the breast, especially around the time of a menstrual period, or a clear or cloudy fluid discharge from the nipple. Most breast cysts are not cancer and do not increase the risk of breast cancer. They can occur at any age but are most common in premenopausal women and in women taking hormone therapy for menopause.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809774" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast cyst&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;quiste de mama&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>quiste de mama</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Saco lleno de líquido que se forma en la mama y que a veces está lleno de una mezcla de líquido y material sólido. Es posible que los quistes de mama aparezcan en una o en ambas mamas y que haya más de uno. La mayoría de los quistes se sienten como un bulto redondo u ovalado con un borde suave y bien definido que se mueve con facilidad bajo la piel de la mama. Sin embargo, algunos quistes son demasiado pequeños para que puedan sentirse. Los síntomas incluyen dolor o sensibilidad en la mama, en especial durante la menstruación, o una secreción de líquido claro o turbio que sale por el pezón. La mayoría de los quistes de mama no son cancerosos y no aumentan el riesgo de cáncer de mama. Aparecen a cualquier edad, pero son más frecuentes en las mujeres premenopáusicas y en las que toman terapia hormonal para la menopausia. También se llama quiste de seno y quiste mamario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-03-16</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/significado-cambios-en-los-senos" UseWith="es">Significado de cambios y afecciones de los senos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
