<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000806950">
  <TermName>ropeginterferon alfa-2b</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(roh-peg-IN-ter-FEER-on AL-fuh …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with polycythemia vera (a disease in which too many red blood cells are made in the bone marrow). It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and some types of cancer. Ropeginterferon alfa-2b is a form of recombinant interferon alfa-2b that is made in the laboratory and linked to a substance called PEG, which makes the drug stay in the body longer.  Ropeginterferon alfa-2b may lower the number of red blood cells made in the bone marrow. It is a type of cytokine and a type of immunomodulating agent. Also called Besremi.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808512" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ropeginterferon alfa-2b&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000808513" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ropeginterferon alfa-2b&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ropeginterferón alfa-2b</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con policitemia vera (enfermedad por la que se producen muchos glóbulos rojos en la médula ósea). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y algunos tipos de cáncer. El ropeginterferón alfa-2b es una forma de interferón alfa-2b recombinante que se elabora en el laboratorio y se une a una sustancia llamada PEG, lo que hace que el medicamento permanezca durante más tiempo en el cuerpo. El ropeginterferón alfa-2b quizás reduzca el número de glóbulos rojos que produce la médula ósea.  Es un tipo de citocina y de inmunomodulador. También se llama Besremi.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2021-11-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000806960" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ropeginterferon-alfa-2b-njft">Ropeginterferon Alfa-2b-njft</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
