<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000808299"><TermName>squamocolumnar junction</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SKWAY-moh-kuh-LUM-nar JUNK-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The area around the opening of the cervix where the endocervix (inner part) and ectocervix (outer part) come together. This area contains both glandular cells (cells that make mucus) from the endocervix and squamous cells (thin, skin-like cells) from the ectocervix. Most abnormal cell changes and most cervical cancers begin in the squamous cells of the squamocolumnar junction. Also called transformation zone.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000810311" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;squamocolumnar junction&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000810989" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;unión escamocolumnar&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000810405" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the anatomy of the cervix showing the internal OS, endocervical canal, endocervix, ectocervix, and external OS. The uterus and vagina are also shown. There is also a pullout that shows a close up of the squamocolumnar junction (the area where the endocervix and ectocervix meet) and the cells that line the endocervix and ectocervix." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the cervix. The cervix is the lower, narrow end of the uterus that connects the uterus to the vagina. It is made up of the internal OS (the opening between the cervix and the upper part of the uterus), the endocervix (the inner part of the cervix that forms the endocervical canal), the ectocervix (the outer part of the cervix that opens into the vagina) and the external OS (the opening between the cervix and vagina). The area where the endocervix and ectocervix meet is called the squamocolumnar junction, which contains both glandular cells (column-shaped cells that make mucus) from the endocervix and squamous cells (thin, flat cells) from the ectocervix. The squamocolumnar junction is sometimes  referred to as the transformation zone.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812204" type="image/jpeg" alt="En el dibujo se observan las aracterísticas anatómicas del cuello uterino. Se muestran el orificio interno, el conducto endocervical, el endocérvix, el ectocérvix y el orificio externo. También se observan el útero y la vagina. Además, en un recuadro se muestra una vista de cerca de la unión escamocolumnar (área donde el endocérvix se une al ectocérvix) y las células que revisten el endocérvix y el ectocérvix." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Características anatómicas del cuello uterino. El cuello uterino es la porción final, inferior y estrecha del útero que conecta al útero con la vagina. Está formado por el orificio interno (abertura entre el cuello uterino y la parte superior del útero), el endocérvix (parte interna del cuello uterino que forma el conducto endocervical), el ectocérvix (parte externa del cuello uterino que se conecta con la vagina) y el orificio externo (abertura entre el cuello uterino y la vagina). El área donde el endocérvix se une al ectocérvix se llama unión escamocolumnar, y contiene células glandulares (células en forma de columna que elaboran moco) del endocérvix y células escamosas (células delgadas y planas) del ectocérvix. La unión escamocolumnar también se conoce como zona de transformación.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>unión escamocolumnar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Área que rodea la abertura del cuello uterino donde se unen el endocérvix (parte interna) y el ectocérvix (parte externa). Esta área contiene células glandulares (células que producen moco) del endocérvix y células escamosas (células delgadas, parecidas a la piel) del ectocérvix. La mayoría de los cambios celulares anormales y la mayoría de los cánceres de cuello uterino comienzan en las células escamosas de la unión escamocolumnar. También se llama unión escamocilíndrica y zona de transformación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-06-02</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-04-24</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
