<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000808253">
  <TermName>Kimmtrak</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KIM-trak)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with uveal melanoma (a type of eye cancer) that has spread or cannot be removed by surgery.   It is used in patients who have the HLA-A*02:01 antigen. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Kimmtrak binds to certain antigens found on the surfaces of uveal melanoma cells and T cells (a type of immune cell). This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Kimmtrak is a type of bispecific fusion protein. Also called tebentafusp.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809794" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Kimmtrak&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809795" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Kimmtrak&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Kimmtrak</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con melanoma uveal (tipo de cáncer de ojo) que se diseminó o que no se puede extirpar con cirugía. Se utiliza en pacientes que tienen el antígeno  HLA-A*02:01. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Kimmtrak se une a ciertos antígenos en la superficie de las células del melanoma uveal y de las células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria). Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Kimmtrak es un tipo de proteína de fusión biespecífica. También se llama tebentafusp.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-01-27</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-03-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000808359" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tebentafusp-tebn">Tebentafusp-tebn</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
