<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000808596">
  <TermName>ciltacabtagene autoleucel</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(SIL-tuh-KAB-tuh-jeen AW-toh-LOO-sel)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A treatment used for adults with multiple myeloma that came back or did not get better after treatment with at least one line of anticancer therapy that included a proteasome inhibitor and an immunomodulating agent. It is used in patients whose cancer did not respond to treatment with lenalidomide. Ciltacabtagene autoleucel is made using a patient’s T cells (a type of immune system cell). A gene for a special receptor called chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is added to the T cells in the laboratory. These changed T cells called CAR T cells are grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. Ciltacabtagene autoleucel binds to a protein called BCMA, which is found on myeloma cells and some types of immune cells. This helps the body’s immune system kill cancer cells. Ciltacabtagene autoleucel is a type of cellular immunotherapy called CAR T-cell therapy. Also called Carvykti.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809820" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ciltacabtagene autoleucel&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809821" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ciltacabtagén autoleucel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ciltacabtagén autoleucel</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con mieloma múltiple que volvió o no mejoró después de recibir por lo menos una línea de terapia contra el cáncer que incluyó un inhibidor del proteasoma y un inmunomodulador. El ciltacabtagén autoleucel se produce utilizando las células T (tipo de célula del sistema inmunitario) del paciente. En el laboratorio, se añade a las células T el gen de un receptor especial llamado receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR). Estas células T modificadas, llamadas células T con CAR, se producen en grandes cantidades en el laboratorio y se administran al paciente mediante infusión. El ciltacabtagén autoleucel se une a una proteína denominada BCMA, que se encuentra en las células de mieloma y en algunos tipos de células inmunitarias, lo que ayuda al sistema inmunitario del cuerpo a destruir células cancerosas. El ciltacabtagén autoleucel es un tipo de inmunoterapia celular llamada terapia de células T con CAR. También se llama Carvykti.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-03-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-17</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000808601" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ciltacabtagene-autoleucel">Ciltacabtagene Autoleucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
