<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809064"><TermName>molecular characterization</TermName><TermPronunciation>(muh-LEH-kyoo-ler KAYR-ik-ter-rih-ZAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A broad term that refers to using molecular markers, including DNA, RNA, and proteins, to determine the genetic characteristics of cells or tissues. In cancer, molecular characterization may provide information about the presence of certain biomarkers or genetic changes in tumor tissue, such as gene mutations, patterns of gene expression, and other changes in tumor DNA or RNA. Molecular characterization can play an important role in how diseases, such as cancer, are diagnosed and treated and how they respond to treatment. Genomic sequencing, molecular profiling, and liquid biopsy are all types of molecular characterization.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809828" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;molecular characterization&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809829" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;caracterización molecular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>caracterización molecular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término amplio que hace referencia al uso de marcadores moleculares, como el ADN, el ARN y las proteínas, para determinar las características genéticas de las células o los tejidos. En el cáncer, la caracterización molecular tal vez proporcione información sobre la presencia de determinados biomarcadores o cambios genéticos en el tejido tumoral, como mutaciones genéticas, patrones de expresión de los genes y otros cambios en el ADN o ARN del tumor. La caracterización molecular a veces cumple una función importante en el diagnóstico y el tratamiento de enfermedades como el cáncer y en su respuesta al tratamiento. La secuenciación genómica, el perfil molecular y la biopsia líquida son tipos de caracterización molecular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-03-16</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
