<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809192"><TermName>Pluvicto</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ploo-VIK-toh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A radioactive drug used to treat adults with PSMA-positive prostate cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and has not responded to treatments that lower testosterone levels. It is used in patients whose cancer has been treated with an androgen receptor inhibitor and who can either delay or have received treatment with a type of anticancer drug called a taxane. Pluvicto binds to a protein called PSMA, which is found on some prostate cancer cells. It gives off radiation that may kill the cancer cells. Pluvicto is a type of radioconjugate. Also called lutetium Lu 177 vipivotide tetraxetan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809840" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Pluvicto&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000809841" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Pluvicto&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Pluvicto</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento radiactivo que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de próstata positivo para PSMA que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y no respondió a los tratamientos que reducen las concentraciones de testosterona. Se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer se trató con un inhibidor del receptor de andrógeno y en quienes se retrasó el tratamiento con un taxano (tipo de medicamento anticanceroso) o ya lo recibieron. Pluvicto se une a una proteína llamada PSMA, que se encuentra en algunas células de cáncer de próstata. Este medicamento emite radiación, lo que quizás destruya las células cancerosas. Pluvicto es un tipo de radioconjugado. También se llama lutecio Lu 177 vipivotida tetraxetán.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-03-31</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-04-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000809237" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/lutetium-Lu-177-vipivotide-tetraxetan">Lutetium Lu 177 Vipivotide Tetraxetan</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
