<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809171">
  <TermName>nivolumab and relatlimab</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(nih-VOL-yoo-mab … reh-LAT-lih-mab)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A combination of two drugs used to treat adults and children aged 12 years or older with melanoma that has spread or cannot be removed by surgery. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Nivolumab and relatlimab binds to the proteins PD-1 and LAG-3, which are found on T cells (a type of immune cell). Blocking these proteins may help the immune system kill cancer cells. The combination of nivolumab and relatlimab may work better than either drug alone. Nivolumab and relatlimab is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called Opdualag.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809834" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nivolumab and relatlimab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000809835" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nivolumab y relatlimab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>nivolumab y relatlimab</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento compuesto por una combinación de  dos fármacos que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos y niños de 12 años o más con melanoma que se diseminó o que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Este medicamento se une  a las proteínas PD-1 y LAG-3, que se encuentran en las células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria). Bloquear estas proteínas quizás ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es posible que la combinación de nivolumab y relatlimab funcione mejor que cada fármaco solo. Este medicamento incluye un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de puntos de  control inmunitario. También se llama Opdualag.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-03-22</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000809173" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/nivolumab-and-relatlimab-rmbw">Nivolumab and Relatlimab-rmbw</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
