<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809577">
  <TermName>laser interstitial thermal therapy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LAY-zer IN-ter-STIH-shul THER-mul THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of treatment that uses heat created by a laser beam to remove or destroy abnormal tissue, such as cancer tissue. During laser interstitial thermal therapy, an imaging test, such as MRI, is used to help guide a wire or catheter (thin tube) into the abnormal area of tissue. A laser inserted through the catheter creates heat, which destroys the abnormal tissue. Laser interstitial thermal therapy may be used to treat certain types of brain tumors, including tumors that have spread to the brain from other parts of the body, radiation necrosis (tissue death caused by radiation therapy), and some types of epilepsy. Also called LITT.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000811490" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;laser interstitial thermal therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000811491" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia térmica intersticial con láser&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>terapia térmica intersticial con láser</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento en el que se usa el calor producido por un rayo láser para extirpar o destruir tejido anormal, como el tejido canceroso. Durante la terapia térmica intersticial con láser, se usa una prueba con imágenes, como las imágenes por resonancia magnética, para guiar un alambre o catéter (tubo delgado) hacia el área con tejido anormal. A través del catéter, se introduce un láser que produce calor, lo que destruye el tejido anormal. La terapia térmica intersticial con láser se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de tumores en el encéfalo (incluso los tumores que se diseminaron a este órgano desde otras partes del cuerpo), la necrosis causada por radiación (tejido que se destruye con la radioterapia) y algunos tipos de epilepsia. También se llama LITT, terapia térmica intersticial inducida por láser y termoterapia intersticial inducida por láser.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-08-05</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
