<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809550"><TermName>high-resolution micro-ultrasound</TermName><TermPronunciation>(hy-reh-zuh-LOO-shun MY-kroh-UL-truh-sownd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses high-energy sound waves to create pictures of the prostate and surrounding tissue that are much more detailed than standard ultrasound. This makes it easier to see a suspicious or abnormal area of the prostate and determine if a biopsy is needed. High-resolution micro-ultrasound may also be used during a biopsy to help guide the removal of a sample of abnormal prostate tissue. It may be used to help diagnose prostate cancer, monitor prostate cancer growth over time, and plan treatment.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811482" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;high-resolution micro-ultrasound&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811483" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;microecografía de alta resolución&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>microecografía de alta resolución</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se usan ondas de sonido de alta energía para crear imágenes, más detalladas que las de una ecografía estándar, de la próstata y los tejidos que la rodean. Este procedimiento facilita la observación de áreas anormales o sospechosas de malignidad en la próstata para determinar si es necesaria una biopsia. También es posible usar una microecografía de alta resolución durante una biopsia para  guiar la extracción de una muestra de tejido anormal de la próstata. Se utiliza para ayudar a diagnosticar el cáncer de próstata, vigilar el crecimiento del cáncer a lo largo del tiempo y planear el tratamiento. También se llama microultrasonido de alta resolución.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-08-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
