<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809584"><TermName>adipokine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-dih-poh-kine)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a large group of molecules that is made by fat cells in the body. Adipokines circulate in the blood and help control many important body functions, including appetite, fat storage, glucose and fat metabolism, blood pressure, inflammation, and immune response. Changes in the levels of adipokines in the blood may play a role in the development of obesity and other diseases, such as diabetes, heart disease, and cancer. Adipokines can act as hormones, growth factors, and cytokines, and include the molecules leptin, adiponectin, resistin, and many others.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811496" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adipokine&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811497" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adipocitocina&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>adipocitocina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de molécula que forma parte de un gran grupo de moléculas que producen las células adiposas (adipocitos) del cuerpo. Las adipocitocinas circulan por la sangre y ayudan a controlar muchas funciones importantes del cuerpo, como el apetito, el almacenamiento de grasa, el metabolismo de la glucosa y la grasa, la presión arterial, la inflamación y la respuesta inmunitaria. Los cambios en las concentraciones de adipocitocinas en la sangre quizás cumplan una función en la aparición de la obesidad y otras enfermedades, como la diabetes, la cardiopatía y el cáncer. Funcionan como hormonas, factores de crecimiento y citocinas. Las adipocitocinas incluyen las moléculas leptina, adiponectina y resistina entre otras. También se llama adipocina y adipoquina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-08-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
