<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809582"><TermName>cross-sectional study</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kros-SEK-shuh-nul STUH-dee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of research study in which a group of people is observed, or certain information is collected, at a single point in time or over a short period of time. For example, a survey may be done to collect information about the total number of people in a group who have or had a certain disease (such as cancer) or risk factor (such as smoking or obesity). In this example, the survey may be able to provide some information about whether there is an association between the smoking (risk factor) and the cancer (disease) but does not prove that they are linked. Results from a cross-sectional study may be used to plan other research studies. A cross-sectional study is a type of observational (epidemiologic) study.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811494" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cross-sectional study&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811495" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;estudio transversal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>estudio transversal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de estudio de investigación en el que se observa a un grupo de personas o se recopila cierta información, en un  momento determinado o en el transcurso de un periodo corto. Por ejemplo, es posible que se realice una encuesta para recopilar información sobre el número total de personas en un grupo que tienen o tuvieron una enfermedad (como el cáncer) o un factor de riesgo (como el hábito de fumar o la obesidad). En este ejemplo, la encuesta quizás proporcione cierta información que indique si hay una relación entre el hábito de fumar (factor de riesgo) y el cáncer (enfermedad), pero no prueba que estos estén vinculados. Los resultados de un estudio transversal tal vez se usen para planificar otros estudios de investigación. Un estudio transversal es un tipo de estudio de observación (epidemiológico).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-08-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
