<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809872"><TermName>non-serous epithelial ovarian cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… SEER-us eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul oh-VAYR-ee-un KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term that describes certain types of ovarian cancers that form in the tissue covering the ovary. The main types of non-serous epithelial ovarian cancer are clear cell carcinoma, endometroid carcinoma, and mucinous carcinoma. Each type differs as to how the cancer cells look under a microscope, the tumor markers present, how quickly the cancer cells are likely to grow and spread, and their likely response to treatment. Non-serous epithelial ovarian cancers are much less common than serous epithelial ovarian cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811520" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;non-serous epithelial ovarian cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811521" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de ovario epitelial no seroso&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de ovario epitelial no seroso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que describe ciertos tipos de cánceres de ovario que se forman en el tejido que recubre el ovario. Los principales tipos de cáncer de ovario epitelial no seroso son el carcinoma de células claras, el carcinoma endometroide y el carcinoma mucinoso. Cada tipo difiere en cuanto al aspecto de las células cancerosas al microscopio, los marcadores tumorales presentes, la rapidez con la que las células cancerosas se multiplican y diseminan, y su respuesta probable al tratamiento. Los cánceres de ovario epiteliales no serosos son mucho menos frecuentes que los cánceres de ovario epiteliales serosos. También se llama cáncer epitelial no seroso de ovario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-08-26</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
