<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000809979">
  <TermName>C-reactive protein</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… ree-AK-tive PROH-teen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A protein that is made by the liver when there is inflammation or tissue damage in the body. C-reactive protein levels are usually low or not detectable in the blood of healthy people. A high level of C-reactive protein in the blood may be a sign of certain conditions, including cancer, infection, inflammatory bowel disease, rheumatoid arthritis, and lupus. Increased levels of C-reactive protein may also signal a high risk of heart attack or stroke.  Measuring the level of C-reactive protein may be done to help diagnose certain diseases, find out how well treatment is working, or determine a person’s risk of developing heart disease. Also called CRP.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812212" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;C-reactive protein&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812213" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proteína C-reactiva&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>proteína C-reactiva</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Proteína que  elabora  el hígado cuando se presenta inflamación o daño de un tejido en el cuerpo. La concentración de proteína C-reactiva por lo general es baja o indetectable en la sangre de  personas sanas. Una concentración alta de proteína C-reactiva en sangre quizás sea un signo de ciertas afecciones, como cáncer, infección, enfermedad intestinal inflamatoria, artritis reumatoide y lupus. Las concentraciones elevadas de esta proteína en ocasiones también indican un mayor riesgo de infarto de miocardio o accidente cerebrovascular. Es posible medir  la concentración de proteína C-reactiva para ayudar a diagnosticar ciertas enfermedades, evaluar la eficacia de un tratamiento o determinar el riesgo de una persona de presentar una enfermedad en el corazón.  También se llama PrCR y proteína reactiva C.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-12-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
