<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810196">
  <TermName>positron emission tomography-magnetic resonance imaging scan</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(PAH-zih-tron ee-MIH-shun toh-MAH-gruh-fee-mag-NEH-tik REH-zuh-nunts IH-muh-jing skan)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A procedure that combines the pictures from a positron emission tomography (PET) scan and a magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan. A PET scan uses a radioactive tracer to highlight abnormal areas in the body. An MRI scan uses radio waves and a powerful magnet to take detailed pictures of tissues in the body. For a positron emission tomography-magnetic resonance imaging scan, the scans are done at the same time with the same machine. The combined scans give more detailed pictures of areas inside the body than either scan gives by itself. The overall amount of radiation a person is exposed to is also reduced. A positron emission tomography-magnetic resonance imaging scan may be used to help diagnose disease, such as cancer, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working. Also called PET-MRI scan.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812219" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;positron emission tomography-magnetic resonance imaging scan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812220" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tomografía por emisión de positrones-imágenes por resonancia magnética&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tomografía por emisión de positrones-imágenes por resonancia magnética</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Procedimiento que combina las imágenes de una tomografía por emisión de positrones (TEP) y de una resonancia magnética (IRM). La TEP utiliza un marcador radiactivo para resaltar áreas anormales en el cuerpo. La  IRM utiliza ondas de radio y un imán potente para tomar imágenes detalladas de los tejidos del cuerpo. La tomografía y la resonancia se hacen al mismo tiempo con la misma máquina y se combinan para crear imágenes más detalladas de  áreas internas del cuerpo que las que se obtienen por separado. También se reduce la cantidad total de radiación a la que se expone la persona. La  tomografía por emisión de positrones-imágenes por resonancia magnética a veces se usa para ayudar a diagnosticar una enfermedad, como el cáncer, diseñar un tratamiento o determinar la eficacia de un tratamiento. También se llama TEP-IRM.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-12-29</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
