<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810101">
  <TermName>measurable residual disease</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MEH-zur-uh-bul ree-ZID-yoo-ul dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A term that is increasingly being used in place of the term minimal residual disease to describe a very small number of cancer cells that remain in the body during or after treatment.  Measurable residual disease can be found only by highly sensitive laboratory methods that are able to find one cancer cell among one million normal cells. Checking to see if there is measurable residual disease may help plan treatment, find out how well treatment is working or if cancer has come back, or make a prognosis. Measurable residual disease testing is used mostly for blood cancers such as lymphoma and leukemia. Also called minimal residual disease and MRD.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000810332" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;measurable residual disease&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000811008" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad residual medible&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/>
  <SpanishTermName>enfermedad residual medible</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Término cuyo uso está en aumento en lugar del término enfermedad residual mínima para describir la presencia de un número muy pequeño de células cancerosas que permanecen en el cuerpo durante el tratamiento o después de este.  Solo se puede detectar la enfermedad residual medible mediante métodos de laboratorio muy sensibles que permiten encontrar una célula cancerosa entre un millón de células normales.  Comprobar si hay  enfermedad residual medible quizás ayude  a planificar el tratamiento, determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz o si el cáncer volvió, o establecer un pronóstico. Las pruebas que miden  la enfermedad residual medible se usan sobre todo para los cánceres de sangre, como los linfomas  y las leucemias. También se llama enfermedad residual cuantificable, enfermedad residual mensurable, enfermedad residual mínima y ERM.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-07-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2022-07-07</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
