<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810373"><TermName>LP</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a thin, hollow needle is inserted into the lower part of the spine to collect a sample of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). This is done by placing the needle between two bones in the spine and into the subarachnoid space (the fluid-filled space between the thin layers of tissue around the spinal cord). After the CSF sample is removed, it is checked under a microscope for signs of infection, inflammation, or diseases, such as cancer or certain nervous system conditions. An LP may also be done to measure or reduce CSF pressure around the spinal cord and brain, to inject drugs, such as chemotherapy or anesthesia drugs, directly into the CSF, or to inject contrast dye for certain imaging tests. Also called lumbar puncture and spinal tap.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000503953" type="image/jpeg" alt="Lumbar puncture; drawing shows a patient lying in a curled position on a table and a spinal needle (a long, thin needle) being inserted into the lower back. Inset shows a close-up of the spinal needle inserted into the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) in the lower part of the spinal column." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Lumbar puncture. A patient lies in a curled position on a table. After a small area on the lower back is numbed, a spinal needle (a long, thin needle) is inserted into the lower part of the spinal column to remove cerebrospinal fluid (CSF, shown in blue). The fluid may be sent to a laboratory for testing.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000581236" type="image/jpeg" alt="Punción lumbar. En el dibujo se muestra a una persona acostada de lado, en posición encorvada, sobre una camilla. Se le inserta en la parte inferior de la espalda una larga y fina aguja espinal o intrarraquídea. En un recuadro se observa una ampliación de la aguja que penetra la columna vertebral, se señala la médula espinal y el líquido cefalorraquídeo en color azul." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Punción lumbar. La persona se acuesta de lado, en posición encorvada, sobre una camilla. Después de adormecer un área pequeña en la parte inferior de la espalda, se inserta una larga y fina aguja espinal o intrarraquídea en la columna vertebral. Se extrae una muestra de líquido cefalorraquídeo (se observa en azul). En ocasiones, se envía esta muestra a un laboratorio para que la examinen.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>PL</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se introduce una aguja fina y hueca en la parte inferior de la columna vertebral para extraer una muestra de líquido cefalorraquídeo (LCR). Para ello, se coloca la aguja entre dos huesos de la columna vertebral y se introduce en el espacio subaracnoideo (espacio lleno de líquido entre las capas finas de tejido que rodean la médula espinal). Una vez extraída la muestra de LCR, se examina bajo el microscopio para detectar signos de infecciones, inflamaciones o enfermedades, como el cáncer o ciertas afecciones del sistema nervioso. También se realiza una PL con el fin de medir o reducir la presión del LCR alrededor de la médula espinal y el encéfalo, para inyectar fármacos, como quimioterapia o medicamentos anestésicos, directamente en el LCR, o para inyectar un colorante de contraste para determinadas pruebas con imágenes. También se llama punción espinal y punción lumbar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-08-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-08-25</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
