<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810451"><TermName>rectovaginal exam</TermName><TermPronunciation>(REK-toh-VA-jih-nul eg-ZAM)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A physical exam of the rectum and vagina. During a rectovaginal exam, a health care provider inserts one lubricated, gloved finger into the vagina and another finger of the same hand into the rectum, and presses on the lower abdomen with the other hand. This allows the health care provider to feel for lumps or other abnormal changes in the rectum and vagina and to check the size, shape, and position of the pelvic organs, including the ovaries, fallopian tubes, uterus, and the ligaments that hold the uterus in place. A small sample of stool may be collected to check for blood. A rectovaginal exam may be done as part of a pelvic exam.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812229" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rectovaginal exam&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812230" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;examen rectovaginal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>examen rectovaginal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Examen físico del recto y la vagina. Durante un examen rectovaginal, el profesional de la salud introduce en la vagina un dedo cubierto con un guante lubricado, y otro dedo de la misma mano lo introduce en el recto. A continuación, con la otra mano, hace presión sobre la parte baja del abdomen. Esto permite detectar bultos u otros cambios anormales en el recto y la vagina, así como evaluar el tamaño, la forma y la posición de los órganos pélvicos, como los ovarios, las trompas de Falopio, el útero y los ligamentos que mantienen el útero en su lugar. Es posible que se obtenga una muestra pequeña de material fecal para verificar si hay sangre. El examen rectovaginal a veces es parte del examen pélvico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-12-29</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
