<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810445">
  <TermName>gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(GAS-troh-in-TES-tih-nul NOOR-oh-EN-doh-krin TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare, slow-growing type of cancer that forms in the lining of the gastrointestinal (GI) tract, usually in the small intestine, rectum, or appendix. Sometimes more than one tumor may form. Gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors form in neuroendocrine cells that make hormones that help control digestive juices and the muscles used in moving food through the stomach and intestines. Signs and symptoms of gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors vary by where they are found in the GI tract. In some cases, the hormones made by these tumors may cause a condition called carcinoid syndrome. Symptoms of carcinoid syndrome include facial flushing, diarrhea, wheezing, and a rapid heartbeat. Also called gastrointestinal carcinoid tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000811528" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000811529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor neuroendocrino gastrointestinal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000741567" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the gastrointestinal tract showing the stomach, small intestine (including the duodenum, jejunum, and ileum), appendix, colon, and rectum." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors form in the lining of the gastrointestinal tract, most often in the small intestine, appendix, or rectum.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743058" type="image/jpeg" alt="Imagen del tubo digestivo donde se muestran la porción gastrointestinal, que incluye el estómago, el intestino delgado (que abarca el duodeno, el yeyuno y el íleon), el apéndice, el colon y el recto." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">Los tumores neuroendocrinos gastrointestinales se forman en el revestimiento del tubo digestivo; con más frecuencia en el tubo gastrointestinal (en el apéndice, el intestino delgado y el recto).</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor neuroendocrino gastrointestinal</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer raro de crecimiento lento que se forma en el revestimiento del tubo gastrointestinal, por lo general en el intestino delgado, el recto o el apéndice. En ocasiones, surge más de un tumor. Los tumores neuroendocrinos gastrointestinales se originan en las células neuroendocrinas, encargadas de elaborar las hormonas que ayudan a controlar los jugos digestivos y los músculos que mueven los alimentos a través del estómago y los intestinos. Los signos y síntomas de los tumores neuroendocrinos gastrointestinales varían según el lugar donde estos se encuentran en el tubo gastrointestinal. En algunos casos, las hormonas producidas por los tumores causan una afección llamada síndrome carcinoide o carcinoideo. Los síntomas de este síndrome son enrojecimiento de la cara, sofocos, diarrea, sibilancias y latidos cardíacos rápidos. También se llama tumor carcinoide gastrointestinal y tumor neuroendocrino digestivo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-09-08</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-02-24</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/gi-neuroendocrine-tumors">Gastrointestinal Neuroendocrine Tumors</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/tumores-carcinoides-gi">Tumores carcinoides gastrointestinales</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
