<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810642">
  <TermName>fibroblast growth factor receptor 1 gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FY-broh-blast grothe FAK-ter reh-SEP-ter … jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A gene that makes a protein involved in cell division, cell growth and maturation, formation of new blood vessels, wound healing, and the growth and development of many parts of the body. Mutations (changes) in the fibroblast growth factor receptor 1 gene may cause the FGFR1 protein to become overactive, which may cause cells to grow and divide too quickly or in an uncontrolled way. Fibroblast growth factor receptor 1 gene mutations have been found in certain genetic conditions and in some types of cancer. Also called FGFR1 gene.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812239" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fibroblast growth factor receptor 1 gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812240" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen del receptor 1 del factor de crecimiento de fibroblastos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen del receptor 1 del factor de crecimiento de fibroblastos</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Gen que da origen a una proteína que participa en la división celular, el desarrollo y la maduración de las células, la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos, la cicatrización de las heridas, así como en el crecimiento y el desarrollo de muchas partes del cuerpo. En ocasiones, las mutaciones (cambios) en el gen del receptor 1 del factor de crecimiento de fibroblastos hacen que la proteína FGFR1 se vuelva hiperactiva, lo que quizás cause que las células maduren y se multipliquen demasiado rápido o sin control. Se han encontrado mutaciones en el gen del receptor 1 del factor de crecimiento de fibroblastos en ciertas afecciones genéticas y en algunos tipos de cáncer. También se llama gen FGFR1.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-03-02</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
