<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810677"><TermName>chromatin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KROH-muh-tin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A highly organized condensed structure made up of DNA, RNA, and proteins that forms the chromosomes in the nucleus of a cell. Chromatin is formed when long strands of DNA molecules wrap around spool-like complexes of proteins called histones to form structures that resemble beads on a string called nucleosomes. The nucleosomes then fold tightly around each other to form a chromatin fiber that further condenses to form chromosomes. Chromatin allows the DNA to fit inside the cell’s nucleus and allows many important cell processes to occur, including DNA replication, transcription, DNA repair, genetic recombination, and cell division.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812253" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chromatin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812254" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cromatina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cromatina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estructura condensada muy organizada compuesta por ADN, ARN y proteínas que da origen a los cromosomas en el núcleo de la célula. La cromatina se forma cuando cadenas largas de moléculas de ADN se enrollan alrededor de complejos (con forma de carrete) de proteínas llamadas histonas para dar lugar a los nucleosomas, unas estructuras que parecen perlas en un collar. Luego, los nucleosomas se pliegan entre sí de manera apretada para formar una fibra de cromatina que se condensa y da lugar a los cromosomas. La cromatina permite que el ADN quepa en el núcleo de la célula y hace posible muchos procesos celulares importantes, como la replicación del ADN, la transcripción, la reparación del ADN, la recombinación genética y la división celular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-02-24</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.genome.gov/genetics-glossary/Chromatin" UseWith="en">Chromatin (National Human Genome Research Institute)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
