<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810835">
  <TermName>RET gene</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… jeen)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A gene that makes a protein that plays an important role in cell growth and differentiation and in the development of nerve cells in the body. Mutations (changes) in the 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       gene may cause the protein made by this gene to become overactive, which may cause abnormal cells, including cancer cells, to grow. 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       gene mutations have been found in certain genetic conditions, including MEN2 syndrome and Hirschsprung disease, and in some types of cancer, including non-small cell lung cancer and thyroid cancer. The 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       gene is a type of proto-oncogene and a type of receptor tyrosine kinase gene.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812259" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;RET gene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812260" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gen RET&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>gen RET</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Gen que da origen a una proteína que cumple una función importante en la multiplicación y diferenciación de las células, así como en el desarrollo de las células nerviosas del cuerpo. Es posible que las mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       hagan que la proteína a la que da origen se vuelva muy activa, lo que causa la multiplicación de células anormales, incluso células cancerosas. Se han encontrado mutaciones en el gen 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       en ciertas afecciones genéticas, como el síndrome de MEN2, la enfermedad de Hirschsprung, y en algunos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas y el cáncer de tiroides. El gen 
      <GeneName>RET</GeneName>
       es un tipo de protooncogén y de gen de receptor de tirosina–cinasas.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-02-24</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/ret/" UseWith="en">RET gene (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
