<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810833"><TermName>common iliac artery</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAH-mun ILL-ee-ak AR-tuh-ree)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A set of two major blood vessels that carry blood to the lower part of the body, including the pelvis, reproductive organs, and legs. The common iliac artery branches off from the bottom part of the abdominal aorta (the largest blood vessel in the abdomen) into the right common iliac artery and left common iliac artery. Each common iliac artery further branches into an external iliac artery and an internal iliac artery, one on each side of the body. The external iliac arteries supply blood to the legs and feet. The internal iliac arteries supply blood to the tissues and organs in and around the pelvis, including the bladder, rectum, reproductive organs, groin, hips, and buttocks.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812257" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;common iliac artery&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812258" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;arteria ilíaca común&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>arteria ilíaca común</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cada uno de dos vasos sanguíneos principales que llevan la sangre a la parte inferior del cuerpo, como la pelvis, los órganos genitales y las piernas. La arteria ilíaca común derecha y la arteria ilíaca común izquierda se originan en la parte baja de la aorta abdominal (vaso sanguíneo más grande del abdomen). Las dos arterias ilíacas comunes se dividen a su vez en las arterias ilíacas externa e interna a cada lado del cuerpo. Las arterias ilíacas externas llevan la sangre a las piernas y los pies. Las arterias ilíacas internas llevan la sangre a los tejidos y los órganos que están en la pelvis y alrededor de esta, como  la vejiga, el recto, los órganos genitales, la ingle, las caderas y los glúteos. También se llama arteria ilíaca primitiva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-02-24</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
