<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810914"><TermName>histiocytic neoplasm</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HIS-tee-oh-SIH-tik NEE-oh-PLA-zum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of rare disorders in which too many histiocytes (a type of white blood cell) build up in certain tissues and organs, including the skin, bones, spleen, liver, lungs, and lymph nodes. This can cause damage to tissue or tumors to form in one or more parts of the body. The tumor may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). There are different types of histiocytic neoplasms, including Langerhans cell histiocytosis (LCH), hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis (HLH), and malignant histiocytic disorders. Histiocytic neoplasms occur most often in children, but can occur at any age. Also called histiocytosis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811544" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;histiocytic neoplasm&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000811545" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia histiocítica&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia histiocítica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de enfermedades raras en las que se acumulan demasiados histiocitos (tipo de glóbulo blanco) en determinados tejidos y órganos, como la piel, los huesos, el bazo, el hígado, los pulmones y los ganglios linfáticos. Esto en ocasiones produce daño en los tejidos o formación de tumores en una o más partes del cuerpo. Es posible que el tumor sea benigno (no canceroso) o maligno (canceroso). Hay diferentes tipos de neoplasias histiocíticas, como la histiocitosis de células de Langerhans (HCL), la linfohistiocitosis hemofagocítica (LHH) y los trastornos histiocíticos malignos. Las neoplasias histiocíticas  se pueden presentar  a cualquier edad, aunque son más frecuentes en la niñez. También se llama histiocitosis y neoplasia histiocitaria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-11-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2022-11-03</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
