<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000810987">
  <TermName>Elahere</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(el-ah-HEER)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with folate receptor alpha–positive ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer that has not gotten better after treatment with platinum chemotherapy. It is used in patients whose cancer was treated with one to three other systemic therapies. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Elahere contains a monoclonal antibody that binds to a protein called folate receptor alpha, which is found on some cancer cells. It also contains an anticancer drug, which may help kill cancer cells. Elahere is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called mirvetuximab soravtansine.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812269" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Elahere&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812270" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Elahere&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Elahere</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompas de Falopio o primario de peritoneo positivo para el receptor de folato alfa que no mejora después del tratamiento de quimioterapia con derivados del platino. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer se trató con 1 a 3 terapias sistémicas diferentes. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Elahere contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal que se une a una proteína llamada receptor de folato alfa que se encuentra en algunas células cancerosas. También contiene un medicamento contra el cáncer, que quizás ayude a destruir las células cancerosas. Elahere es un tipo de conjugado anticuerpo-fármaco. También se llama mirvetuximab soravtansina.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-12-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-04-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000811110" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/mirvetuximab-soravtansine-gynx">Mirvetuximab Soravtansine-gynx</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
