<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811137">
  <TermName>Krazati</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(krah-ZAH-tee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used alone or with cetuximab to treat adults with colorectal cancer or non-small cell lung cancer that has spread and has a certain mutation (change) in the 
      <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName>
       gene. It is used in patients whose cancer was treated with other systemic therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Krazati blocks a protein (KRAS G12C) made by the mutated 
      <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName>
       gene, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It is a type of targeted therapy. Also called adagrasib.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812281" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Krazati&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812282" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Krazati&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Krazati</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa, solo o con cetuximab, para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer colorrectal o cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se diseminó y presenta ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en el gen 
      <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName>
      . Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer se trató con otra terapia sistémica. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Krazati bloquea una proteína (KRAS G12C) que se origina a partir del gen 
      <GeneName>KRAS</GeneName>
       mutado, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas y las destruya. Es un tipo de medicamento de terapia dirigida. También se llama adagrasib.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2022-12-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-06-27</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000811191" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/adagrasib">Adagrasib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
