<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811118">
  <TermName>hedgehog signaling pathway</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(HEJ-hog SIG-nuh-ling PATH-way)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Describes a group of proteins that work together in a cell to send signals from the cell membrane to the nucleus. The hedgehog signaling  pathway is involved in cell growth and differentiation that occurs during the formation of tissues and organs in an embryo. It also plays an important role in the maintenance of stem cells (cells from which other types of cells develop) and in the repair and regeneration of adult tissues. Abnormalities in proteins that are part of the hedgehog signaling pathway may lead to birth defects or diseases such as cancer. Drugs that target this pathway are being used to treat some types of cancer. These drugs may help keep cancer cells from growing.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812277" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hedgehog signaling pathway&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812278" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vía de señalización del erizo&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>vía de señalización del erizo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Grupo de proteínas que trabajan juntas en una célula para enviar señales desde la membrana celular hasta el núcleo. La vía de señalización del erizo participa en la multiplicación celular y en la diferenciación que ocurre durante la formación de tejidos y órganos de un embrión. También tiene una función importante en el mantenimiento de células madre (células que dan origen a otros tipos de células) y en la reparación y regeneración de tejidos en adultos. Es posible que las alteraciones en las proteínas que conforman la vía de señalización del erizo produzcan anomalías congénitas o enfermedades como el cáncer. Los medicamentos dirigidos a esta vía de señalización se usan en el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Estos medicamentos quizás ayuden a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas. También se llama vía de señalización hedgehog.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-02-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000046477" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">cell differentiation</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000046477" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">diferenciación celular</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
