<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811175"><TermName>Adstiladrin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ad-STIH-luh-drin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with a certain type of high-risk bladder cancer that has not invaded the muscle layers of the bladder. It is used in patients whose cancer has not gotten better after treatment with Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Adstiladrin is a weakened adenovirus that carries a copy of the gene for interferon alfa-2b into bladder cancer cells. This may help the body’s immune system recognize the cancer cells and kill them.  Adstiladrin is given in a solution that is placed directly into the bladder using a thin tube called a catheter. It is a type of gene therapy. Also called nadofaragene firadenovec.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812285" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Adstiladrin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812286" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Adstiladrin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Adstiladrin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con un tipo determinado de cáncer de vejiga de riesgo alto que no ha invadido las capas musculares de la vejiga. Se emplea en pacientes cuyo cáncer no mejoró después del tratamiento con el bacilo de Calmette-Guérin (BCG). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Adstiladrin es un adenovirus atenuado que lleva una copia del gen para el interferón alfa-2b y lo introduce en las células del cáncer de vejiga. Esto tal vez posibilite que el sistema inmunitario reconozca las células cancerosas y las elimine.  Adstiladrin se administra como una solución que se introduce de forma directa en la vejiga a través de un tubo delgado llamado catéter. Es un tipo de terapia génica. También se llama nadofaragén firadenovec.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2022-12-22</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000811177" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/nadofaragene-firadenovec-vncg">Nadofaragene Firadenovec-vncg</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
