<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811116">
  <TermName>incomplete colonoscopy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(in-kum-PLEET KOH-luh-NOS-koh-pee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A colonoscopy that was attempted but could not be completed. A colonoscopy is an examination of the inside of the colon using a thin, lighted, tube-like instrument called a colonoscope to look for polyps, cancer, or other abnormal areas in the colon. An incomplete colonoscopy occurs when the health care provider is not able to advance the colonoscope through the entire colon to the cecum (a pouch that connects the colon to the small intestine). An incomplete colonoscopy is more likely to occur if the colon is not completely clear of stool or if a person has a low body weight, is a young female, or is having pain due to the test. Other factors that may lead to an incomplete colonoscopy include the presence of scar tissue, diverticulosis (small sacs or pouches in the walls of the colon), or a twisted, looped, or abnormally long colon.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812275" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;incomplete colonoscopy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000812276" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colonoscopia incompleta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000741570" type="image/jpeg" alt="Parts of the colon; drawing shows the ascending colon, cecum, transverse colon, descending colon, sigmoid colon, and rectum." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">The colon includes the ascending colon, cecum, transverse colon, descending colon, sigmoid colon, and rectum.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000743059" type="image/jpeg" alt="Partes del colon; el dibujo muestra el colon ascendente, el ciego, el colon transverso, el colon descendente, el colon sigmoide y el recto." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El colon comprende el colon ascendente, el ciego, el colon transverso, el colon descendente, el colon sigmoide y el recto.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>colonoscopia incompleta</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Colonoscopia que no fue posible completar. Una colonoscopia es un examen del interior del colon en el que se usa un colonoscopio (instrumento delgado en forma de tubo, con una luz) para encontrar pólipos, cáncer u otras áreas anormales. En una colonoscopia incompleta, el proveedor de atención de la salud no puede pasar  el colonoscopio a través de todo el colon para llegar al ciego (bolsa que conecta el intestino delgado con el colon). Es más probable que esto ocurra cuando quedan heces en el colon, la persona tiene un peso corporal bajo, es una mujer joven o siente dolor durante la prueba. Otros factores que a veces impiden que se complete la colonoscopia son la presencia de tejido cicatrizado, la diverticulosis (cavidades o bolsas pequeñas en las paredes del colon), así como un colon demasiado largo o que ha rotado  sobre sí mismo (vólvulo intestinal).</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-02-09</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2023-02-09</DateLastModified>
</GlossaryTerm>
