<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811264"><TermName>oral potentially malignant disorder</TermName><TermPronunciation>(OR-ul poh-TEN-shuh-lee muh-LIG-nunt dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of conditions in which  there are abnormal tissue changes in the mouth that may become cancer. These changes may include a lump, thickening, or abnormal patch of red and/or white tissue that forms on the lips, gums, tongue, inner lining of the cheeks, or other areas in the mouth. There are many different types of oral potentially malignant disorders, but the most common types are leukoplakia and erythroplakia. Oral potentially malignant disorders may occur in people who have certain rare hereditary conditions, including dyskeratosis congenita, epidermolysis bullosa, xeroderma pigmentosum, and Plummer-Vinson syndrome. Having an oral potentially malignant disorder increases a person’s risk of developing oral cancer.   Also called OPMD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812293" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oral potentially malignant disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000812294" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno oral potencialmente maligno&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>trastorno oral potencialmente maligno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de afecciones en las que se producen cambios anormales en el tejido de la boca y que a veces, se vuelven cancerosas. Es posible que estos cambios incluyan bultos, áreas endurecidas y manchas anormales de tejido rojo o blanco que se forman en los labios, las encías, la lengua, el interior de las mejillas, o en  las otras áreas de la boca. Hay muchos tipos diferentes de trastornos orales potencialmente malignos, pero los más comunes son la leucoplasia y la eritroplasia. A veces se presentan en personas que tienen ciertas afecciones hereditarias raras, como disqueratosis congénita, epidermólisis ampollosa, xeroderma pigmentoso y síndrome de Plummer-Vinson. Tener un trastorno oral potencialmente maligno aumenta el riesgo de una persona de presentar cáncer oral. También se llama lesiones orales potencialmente malignas, lesiones potencialmente malignas en la cavidad oral y TOPM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-02-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
