<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811568"><TermName>circulating tumor marker</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-kyoo-LAY-ting TOO-mer MAR-ker)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance, such as a protein or fragment of DNA, that is released into a person’s blood, urine, other body fluid, or stool by tumor cells or other cells of the body. Circulating tumor markers may be a sign of cancer or certain benign (noncancer) conditions. Measurements of circulating tumor marker levels in blood or other body fluid may be used along with results of other tests, such as biopsies and imaging, to help diagnose some types of cancer. Knowing the levels of circulating tumor markers may also help plan cancer treatment, make a likely prognosis, and find out how well treatment is working or if cancer has come back. Examples of circulating tumor markers include CA-125 (in ovarian cancer), calcitonin (in medullary thyroid cancer), <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName> mutations (in lung cancer), and beta-2-microglobulin (in multiple myeloma, chronic lymphocytic leukemia, and some lymphomas).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813978" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;circulating tumor marker&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813979" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;marcador tumoral circulante&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>marcador tumoral circulante</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia, como una proteína o un fragmento de ADN, que las células tumorales u otras células del cuerpo liberan en la sangre, la orina, otros líquidos corporales o las heces. Los marcadores tumorales circulantes a veces son un signo de cáncer o de ciertas afecciones benignas (no cancerosas). Las mediciones de las concentraciones de estos marcadores en sangre u otros líquidos corporales se usan con los resultados de otras pruebas, como biopsias e imágenes, para ayudar a diagnosticar algunos tipos de cáncer. Conocer las concentraciones de marcadores tumorales circulantes también puede ayudar a planificar el tratamiento del cáncer, determinar un pronóstico probable y  averiguar cuán bien está funcionando el tratamiento, o si el cáncer volvió. Algunos ejemplos de marcadores tumorales circulantes son el CA-125 (en el cáncer de ovario), la calcitonina (en el cáncer medular de tiroides), las mutaciones en <GeneName>EGFR</GeneName> (en el cáncer de pulmón) y la beta-2-microglobulina (en el mieloma múltiple, la leucemia linfocítica crónica y algunos linfomas).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-06-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2023-06-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/diagnosis/tumor-markers-fact-sheet">Tumor Markers</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/hoja-informativa-marcadores-de-tumores" UseWith="es">Marcadores tumorales</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
