<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811574"><TermName>acoustic neuroma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-KOOS-tik noor-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer) tumor that forms on the nerves in the inner ear and can affect hearing and balance. Acoustic neuromas usually grow slowly and affect one side of the body. Common signs and symptoms include hearing loss or ringing in one ear, loss of balance, dizziness, and numbness and paralysis in the face. Sometimes these tumors may grow large and press against the facial nerve or other nearby nerves. Rarely, they may press against certain parts of the brain, which could be life threatening. Acoustic neuromas that affect the nerves in both ears are often caused by a genetic disorder called neurofibromatosis type 2. Acoustic neuromas usually occur in people aged 30 to 60 years.
 Also called vestibular schwannoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813984" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acoustic neuroma&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813985" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neurinoma del acústico&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/><SpanishTermName>neurinoma del acústico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor benigno (no canceroso) que se forma en los nervios del oído interno y puede afectar la audición y el equilibrio. El neurinoma del acústico suele crecer de manera lenta y afectar un lado del cuerpo. Los signos y síntomas más frecuentes son pérdida de audición o zumbidos en un oído, pérdida del equilibrio, mareos y entumecimiento y parálisis facial (en la cara). A veces, estos tumores aumentan de tamaño y presionan el nervio facial u otros nervios cercanos. Además, en raras ocasiones presionan ciertas partes del cerebro, lo que podría poner en peligro la vida. El neurinoma del acústico que afecta los nervios de ambos oídos suele producirse debido a un trastorno genético denominado neurofibromatosis tipo 2. Por lo general, el neurinoma del acústico se presenta en personas de 30 a 60 años. También se llama neurinoma del nervio acústico, neurinoma vestibular, neuroma acústico y schwannoma vestibular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-06-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
