<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811577"><TermName>meningococcal disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(meh-NIN-jeh-KAH-kul dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A serious disease caused by infection with bacteria called <ScientificName>Neisseria meningitidis</ScientificName>. The bacteria can invade the blood, the thin layers of tissue that cover and protect the brain and spinal cord called the meninges, and rarely, the lungs. Meningococcal disease can be passed from one person to another through close contact with saliva, mucus, or other fluids from the nose, throat, or mouth. The signs and symptoms usually get worse very quickly. They include fever, headache, stiff neck, nausea, vomiting, confusion, sensitivity to light, a dark purple rash, fatigue, cold hands and feet, severe muscle or joint pain, rapid breathing, and diarrhea. Meningococcal disease is a life-threatening condition that can cause long-term problems, including brain or kidney damage, nervous system problems, hearing loss, and loss of arms, legs, fingers, or toes. It is more common in infants, teens, and young adults. Other people who are at increased risk of the disease include those with a weakened immune system, those who take certain medicines, college students who live in dorms, and those who travel to, work, or live in areas where the disease is more common.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813988" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;meningococcal disease&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000813989" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad meningocócica&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad meningocócica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad grave causada por la infección por una bacteria llamada <ScientificName>Neisseria meningitidis</ScientificName>. Esta bacteria puede penetrar en la sangre, las meninges (finas capas de tejido que cubren y protegen el encéfalo y la médula espinal) y, en raras ocasiones, los pulmones. La enfermedad meningocócica se transmite entre las personas mediante el contacto estrecho con saliva, mucosidades u otros fluidos de la nariz, la garganta o la boca. Los signos y síntomas suelen empeorar muy rápido e incluyen fiebre, dolor de cabeza, rigidez de cuello, náuseas, vómitos, confusión, sensibilidad a la luz, erupción cutánea de color morado oscuro, fatiga, manos y pies fríos, dolor muscular o articular intenso, respiración rápida y diarrea. La enfermedad meningocócica es una afección potencialmente mortal que puede causar problemas a largo plazo, como lesiones cerebrales o renales, problemas en el sistema nervioso, sordera y amputación  de brazos, piernas, dedos de las manos o de los pies. Es más frecuente en lactantes, adolescentes y adultos jóvenes. Otras personas con un riesgo mayor de contraer la enfermedad son aquellas que tienen el sistema inmunitario debilitado, las que toman determinados medicamentos, los estudiantes universitarios que viven en residencias universitarias y aquellas personas que viajan, trabajan o viven en zonas donde la enfermedad es más frecuente. También se llama meningococia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-06-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
