<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811572">
  <TermName>wheezing</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(WEE-zing)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A high-pitched, whistling sound that can occur during breathing when the airways in the lungs become narrowed or blocked. Wheezing is a sign that a person may be having trouble breathing. There are many causes of wheezing, but the most common causes are asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, bronchitis, and pulmonary edema. Other causes include cystic fibrosis, pneumonia or other respiratory infections, breathing a foreign object into the lungs, congestive heart failure, vocal cord problems, acid reflux disease, allergies, severe allergic reactions, certain medicines, smoking, or a tumor in the lung or airway.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813982" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;wheezing&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813983" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sibilancia&quot;" language="es" id="_7"/>
  <SpanishTermName>sibilancia</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Sonido agudo y silbante que puede producirse al respirar cuando las vías respiratorias de los pulmones se estrechan o bloquean. Las sibilancias son un signo de que una persona tiene problemas para respirar. Hay muchas causas de sibilancias, pero las más habituales son el asma, la enfermedad pulmonar obstructiva crónica, la bronquitis y el edema pulmonar. Otras causas son la fibrosis quística, la neumonía u otras infecciones respiratorias, la inhalación de un objeto extraño en los pulmones, la insuficiencia cardiaca congestiva, los problemas en las cuerdas vocales, la enfermedad por reflujo gastroesofágico, las alergias, las reacciones alérgicas graves, determinados medicamentos, el consumo de tabaco o un tumor en el pulmón o las vías respiratorias. También se llama estertor sibilante, respiración sibilante y sibilación.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-06-23</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
