<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811782">
  <TermName>DES son</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A male who was exposed before birth to a synthetic form of the hormone estrogen called diethylstilbestrol (DES) because their mother took DES while pregnant with them. DES was prescribed to some pregnant women between about 1940 and 1971 because it was thought to prevent miscarriage, premature labor, and other complications related to pregnancy. It was stopped in 1971 due to medical problems that were seen in the children of women who took it. DES sons have an increased risk of cysts in the testicles and may have other testicular problems, such as undescended testicles (a condition in which one or both testicles fail to move from the abdomen into the scrotum) and an increased risk of inflammation or infection of the testicles.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814008" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;DES son&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814009" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hijo expuesto al dietilestilbestrol&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hijo expuesto al dietilestilbestrol</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Varón que antes de nacer estuvo expuesto a una forma sintética de la hormona estrógeno llamada dietilestilbestrol (DES) porque su madre la tomó durante el embarazo. Entre 1940 y 1971, el dietilestilbestrol se recetó a algunas mujeres embarazadas porque se pensaba que evitaba abortos espontáneos, partos prematuros y otras complicaciones relacionadas con el embarazo. Se dejó de recetar en 1971 debido a los problemas médicos que se observaron en los hijos e hijas de las mujeres que lo tomaron. Los hijos con exposición a dietilestilbestrol presentan un mayor riesgo de quistes en los testículos y pueden tener otros problemas testiculares, como criptorquidia (una afección en la que uno o ambos testículos no pasan del abdomen al escroto) y un mayor riesgo de inflamación o infección de los testículos. También se llama hijo expuesto al DES.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-07-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/hormones/des-fact-sheet">Diethylstilbestrol (DES) Exposure and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/hormonas/hoja-informativa-des" UseWith="es">Exposición al dietilestilbestrol y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
