<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811780">
  <TermName>DES daughter</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… DAH-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A female who was exposed before birth to a synthetic form of the hormone estrogen called diethylstilbestrol (DES) because their mother took DES while pregnant with them. DES was prescribed for some pregnant women between about 1940 and 1971 because it was thought to prevent miscarriage, premature labor, and other complications related to pregnancy. It was stopped in 1971 due to medical problems that were seen in the children of women who took it. DES daughters were found to have an increased risk of precancerous lesions in the cervix and clear cell adenocarcinoma of the cervix or vagina. DES daughters may also have an increased risk of breast cancer, pancreatic cancer or other pancreatic disorders, cardiovascular disease, and depression. Other health problems that may have affected DES daughters include early menopause, fertility and pregnancy problems, and structural changes in the female reproductive tract.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814006" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;DES daughter&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814007" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hija expuesta al dietilestilbestrol&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>hija expuesta al dietilestilbestrol</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Mujer que antes de nacer estuvo expuesta a una forma sintética de la hormona estrógeno llamada dietilestilbestrol (DES) porque su madre la tomó durante el embarazo. Entre 1940 y 1971, el dietilestilbestrol se recetó a algunas mujeres embarazadas porque se pensaba que evitaba abortos espontáneos, partos prematuros y otras complicaciones relacionadas con el embarazo. Se dejó de recetar en 1971 debido a los problemas médicos que se observaron en los hijos e hijas de las mujeres que lo tomaron. Las hijas con exposición a dietilestilbestrol presentan un mayor riesgo de lesiones precancerosas en el cuello uterino y de adenocarcinoma de células claras en el cuello uterino o la vagina. También tienen mayor riesgo de cáncer de mama, cáncer de páncreas u otros trastornos pancreáticos, enfermedades cardiovasculares y depresión. Otros problemas de salud que pueden afectar a las hijas con exposición a dietilestilbestrol son menopausia precoz, problemas de fertilidad y embarazo, y cambios estructurales en el aparato reproductor femenino. También se llama hija expuesta al DES.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-07-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/hormones/des-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Diethylstilbestrol (DES) Exposure and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/hormonas/hoja-informativa-des" UseWith="es">Exposición al dietilestilbestrol y el cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
