<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811786">
  <TermName>miscarriage</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MIS-kayr-ij)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>An unexpected loss of pregnancy before the 20th week of pregnancy. Most miscarriages happen very early in pregnancy, often before a person even knows they are pregnant. Signs include vaginal spotting or bleeding, pain or cramping in the abdomen or lower back, and the passing of fluid or tissue from the vagina.  Miscarriages often occur because of genetic problems in the fetus. Maternal factors or conditions that could contribute to having a miscarriage include problems with the uterus or cervix, infection, hormone problems, severe malnutrition, smoking, drinking alcohol, taking certain medicines, or exposure to radiation. Being older or having certain diseases, such as polycystic ovary syndrome, uncontrolled diabetes, congenital heart disease, thyroid or kidney disease, and immune system disorders, may also put a person at higher risk of having a miscarriage. Also called spontaneous abortion.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814012" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;miscarriage&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814013" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aborto natural&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>aborto natural</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Pérdida inesperada del embarazo antes de la semana 20 de gestación. Por lo general, el  aborto natural sucede al principio del embarazo, a menudo incluso antes de que la persona sepa que está embarazada. Los signos incluyen manchado o sangrado vaginal, dolor o calambres en el abdomen o en la parte baja de la espalda y pérdida de líquido o tejido a través de la vagina. El  aborto natural suele producirse por problemas genéticos del feto. Los factores o afecciones maternos que quizás contribuyan a tener un aborto natural incluyen los siguientes: problemas en el útero o el cuello uterino, infecciones, problemas hormonales, desnutrición grave, fumar, beber alcohol, tomar ciertos medicamentos o la exposición a radiaciones. Una edad avanzada o presentar determinadas enfermedades, como el síndrome de ovario poliquístico, diabetes no controlada, cardiopatías congénitas, enfermedades tiroideas o renales y trastornos del sistema inmunitario, también pueden hacer que una persona tenga un mayor riesgo de tener un aborto natural. También se llama aborto espontáneo y aborto no provocado.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-07-07</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
