<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811796"><TermName>dermatoscope</TermName><TermPronunciation>(der-MA-toh-SKOPE)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A small, handheld device used to examine the skin, nails, scalp, and hair. A dermatoscope has a light and a special magnifying lens that can show skin lesions or other suspicious areas on the skin more clearly than the eye alone. Sometimes a thin layer of alcohol, gel, or oil is placed on the skin lesion to make it easier to see. Some dermatoscopes can also take pictures or videos of the area being examined. A dermatoscope may be used to help diagnose skin cancer or other skin-related conditions, such as vitiligo, scabies, and hair loss.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814018" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dermatoscope&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814019" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dermatoscopio&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>dermatoscopio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Pequeño dispositivo portátil que se usa para examinar la piel, las uñas, el cuero cabelludo y el cabello. Un dermatoscopio tiene una luz y una lupa especial que permite ver las lesiones en la piel u otras áreas sospechosas de la piel con más claridad que el ojo solo. A veces se coloca una fina capa de alcohol, gel o aceite sobre la lesión en la piel para facilitar su visualización. Con algunos dermatoscopios se pueden tomar fotografías o videos del área examinada. Es posible usarlo para ayudar a diagnosticar el cáncer de piel u otras afecciones cutáneas, como el vitíligo, la sarna o la caída del cabello. También se llama dermoscopio y microscopio de epiluminiscencia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-07-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
