<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000811800"><TermName>advanced practice provider</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ad-VANST PRAK-tis proh-VY-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A medical professional who is not a doctor but has special training and is licensed to diagnose, treat, and manage many common medical conditions. Advanced practice providers can perform physical exams, order laboratory tests and imaging tests, review test results, prescribe medications, perform or assist with certain procedures, such as biopsies, and make referrals to other health care providers. They may also provide information about screening tests and give counseling on living a healthy lifestyle, such as changes in diet and exercise and quitting smoking. Examples of advanced practice providers are nurse practitioners and physician assistants.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814022" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;advanced practice provider&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814023" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proveedor de práctica avanzada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>proveedor de práctica avanzada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Profesional de la medicina que no es médico, pero que ha recibido una formación especial y tiene autorización para diagnosticar, tratar y gestionar muchas afecciones comunes. Las personas que ejercen una práctica avanzada hacen exámenes físicos, solicitan pruebas de laboratorio y de imagen, revisan los resultados de pruebas, recetan medicamentos, realizan o ayudan con ciertos procedimientos, como biopsias, y derivan a los pacientes a otros profesionales de la salud. También pueden proporcionar información sobre pruebas de detección y asesorar sobre cómo llevar un estilo de vida saludable, por ejemplo, cambios en la dieta, ejercicio y dejar de fumar. Los enfermeros practicantes y los asociados médicos son ejemplos de proveedores de práctica avanzada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-07-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
