<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812045">
  <TermName>Zynyz</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ZY-niz)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with Merkel cell carcinoma (a type of skin cancer) that has come back or has spread to other parts of the body. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Zynyz binds to a protein called PD-1, which is found on T cells (a type of immune cell). Zynyz may block PD-1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called retifanlimab.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813021" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zynyz&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813022" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zynyz&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Zynyz</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con carcinoma de células de Merkel (tipo de cáncer de piel) que volvió o se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Zynyz se une a una proteína llamada PD-1, que se encuentra en las células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria). Es posible que Zynyz bloquee PD-1 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama retifanlimab.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-03-29</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000812014" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/retifanlimab-dlwr">Retifanlimab-dlwr</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
