<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812079"><TermName>adenovirus vector</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-deh-noh-VY-rus VEK-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of a common virus called adenovirus that is used to deliver genetic material, such as a new gene or a normal copy of a mutated (changed) gene, directly into the nucleus of a cell. Before adenovirus is used in this way, it is changed in the laboratory so that it cannot cause disease in people. When an adenovirus vector is used for gene therapy, a broken, defective, or missing gene inside the body's cells can be repaired or replaced with a healthy version of that gene. Adenovirus vectors may also carry genes that can change abnormal cells, such as cancer cells, back to normal. And they may be used in vaccines to help prevent certain types of viral infections.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814028" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenovirus vector&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814029" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vector de adenovirus&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>vector de adenovirus</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma de un virus común llamado adenovirus que se usa para transportar material genético, como un gen nuevo o una copia normal de un gen mutado (cambiado), directamente al interior del núcleo de una célula. Antes de usar el adenovirus de esta manera, este se modifica en el laboratorio para evitar que produzca enfermedades en las personas. Cuando se utiliza un vector de adenovirus en la terapia génica, es posible reparar o reemplazar  un gen roto, defectuoso o faltante por una versión sana de dicho gen. Los vectores de adenovirus, a veces, también portan genes que convierten las células anormales, como las células cancerosas, en células normales (sanas). Además, estos vectores se usan en vacunas que previenen ciertos tipos de infecciones por virus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-07-14</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
