<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812341">
  <TermName>mucosal human papillomavirus</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(myoo-KOH-sul HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A group of human papillomaviruses (HPV) that can infect the cells on the moist surfaces or inner lining of some organs and body cavities, such as the cervix, vagina, vulva, penis, anus, mouth, and throat. Mucosal human papillomaviruses can be grouped into high-risk HPV and low-risk HPV types. Low-risk HPV infections can cause warts on or around the genitals, anus, mouth, larynx, or other parts of the respiratory tract but rarely cause cancer.  A long-lasting infection with a high-risk HPV type can cause cell changes that become cancer over time if not found and removed. HPV-related cancers include cancers of the cervix, anus, oropharynx, vagina, vulva, and penis. Mucosal human papillomavirus is transmitted through intimate skin-to-skin contact, most often during vaginal, anal, or oral sex.  Also called mucosal HPV.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814034" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mucosal human papillomavirus&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814035" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;virus del papiloma humano mucosos&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>virus del papiloma humano mucosos</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Grupo de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) que infectan las células de las superficies húmedas o del revestimiento interno de algunos órganos y cavidades corporales, como el cuello uterino, la vagina, la vulva, el pene, el ano, la boca o la garganta. Los virus del papiloma humano mucosos se agrupan en  VPH de riesgo alto y VPH de riesgo bajo. Las infecciones por VPH de riesgo bajo pueden causar verrugas en, o alrededor de, los genitales, el ano, la boca, la laringe y en otras áreas de las vías respiratorias, pero rara vez producen cáncer.   La infección duradera por un tipo de VPH de riesgo alto  puede causar cambios en las células que, si no se encuentran y se extirpan, con el tiempo se vuelven cancerosos. Los cánceres relacionados con este grupo de virus son los de cuello uterino, ano, orofaringe, vagina, vulva y pene. Los virus del papiloma humano mucosos se trasmiten por el contacto íntimo piel con piel, en especial durante las relaciones sexuales vaginales, anales u orales. También se llama virus del papiloma humano de mucosas y VPH mucosos.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-07-07</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-09-25</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000753086" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">low-risk HPV</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000753086" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">VPH de riesgo bajo</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000753083" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">high-risk HPV</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000753083" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">VPH de riesgo alto</RelatedGlossaryTermRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-and-cancer" UseWith="en">HPV and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-vaccine-fact-sheet" UseWith="en">Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccines</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
