<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812588"><TermName>intubation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-too-BAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a tube is inserted through the mouth or nose into the trachea (windpipe) or into a hollow organ, such as the stomach. Intubation of the trachea is usually done to keep a person’s airway open so oxygen can flow into the lungs and to help a person breathe when they cannot breathe on their own. It may also be done to give medicine directly into the lungs, to keep food or fluid from getting into the lungs, or to remove blockages from the airway. Intubation of the stomach is usually done to remove air or other substances from the stomach or to give drugs or liquid foods into the stomach or small intestine.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814874" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intubation&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814875" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intubación&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>intubación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se inserta un tubo (sonda) por la boca o la nariz hasta llegar a la tráquea o un órgano hueco, como el estómago. La intubación de la tráquea  se suele hacer para mantener abiertas las vías respiratorias de forma que el oxígeno fluya hacia los pulmones  y la persona pueda respirar cuando no puede hacerlo por sí sola. La intubación también se usa para administrar medicamentos directamente en los pulmones, evitar la aspiración de alimentos y bebidas o  eliminar obstrucciones en las vías respiratorias. La intubación del estómago por lo general se usa para sacar aire u otras sustancias de este órgano, y para administrar medicamentos o alimentos líquidos dentro del estómago o el intestino delgado. También se llama entubación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-09-12</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
