<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812501">
  <TermName>Epkinly</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ep-KIN-lee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with certain types of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, high-grade B-cell lymphoma, or follicular lymphoma that came back or did not get better after treatment with at least two other systemic therapies. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Epkinly binds to a protein called CD3, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell). It also binds to a protein called CD20, which is found on B cells (another type of white blood cell) and some lymphoma cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Epkinly is a type of bispecific T-cell engager. Also called epcoritamab.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813041" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Epkinly&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000813042" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Epkinly&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Epkinly</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de linfoma difuso de células B grandes, linfoma de células B de grado alto o linfoma folicular que volvió o que no mejoró después de recibir, por lo menos, otras dos terapias sistémicas. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Epkinly se une a una proteína llamada CD3, que se encuentra en las células T (un tipo de glóbulo blanco). Además, se une a una proteína llamada CD20, que se encuentra en las células B (otro   tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunas células de linfoma. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Epkinly es un tipo de captador biespecífico de células T. También se llama epcoritamab.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-05-23</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-07-01</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000812508" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/epcoritamab-bysp">Epcoritamab-bysp</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
