<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812578"><TermName>gastric adenocarcinoma and proximal polyposis of the stomach</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GAS-trik A-deh-noh-KAR-sih-NOH-muh … PROK-sih-mul PAH-lee-POH-sis … STUH-muk)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder in which many polyps (usually hundreds) form in the lining of the upper part of the stomach. Polyps are abnormal growths that may become cancer if they are not removed. People with gastric adenocarcinoma and proximal polyposis of the stomach have an increased risk of developing a type of stomach cancer called intestinal gastric adenocarcinoma. This cancer begins in the mucus-producing cells in the innermost lining of the stomach. Gastric adenocarcinoma and proximal polyposis of the stomach is caused by certain mutations (changes) in a specific part of the <GeneName>APC</GeneName> gene. The age that people with one of these specific mutations in the <GeneName>APC</GeneName> gene develop gastric adenocarcinoma and proximal polyposis of the stomach varies. Also called GAPPS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814866" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gastric adenocarcinoma and proximal polyposis of the stomach&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814867" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenocarcinoma gástrico y poliposis proximal del estómago&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>adenocarcinoma gástrico y poliposis proximal del estómago</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario raro en el que se forman muchos pólipos (por lo general cientos) en el revestimiento de la parte superior del estómago. Los pólipos son bultos anormales que si no se extirpan se pueden volver cancerosos. Las personas con adenocarcinoma gástrico y poliposis proximal del estómago tienen más riesgo de presentar un tipo de cáncer de estómago llamado adenocarcinoma gástrico intestinal. Este cáncer comienza en las células que producen moco en el revestimiento más interno del estómago. La causa de este trastorno son ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en una parte determinada del gen <GeneName>APC</GeneName>. La edad a la que se presenta el adenocarcinoma gástrico y poliposis proximal del estómago en las personas con dichas mutaciones varía. También se llama adenocarcinoma gástrico asociado a poliposis proximal en estómago y GAPPS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-09-12</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/pediatric-adult-rare-tumor/rare-tumors/rare-digestive-system-tumors/gastric-adenocarcinoma-and-proxymal-polyposis" UseWith="en">Gastric Adenocarcinoma and Proximal Polyposis of the Stomach (GAPPS)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/pediatric-adult-rare-tumor/espanol/tumores-raros/tumores-raros-aparato-digestivo/adenocarcinoma-gastrico-y-poliposis-proximal" UseWith="es">Adenocarcinoma gástrico y poliposis proximal del estómago</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
