<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812603"><TermName>serrated polyp</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-ray-ted PAH-lip)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of polyp (abnormal growth) that usually forms on the inner lining of the colon or rectum but can also form in the appendix. Serrated polyps have a saw-tooth appearance when looked at under a microscope. There are three types of serrated polyps: hyperplastic polyps (HPs), sessile (flat) serrated polyps (SSPs, also known as sessile serrated adenomas or SSAs), and traditional serrated adenomas (TSAs). HPs are usually small and rarely become cancer. They are the most common type of serrated polyp. SSPs and TSAs are larger than HPs and are more likely to become cancer if they are not removed.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814880" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;serrated polyp&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814881" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pólipo serrado&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>pólipo serrado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de pólipo (bulto anormal) que suele formarse en el revestimiento interno (mucosa) del colon y el recto, pero que también se forma en el apéndice. Los pólipos serrados tienen el aspecto de dientes de sierra cuando se observan al microscopio. Hay tres tipos de pólipos serrados: pólipos hiperplásicos; pólipos serrados sésiles o planos, también conocidos como adenomas serrados sésiles; y adenomas serrados tradicionales. Los pólipos hiperplásicos por lo general son pequeños, es infrecuente que se vuelven cancerosos y son el tipo más común de pólipos serrados. Los pólipos serrados sésiles y los adenomas serrados tradicionales son más grandes que los pólipos hiperplásicos, y si no se extirpan, la probabilidad de que se vuelvan cancerosos es más alta. También se llama pólipo dentado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-09-12</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
