<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812871"><TermName>eHealth</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EE-helth)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The use of digital technology, such as computers, mobile devices, and the Internet, to deliver and manage health care information and services. Examples of eHealth include electronic medical records, telemedicine, patient portals (secure websites), mobile health applications (apps), wearable health tracking and monitoring devices, and online health education resources. The use of eHealth technology may help promote communication among patients, family members, and the health care team. It also may help patients learn more about their health and take an active role in managing it. eHealth may also help improve access to health care services, reduce costs, and improve the quality of care.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814886" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eHealth&quot;" language="en" id="_10"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814887" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;salud digital&quot;" language="es" id="_11"/><SpanishTermName>salud digital</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Uso de tecnología digital, como los computadores, los dispositivos móviles y el internet para proporcionar y gestionar la información y los servicios relacionados con el cuidado de la salud. Algunos ejemplos son los registros médicos electrónicos, la telemedicina, los portales para pacientes (sitios de internet seguros), las aplicaciones sanitarias para aparatos móviles, los dispositivos médicos portátiles para el seguimiento y supervisión del estado del paciente y los recursos de educación sanitaria en línea. Es posible que el uso de este tipo de tecnología ayude a fomentar la comunicación entre pacientes, familiares y el equipo de atención de la salud. También quizás sea útil para que los pacientes obtengan más información sobre su salud y desempeñen una función más activa en la gestión de esta. Además,  este tipo de tecnología tal vez favorezca el acceso a los servicios de salud, reduzca costos y mejore la calidad de la atención. También se llama cibermedicina, cibersalud, cibersanidad, e-salud, eSalud, salud electrónica y sanidad electrónica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-09-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
