<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812873"><TermName>prediabetes</TermName><TermPronunciation>(pree-dy-uh-BEE-teez)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A common condition in which glucose levels in the blood are higher than normal but not high enough to be diagnosed as type 2 diabetes. Having prediabetes increases the risk of developing type 2 diabetes, heart disease, and stroke. Prediabetes usually occurs when the body does not make enough insulin or use it the way it should. Most people with prediabetes do not have symptoms. 
There are many factors that may increase a person’s risk of developing prediabetes. These include being overweight; being age 45 years or older; having a parent, brother, sister, or child with type 2 diabetes; and not getting enough exercise. Certain health conditions, such as obesity, high blood pressure, abnormal cholesterol levels, heart disease, stroke, and polycystic ovary syndrome, can also increase a person’s risk of prediabetes. People who had diabetes during pregnancy, gave birth to a baby who weighed more than 9 pounds, or who are members of certain racial or ethnic groups also have an increased risk of prediabetes. Lifestyle changes, such as losing extra weight, eating a healthy diet, and getting regular exercise, can lower the risk of developing prediabetes or type 2 diabetes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814888" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prediabetes&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814889" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prediabetes&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/><SpanishTermName>prediabetes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección común en la que las concentraciones de glucosa en la sangre son más altas de lo normal, pero no lo suficiente como para diagnosticar diabetes de tipo 2. La prediabetes aumenta el riesgo de presentar diabetes de tipo 2, cardiopatía y accidente cerebrovascular. Suele aparecer cuando el cuerpo no produce la insulina que necesita o no la usa como debería. La mayoría de las personas con esta afección no presentan síntomas. Hay muchos factores de riesgo que aumentan la probabilidad de que una persona tenga prediabetes; entre ellos, el sobrepeso, tener 45 años o más; tener un padre o madre, hermano o hermana, hijo o hija con diabetes de tipo 2 y no hacer suficiente ejercicio. Ciertas afecciones médicas, como la obesidad, la hipertensión, las concentraciones anormales de colesterol, las cardiopatías, los accidentes cerebrovasculares y el síndrome de ovario poliquístico también pueden aumentar el riesgo de prediabetes. Asímismo, las personas que tuvieron diabetes durante el embarazo y cuyo bebé pesó más de 9 libras o aquellas que pertenecen a determinadas razas o grupos étnicos tienen más riesgo de prediabetes. Los cambios en el estilo de vida, como perder el exceso de peso, comer alimentos saludables y hacer ejercicio con regularidad pueden reducir el riesgo de presentar prediabetes o diabetes de tipo 2. También se llama diabetes asintomática, diabetes latente, diabetes química y diabetes subclínica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-09-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/prevention-type-2/prediabetes-prevent-type-2.html" UseWith="en">Prediabetes – Your Chance to Prevent Type 2 Diabetes (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/patientinstructions/000778.htm" UseWith="en">Prediabetes (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/es/prevention-type-2/la-prediabetes-su-oportunidad-para-prevenir-la-diabetes-tipo-2.html" UseWith="es">La prediabetes: su oportunidad para prevenir la diabetes tipo 2 (Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/patientinstructions/000778.htm">Prediabetes (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
