<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000812880"><TermName>chimerism</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KY-mer-ih-zum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which some cells or tissues in a person’s body contain at least two different sets of DNA. Chimerism can occur in different ways. One way it can occur is through an organ or stem cell transplant from another person (donor). After a stem cell transplant, the recipient has a mix of DNA from their own blood cells and DNA from the donor's transplanted cells. Another way chimerism can occur is through pregnancy, when some fetal cells are absorbed into the bloodstream of the pregnant person. The DNA from the fetal cells may remain in that person’s body tissues for many years after childbirth. Chimerism can also occur during a twin pregnancy when cells and genetic material are exchanged between twins or during early development when one twin absorbs cells from another twin who does not survive. Most people with chimerism rarely show visible signs and are unaware they have the condition. Chimerism is usually diagnosed through genetic testing.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814890" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chimerism&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814891" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;quimerismo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>quimerismo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que algunas células o tejidos del cuerpo de una persona contienen por lo menos dos tipos de ADN. El quimerismo se origina de diferentes maneras. Una de ellas es a través del trasplante de un órgano o médula ósea de otra persona (donante). Después de un trasplante de médula ósea, el receptor tiene una mezcla del ADN que proviene de sus propias células sanguíneas y el ADN de las células trasplantadas del donante. Otra forma de que se produzca quimerismo es a través del embarazo, cuando algunas células fetales entran en la corriente sanguínea de la persona embarazada. Es posible que el de ADN de las células fetales permanezca en los tejidos corporales muchos años después del parto. También puede ocurrir durante un embarazo gemelar al producirse un intercambio de células y material genético entre los gemelos, o durante el desarrollo temprano, cuando un gemelo absorbe las células del otro gemelo que no sobrevive. La mayoría de las personas con quimerismo no presentan signos visibles de la afección e ignoran que la tienen. Por lo general, el quimerismo se diagnostica mediante pruebas genéticas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-09-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
