<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813261">
  <TermName>luminal A breast cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LOO-mih-nul … brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A subtype of hormone receptor-positive breast cancer. Luminal A breast cancer cells typically have estrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PR) proteins inside them and a small amount or none of a protein called HER2 on their surface. Luminal A breast cancer cells also tend to have low levels of a protein called Ki-67, which is found only in cells that are dividing. Under a microscope, luminal A breast cancer cells look more like normal cells than other subtypes of breast cancer. They tend to grow slowly and have a good prognosis. Most breast cancers are luminal A.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815627" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;luminal A breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815628" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama luminal A&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama luminal A</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Subtipo de cáncer de mama positivo para receptores hormonales. Las células del cáncer de mama luminal A suelen tener en su interior unas proteínas llamadas receptores de estrógeno (ER) y receptores de progesterona (PR). También suelen tener en su  superficie una cantidad pequeña de una proteína llamada HER2, pero otras veces no tienen esta proteína HER2; además suelen presentar concentraciones bajas de una proteína llamada Ki-67, que solo se encuentra en las células que se están dividiendo. Al microscopio, las células del cáncer de mama luminal A se parecen más a las células normales que las de otros subtipos de cáncer de mama. Este tipo de cáncer suele crecer de forma lenta y tiene buen pronóstico. La mayoría de los cánceres de mama son de tipo luminal A. También se llama cáncer de seno luminal A.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-12-15</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
