<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813266">
  <TermName>Ki-67 proliferation index</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… proh-LIH-feh-RAY-shun …)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A way to measure how fast cancer cells in a tumor are dividing. Ki-67 is a protein that is found only in cells that are dividing. A high Ki-67 proliferation index means many cells are dividing quickly and that the cancer is likely to grow and spread. A Ki-67 proliferation index over 30% is typically considered high. The Ki-67 proliferation index may be used to help predict how well some cancers, such as breast cancer, will respond to certain treatments, such as chemotherapy. Also called Ki-67 score.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815633" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Ki-67 proliferation index&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815634" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;índice de proliferación Ki-67&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>índice de proliferación Ki-67</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Forma de medir la velocidad a la que se dividen las células cancerosas de un tumor. La Ki-67 es una proteína que solo se encuentra en las células que se están dividiendo. Un índice de proliferación Ki-67 alto significa que muchas células se dividen de forma rápida y que es probable que el cáncer crezca y se disemine. Un índice de proliferación Ki-67 superior al 30 % suele considerarse alto. Esta medida se puede usar para ayudar a predecir la respuesta de algunos tipos de cáncer, como el de mama, a determinados tratamientos, como la quimioterapia. También se llama puntuación de Ki-67.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-12-15</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
