<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813334"><TermName>CBD</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A chemical that comes from the hemp (<ScientificName>Cannabis sativa</ScientificName>) plant. CBD contains very low levels of delta-9-THC (the main chemical that causes the “high” of marijuana). It may help relieve pain, lower inflammation, and reduce anxiety without causing the mind-altering effects of marijuana. CBD comes in many forms, including oils, extracts, capsules, and patches. One specific form has been approved in the United States as a drug to treat seizures in certain people. CBD is also being studied in the treatment of symptoms or side effects caused by cancer and cancer treatment. It is a type of cannabinoid.  Also called cannabidiol.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>CBD</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia química procedente de la planta del cáñamo común (<ScientificName>Cannabis sativa</ScientificName>). El CBD contiene concentraciones muy bajas de delta-9-THC (la principal sustancia química que es responsable de los efectos de "subidón o droga" de la marihuana). Es posible que alivie el dolor, baje la inflamación y reduzca la ansiedad sin causar los efectos de la marihuana que alteran la mente. El CBD se presenta en muchas formas, como aceites, extractos, cápsulas y parches. En los Estados Unidos se ha aprobado una forma específica de esta sustancia como medicamento para tratar las convulsiones en determinadas personas. El CBD también está en estudio para el tratamiento de los síntomas y efectos secundarios causados por el cáncer y su tratamiento. Es un tipo de canabinoide. También se llama canabidiol.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-12-15</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000688139" url="/about-cancer/treatment/cam/patient/cannabis-pdq">Cannabis and Cannabinoids</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000775868" url="/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/mca/paciente/cannabis-pdq">Cannabis y canabinoides</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
