<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813463"><TermName>niraparib tosylate monohydrate and abiraterone acetate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(nih-RA-puh-rib TOH-suh-layt MAH-noh-HY-drayt … A-bih-RA-teh-rone A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A combination of two drugs used with prednisone to treat adults with prostate cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and is castration resistant (has not responded to treatments that lower testosterone levels). It is used in patients who have a certain type of abnormal <GeneName>BRCA</GeneName> gene.  Niraparib tosylate monohydrate blocks an enzyme involved in many cell functions, including the repair of DNA damage. Blocking this enzyme may help keep cancer cells from repairing their damaged DNA, causing them to die. Abiraterone acetate lowers the amount of androgens (male hormones), such as testosterone, made by the body. This may stop the growth of cancer cells that need androgens to grow. The combination of niraparib tosylate monohydrate and abiraterone acetate may work better than either drug alone. Niraparib tosylate monohydrate and abiraterone acetate is a type of PARP inhibitor and a type of antiandrogen.
 Also called Akeega.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814899" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;niraparib tosylate monohydrate and abiraterone acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814900" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib y acetato de abiraterona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib y acetato de abiraterona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento compuesto por una combinación de dos fármacos que se usa con prednisona para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de próstata que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y es resistente a la castración (no respondió a los tratamientos que disminuyen las concentraciones de testosterona). Se usa en pacientes con un tipo específico de gen <GeneName>BRCA</GeneName> anormal. El monohidrato de tosilato de niraparib bloquea una enzima que participa en muchas funciones celulares, entre ellas, la reparación del daño al ADN. Bloquear esta enzima quizás ayude a evitar que las células cancerosas reparen el daño a su ADN y esto las destruya. El acetato de abiraterona reduce la cantidad de andrógenos (hormonas masculinas), como la testosterona, que el cuerpo elabora. Es posible que esto impida la multiplicación de células cancerosas que necesitan andrógenos para hacerlo. En ocasiones, esta combinación de fármacos funciona mejor que cada uno solo. Este medicamento incluye un tipo de antiandrógeno y de inhibidor de PARP. También se llama Akeega.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-08-22</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000813502" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/niraparib-tosylate-monohydrate-and-abiraterone-acetate">Niraparib Tosylate Monohydrate and Abiraterone Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
