<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813454"><TermName>Talvay</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TAL-vay)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with multiple myeloma that came back or did not get better after treatment with at least four other anticancer therapies. These therapies had to  include an immunomodulating agent, a proteasome inhibitor, and an anti-CD38 monoclonal antibody. Talvay binds to a protein called CD3, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell), and to a protein called GPRC5D, which is found on myeloma cells and some other types of cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Talvay is a type of bispecific T-cell engager. Also called talquetamab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814897" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Talvay&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000814898" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Talvay&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Talvay</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con mieloma múltiple que volvió o no mejoró después del tratamiento con, al menos, otras cuatro terapias anticancerosas. Estas terapias tienen que haber incluido un inmunomodulador, un inhibidor del proteasoma y un anticuerpo monoclonal anti-CD38. Talvay  se une a una proteína llamada CD3, que se encuentra en las células T (tipo de glóbulo blanco), y a una proteína llamada GPRC5D, que se encuentra en las células del mieloma y en otros tipos de células. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Talvay  es un tipo de captador biespecífico de células T. También se llama talquetamab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-08-24</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000813524" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/talquetamab-tgvs">Talquetamab-tgvs</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
