<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813545">
  <TermName>NAFLD</TermName>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A common condition in which fat builds up in the liver of people who drink little or no alcohol. There are two types of NAFLD, simple or nonalcoholic fatty liver (NAFL) and nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). NAFL causes little or no inflammation or damage in the liver and usually does not cause serious liver problems. NASH is the more serious type of NAFLD. It can cause liver inflammation and damage to the cells in the liver. This may lead to cirrhosis (scarring of the liver), liver failure, or liver cancer. NAFLD usually affects  middle-aged and older adults but is becoming more common in children and teens. It is especially common in people who are overweight or who have obesity, diabetes, or high levels of cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat) in the blood. Also called nonalcoholic fatty liver disease.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <SpanishTermName>EHGNA</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección común por la que se acumula grasa en el hígado de las personas que consumen pocas o ninguna bebida alcohólica. Hay dos tipos de EHGNA: hígado graso simple (HGS) o no alcohólico  y esteatohepatitis no alcohólica (EHNA). La HGS produce poca o ninguna inflamación o daño hepático y por lo general no causa problemas graves de hígado. La EHNA es un tipo más grave de EHGNA. Las personas con esta afección presentan inflamación hepática y daño en las células del hígado. Esto en ocasiones causa cirrosis (tejido cicatricial en el hígado), insuficiencia hepática o cáncer de hígado. La EHGNA suele presentarse en adultos de mediana edad o mayores, aunque cada vez es más común en niños y adolescentes. Es frecuente en las personas con sobrepeso, obesidad, diabetes o concentraciones altas de colesterol y triglicéridos (tipo de grasa) en la sangre. También se llama enfermedad del hígado graso no alcohólico.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-12-20</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease/" UseWith="en">Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/fattyliverdisease.html" UseWith="es">¿Qué es la enfermedad del hígado graso no alcohólico? (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
