<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813558">
  <TermName>DNA ploidy</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(… PLOY-dee)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>In medicine, a measure of the amount of DNA or number of chromosomes in cancer cells compared to that in normal cells. Most human cells, except for egg and sperm cells, normally contain 46 chromosomes (23 pairs) in each cell. Cancer cells that have a DNA ploidy of 1 have about the same amount of DNA or number of chromosomes as normal cells. If the DNA ploidy is more than 1, the cancer cells have a higher-than-normal amount of DNA or extra chromosomes. The DNA ploidy may be used to help plan treatment and estimate prognosis for some types of cancer, such as leukemia and neuroblastoma. Also called DNA index.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815651" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;DNA ploidy&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815652" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ploidia de ADN&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <SpanishTermName>ploidia de ADN</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, medida del ADN o del número de cromosomas que tienen las células cancerosas comparada con la de una célula normal. La mayoría de las células humanas, excepto los óvulos y los espermatozoides, por lo general tienen un total de 46 (23 pares) cromosomas en cada célula. Las células cancerosas con una ploidía de ADN de 1 tienen casi la misma cantidad de ADN o número de cromosomas que una célula normal. Si la ploidia de ADN es más de 1, las células cancerosas tienen una cantidad más alta de la normal de ADN o cromosomas extra. Es posible usar la ploidia de ADN para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento y determinar el pronóstico en algunos tipos de cáncer, como la leucemia y el neuroblastoma. También se llama índice de ADN, ploidía de ADN y ploidia de DNA.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-12-20</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
