<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813575">
  <TermName>gastric cardia cancer</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(GAS-trik KAR-dee-uh KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A type of stomach cancer that begins in the mucous-producing cells in the inner lining of the cardia (the part of the stomach that is closest to the esophagus). Food and liquids pass through the cardia to enter the stomach from the esophagus. Risk factors associated with gastric cardia cancer include obesity, smoking tobacco, and gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD). Most gastric cardia cancers are adenocarcinomas.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815665" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gastric cardia cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815666" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cardias gástrico&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000791862" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of the stomach showing the cardia, the fundus, the body, the antrum, and the pylorus." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_2">
    <Caption language="en">The stomach is an organ in the upper abdomen. It can be divided into the cardia and the non-cardia, which includes the fundus, the body, the antrum, and the pylorus. The stomach is part of the digestive system.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000792160" type="image/jpeg" alt="Imagen del estómago en la que se observa el cardias, el fondo, el cuerpo, el antro y el conducto pilórico." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">El estómago es un órgano que se encuentra en la parte superior del abdomen. En la imagen se observa el cardias y el resto del estómago (región no cardial), que incluye el fondo, el cuerpo, el antro y el conducto pilórico. El estómago forma parte del aparato digestivo.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>cáncer de cardias gástrico</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer de estómago que surge en las células que producen mucosa del revestimiento interno del cardias (parte del estómago más cercana al esófago). Los alimentos y los líquidos pasan del esófago al estómago a través del cardias. Los factores de riesgo relacionados con el cáncer de cardias gástrico son la obesidad, el consumo de tabaco y la enfermedad por reflujo gastroesofágico (ERGE). La mayoría de los cánceres de cardias gástrico son adenocarcinomas.
 También se llama cáncer gástrico cardial.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-12-27</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/stomach" UseWith="en">What Is Stomach Cancer?</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/estomago" UseWith="es">¿Qué es el cáncer de estómago?</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
