<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813565"><TermName>non-myeloablative transplant</TermName><TermPronunciation>(non-MY-eh-loh-a-BLAY-tiv TRANZ-plant)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of donor stem cell transplant in which a patient receives lower doses of chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy than in a standard transplant. The lower doses of anticancer therapy do not kill all of the blood-forming stem cells or all of the cancer cells in the patient's bone marrow. However, the anticancer therapy is  still strong enough to suppress the patient's immune system and prevent rejection of the donor stem cells. The patient’s stem cells and those from the donor both live in the patient’s body for a time after a non-myeloablative transplant. Once the cells from the donor begin to grow and divide in the bone marrow, they replace the patient’s own bone marrow cells and destroy the remaining cancer cells. A non-myeloablative transplant may be an option for certain people who are older or who are not healthy enough to receive a standard donor stem cell transplant with high-dose chemotherapy. Also called mini-transplant and reduced-intensity transplant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;non-myeloablative transplant&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trasplante no mieloablativo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trasplante no mieloablativo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de trasplante de células madre de un donante en el que un paciente recibe dosis más bajas de quimioterapia o radioterapia que las de un trasplante estándar. Las dosis más bajas de terapia contra el cáncer no destruyen todas las células madre formadoras de sangre ni todas las células cancerosas en la médula ósea de un paciente. Sin embargo, la terapia contra el cáncer es de intensidad suficiente como para inhibir el sistema inmunitario del paciente y prevenir el rechazo de las células madre del donante. Las células madre del paciente y del donante conviven en el cuerpo del paciente, por cierto tiempo, después de un trasplante no mieloablativo. Cuando las células del donante empiezan a multiplicarse y dividirse en la médula ósea, remplazan las células de la médula ósea del paciente y destruyen las células cancerosas que quedaron. Un trasplante no mieloablativo puede ser una opción para algunas personas de edad avanzada o que no están lo suficientemente sanas como para recibir un trasplante estándar de células madre de un donante con dosis altas de quimioterapia. También se llama minitrasplante y trasplante de intensidad reducida.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-12-20</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/stem-cell-transplant" UseWith="en">Stem Cell Transplants in Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/trasplante-de-celulas-madre">Trasplantes de células madre en el tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
