<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813539"><TermName>fatty liver disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FA-tee LIH-ver dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A common condition in which fat builds up in the liver. In most people, fatty liver disease does not cause any symptoms or serious liver problems. However, in some cases, it can cause liver inflammation and damage to the cells in the liver. The two main types of fatty liver disease are alcoholic fatty liver disease (AFLD) and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). AFLD occurs in people who drink large amounts of alcohol. NAFLD occurs in people who drink little or no alcohol. It usually affects middle-aged and older adults but is becoming more common in children and teens. It is especially common in people who are overweight or who have obesity, diabetes, or high levels of cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat) in the blood. A severe form of NAFLD called nonalcoholic steatohepatitis can cause cirrhosis (scarring of the liver) that may lead to liver failure or liver cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815637" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fatty liver disease&quot;" language="en" id="_8"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815638" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad por hígado graso&quot;" language="es" id="_9"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad por hígado graso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección común por la que se acumula grasa en el hígado. En la mayoría de las personas, esta enfermedad no produce síntomas ni problemas graves de hígado. Sin embargo, en algunos casos, se presenta inflamación hepática y daño en las células del hígado. Los dos tipos principales de enfermedad por hígado graso son la enfermedad del hígado graso alcohólico (EHGA) y la enfermedad del hígado graso no alcohólico (EHGNA). La EHGA se presenta en las personas que consumen grandes cantidades de bebidas alcohólicas, mientras que la EHGNA se presenta en quienes consumen pocas o ninguna bebida alcohólica. Suele presentarse en adultos de mediana edad o mayores, aunque cada vez es más común en niños y adolescentes. Es frecuente en las personas con sobrepeso, obesidad, diabetes o concentraciones altas de colesterol y triglicéridos (tipo de grasa) en la sangre. La esteatohepatitis no alcohólica es una forma grave de la EHGNA que en ocasiones causa cirrosis (tejido cicatricial en el hígado) que a veces produce insuficiencia hepática o cáncer de hígado. También se llama esteatosis del hígado, esteatosis hepática, hígado adiposo y hígado graso.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2023-12-20</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://medlineplus.gov/fattyliverdisease.html" UseWith="en">Fatty Liver Disease (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/fattyliverdisease.html">Hígado graso (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
