<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000813795"><TermName>bispecific T-cell engager</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BY-speh-SIH-fik … en-GAY-jer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance made in the laboratory that can bind to two target proteins on the surface of different cells. For example, a bispecific T-cell engager may bind to a certain protein on healthy T cells (a type of immune cell) and, at the same time, to a different protein on cancer cells. This brings the T cells and cancer cells close together so the T cells can more effectively kill the cancer cells. Some bispecific T-cell engagers are being used to treat certain types of cancer, including acute lymphoblastic leukemia, multiple myeloma, lymphoma, and small cell lung cancer. They are a type of targeted therapy. Also called BiTE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bispecific T-cell engager&quot;" language="en" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>acoplador biespecífico de células T</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia producida en el laboratorio que se une a dos proteínas diferentes en la superficie de distintos tipos de células. Por ejemplo, es posible que un acoplador biespecífico de células T se una a cierta proteína en las células T (tipo de célula inmunitaria) sanas y al mismo tiempo se una a otra proteína en las células cancerosas. Esto hace que las células T se acerquen a las células cancerosas y las puedan destruir de manera más eficaz. Algunos acopladores biespecíficos de células T se usan para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como la leucemia linfoblástica aguda, el mieloma múltiple, el linfoma y el cáncer de pulmón de células pequeñas. Son un tipo de terapia dirigida. También se llama activador biespecífico de células T, anticuerpo biespecífico de células T, BiTE, captador biespecífico de linfocitos T y molécula biespecífica captadora de células T.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-02-09</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2024-06-13</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
