<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000814474">
  <TermName>capivasertib</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ka-PEE-vah-SER-tib)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A drug used with fulvestrant to treat adults with hormone-receptor positive, HER2-negative breast cancer that has spread and has an abnormal 
      <GeneName>PIK3CA</GeneName>
      , 
      <GeneName>AKT1</GeneName>
      , or 
      <GeneName>PTEN</GeneName>
       gene. It is used in patients whose cancer came back or got worse during or after treatment with hormone therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Capivasertib blocks a protein called AKT, which is involved in cell signaling, cell growth, and cell survival. Blocking this protein may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. Capivasertib is a type of kinase inhibitor. Also called Truqap.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814933" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;capivasertib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000814934" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;capivasertib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>capivasertib</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa con fulvestrant para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de mama negativo para HER2 y positivo para receptores hormonales que se diseminó y que tiene un gen 
      <GeneName>PIK3CA</GeneName>
      , 
      <GeneName>AKT1</GeneName>
       o 
      <GeneName>PTEN</GeneName>
       anormal. Se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer volvió o empeoró durante la terapia hormonal o después de esta. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El capivasertib bloquea una proteína llamada AKT, que participa en la señalización, multiplicación y supervivencia celular. Bloquear esta proteína quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas y es posible que las destruya. El capivasertib es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas. También se llama Truqap.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2023-11-27</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000814585" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/capivasertib">Capivasertib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
