<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000814531">
  <TermName>transcription factor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(tran-SKRIP-shun FAK-ter)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>One of a group of proteins that play an important role in controlling the activity of genes. Transcription factors help control when and how genes are turned on or off in a cell by binding to nearby DNA and to other DNA-associated proteins. This affects the production of RNA, which then affects the production of proteins and their many important cell functions. Mutations and other changes in transcription factor genes may cause abnormal transcription factor proteins to be made. These abnormal proteins may be too active or found in higher-than-normal amounts on or in some types of cancer cells, which may cause the cancer cells to grow. Drugs that block transcription factor proteins and proteins associated with them are being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816231" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;transcription factor&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816232" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;factor de transcripción&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>factor de transcripción</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Pertenece a un grupo de proteínas que cumplen una función importante en el control de la actividad de los genes. Los factores de transcripción ayudan a controlar cuándo y cómo se activan o desactivan los genes de una célula al unirse al ADN cercano y a otras proteínas relacionadas con el ADN. Esto afecta la producción de ARN, que a su vez afecta la elaboración de proteínas y sus numerosas e importantes funciones celulares. Es posible que las mutaciones y otros cambios en los genes de los factores de transcripción hagan que se elaboren proteínas de factores de transcripción anormales. Estas pueden ser demasiado activas o encontrarse en cantidades superiores a las normales en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, lo que quizás provoque su multiplicación. Para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer, están en estudio medicamentos que bloquean los factores de transcripción y las proteínas relacionados con ellos. También se llama factor de trascripción.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-04-16</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
