<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000814534">
  <TermName>Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ser-VAY-lents EH-pih-dee-mee-AH-loh-jee … reh-ZULTS PROH-gram)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A program of the National Cancer Institute that uses information collected by cancer registries to report on the number of new cases of cancer diagnosed and the number of cancer deaths across different geographic areas in the United States. These cancer statistics are updated every year and provide information on cancer cases based on patient demographics (such as age, gender, race, and ethnic group), the primary tumor site, the form and structure of the tumor, the stage of cancer at diagnosis, the first course of treatment, and patient survival information. The Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program also works with other organizations involved in cancer surveillance activities and supports research studies on cancer prevention and control. Also called SEER Program.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816235" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816236" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Programa de Vigilancia, Epidemiología y Resultados Finales&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Programa de Vigilancia, Epidemiología y Resultados Finales</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Programa del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer en el que se usa la información recopilada por los registros de cáncer para notificar el número de diagnósticos nuevos y muertes por cáncer en las distintas áreas geográficas de los Estados Unidos. Estos datos estadísticos se actualizan cada año y proporcionan información sobre los casos de cáncer según las características demográficas de los pacientes (como la edad, el sexo, la raza o el grupo étnico), el sitio del tumor primario, la forma y la estructura del tumor, el estadio del cáncer en el momento del diagnóstico, el primer curso de tratamiento y la supervivencia. El Programa de Vigilancia, Epidemiología y Resultados Finales también colabora con otras organizaciones que participan en actividades de vigilancia del cáncer y apoya estudios de investigación sobre la prevención y el control de esta enfermedad. También se llama Programa SEER.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-04-16</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://seer.cancer.gov/" UseWith="en">Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
