<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000814537"><TermName>CCDI</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A large effort led by the National Cancer Institute to collect, analyze, and share information to address the burden of cancer in children, adolescents, and young adults. The three main goals of CCDI are: (1) to collect data from every child, adolescent, and young adult diagnosed with cancer, (2) to create a national strategy of clinical and molecular testing to speed diagnosis and inform treatment for all types of childhood cancer, and (3) to develop a network of computer systems and programs  that merge clinical care and research data to improve prevention, treatment, quality of life, and survivorship for childhood cancers. Also called Childhood Cancer Data Initiative.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>CCDI</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Importante  iniciativa dirigida por el Instituto Nacional del Cáncer para recopilar, analizar y compartir información con el fin de hacer frente a la carga del cáncer durante la niñez, adolescencia y juventud. Los tres objetivos principales de esta iniciativa son los siguientes: 1) recopilar datos de todos los casos de diagnóstico de cáncer en niños, adolescentes y adultos jóvenes; 2) crear una estrategia nacional de exámenes clínicos y moleculares para acelerar el diagnóstico e informar sobre el tratamiento de todos los tipos de cáncer infantil; y 3) crear una red de sistemas y programas informáticos que fusionen datos de atención clínica e investigación para mejorar la prevención, el tratamiento, la calidad de vida y la supervivencia de los pacientes con cánceres infantiles. También se llama Iniciativa de Datos sobre el Cáncer Infantil.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-04-16</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.cancer.gov/research/areas/childhood/childhood-cancer-data-initiative" UseWith="en">Childhood Cancer Data Initiative (CCDI)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
