<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000814663"><TermName>magnetic resonance lymphangiography</TermName><TermPronunciation>(mag-NEH-tik REH-zuh-nunts lim-FAN-jee-AH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses radio waves, a powerful magnet, and a computer to make a series of detailed pictures of the lymphatic system. A dye is injected into the body to make the lymphatic vessels and lymph nodes easier to see. Magnetic resonance lymphangiography may be used to check for blockages or leaks in the lymphatic system and to help diagnose certain conditions, such as lymphedema or lymphoma, or find out whether cancer has spread. It may also be used to help plan treatment or find out how well treatment is working. Magnetic resonance lymphangiography is sometimes used before surgery to learn more about the structure of a person's lymphatic system. Also called MRL.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815687" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;magnetic resonance lymphangiography&quot;" language="en" id="_9"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815688" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfangiografía por resonancia magnética&quot;" language="es" id="_10"/><SpanishTermName>linfangiografía por resonancia magnética</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usan ondas de radio, un imán potente y una computadora para crear una serie de imágenes detalladas del sistema linfático. Se inyecta un tinte en el cuerpo para que los vasos y los ganglios linfáticos se vean con más claridad. linfangiografía por resonancia magnética sirve para comprobar si hay obstrucciones o fugas en el sistema linfático y para ayudar a diagnosticar determinadas afecciones, como el linfedema o el linfoma, o averiguar si el cáncer se diseminó. También se utiliza para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento o determinar si es eficaz. Este procedimiento a veces se usa antes de una cirugía para saber cómo se ve la estructura del sistema linfático de una persona. También se llama linfo-resonancia magnética, linfografía mediante imagen por resonancia magnética y LRM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-03-01</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
