<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815033">
  <TermName>lifileucel</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LIH-fih-LOO-sel)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      A treatment used for adults with melanoma that has spread to other parts of the body or cannot be removed by surgery. It is used in patients whose cancer did not get better after treatment with an antibody that blocks PD-1 (and treatment with a BRAF inhibitor, for those with a 
      <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>
       mutation). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Lifileucel is made using tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (a type of immune cell that can recognize and kill tumor cells) from a patient’s tumor. These lymphocytes are tested in the laboratory to find out which ones best recognize the tumor cells. The selected lymphocytes are then grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given back to the patient to help the immune system kill the tumor cells. Lifileucel is a type of cellular immunotherapy called tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte therapy. Also called Amtagvi.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815697" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lifileucel&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815698" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lifileucel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>lifileucel</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Tratamiento que se usa en adultos con melanoma que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo o que no es posible extirpar mediante cirugía. Se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer no mejoró después del tratamiento con un anticuerpo que bloquea PD-1 (y  tratamiento con un inhibidor de BRAF, para aquellos con una mutación en 
      <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>
      ). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El lifileucel se produce a partir de linfocitos infiltrantes tumorales (tipo de célula inmunitaria que reconoce y destruye células tumorales) del tumor de un paciente. Estos linfocitos se analizan en el laboratorio para encontrar aquellos que reconocen mejor las células tumorales. A continuación, los linfocitos seleccionados se multiplican en grandes cantidades en el laboratorio y se devuelven al paciente para ayudar al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. El lifileucel es un tipo de inmunoterapia celular denominada terapia con linfocitos infiltrantes tumorales. También se llama Amtagvi.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-03-26</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000815042" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/lifileucel">Lifileucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
