<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815102"><TermName>effective radiation dose</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-FEK-tiv RAY-dee-AY-shun …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An estimate of the overall risk of potential harm from exposure to ionizing radiation. Ionizing radiation can come from natural sources, such as radon and radiation from outer space, and from medical imaging tests, such as x-rays, CT scans, or PET scans. The effective radiation dose is calculated based on certain factors, such as the type of radiation and its likelihood to cause harm, the amount of radiation absorbed by all organs of the body, and the sensitivity of different tissues and organs to radiation. The effective radiation dose is used to compare different levels of exposure to ionizing radiation in a population. It does not predict the risk of health effects from radiation exposure in individual people. Effective radiation dose may help in understanding the risk of potential long-term health effects from radiation exposure, such as the risk of developing cancer later in life. It is used to set radiation safety standards in health care and other industries. Sievert (Sv) is the unit of measurement for effective radiation dose.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815701" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;effective radiation dose&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000815702" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dosis efectiva de radiación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>dosis efectiva de radiación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Valor estimado del riesgo general de daño por la exposición a la radiación ionizante. La radiación ionizante proviene de fuentes naturales, como el radón y la radiación del espacio exterior (cosmos). También proviene de fuentes artificiales, como los aparatos médicos que se usan para hacer pruebas por imágenes: radiografías, tomografías computarizadas (TC) y tomografías por emisión de positrones (TEP). La dosis efectiva de radiación se calcula a partir de ciertos factores, como el tipo de radiación y el potencial que tiene para causar daños; la cantidad de radiación absorbida por todos los órganos del cuerpo; y la sensibilidad de los diferentes tejidos y órganos a la radiación. La dosis efectiva de radiación se usa para comparar diferentes niveles de exposición a la radiación ionizante en una población. No predice el riesgo de efectos en la salud de cada persona por la exposición, pero quizás sea útil para entender los posibles efectos a largo plazo de la exposición en la salud, como el riesgo de cáncer futuro. Se usa para establecer las normas de seguridad en la industria sanitaria entre otras funciones. La unidad de medida de la dosis efectiva de radiación es el sievert (Sv).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-03-12</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
