<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815394">
  <TermName>nogapendekin alfa inbakicept</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(noh-GAP-en-DEH-kin AL-fuh in-BAK-ih-sept)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used with bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG) to treat adults with bladder cancer that has not invaded the muscle layers of the bladder and with carcinoma in situ. Patients may or may not have a papillary tumor (a tumor that looks like long, thin “finger-like” growths). Nogapendekin alfa inbakicept is used in patients whose cancer has not gotten better after treatment with BCG. It is given with BCG as a solution through a catheter (thin tube) that is placed into the bladder. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Nogapendekin alfa inbakicept binds to receptors for the protein  interleukin-15 (IL-15), which is found on certain types of immune cells. This may help the immune cells kill cancer cells better than BCG alone. Nogapendekin alfa inbakicept is a type of IL-15 receptor agonist and a type of immunotherapy. Also called Anktiva.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816251" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nogapendekin alfa inbakicept&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816252" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nogapendekin alfa inbakicept&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>nogapendekin alfa inbakicept</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Medicamento que se usa con el bacilo de Calmette-Guérin (BCG) para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer vesical que no se ha diseminado a las capas musculares de la vejiga y que tienen carcinoma 
      <Emphasis>in situ</Emphasis>
       con tumor papilar (tumor con aspecto de bultos en forma de dedos largos y delgados) o sin este.  El nogapendekin alfa inbakicept se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer no mejoró después del tratamiento con el BCG. Se administra en forma de solución, junto con el BCG, a través de un catéter (tubo delgado) que se coloca en la vejiga. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.  El nogapendekin alfa inbakicept se une a los receptores de la proteína interleucina-15 (IL-15), que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células inmunitarias. Es posible que esto ayude a que las células inmunitarias destruyan más células cancerosas que el BCG solo.  El nogapendekin alfa inbakicept es un tipo de agonista del receptor de  IL-15 y un tipo de inmunoterapia. También se llama Anktiva.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-05-01</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000815439" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/nogapendekin-alfa-inbakicept-pmln">Nogapendekin Alfa Inbakicept-pmln</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
