<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815400"><TermName>tovorafenib</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TOH-voh-RA-feh-nib)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat children aged 6 months and older with low-grade glioma (a type of brain tumor) that has certain mutations (changes) in the <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> gene. It is used in patients whose tumor came back or did not get better after treatment with other therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Tovorafenib blocks certain proteins made by the mutated <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> gene, which may help keep tumor cells from growing. It is a type of kinase inhibitor. Also called Ojemda.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000816255" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tovorafenib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000816256" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tovorafenib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tovorafenib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de niños de 6 meses o más con un glioma de grado bajo (tipo de tumor de encéfalo) que tiene ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en el gen <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName>. Se usa en pacientes cuyo tumor recidivó (volvió) o no mejoró después de recibir otras terapias. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El tovorafenib bloquea ciertas proteínas que se originan del gen <GeneName>BRAF</GeneName> mutado, lo que quizás ayude a impedir la multiplicación de células tumorales. Es un tipo de inhibidor de tirosina–cinasas. También se llama Ojemda.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-05-06</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000815450" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tovorafenib">Tovorafenib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
