<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815503"><TermName>strabismus</TermName><TermPronunciation>(struh-BIZ-mus)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which both eyes do not line up with one another in the same direction when looking at an object. For example, one eye may look straight ahead while the other eye turns inward toward the nose. When this occurs, two different images are sent to the brain, one from each eye. In children with strabismus, the brain may learn to ignore the image from one eye. If not treated, this can lead to permanent vision loss in that eye. Strabismus is usually caused by problems with how the muscles involved in eye movement are controlled by the brain. It can occur at any age but is more common in children. There are different forms of strabismus. The most common form is called crossed eyes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817377" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;strabismus&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817378" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;estrabismo&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>estrabismo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección en la que los ojos no miran en la misma dirección al enfocar un objeto. Por ejemplo, un ojo mira hacia el frente mientras que el otro se desvía hacia la nariz. Cuando esto ocurre, se envían dos imágenes diferentes al  cerebro, una de cada ojo. Si el estrabismo se presenta en la niñez, es posible que el cerebro aprenda a ignorar la imagen de uno de los ojos. El estrabismo puede llevar a una ceguera permanente en ese ojo si no se administra tratamiento. La causa del estrabismo son problemas en el control cerebral del movimiento de los músculos de los ojos. Se puede presentar a cualquier edad, aunque es más común en la niñez. Hay diferentes formas de estrabismo, pero la más común se llama estrabismo convergente o  interno. También se llama bizquera y heterotropía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-10-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
