<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815507">
  <TermName>folate receptor alpha positive</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(FOH-layt reh-SEP-ter-AL-fuh PAH-zih-tiv)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Describes cells that have a protein called folate receptor alpha on their surface. This protein is involved in the movement of folate into cells. Folate is a nutrient rapidly dividing cells need to make and repair DNA. Some ovary, breast, lung, and endometrium cancers may be folate receptor alpha positive. Cancer cells that make too much folate receptor alpha may grow more quickly and spread to other parts of the body. Knowing whether a cancer is folate receptor alpha positive may help plan treatment.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817381" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;folate receptor alpha positive&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817382" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;positiva para el receptor de folato alfa&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>positiva para el receptor de folato alfa</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Característica de una célula que tiene en su superficie una proteína llamada receptor de folato alfa. Esta proteína permite la entrada  del folato  a las células. El folato es un nutriente que necesitan las células que se dividen rápido para reparar el ADN. Algunos cánceres de ovario, mama, pulmón y endometrio son positivos para el receptor de folato alfa. Es posible que las células cancerosas que producen demasiada  proteína receptora de folato alfa se multipliquen más rápido y se diseminen a otras partes del cuerpo. Saber si un cáncer es positivo para el  receptor de folato alfa es útil para planificar el tratamiento. También se llama célula que expresa el receptor de folato alfa.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-10-28</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
