<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815526"><TermName>mosaic Down syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(moh-ZAY-ik … SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of Down syndrome caused by having an extra chromosome 21 in some of the body’s cells. Cells with an extra chromosome 21 have three copies of it, while the other cells have two copies. Down syndrome is a genetic condition marked by certain physical features, delays (growth, development, and learning), and other health problems. People with mosaic Down syndrome can have the same physical features and health and learning problems as those who have other types of Down syndrome, but how mosaic Down syndrome presents can vary depending on how many cells have the extra chromosome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817385" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mosaic Down syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817386" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Down en mosaico&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Down en mosaico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma del síndrome de Down causada por la presencia de un cromosoma 21 adicional en algunas células del cuerpo. Estas células tienen tres copias del cromosoma 21 y el resto de las células tienen dos copias. El síndrome de Down es una afección genética caracterizada  por determinados rasgos físicos, retrasos (crecimiento, desarrollo y aprendizaje) y otros problemas de salud. Es posible que las personas con síndrome de Down en mosaico tengan los mismos rasgos físicos, problemas de salud y dificultades de aprendizaje que las personas con otros tipos de síndrome de Down, pero las manifestaciones varían según qué cantidad de células contienen el cromosoma extra. También se llama mosaicismo del síndrome de Down y trisomía 21 en mosaico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-10-29</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000045488" UseWith="en" audience="Patients">Down syndrome</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000045488" UseWith="es" audience="Patients">síndrome de Down</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
