<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815618">
  <TermName>Imdelltra</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(im-DEL-trah)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with extensive-stage small cell lung cancer that got worse during or after treatment with platinum chemotherapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Imdelltra binds to a protein called CD3, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell). It also binds  to a protein called DLL3, which is found on some types of cancer cells. This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Imdelltra is a type of bispecific T-cell engager.  Also called tarlatamab.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816261" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Imdelltra&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000816262" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Imdelltra&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>Imdelltra</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de pulmón de células pequeñas en estadio extendido que empeoró durante o después del tratamiento con quimioterapia con derivados del platino. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Imdelltra se une a una proteína llamada CD3, que se encuentra en las células T (tipo de glóbulo blanco). También se une a otra proteína llamada DLL3, que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que esto ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Imdelltra es un tipo de captador biespecífico de células T. También se llama tarlatamab.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-05-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000815621" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/tarlatamab-dlle">Tarlatamab-dlle</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
