<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815763">
  <TermName>chronic kidney disease</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(KRAH-nik KID-nee dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition in which the kidneys become damaged slowly over time and are not able to remove waste products and extra water from the blood to make urine. This can cause an imbalance of important minerals and chemicals in the body. Chronic kidney disease usually gets worse over time and can lead to kidney failure and other health problems, such as heart disease, stroke, anemia, bone disease, and malnutrition. Most people with chronic kidney disease do not have symptoms until the disease is very advanced. The two most common causes of chronic kidney disease are diabetes and high blood pressure. Other risk factors include heart disease, obesity, smoking, older age, and having a family history of kidney disease or failure. There is no cure for chronic kidney disease, but certain medicines, such as those that lower blood pressure or manage blood sugar levels, and healthy behaviors, such as eating a healthy diet, exercising regularly, losing extra weight, and quitting smoking, can help manage the disease. Chronic kidney disease is common among adults in the United States. Also called CKD.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817389" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chronic kidney disease&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817390" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad renal crónica&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>enfermedad renal crónica</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección en la que los riñones se dañan de manera progresiva con el paso del tiempo y dejan de filtrar los desechos y el exceso de agua de la sangre para producir la orina. Esto puede provocar desequilibrio de minerales y sustancias químicas importantes en el cuerpo. La enfermedad renal crónica suele empeorar con el tiempo y convertirse en una insuficiencia del riñón  causando otros problemas de salud, como cardiopatía (enfermedad del corazón), ictus (accidente cerebrovascular), anemia, enfermedad ósea y desnutrición. La mayoría de las personas con enfermedad renal crónica no presentan síntomas  hasta que la enfermedad está muy avanzada. Las dos casusas principales de esta enfermedad son la diabetes y la presión arterial alta. Otros factores de riesgo son la cardiopatía, la obesidad, el consumo de tabaco, la edad avanzada y los antecedentes familiares de enfermedad o insuficiencia renal. Esta enfermedad no es curable, pero el tratamiento con determinados medicamentos, como aquellos que bajan la presión arterial o controlan el azúcar sanguíneo,   además de los hábitos saludables, como llevar una buena alimentación, practicar ejercicio  con regularidad, perder el exceso de peso y dejar de fumar, pueden ayudar a controlar esta enfermedad. La enfermedad renal crónica es frecuente entre las personas adultas en los Estados Unidos. También se llama ERC y nefropatía crónica.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-11-01</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/000471.htm">Chronic kidney disease (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.niddk.nih.gov/health-information/kidney-disease/chronic-kidney-disease-ckd" UseWith="en">Chronic Kidney Disease (CKD)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/ency/article/000471.htm">Enfermedad renal crónica (MedlinePlus)</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef xref="https://www.niddk.nih.gov/health-information/informacion-de-la-salud/enfermedades-rinones/informacion-general" UseWith="es">Información general sobre la enfermedad de los riñones</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
