<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000815790"><TermName>imetelstat sodium</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ih-MEH-tel-stat SOH-dee-um)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat low-risk or intermediate-1 risk myelodysplastic syndromes in adults with anemia. It is used in patients who need regular red blood cell transfusions and did not respond to or cannot be treated with an erythropoiesis-stimulating agent. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Imetelstat sodium binds to an enzyme called telomerase, which is found at high levels in certain types of cells, including cancer cells. Blocking the activity of this enzyme may help keep cancer cells from growing and dividing and cause them to die. Imetelstat sodium is a type of enzyme inhibitor. Also called Rytelo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000816267" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;imetelstat sodium&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000816268" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;imetelstat sódico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>imetelstat sódico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de los síndromes mielodisplásicos de riesgo bajo o intermedio 1 en adultos con anemia. Se usa en pacientes que necesitan transfusiones frecuentes de glóbulos rojos y cuya anemia no respondió a un medicamento estimulante de la eritropoyesis o que no es posible tratar con este tipo de medicamentos. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El imetelstat sódico se une a una enzima llamada telomerasa, que se encuentra en concentraciones elevadas en ciertos tipos de células, incluidas las cancerosas. El bloqueo de la actividad de esta enzima en las células cancerosas quizás ayude a evitar su formación y multiplicación y provocar su destrucción. Es un tipo de inhibidor enzimático. También se llama Rytelo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-06-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000815811" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/imetelstat-sodium">Imetelstat Sodium</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
