<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816297">
  <TermName>mammary Paget disease</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(MA-muh-ree PA-jet dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare type of breast cancer that involves the nipple and, usually, the areola (the darker circle of skin around the nipple). Symptoms of mammary Paget disease include itching, tingling, or redness in the nipple and/or areola; flaking, crusty, or thickened skin on or around the nipple; a flattened nipple; and yellowish or bloody discharge from the nipple. The affected breast may also have one or more tumors. Most people with mammary Paget disease also have ductal carcinoma in situ (stage 0 breast cancer) or invasive breast cancer. Also called Paget disease of the breast and Paget disease of the nipple.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817399" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mammary Paget disease&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817400" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad de Paget mamaria&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000815603" type="image/jpeg" alt="Illustration of Paget disease of the breast. Drawing shows a front view of the breast with redness and crusting of the nipple and areola. Also shown is a cross section of the breast with cancer cells in the breast ducts." language="en" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_3">
    <Caption language="en">Paget disease of the breast is a rare type of cancer involving the nipple and usually the areola (the darker circle of skin around the nipple). Symptoms usually include redness in the nipple and/or areola and itchy, crusty, flaking, or thickened skin on or around the nipple.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817021" type="image/jpeg" alt="Enfermedad de Paget de la mama. En el dibujo se muestra una vista frontal de la mama donde el pezón y la aréola están enrojecidos y con costras. También se muestra una vista lateral de la mama con células cancerosas en los conductos mamarios." language="es" audience="Patients" placement="image-center" id="_4">
    <Caption language="es">La enfermedad de Paget de la mama es un tipo de cáncer raro que afecta el pezón y a menudo también la aréola (círculo de piel más oscura que rodea el pezón).  Los síntomas por lo general incluyen enrojecimiento del pezón y la aréola, así como picazón, formación de costras, descamación o engrosamiento de la piel que rodea el pezón.</Caption>
  </MediaLink>
  <SpanishTermName>enfermedad de Paget mamaria</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>
      Tipo raro de cáncer de mama que compromete el pezón y, por lo general, la aréola (círculo de piel oscura que rodea el pezón). Los síntomas de la enfermedad de Paget mamaria incluyen picazón, hormigueo o enrojecimiento del pezón o la aréola; descamación, costras o engrosamiento de la piel del pezón y alrededor de este; pezón aplanado y secreción amarillenta o sanguinolenta que sale por el pezón. La mama (seno) afectada a veces presenta uno o más tumores. La mayoría de las personas con enfermedad de Paget mamaria también presentan un carcinoma ductal 
      <Emphasis>in situ</Emphasis>
       (cáncer de mama en estadio 0) o cáncer de mama invasivo. También se llama cáncer de Paget de la mama, carcinoma de Paget de la mama, enfermedad de Paget de la mama y enfermedad de Paget del pezón.
    </DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-10-28</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-10-28</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/paget-breast-fact-sheet">Paget Disease of the Breast</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-paget-seno">Enfermedad de Paget de seno</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
