<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816531"><TermName>afamitresgene autoleucel</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-fam-ih-TRES-jeen AW-toh-LOO-sel)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A treatment used for adults with synovial sarcoma that has the MAGE-A4 antigen and has spread to other parts of the body or cannot be removed by surgery. It is used in patients who have certain HLA-A*02 antigens and have received chemotherapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Afamitresgene autoleucel is made using a patient’s T cells (a type of immune system cell). A special T-cell receptor that can recognize the MAGE-A4 antigen is added to the T cells in the laboratory. These changed T cells are then grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given back to the patient by infusion. Afamitresgene autoleucel binds to the MAGE-A4 antigen, which is found on some types of cancer cells. This helps the body’s immune system kill cancer cells. Afamitresgene autoleucel is a type of cellular immunotherapy. Also called Tecelra.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817403" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;afamitresgene autoleucel&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817404" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;afamitresgén autoleucel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>afamitresgén autoleucel</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tratamiento que se usa en adultos con sarcoma sinovial que presenta el antígeno MAGE-A4 y que se ha diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo o no se puede extirpar con cirugía. Se usa en pacientes con ciertos antígenos HLA-A*02  que recibieron quimioterapia. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El afamitresgén autoleucel se elabora con las células T del paciente (tipo de célula del sistema inmunitario). En el laboratorio, se añade a la célula T un receptor de célula T especial capaz de reconocer el antígeno MAGE-A4. Estas células T modificadas se producen en grandes cantidades en el laboratorio y se devuelven al paciente mediante infusión. El afamitresgén autoleucel se une al antígeno MAGE-A4, que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Esto ayuda al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inmunoterapia celular. También se llama Tecelra.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-08-12</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000816534" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/afamitresgene-autoleucel">Afamitresgene Autoleucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
