<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816539"><TermName>Voranigo</TermName><TermPronunciation>(voh-rah-NEE-goh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults and children aged 12 years and older with grade 2 astrocytoma or oligodendroglioma (types of brain tumors) that has an abnormal <GeneName>IDH1</GeneName> or <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> gene. It is used in patients who had a biopsy or surgery to remove the tumor. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Voranigo blocks the proteins made by the mutated <GeneName>IDH1</GeneName> and <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> genes, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of enzyme inhibitor and a type of targeted therapy. Also called vorasidenib citrate.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817407" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Voranigo&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817408" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Voranigo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Voranigo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento en adultos y niños de 12 años o más con astrocitoma u oligodendroglioma (tipos de tumores de encéfalo) de grado 2 que presentan un gen <GeneName>IDH1</GeneName> o <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> anormal. Se usa en pacientes a los que se les hizo una biopsia o una cirugía para extirpar el tumor. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Voranigo bloquea las proteínas que se originan de los genes <GeneName>IDH1</GeneName> y <GeneName>IDH2</GeneName> mutados, lo que quizás ayude a impedir la multiplicación de células tumorales. Es un tipo de inhibidor enzimático y de terapia dirigida. También se llama citrato de vorasidenib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-08-19</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000816536" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/vorasidenib-citrate">Vorasidenib Citrate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
