<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816544">
  <TermName>leuprolide mesylate</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LOO-proh-lide MEH-zih-layt)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with advanced prostate cancer. Leuprolide mesylate initially causes the pituitary gland to make more luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), temporarily increasing testosterone levels in men. With continued use, leuprolide mesylate lowers the amount of LH and FSH the pituitary gland releases, leading to a drop in testosterone levels. Leuprolide mesylate may stop the growth of cancer cells that need testosterone to grow. It is a type of hormone therapy called a luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH)  agonist. Also called Camcevi.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817409" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leuprolide mesylate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817410" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesilato de leuprorelina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>mesilato de leuprorelina</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de próstata avanzado. Al principio, el mesilato de leuprorelina hace que la hipófisis produzca más hormona luteinizante (LH) y hormona foliculoestimulante (FSH), lo que aumenta de forma temporal la concentración de testosterona en los hombres. Con el uso continuo, reduce la cantidad de LH y FSH que libera la hipófisis, lo que disminuye la concentración de testosterona. El mesilato de leuprorelina en ocasiones detiene la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan testosterona para multiplicarse. Pertenece a un grupo de medicamentos de terapia hormonal llamados agonistas de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante (LHRH). También se llama Camcevi.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-08-14</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2025-01-09</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000816535" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/leuprolide-mesylate">Leuprolide Mesylate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
