<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816654"><TermName>magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography</TermName><TermPronunciation>(mag-NEH-tik REH-zuh-nunts koh-LAN-jee-oh-PAN-kree-uh-TAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a magnet, radio waves, and a computer to make a series of detailed pictures of the liver, bile ducts, gallbladder, pancreas, and pancreatic duct. A dye may be injected into the body to make the ducts and organs easier to see. Magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography may be used to help diagnose certain conditions, such as gallstones, inflammation of the pancreas or gallbladder, and bile duct or pancreatic duct problems. It may also be used to help diagnose certain types of cancer, such as bile duct cancer (cholangiocarcinoma) and pancreatic cancer. Magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography is a type of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Also called MRCP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817767" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817768" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colangiopancreatografía por resonancia magnética&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>colangiopancreatografía por resonancia magnética</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usan un imán, ondas de radio y una computadora para crear una serie de imágenes detalladas del hígado, las vías o conductos biliares, la vesícula biliar, el páncreas y el conducto pancreático. En ocasiones, se inyecta un tinte en el cuerpo para que los conductos y órganos se vean con más claridad. La colangiopancreatografía por resonancia magnética se usa para ayudar a diagnosticar ciertas afecciones, como cálculos biliares, inflamación del páncreas o la vesícula biliar y problemas en las vías biliares o el conducto pancreático. También se usa para ayudar a diagnosticar ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de vías biliares (colangiocarcinoma) y el cáncer de páncreas. La colangiopancreatografía por resonancia magnética es un tipo de imagen por resonancia magnética (IRM). También se llama colangiopancreatografía magnética y MRCP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-12-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
