<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816658">
  <TermName>wasting syndrome</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(WAY-sting SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A condition marked by a loss of more than 10% of body weight, including loss of muscle mass and fat, in a person who is not trying to lose weight. Some people with wasting syndrome may also have diarrhea or weakness and fever that have lasted at least 30 days. Wasting syndrome is a sign of malnutrition and can happen when there are changes in the way the body uses nutrients from food. This may be caused by certain factors, such as inflammation and increased metabolism. Wasting syndrome is most common in people with advanced cancer or other chronic diseases, such as AIDS, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, and congestive heart failure. Wasting syndrome is hard to reverse once it starts and usually happens at the end of life. Also called cachexia.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817769" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;wasting syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_7"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817770" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome consuntivo&quot;" language="es" id="_8"/>
  <SpanishTermName>síndrome consuntivo</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Afección caracterizada por una pérdida de más del 10 % del peso corporal, que incluye pérdida de masa muscular y grasa, en una persona que no está tratando de perder peso. Algunas personas con síndrome consuntivo también presentan diarrea,  debilidad o fiebre que duran por lo menos 30 días. Esta afección es un signo de desnutrición que ocurre cuando cambia la manera como el cuerpo usa los nutrientes de los alimentos debido a ciertos factores, como inflamación o aumento del metabolismo. El síndrome consuntivo es más frecuente en personas con cáncer avanzado u otras enfermedades crónicas, como el SIDA, la enfermedad pulmonar obstructiva crónica o la insuficiencia cardiaca congestiva. Es difícil de revertir una vez que comienza y suele ocurrir al final de la vida. También se llama caquexia, síndrome de consunción, síndrome de desgaste, síndrome de deterioro progresivo y síndrome de emaciación.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-12-03</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-12-03</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/side-effects/cancer-cachexia">Cancer Cachexia</RelatedExternalRef>
    <RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="https://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/efectos-secundarios/caquexia-cancer">Caquexia por cáncer</RelatedExternalRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
