<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816733"><TermName>Tecentriq Hybreza</TermName><TermPronunciation>(teh-SEN-trik hy-BREE-zuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A combination of two drugs used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of alveolar soft part sarcoma (a type of soft tissue tumor), hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), melanoma, non-small cell lung cancer, and small cell lung cancer. Atezolizumab binds to a protein called PD-L1, which is found on some normal cells and some types of cancer cells. Atezolizumab may block PD-L1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. Hyaluronidase allows atezolizumab to be given by injection under the skin. Tecentriq Hybreza can be given in less time than atezolizumab alone, which is given as an infusion. Also called atezolizumab and hyaluronidase.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817421" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Tecentriq Hybreza&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817422" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Tecentriq Hybreza&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Tecentriq Hybreza</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Combinación de dos medicamentos que se usa sola o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de sarcoma alveolar de partes blandas (tipo de tumor de tejidos blandos), carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), melanoma, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas y cáncer de pulmón de células pequeñas. El atezolizumab se une a una proteína llamada PD-L1, que se encuentra en algunas células normales y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que esta unión bloquee la PD-L1 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir las células cancerosas. La hialuronidasa permite que el atezolizumab se administre mediante una inyección debajo de la piel. La administración  de Tecentriq Hybreza es más rápida que la del atezolizumab solo, que se hace mediante infusión. También se llama atezolizumab y hialuronidasa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-09-30</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000816789" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/atezolizumab-and-hyaluronidase-tqjs">Atezolizumab and Hyaluronidase-tqjs</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
