<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816813">
  <TermName>ribociclib succinate and letrozole</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(RY-boh-SY-klib SUK-sih-nayt … LEH-truh-zole)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A combination pack of two drugs used to treat adults with certain types of hormone-receptor positive, HER2-negative breast cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ribociclib succinate blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor. Letrozole lowers the amount of estrogen made by the body, which may stop the growth of cancer cells that need estrogen to grow. It is a type of aromatase inhibitor. Ribociclib succinate and letrozole may work better than either drug alone. Also called Kisqali Femara Co-Pack.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817423" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ribociclib succinate and letrozole&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817424" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;succinato de ribociclib y letrozol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>succinato de ribociclib y letrozol</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Combinación de dos medicamentos que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer de mama negativo para HER2 y positivo para receptores hormonales. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El succinato de ribociclib bloquea ciertas proteínas, lo que quizás ayude a evitar la multiplicación de células cancerosas; es un tipo de inhibidor de cinasas dependientes de ciclinas. El letrozol disminuye la cantidad de estrógeno que produce el cuerpo, lo que quizás impida la multiplicación de las células cancerosas que necesitan estrógeno para su desarrollo; es un tipo de inhibidor de la aromatasa. Es posible que la combinación de succinato de ribociclib y letrozol funcione mejor que cualquiera de los dos medicamentos por separado. También se llama Kisqali Femara Co-Pack.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-10-04</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000816806" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/ribociclib-succinate-and-letrozole">Ribociclib Succinate and Letrozole</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
