<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816962"><TermName>juicing</TermName><TermPronunciation>(JOO-sing)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The process of extracting the liquid contents from fruits and vegetables. This results in a drink that contains water, vitamins, minerals, and antioxidants but no fiber. Juicing may also refer to a diet in which some or all of a person’s calories come from fresh juice. Fresh juice can be made from a single type of fruit, vegetable, or combination. Drinking fresh juice can be part of a balanced diet. It may help people get nutrients from fruits and vegetables they would normally not eat. There is no proof that drinking fresh juice can slow, cure, or keep diseases such as cancer from coming back.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;juicing&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817776" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extracción de jugos&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/><SpanishTermName>extracción de jugos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el que se extrae el contenido líquido de frutas y verduras cuyo resultado es una bebida o licuado que contiene agua, vitaminas, minerales y antioxidantes, pero sin fibra. Este proceso se usa para la jugoterapia, una dieta a base de jugos en la que algunas o todas las calorías que ingiere una persona proceden de jugo fresco, que se elabora a partir de un solo tipo de fruta o verdura, o de una combinación. El consumo de jugos puede ser parte de una dieta equilibrada y es posible que facilite la obtención de nutrientes de frutas y verduras que normalmente la persona no consumiría. No se ha comprobado que beber jugos frescos retrase, cure, evite la reaparición de enfermedades como el cáncer. También se llama elaboración de jugos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2024-12-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
