<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000816964">
  <TermName>zolbetuximab</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(ZOL-beh-TUK-sih-mab)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used with chemotherapy containing fluoropyrimidine and platinum to treat adults with gastric (stomach) cancer or gastroesophageal junction cancer that has the CLDN18.2 protein, is HER2-negative, and has spread to other parts of the body or cannot be removed by surgery.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Zolbetuximab binds to CLDN18.2, which is found on the surface of some cancer cells. This may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Vyloy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817777" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;zolbetuximab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817778" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;zolbetuximab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>zolbetuximab</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se combina con quimioterapia de fluoropirimidina y derivados del platino. Se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con cáncer de estómago (gástrico) o cáncer de unión gastroesofágica que presenta la proteína CLDN18.2, es negativo para HER2, y se ha diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo o no se puede extirpar con cirugía.  También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El zolbetuximab se une a CLDN18.2, que se encuentra en la superficie de algunas células cancerosas. Es posible que esto ayude a evitar que las células cancerosas se multipliquen y las destruya. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Vyloy.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-11-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <DateLastModified>2024-11-21</DateLastModified>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000816969" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/zolbetuximab-clzb">Zolbetuximab-clzb</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
