<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000817081">
  <TermName>obecabtagene autoleucel</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(OH-beh-KAB-tuh-jeen AW-toh-LOO-sel)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A drug used to treat adults with acute lymphoblastic leukemia that came back or did not get better during or after other treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Obecabtagene autoleucel is made using a patient’s T cells (a type of immune system cell). A gene for a special receptor called chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) is added to the T cells in the laboratory. These changed T cells called CAR T cells are grown in large numbers in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. Obecabtagene autoleucel binds to a protein called CD19, which is found on some leukemia cells. This helps the body’s immune system kill cancer cells. Obecabtagene autoleucel is a type of CAR T-cell therapy. Also called Aucatzyl.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817789" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;obecabtagene autoleucel&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817790" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;obecabtagén autoleucel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/>
  <SpanishTermName>obecabtagén autoleucel</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento de adultos con leucemia linfoblástica aguda que reapareció o no mejoró durante o después de otro tratamiento. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. El obecabtagén autoleucel se elabora con las células T del paciente (tipo de célula del sistema inmunitario). En el laboratorio, se añade a la célula T un receptor especial llamado receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR). Estas células T modificadas, llamadas células T con CAR, se producen en grandes cantidades en el laboratorio y se administran al paciente mediante infusión. El obecabtagén autoleucel se une a una proteína llamada CD19 que se encuentra en algunas células leucémicas. Esto ayuda al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. El obecabtagén autoleucel es un tipo de terapia de células T con CAR. También se llama Aucatzyl.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2024-11-21</DateFirstPublished>
  <RelatedInformation>
    <RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000817079" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/obecabtagene-autoleucel">Obecabtagene Autoleucel</RelatedDrugSummaryRef>
  </RelatedInformation>
</GlossaryTerm>
