<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000817251">
  <TermName>Leydig cell tumor</TermName>
  <TermPronunciation>(LY-dig sel TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation>
  <TermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>A rare tumor that usually forms in the testicles. It may also form in the ovaries, but this is very rare. Leydig cell tumors make a male sex hormone called testosterone. These tumors can cause early puberty and an abnormal growth of breast tissue in males. In females, they can cause male features such as facial hair and a deep voice. Leydig cell tumors are usually benign (not cancer), but they may sometimes become malignant (cancer). Leydig cell tumors tend to have a good prognosis if diagnosed and treated early. They can occur in both adults and children. Leydig cell tumors are a type of sex cord-stromal tumor.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </TermDefinition>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817805" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Leydig cell tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/>
  <MediaLink ref="CDR0000817806" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor de células de Leydig&quot;" language="es" id="_5"/>
  <SpanishTermName>tumor de células de Leydig</SpanishTermName>
  <SpanishTermDefinition>
    <DefinitionText>Tumor raro que, por lo general, se forma en los testículos. También se presenta en los ovarios, pero esto es muy poco frecuente. Estos  tumores de células de Leydig producen una hormona sexual masculina llamada testosterona. En los hombres, estos tumores pueden causar pubertad precoz y crecimiento anormal del tejido mamario. En las mujeres, pueden provocar rasgos masculinos, como vello facial y voz grave. Estos tumores suelen ser benignos (no cancerosos), aunque algunos se vuelven malignos (cancerosos). Suelen tener buen pronóstico si se diagnostican y tratan a tiempo. Se presentan tanto en adultos como en niños. Los tumores de células de Leydig son un tipo de tumor de estroma de cordón sexual. También se llama tumor de células intersticiales de testículo.</DefinitionText>
    <Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary>
    <Audience>Patient</Audience>
  </SpanishTermDefinition>
  <DateFirstPublished>2025-02-14</DateFirstPublished>
</GlossaryTerm>
