<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000817313"><TermName>pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik DUK-tul A-deh-noh-KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The most common type of pancreatic cancer. Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma forms in exocrine cells of the pancreas. Exocrine pancreas cells make up the glands and ducts that produce enzymes (digestive juices) to help with digestion. Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma occurs when exocrine cells grow out of control and form a tumor. Factors that may increase a person’s risk of developing pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma include having a family history of the disease, chronic pancreatitis (inflammation of the pancreas), certain genetic syndromes, type 2 diabetes, excess body weight or obesity, exposure to certain chemicals, and smoking. It is usually found at an advanced stage because it usually does not cause symptoms early on. Also called PDAC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>adenocarcinoma ductal de páncreas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo más común de cáncer de páncreas. El adenocarcinoma ductal de páncreas surge en las células exocrinas del páncreas. Estas células forman las glándulas y los conductos que elaboran las enzimas (jugos digestivos) que ayudan en la digestión. El adenocarcinoma ductal de páncreas se produce cuando las células exocrinas crecen sin control y forman un tumor. Los factores que aumentan el riesgo de adenocarcinoma ductal de páncreas incluyen tener antecedentes familiares de la enfermedad, pancreatitis crónica (inflamación del páncreas), determinados síndromes genéticos, diabetes tipo 2, o sobrepeso u obesidad, así como la exposición a determinadas sustancias químicas o el consumo de tabaco. Suele detectarse en una fase avanzada porque no causa síntomas al inicio. También se llama adenocarcinoma pancreático ductal y ADP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2025-04-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
