<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000817320"><TermName>Opdivo Qvantig</TermName><TermPronunciation>(op-DEE-voh kyoo-VAN-tig)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A combination of two drugs used alone or with other drugs to treat adults with certain types of colorectal cancer, esophageal cancer, gastric (stomach) cancer, gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma, hepatocellular carcinoma (a type of liver cancer), melanoma, non-small cell lung cancer, renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer), squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck, and urothelial carcinoma (a type of cancer in the bladder or urinary tract). Nivolumab binds to a protein called PD-1, which is found on some normal cells and some types of cancer cells. Nivolumab may block PD-1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. Hyaluronidase allows nivolumab to be given by injection under the skin. Opdivo Qvantig can be given in less time than nivolumab alone, which is given as an infusion. Also called nivolumab and hyaluronidase.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817829" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Opdivo Qvantig&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000817830" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Opdivo Qvantig&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Opdivo Qvantig</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Combinación de dos medicamentos que se usa sola o con otros medicamentos para el tratamiento de adultos con ciertos tipos de cáncer colorrectal, cáncer de esófago, cáncer gástrico (estómago), adenocarcinoma de unión gastroesofágica, carcinoma hepatocelular (tipo de cáncer de hígado), melanoma, cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas, carcinoma de células renales (tipo de cáncer de riñón), carcinoma de células escamosas de cabeza y cuello y carcinoma urotelial  (tipo de cáncer de vejiga o de aparato urinario). El nivolumab se une a una proteína llamada PD-1, que se encuentra en algunas células normales y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Es posible que esta unión bloquee la PD-1 y ayude al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. La hialuronidasa permite que el nivolumab se administre mediante una inyección debajo de la piel. La administración de Opdivo Qvantig es más rápida que la del nivolumab solo, que se hace mediante infusión. También se llama nivolumab y hialuronidasa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2025-02-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-03-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000817349" url="/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/nivolumab-and-hyaluronidase-nvhy">Nivolumab and Hyaluronidase-nvhy</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
