<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000817729"><TermName>stage I ovarian borderline tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… oh-VAYR-ee-un BOR-der-line tumor)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes. Stage I is divided into stages IA, IB, and IC. In stage IA, the tumor is found inside a single ovary or fallopian tube. In stage IB, the tumor is found inside both ovaries or fallopian tubes. In stage IC, the tumor is found inside one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and one of the following is true: (1) the tumor ruptured (broke open) during surgery; or (2) the capsule (outer covering) of the ovary ruptured before surgery, or there are tumor cells on the surface of the ovary or fallopian tube; or (3) tumor cells are found in the fluid of the peritoneal cavity (the body cavity that contains most of the organs in the abdomen) or in washings of the peritoneum (tissue lining the peritoneal cavity). Also called stage I ovarian low malignant potential tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>tumor limítrofe de ovario en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios, o en una o ambas trompas de Falopio. El estadio l se divide en los estadios lA, lB y lC. En el estadio lA, el tumor se encuentra en el interior de un solo ovario o una sola trompa de Falopio. En el estadio IB, el tumor se encuentra en el interior de ambos ovarios o ambas trompas de Falopio. En el estadio lC, el tumor se encuentra en el interior de uno o ambos ovarios, o una o ambas trompas de Falopio, y se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor se rompió (se abrió) durante la cirugía; 2) la cápsula (revestimiento externo) del ovario se rompió antes de la cirugía o se encuentran células tumorales en la cubierta exterior del ovario o la trompa de Falopio; 3) se encuentran células tumorales en el líquido de la cavidad peritoneal (cavidad del cuerpo que contiene la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen) o en los lavados del peritoneo (tejido que reviste la cavidad peritoneal). También se llama tumor de ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio I.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2025-03-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2025-03-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062968" url="/types/ovarian/patient/ovarian-low-malignant-treatment-pdq">Ovarian Borderline Tumors Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256839" url="/espanol/tipos/ovario/paciente/tratamiento-ovario-bajo-potencial-maligno-pdq">Tratamiento de los tumores limítrofes de ovario</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
